covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias it's official
japanese giant toshiba has sold its
final stake in the personal computer
maker dino book
which means the firm no longer has a
connection with making pcs
or laptops sharp bought 80 of toshiba's
personal computing arm in 2018 for 36
million dollars
27 million pounds and has now bought the
remaining shares
toshiba said in a statement toshiba's
first laptop the t-1000
1100 the t1100 launched in 1985.
it weighed four kilograms and worked
with three and a half
inch floppy disks according to the
toshiba science museum website it was
launched only in europe at first
and had an annual sales target of just
10 000
units in the year 2011 toshiba sold more
than
17 million pcs but my how times have
changed
by 2017 this had fallen to just 1.9
million
in 2016 it had ceased making consumer
laptops for the european market
focusing only on hardware for businesses
recent years have been difficult for the
conglomerate in 2015 the firm
posted a full year loss of 318 million
dollars
that same year its president and vice
president resigned
after an independent panel found the
company had overstated its profits for
the previous six
years last year they wound up their
nuclear business new gen in the uk
after failing to find a buyer for it
consumer demand
for laptops has soared in the last few
months because of the coronavirus
pandemic
and global lockdowns but overall the
market for personal computers has been
tough for quite a while
analyst marina kocheva from the firm ccs
insight says only those who have managed
to sustain
scale and price like lenovo or have a
premium brand like
apple have succeeded in the unforgiving
pc market where volumes have been
falling for years
you