covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias the bbc micro
bit mini computer used by
millions of school children around the
world is receiving its first major
update since
2016. formerly a bbc
led project it is now led by a
foundation that aims to make coding
accessible for children the bbc microbit
is designed to inspire young people
providing the key knowledge
understanding and skills to become
creators
not just users of technology
the latest version of the microbit has
all the features of the original
and some fantastic extras so you can
learn and play
in new and exciting ways the new model
includes a speaker and microphone as
well as a capacitive touch sensor
the device will be released in november
with prices starting at 11 pounds 50
a bit more than 14 u.s gareth stockdale
chief executive of the microbit
educational foundation said
the purpose of the microbit is to help
children unlock their creative potential
and learn how to shape the world around
them he believes that learning coding
and computational thinking
can enhance skills that will help them
in their careers in the 21st century
since its launch the microbit has been
designed for education
with an estimated 25 million children
learning computer skills on the device
in over 60 countries the previous model
launched in the uk in 2016 with the bbc
giving away a free micro bit to every
grade 7 student
it is now used in most secondary schools
as well as primary schools
universities and libraries the
foundation has also donated 5000 devices
to families in the uk
to help with homeschooling during the
covet 19 pandemic
the micro bid is a palm size circuit
board with an array of 25 lights that
can be programmed
to show letters numbers and other shapes
and a bluetooth chip
for wireless connectivity as the
hardware is most powerful
sorry is now powerful enough to run
machine learning systems
the foundation has plans to expand into
this area
in future big thanks to roy w
nash and our community of viewers for
submitting stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
you