hello this is
uh category five coffee break
uh today is sunday the 11th of october
2020.
uh i'm bp 9. hello and
with me we have sobu give us a way of
sobu and we have doug
give us a wave doug and uh we've got
peter here
in the uh in in the uh meeting but uh
i've got no audio from peter so i don't
know what's
going on right now can you hear me now
oh rather i do have good audio i'm sorry
we do have good audio i've got no video
from you peter
your audio's perfect but i've just got
no camera
okay let me let me i'll start hitting
the game about
that back to that yeah much better there
we go
we can see you now very good complete
with complete with sound bars from the
um uh from the from your lighting i
don't know if that's your fluorescent
lighting or your
led lighting or what it is but adorable
yeah all right then so uh
uh i've had some fun this week i have
been having all kinds of fun
um i'm still i'm trying to figure out
this thing called
docker i don't know if anyone's actually
used that here on the
on the uh on the list but i'm trying to
figure that out because
um i still have some cbs uh
um repositories source code in cvs
repositories
that i need to convert to get and the
problem is that the tool that i used
the tool that i use called cbs to svn
requires python 2. and the problem is
python 2
is gone and it still exists in
in ubuntu 18.04 but it no longer it no
longer exists it's been
it's been gone and so there are a few
packages that i've that i've
been using that i've been trying to use
that just plain
don't exist anymore and cvs
to svn is one of them it's gone now
you just can't get it and if they ever
if they ever go to um if they ever
upgrade it so that it can use um
so that it can use python 3 then we
should be good shape but
currently there's no uh there's no
there's no uh
plan for that so i'm running
uh ubuntu 18.04 on the pine book
and the pine book is starting to bug me
now because it says
i want to upgrade i want to upgrade to
ubuntu 20.04
and i don't want to do the upgrade
because if i do the upgrade i'm going to
lose all the
python 2 stuff so i've
stopped that upgrade for right now and
so far that's working out okay
but um i need a way
to uh to to either start up a virtual
machine
that's an 1804 virtual machine or i need
a way to
um to run docker also docker seems to be
a better option just because it's more
lightweight
but what about virtual well virtualbox
is an option too peter that that's one
of my options as well and i can
certainly do that
i've got enough cpu and enough memory to
be able to do it as a virtual machine
but i wanted to try docker because i've
never tried it before
so i have no problem doing doing virtual
machine if i can
you know if i need to um but i will
i will try um i do want to have a good
docker first
so uh if anyone has used docker before
i'd be
more than happy to to chat about that
also test harnesses now
i don't know
whether anybody has has has done this
in my computing professional computing
career
i have worked on all kinds of languages
starting from cobol way way way back
when
to c
[Music]
c plus plus java all kinds of assembly
language all kinds of other languages as
well
but one of the things i really liked
about
uh not java specifically
but a toolkit that you can use with java
called
spring um or
or spring boot which is a variant of
spring
and one of the things that lets you do
is to define
test at what's called a test harness
which consists of nothing but
test code um code that you use to
exercise your library or your
application that you're trying to run
usually you would run this application
as a
you know command line argument or a gui
or whatever it is that you're trying to
run your application to do
but you can actually execute you can
actually
build an executable that is a test
harness
that does nothing but exercise the
various parts of your
of the rest of your application doesn't
run the gui or any of that mess it's a
separate application
it's all part of g lab is
is what i use it for and i love it
i've just started uh i mean i've built
myself a pretty crappy
uh test harness originally but all i
could do is say
run all the tests i couldn't really
select which ones they were nor could i
effectively
see what the test results were but with
glib it's sort of built in
so anyway that's what i've been working
on i've been having all kinds of fun
with that
and um yeah my fine time
still bricked still not showing at home
still bricked i haven't i i haven't had
a chance to go back and
work on it yet i do charge it up i'm
pretty confident that it charges
um but i really need to get back onto
this but i'm having so much fun with
with test harnesses and fun stuff like
that but i haven't really
really done anything with the time time
so i really need to
to hurry up and do that um anyway
so that's pretty much what i've been up
to
robbie's not with us today because i
think it's canadian
thanksgiving this weekend which i
believe is
believe it's monday in the us when we
have thanksgiving it's usually the
thursday
you get the friday off and then you've
got the two so you've got like a four
day weekend it's great
but um i think the canadian
thanksgiving is the other way around i
think it's i think you get the weekend
and then you get the monday off
um i haven't really looked into that so
that's what i've been up to um so what
what sort of mess have you been i see
you back on the bridge of uh what is
that voyager
yeah uh oh nice yeah i'm
i just i'm having the
night shift so and uh nelixia came with
some food for me today how nice what is
that pizza
yeah oh yeah he he finally managed how
to do pizza so
oh very nice nice
it's looking good i like it it's looking
very good i
finally i finally managed how to hang
the backdrop
so i found on um in the basement
of my house the premium owners
left behind some uh curtain hangers
at the pole that they couldn't hang
around yeah yeah
so i mean i'm using one of those two um
between two
uh um poles or something
because it lags down in the middle right
yeah
yeah and if you get too energetic with
your hand
movements it gets confused and it starts
to bleed through
so just just so you know that yeah
other than that i i used
a full hour in an attempt to change uh
one of the uh
main headlights on on my car uh
i noticed that yesterday uh it was
broken
um after i'm i had a
sound engineering job in my church
yesterday from
11 o'clock and uh until uh
a.m and until until uh 10 o'clock
p.m um and i got
dinner and supper and yeah
so i had to wait until today in order to
change it
and then um
in modern cars it's not too much room in
order to
change a light bulb in a modern car so
i had to fiddle in order to get the
broken
light bulb out and then i went into the
gas station where i stopped and i bought
a new one
and i couldn't get it to fit in my new
car so i needed some tools and
so i went home in order to change it
and still couldn't make it fit and then
i called my brother who
after a little searching found out that
they sold me their own bulb
so yeah
problematic could be to chase the bulb
if the socket doesn't fit
yeah i've been taking taking notes and
i've
i forgot that i mentioned this i got
fountain pens now
hey yeah i i have like three or four of
them
this thing cost a grand total of like a
dollar fifty
or two dollars for that that's um it
came pre-inked i don't think you can
even uh i don't think you can even
change the ink on it
but i've got i've got i don't know three
or four of them all different types that
i
i got as a sample pack basically and i
wanted to try them all
out and believe it or not this dinky
tiny little thing out of the sample pack
is the is the
the easiest the nicest one to write so
yeah
you know i'm so retro but now this these
headlights of yours
um what did you get led headlights now
are you swapping them out because i mean
my vehicle
i've got the old incandescent headlights
that are getting dimmer and dimmer and
dimmer over time
and i really need to replace them but um
i would love to just pull them out
according to my
brother who know a few things about this
here is that if you are changing um
from uh old-fashioned light bulbs and
and
fitting uh led lights you most likely
you most likely also need to change the
light the entire thing
because it's not uh calibrated to uh
led and it might um be too bright or
not um like in the right places or
yeah so um well i can
also one of the problems with led lights
because i have
the head beams and i have another an
extra set
of lights
yeah and and there are two filaments in
the um
in the headlight actual bulb isn't there
one filament for the
downward facing uh uh headlights
and the other for the for the brights
yeah i have um
in my car i have a kia seed a 2007
version
the main lights and another smaller um
lamp with the i mean maybe the main
beams
um so it has only one um
thread and it's a different socket than
the usual
but mine is a minus in this unleash it's
a full 100
electric car and it actually has leds
for the downward facing lights you know
for the lights that
cast down onto the under the road and
then
incandescent lights for the high beams
and you it does a control in in at the
driver's station at the driver's
location that you can actually twist and
knob
and it it brings the head beams it
brings the headlights down like that so
they don't shine into
um
old clunkers and i've never seen that
before i love it it's great
i'm such a child
uh back to their recent uh
an argument against uh replacing their
bulb old-fashioned light bulbs with led
lights
is that the led lights there doesn't
generate heat
and because i noticed in my led
extra head beams um when i use those
and it's snowing um there's no sticks to
the to
to the lights and uh after a few um
a few months there um they are not good
it takes their
from there from downtown and in
onto my house it takes them a 20 minute
drive
and if it's snowing i have to stop for
20 minutes i have to stop three times in
order to clean
those uh lights whereas
um so the leds do or do not generate
heat
they do not so they don't so they don't
and they do not
melt the snow that's funny
yeah i know i know peter i know they're
great
that's why i like them because i've got
them in the airplane i've replaced all
of my um incandescent lights in the
aeroplane with leds and it's wonderful
because
i still use a generator not an
alternator because it's that old like me
and and the uh
you hardly see the ammeter wobble
anymore when the um
uh uh when you turn the light i can have
the landing lights on and uh
and and the ammeter hardly even wavers
now
whereas with the old incandescent lights
it used to pull like 10 amps or
something i mean it was a
crazy thing right now the led lights
don't ice over
uh well i don't fly in ice
i'm pfr only i stay out of i stay out of
bad weather it's it's a
i'm a very conservative pilot i don't i
fly when it's pretty weather
i mean we've got some crappy weather
today because of the hurricane
but i thought even on a nice day if you
got up high enough you'd get ice
no um well well you can if it's really
humid
outside and that's the thing and you
don't have to be in freezing
temperatures for that to happen
um it's the humidity because what can
happen
i've had carbice happen before in the um
in the airplane because when you're up
at nine and a half ten thousand feet
and it's still humid up there what will
happen is that
as air travels through the throat
of the carburetor what will happen is
ice will
will appear here and here and eventually
it will just sort of you know
go deeper and deeper and deeper close up
the throat it'll make the throat less
and less
you know um uh less air and
fuel mixture can get through and what
will happen is eventually the mixture
will
be messed up to the point where it just
can't run the engine anymore
um and so the engine will quit producing
power it never stopped turning
but um it uh it did uh uh
it did stop um generating power
so luckily i was right over the top of
another
over the top of an airport whose
controlled airspace didn't start till
like 5000 feet so
i just started circling and then um
in order to try and figure out the
problem before i called mayday
i did not have to because i sorted it
out well before then
and then flew home so that worked out
pretty well for me so
so doug how are you going sir what's
what's new in your world
well they figured out that i have a
bacteria called um carbolobacter
that's not the phrase for this kind no
it doesn't sound good at all it's one of
the bacteria that's known to cause food
poisoning
um you've heard of salmonella that
that's pretty common
yeah oh yeah oh yeah but this one is i
guess not
as common but it's known the card food
cause
food poisoning and um i'm taking a
zithromyosin if you know what that is
it's an uh antibiotic
yeah yeah yeah i took the last dose of
azithromycin today
so i'm going to try some solid food
later
a three day seven day course then three
days three days that's all
three 500 milligrams
yes is that what they call a z-pack the
z-pack
is usually six 250 milligram
tablets i've had that and you take two
the first day
and then one for each for five days
after that
okay okay but you've got a slightly
different dose by the sounds of it
they gave me they my doctor wrote the
script for the
six 250 milligrams and he told me to
take two
a day and um okay
then when i got to the pharmacy the uh
pharmacist says well we told him we have
it in 500 milligram calves
so he rewrote the script to give you the
500 milligram crabs and you just take
one a day for three days
yeah they usually don't like just one a
day do they they'd rather
let you spread it out over time they'd
rather you take two a day or three a day
right
but i guess well it depends on what
you're fighting
for most antibiotics right okay
with a respiratory illness which is what
i've had the zpac for
um i get bronchitis sometimes wow
they and they will give me zpac for that
yeah that's the one
where they have the 250 milligram caps
and you take the two on the first day
and then one for five days after and
and to peter's point that's very true
yeah i was going to say to peter's point
that's very true because what can happen
is
i mean i've had dental issues um over
many many years
and at one point i was taking two
different antibiotics for two different
issues
and my dentist and my dentist said i'm
not gonna
i'm not gonna do any antibiotics because
the last thing i want to do
is tear up your stomach so what we're
gonna do is let these
let the current cause that you're on run
through
and you're just gonna have to put up
with what's going on in your mouth
and then whenever whenever that's done
then we'll address your um antibiotics
but that's a very good point peter
antibiotics certainly seen that before
antibiotics can kill the good bacteria
in your gut
right right right well i'm so glad
you're feeling better doug and i'm
certain i'm very happy that they figured
out
what was what was wrong i hope you i
hope you're getting to feeling better
now
i'm probably going to go back to work
tuesday
especially since i might have paid time
off oh
yeah i hate it when that happens well
i'm contracting at the moment so if i
don't work i don't get paid so
i haven't had any yes i haven't had any
vacation that's gotta hurt
yeah it's okay it's it's a time but you
know you deal with it you plan you plan
ahead and
and and and work through it so
so doug what else you've been up to then
i'll hand it off to peter
well basically nothing just trying to
recover
okay okay sounds good
all right peter what uh what sort of
trouble have you been caught i mean
getting into
careful um and by the way let me say
peter thank you for
um for uh working so hard on yours on
your audio because it's perfect this
time around
that headset that you're wearing i see
that it's working
really well and you've got great audio
and great video and i very much
appreciate it and that's why i've tried
all things out yeah
i've been i've been having type problems
with their
provider who don't uh
do anything particularly uh i've been
having intermittent problems whether
the provider used to keep dropping out
every night
you mean your internet provider right
yeah okay
but there's a blue light on the modem
otherwise the carriers coming through
but there was nothing coming through and
i've complained about six or seven times
over the last three months and
they not didn't want to do anything
particularly well it seems to be working
okay
now what's different i found out what
the problem was
i they spoke to they both have salted
out this time
and giving me back in 48 hours and it's
uh
96 hours plus now and they drove and
done it like that
well don't forget it's a weekend so no
no
this was on tuesday don't worry this was
a long time
they just bloody used to think you
couldn't uh pull the piss up on the
brewery screwed my friends
they really are bad uh everybody in
england said that
but uh i uh unasked your question i got
two switches i got a switch up connected
to the
router which could operate my uh
um network system and then there's a
wire go downstairs
that's connected to a downstairs
computer which i can use downstairs
of course i've got a switch in there as
well
and that's the one that keeps sticking
uh it
needs to keep sticking on or off for
whatever it used to do
and used to erect the internet so i've
taken that and put a back-to-back
connector on it
uh but if you want to have two switches
on the same line almost there
okay oh yeah i do that all the time um
i have um from my
uh from my cable well from my internet
modem
um i have one ethernet cable that runs
to my um that runs to my main
uh uh uh netgear router
um now you know if robbie were here he
would say micro dick
he would say go get a micro tip and i
made
i may do that one day but i got a whole
slew of
of uh linksys routers that i um
uh that i inherited but i can
but i i can plug up my uh cable modem
or my internet modem directly to
the links it for the nick gear router
and it will uh it
how do i put this the the router that
i've got
also offers wi-fi
on 2gig and 5 gig and all that stuff but
the problem is that any devices
that you connect to your internet router
are visible to your internet provider
they may be protected from the general
internet
but your internet provider can see all
those devices
i do not know if it can see all the
stuff
that's on those devices you know if
there's any network ports open or
whatever
i don't know if they can get to that
they can't i'm not i'm not surprised
yeah it doesn't surprise me at all and
that's why the very first thing i did
was shuttle that
stuff down i almost said a bad word
shut all that down no wi-fi no 2gig no
5g wi-fi from the internet modem
and then just one ethernet cable that
runs from the internet modem
to my my own internal router
which is the only thing that provides
the uh
that the the 2gig and the 5 gig wi-fi
so all that the internet company can see
is just my router
that's it and then i've got more routers
in the network
i've got more routers in the network to
spread out the load even further if i
need to
yeah yeah yeah but the the uh
i i also uh trying to tell them they
said can we use wi-fi i said no
because there's too many people next
over the road who said that's why my
door
tried to break in i've seen them do it
so why do it either
i put the radio on and i transmit and it
would
be scattered like no red bits especially
on on
30 meters okay so there's a couple ways
around that peter
you can actually you can actually make
it a
private wi-fi connection
you can make it not transmit the ssid
and in my case anyway and i guess your
modem can do it too
you can allow connections only from
network devices that you recognize and
that is my mac address
that will be done yeah uh uh but i also
do well then nobody should be able to
break in
if they if they don't see your ssid no
no they
but uh i i was trying to explain to them
that i don't
put it on and they don't think he didn't
understand that i told him a number of
times uh about that and they do seem to
want to understand
uh so um good it could have been this
the switch has been a bit
uh no good to switch it's probably
intermittent somewhere because
it goes intermittent every so often it
causes a crash
possible but so my first question is
your wi-fi is coming from the
uh from the bt supply device or is it
coming from your own route
it comes from a bt line and it goes up
into a
wire then it goes into the thing okay so
the first thing i would do
is first thing i would disable that in
the bt router
and then i would go get another router
like a netgear
or a microtech or something like that
plug that into your bt router
and then let the microtech um or
whatever
whatever router you get let that provide
the wi-fi
for you so that all the telecom modem is
doing
is literally just providing you an
internet connection
and then you manage the network from
there in
and also if he uh if he uh
when he turns off the wi-fi from the
bta router
and in in the new router if he uses the
same ssid
and the same password as the bt router
has then he doesn't need to
then all of the uh existing devices will
automatically
start using the new uh the new device
and he doesn't have to
set up anything yeah but but i'm
i've picked my own my own ssid
and set my own password so separate from
the internet device i'm not an expert
are you not because i i i'm i'm just
i i started very late in life
about the networking system so
and uh the uh
uh the roco box in there there's an ssd
god what did they do
i have not had a lot of luck with the sd
card in the roku peter
well what's supposed to happen is as you
cycle through
all the channels in the roku what's
supposed to happen is that
you know each each channel that you can
select at the main menu of the roku
typically has
its own list of channels inside the
application like netflix has all of its
um all of its channels inside the
application
youtube does as well and there's
various others and what the sd card is
supposed to do when when i was able to
make twitch work
it doesn't work on roku anymore unless
anyone knows a way to make that work
but um twitch used to have its own set
of channels as well
and um the sd card was supposed to
record those so it didn't have to
re-download them
every time you switched from like
netflix to
to twitch or or whatever
but i found that not to work very well i
found that what happens is that
it tends to use what's in the sd card
regardless of whether the channel is
changed on the service or not
so that you can so you go back to twitch
and then it says yeah well here's what
i've got out of the sd card i'm not
going to tell you what the service
is offering because i think the sd card
is better
so i would not use an sd card is what i
would recommend
peter i would not use the sd card what
did the usb
port do as well uh the first time i
picked the thing up and actually look at
it
because this is one of the things i
turned off when i try to find the full
what is the uh right people doing there
uh
don't recall i don't recall there being
a usb
port but there should be an ethernet
connector on the roku
and we're running out of time so we we
are running out of time to
go any further