covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias zoom has added
end-to-end encryption to its video
conferencing service at no additional
cost for all users
whether they are paying subscribers or
not the feature has been long awaited
given the service's massive adoption as
a result of pandemic lockdowns
something that swung a spotlight on its
patchy security
the company announced on tuesday that
the new feature is available now as a
technical preview for the next 30 days
and is looking for user feedback before
rolling it out on mass
zoom see so jason lee gives kudos to
keybase who joined the company in may to
develop the security feature
taking just six months to do so zoom
says its end-to-end encryption will use
256-bit aes gcm
and a secure key exchange is performed
beforehand to ensure only the
participants on the call can decrypt
each other's part of the conversations
and no eavesdroppers not even zoom
itself
can listen in zoom had already encrypted
some of its
uh communications though it wasn't truly
end to end until now
in order to use the end-to-end
encryption and account admin
has to enable the feature zoom's
end-to-end encryption is limited to 200
participants so for larger meetings
where encryption may not be a needed
feature
such as a public forum or a digital
comic con
it can be disabled to allow more people
to join
other restrictions of the service are a
lack of cloud recording and live
transcription breakout rooms polling and
one-to-one private chats are also
unavailable when end-to-end encryption
are on
as are live emojis perhaps the biggest
caveat of all though is that each user
must have the official zoom client
installed in order to participate
so browser-based participation will not
be available for encrypted meetings
third-party zoom clients will also not
work when end-to-end encryption is
enabled
the feature is available on new releases
of the zoom software for mac os windows
android linux
and ios big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]