a bit of back story for you before we
jump into an interview with mark noland
at kingston technology
the server we use here at the studio has
been low on space for some time
i've actually had to delete things in
order to make room for the shows each
week
it's an old server but it still runs
great a bit on the loud side with those
dell cooling fans but
it runs well so there's no reason to
replace it yet
the storage however could use an upgrade
since transitioning our editing to 4k
last fall it's become obvious that not
only is the storage array too
small but the drives aren't fast enough
either
so after some research i picked up
kingston data center ssds they've got
ecc to protect against data corruption
and they're meant for business use in
the data center now my data center as
you can this is it
i've got a single old dell r510 server
but what we'll cover today is completely
scalable i don't want to give you the
wrong impression
whether you're a very small business
like myself even a
home server or a web host or large
enterprise with many servers the point
is
that these competitively priced
enterprise ssds from kingston
can really improve your server's
performance now for my use here at
category 5 tv i went with the dc
500rs because they're optimized for read
intensive application
that should do really well for our video
editing of course i also use the server
for general data storage
to hold past seasons of videos plus i
run a few virtual machines on there to
run our internal infrastructure
so needless to say kingston's dc 500rs
are going to be ideal not just for my
general use but the bursts of sudden
read speed i need when loading big video
files
they've also got dc500ms as well and if
you need
higher write speed those will fit the
bill being a really great
big bang for the buck all round ssd for
servers
i wanted to know how much of a
difference the upgrade actually made
so i set up a comparison with the hopes
of making it as close of a one to one as
possible
so i chose a raid 5 with 4 disks each
and before i ran the tests i updated the
raid controller firmware
while it is an old server i thought it
would be best to make sure everything is
as
up to date as possible from there along
with some helpful advice from kingston's
fio expert matt eaton
i wrote a benchmark script that i could
run against both my original spinning
drives and the new kingston ssds
giving me a pretty good view of how the
performance compares
the code's on my github page and the
link is in the video description below
huge thanks to matt for all of his help
and also dave leung for
among other things helping connect me
with the right people at kingston
i did a fair amount of preconditioning
on the drives though
time was of a factor here as well and
since the spinners were taking an
unreal amount of time to precondition
i did cut that process short it should
be noted too that the drives are
different capacities so this is by no
means
apples to apples but in a real world
environment such as ours here at the
studio
i'm happy just to know that there's a
perceptible improvement
with reasonably accurate numbers to back
that up
i brought the server nearly to its knees
the file tests were
brutal on these old spinner drives
but they completed way faster on the
ssds so i grabbed some 2.5 to 3.5 inch
adapters
that'll match up nicely with the
server's backplane since the dell trays
only support 3.5 inch drives
firing up the server with the ssds and
all appears to work great
but all the drives are flashing in amber
light i asked mark from kingston if this
was a concern
well uh with dell where did you get the
drive sled
wait a minute so you're telling me these
fancy expensive drive adapters or what's
causing this
it's the drive sled the drive set has a
chipset on it
all right let's try a different approach
then commander muff posted thing
1830990 to thingiverse which looks
promising
i've got the link in the description
below let's give it a shot
[Music]
oh
success the kingston dc 500s connected
directly to the backplane using 3d
printed adapters
did the trick now i'd like to briefly
digress
because this is another testament to the
cost savings
of owning a 3d printer now i paid
sixteen dollars each for these adapters
the ones i printed myself
these worked better and now while i used
expensive pla plus filament which cost
forty dollars per kilogram each tray
adapter
which is 14 grams uh price that prices
it at only
56 cents each
so the material cost being 56 cents
i saved 15.44
per tray adapter that's a grand total of
123.52 cents
saved to print eight adapters myself
if i did that just two more times i've
already offset
the upfront expense of buying my 3d
printer in
savings alone anyway back to our subject
but first
a quick word from our sponsors when we
return mark nolan joins us from kingston
to make sense of the file results and
talk about how business users can
further improve the performance of the
data center
stick around
[Music]
i've run the fio tests on all the drives
and i've passed the numbers on to the
team
at kingston so they can help make sense
of the test results
and here's what those numbers look like
so in the middle column there i've got
the four
dell constellation es drives those have
the sas interface running at 7200 rpm
and i've configured them in a raid 5.
you can see the iops input output per
second
is very very poor by contrast to the
ssds in the far right column
those are the dc 500rs from kingston and
those again are configured in the same
way a raid 5 with four drives however
these ones are one terabyte drives
versus the spinning drives that are two
terabytes each not
apples to apples but you can see clearly
that the speed
is significantly improved on the ssds
mark noland is a field application
engineer from kingston technology mark
thanks for taking the time to speak with
me
howdy how are you today great tell us a
little bit about
what it is that you do at kingston
uh so i'm my title is field applications
engineer
uh but i interface a lot with uh clients
and users at data centers
um i also you know in my background i i
used to work for autodesk uh in the film
and
video industry um and dealt with like
sort of
everything from the desktop application
back to the data center you know
uh so if you if you break a bottleneck
at the desktop
you know then your next bottleneck is
the network and once you break that then
your bottleneck is on the server
and so um just basically trying to
troubleshoot and
and break bottlenecks whether it's you
know uh
databases or you know uh
8k video editing systems uh things like
that
they all need big fast data going
through pipes
don't i know it don't i know it oh yeah
so you've seen that's quite a setup you
got there cheers yeah well and you've
seen our file numbers from
our test today um and i i do realize
that
those numbers are slightly arbitrary um
however what i did is i ran the same
test
against the same scenario on our old
spinning drives
as i did on dc500rs so
just looking at those numbers can you
help us to make sense of
what's what's actually happening there
uh
okay yeah so uh you know
first of all both you know both the ssds
and the hard drives are
connected to the sata bus right same
server
all the hardware is the same just the
drives have changed yeah
the sata bus is one of the older um
connection methods in in this in the
computer
uh and and it has uh you know
a few uh weaknesses and that uh sort of
you can only be reading or writing to it
at any one time
uh but you know with raid controllers
and that they've gotten really good at
being able to optimize that
uh the best way possible so then you
come down to the
raw you know interface
differences between a hard drive
spinning disk and ssds
and you know s's
ssds have been modified you know it's a
a solid-state disk it's basically you've
got computer memory nand that
is being uh routed to speak uh
disk language right and so uh
in a way you're sort of uh hobbling the
uh
the uh fast nand that's in there by
making it go through
the uh uh sata interface but
uh it has to pretend that it is uh it
has to
like at least translate to speak disc
language
so when you've got like uh the old
school heart spinning discard drives
um you know they're they're pretty good
at doing sequential stuff
uh random they start choking and when it
comes to
iops they really have a hard time
keeping up with
the memory you can see you know which
parts are
uh in the difference between your test
scores
you can see which parts are you know low
because
of the spinning disc itself and ones
that you know
uh uh are like the uh
nand on an ssd is actually able to you
know still
put pretty good uh bandwidth through so
like
in your in your uh read and write
performance
um you know the ssds are
anywhere between like on the read
maybe four times faster than uh the
fastest
rate of hard drives that you have going
right um this is also
you're doing raid five so there's a
little bit of overhead with disk
management so
if you did raid zero on both the ssds
and
i need redundancy yeah yeah yeah you
have no redundancy but if you do raid
zero you know then
you can see raw bandwidth sure uh
happening right yeah
uh but and and that that's when ssds
would even
take a step above you know sad ssds
would be even faster
uh without that redundancy happening
because there's a certain amount of uh
overhead that's happening to to do that
but even with your raid 5 setup
you're still looking at about three
times faster
for ssds than hard drives uh
on uh on a re on a
right and four times faster on the read
uh typically but the the one sort of
secret place that it ends up being much
much faster
is uh in the latency so that's like the
time between when i click
and submit a request to the time that uh
it actually
starts happening right um if
if it's like a random io
event it might be you know
when your drives are warmed up and
everything it might be uh
like 0.8 milliseconds to 1.2
milliseconds depending
uh whereas on the ssd it's going to be
microseconds so even if it's 20
microseconds
uh and you have a rate of four drives if
you say that your average latency per
drive was one millisecond on a hard
drive
and it's like 20 microseconds on the ssd
then uh you haven't even gotten to a
microsecond by the time you add up that
latency
across the four drives
the latency is a big difference and then
the quality of service
so one of the things that we really
tested the data center the dc 500 and
450 and dc 1000 drives
they're they're tested extensively for
you know
quality of service that's the main the
main thing you're looking for if you're
putting them into a
data center like tier two cloud
something like that
uh you want a quality of service where
uh you know a consumer ssd might peak
and
deliver super performance for a short
period of time
and if you're only transferring a couple
gigs at a time that's what you want it's
on your laptop
right you know you're trying to get
things on and off really quick that's
awesome
but if you're if you're running a drive
you know 24 7 with a database with for
online transactions
uh you're writing to it and reading from
it like constantly
and you you don't want to see big spikes
up or down in the performance you want
to see
like a really flat line in that
performance and
and you'll see that with like a hard
drive you know uh it'll spike up really
fast initially because it's got a
dram cat anytime you're transferring a
video file or something it's like
fast and then and then it'll plummet
down to
right 200 megabytes per second and then
it goes 30 megabytes yes
and you're like what happened yeah uh
and the problem is
at a certain point you're running out of
cash or something like that so
in that uh you know in in your fio
script
uh one of the important things to do if
you're wanting to test for
data center use is to do that uh warm up
on the drive to have it burned in
so that uh it's not just like fresh out
of the box i just installed it and all
the sectors are blank and
and you know like uh because it's not
having to have any overhead of managing
uh data on the drive i would see what
the
drives in use so is that is that kind of
the key difference between the consumer
ssds that i have in my laptop in my home
computers
versus these data center drives yeah
that and you might see over provisioning
differences
um like our uh dc
uh drives um number one they have a
decent amount of uh
dram cash on them uh where a lot of
consumer drives might have
uh a pseudo slc where they take tlc or
qlc memory and program it
as slc so rather than you know they
might take a sector a section of the
drive and
and say this is going to be programmed
as slc so i'm only going to store
one bit of data in this cell instead of
the three or four like if it's
uh tlc you're storing three bits of data
and
uh or bytes and and uh
and qlc you're storing four so you've
got much more data that's being
stored there uh you know we had mlc uh
but then it was tlc and
uh qlc and you know we're we're trying
to plan
more more bits into uh uh
the more cells uh and as you do that it
gets
you know it takes a little longer to
program
uh all those uh bytes and bits into
uh the different cells so if you use the
pseudo cache of slc
which we do on a few drives as well and
consumer uh but
uh you're it the reason you do it is
it's much less expensive than using
dram and so uh on our on our data center
drives
there they all have like a nice big dram
cache on them that's one of the big
differences
oh okay and so uh that
that combined with uh the over
provisioning
that is on uh our data center drives
allows for
uh as well as tweaks in the firmware
it allows for really a high level of
quality of service so
you don't see big spikes way up and then
weight down and
and going you know right where you're at
the max performance of the bus
down to zero back to the middle and are
you when you say
when you say over provisioning are you
talking about io
now over provisioning is where if i have
like if you see uh an ssd that has
say it has 940 or 960 gigs
yeah uh of 960 gig capacities
really common right yeah that that's a
terabyte of nand that's on there
and it has over provisioning of uh three
to five percent
for the data itself so the storage yeah
okay and so when
when you see a drive that says one
terabyte
uh lots of times that's still the same
amount of nand as if you bought a
960 but the the thing you'll notice is
like on a consumer drive if you get up
to being
90 full on one that's not over
provisioned
you'll start you'll see the performance
also start to tank
whereas if you have one that if you have
the you know the 960 gig
drive it can be 90 full and you'll still
be riding at the same speed
as when it was empty uh you know
you it well i won't say when it was
empty because one of the things
we do that uh preconditioning right
that's part of our
script that we we're working on there
um that preconditioning basically make
sure that
the drives sort of dirtied up and and
uh is doing real workload type stuff so
you guys
because you can test anything out of the
box and it might look spectacular but
then when you put it into real use
uh throw it into a data center and you
know weak into being used
you're like this is not performing the
way it did you know
i threw these consumer drives in there
and they were great and now they uh are
terrible
yeah um oh i see that yeah i've seen
that on desktop drives and
things like that yeah when they get
warmed up and dirty and make sense
they they're under real world working
conditions and not just
running a benchmark and now my iops
on the and you mentioned iops maybe i
could get you to briefly explain what
that means to us
um but it is through the roof
higher uh on the ssds what is that what
does that tell us
so uh part of that is it's because of
the
it's physics right so on the ssd
it's science we're talking about physics
because
the hard drive is actually relying
uh for the iops it actually has that
that
needle that moves back and forth with
the reader physical drives yeah
the the spinning drives and so it
actually has to
in order to read a point it has to
physically move to somewhere
find that read it uh verify it
and then move to the next point find it
read it and verify it so
uh just because of the way
physics and thermodynamics work the
drive can't spin
any faster they you know hard drives are
really really great for what they do
and that you get really big hard drives
and
they're pretty durable uh but
physics can't take them any farther
because and and so when you go
over to an ssd
uh you're just everything's uh
done through solid state you're not
moving anything
except electrons and so uh
you know you're you you have like your
seek times go down by a thousand
fold uh and that's why you'll see what
the iops difference um the
random read which was your best on the
hard drives random read of
673 iops
whereas the random read on the raid of
dc 500r was 121 000 iops
so 180 times the speed
yeah it's it's just a little faster a
little bit
that's amazing so now we understand now
that
so i've jumped from going from the
spinning drives to the
ssds now my bottleneck is sata
the the connection so
that 121 000 iops
with that if you went to
now you go to pcie based drives
pcie gen 3 nvme type drives
so either m.2 or u.2
u.2 is more friendly to a data center
because it
is in that two and a half inch form
factor rather than the gum stick form
factor which is
a little difficult to manage there's a
few people that have
uh adapters and things like that to put
lots of m.2s into servers but
um you know i think the the u.2 and the
ruler are going to be much more common
uh going forward for putting in lots of
you know like 24
or more uh u.2 drives uh
like nvme ssds into a server
uh but now you're talking like the iops
go up another
factor right um so like an nvme drive
because it's not limited
to uh by the sata bus uh
it uh is limited by the pcie bus so
um you know you go to gen four and
that's
twice as fast as gen three so you know
potentially twice as fast i
haven't seen any models where like it is
twice as fast but you know significantly
gen 4
demos that i've seen are significantly
faster like uh
you know you're talking off of by 16
uh i think uh the fastest demo i've seen
so far is about
25 gigabytes per second off of one
device
on one gen 4 bytes per second wow
and and i don't know how scalable that
is currently but
that was when gen 4 was still
experimental which it's a little
experimental
i think the amd one is is looking really
good but uh
i'll call it kind of experimental until
intel and amd both have their gen 4 out
and all of the enterprise servers are
shipping with gen 4 pcie because at this
point
it's a really cool gamer box or a really
high-end
a really high-end workstation you know
like it
uh nvidia's got a lot of cool demos with
four gpus on an amd proc with uh
you know lots of nvme uh uh
drives connected to it and they're doing
some really neat demos and as is amd
with their
their gpus but
all that right now seems it it's like
if i have to go drop five to
20 grand on a workstation um i i'm gonna
wait
until it's uh somebody else uh
works out all the wrinkles in that
experiment so
thinking about my use case so i
obviously work here in a studio so i'm
doing a lot of video production
maybe some of our viewers are working in
an office environment where they've got
similar scenarios where
hey we've got to replace the drives in
an older server or maybe it's not even
that old but
they're they're not necessarily
replacing an entire server they just
want to put
ssds in instead of the spinning drives
because they're
kind of the way to go right now and
we're certainly seeing a big performance
boost here
um is there you know where where is the
performance gain so for me it's
it's in editing real-time 4k video it's
it's brilliant on the on the dc 500rs
um where where is the the average
business consumer
i.t department going to find gains by
upgrading the servers to ssd
well i i think client satisfaction and
my uh dad's a dentist and my mom's a
lawyer
and and uh i've used to do some computer
tech support for
people in those communities and and you
know like uh
uh doctors and lawyers are notoriously
cheap when it comes to you know like uh
spending money on on systems like that
but the systems also drive all of the
uh all of the uh revenue in their
business so it's really important for
them to keep them updated
and i think the thing that you
get by going from hard drive to ssds
on an upgrade of an older system you
know you'll be able to ring
at least two or three more years out of
it if not more
um you know you'll you you'll you always
hit a bottleneck somewhere but
rather than your system being the
bottleneck it might be the os or the
version of the software
that you're using or something like that
but uh
you'll make something much more usable
have you ever taken an old hard drive ss
or a whole old hard drive laptop and put
an ssd in it and
you know it's like all sudden it's like
why was i going to get rid of this thing
it's so fast
exactly it like breathes new life into
an old system and that's exactly what
this has done
for our server and i and as you're
talking about bottlenecks i'm thinking
okay well sata is six gig a second
so i think my bottleneck actually mark
is going to be my networking because i'm
only on gig
ethernet so yeah that's my bottleneck
but
being a very small business myself
having gig
ethernet and being able to edit video
over
one gig a second is is stellar it's
superb
um well the the trick you know for that
like because my job was breaking those
kind of bottlenecks
uh previously is i would put a 10 gig
uh on your server and have a switch that
distributes it out to
your gigabit clients and and until you
get a 10 gig uh or desktop or something
but
you could always go you know like uh do
it gradually just like adding
uh ssds to your uh uh legacy systems
yeah uh that's a good idea just kind of
upgrade the the networking
as i go that's the next step yeah um
what kind of longevity am i going to be
looking at um
for ssds i know like when ssds first
came out so
years ago um there were those of us who
were hesitant and afraid to switch to
ssd
because the they weren't quite as
reliable but that has completely changed
over the past several years are we like
what kind of lifespan do we expect from
like your your data center drives uh
so our data center drives we warrant
them for five years
uh yeah and then you know like the they
have different
um drive rights per day
warranties as well so like the dc 500
that's a 0.3 drive right per day so if
you have a
four terabyte or a three three point uh
was it 3.86 uh
if you have a four essentially there's
four terabytes in the end on there
but if you have like a four terabyte
drive or an eight terabyte drive
of the r which is a read centric model
you can get
uh up to uh you can do uh 0.3 drive
rights per day
um uh the m
version of that is 1.5 drive rights per
day
and if you think about that for a four
terabyte drive
that's a lot of writing yeah if you're
riding uh
you know like uh six terabytes a day uh
you might be running facebook off of
your uh server i don't know
that's a lot of data to fill up and
delete
because that's it's not so much about um
you know like if you're just collecting
drives or collecting data on your drives
that's what the r is all about
right so the read centric one if i want
to
like have a database full of video and
images
and text files and spreadsheets and
stuff that's going to live there forever
the
the dc 500r is a really great drive
because i'm just adding stuff to it all
the time i'm not
adding you know like a terabyte at a
time and then calculating that data and
deleting the whole thing and
and putting in the answer that's another
terabyte um
you know that that's something like uh
uh lamp where you've got
you know apache server and and or an
oltp
server or you know some kind of online
transaction thing where you know
uh uh you're you're just grinding
through the data like you know
facebook where you're just adding new
cat videos all the time and then
deleting them as they get old
right um you know uh most people
don't do that like i i've got a a drobo
uh server that i just add stuff to
constantly
so uh i actually had to unplug it
because it's so loud because of all the
hard drives i'm gonna put uh
four four terabyte ssds in there perfect
that'll make it quiet yeah yeah
it's pretty quiet all of a sudden it's
interesting you say that like
because that's the other thing that we
don't necessarily think about with the
upgrade is this
the silence of them the energy
efficiency yeah
i i have to say that ssds uh
compared to hard drive energy efficiency
hard drives are actually really good at
when they're not being used
shutting down like they've they've
really gotten good at being energy
efficient uh and and
i don't think that anybody's replacing
hard drives
with like well they have that that's
exactly what we are exactly
replacing hard drugs but they have their
places like if i want to store
40 uh terabytes of data that's just cold
data
that i'm not going to access all the
time but i really i need for legal
reasons or
you know like to make me feel secure or
it's my backup
that's a perfect use for hard drives if
you have data that you want to be able
to read and work off of
hard drives are terrible for that just
because the latency and you know it's
like
if you're one user and you are getting
the data off the hard drives
it's bad enough to have to wait for it
but if you've got like 10 users
or even you know three or four users
that are all hitting that
uh hard drive array at the same time
you can start you know like hey you know
like why why is everything slowing down
so much
it's like um you know you'll also see a
lot better
multi-user uh efficacy happening when
uh when you go to uh ssds
just because the the latency lots of
great information i mean i'm i'm
all kinds of thoughts going through my
head i'm thinking about how some servers
like you've got multiple users all
connecting for
samba shares and accessing files or even
accessing things like their bookkeeping
software
simultaneously on a single spinning hard
drive in a
system or something that's like the the
difference in the well if
you think about the the uh vm language
of spin-up
uh a virtual machine yeah when you
are coming off of uh sata drive there's
still a little spin up time but it
it's like a fraction of uh what the spin
up time
because it really is a spin up time off
of hard drives
uh and then if you go to nvme it's it's
almost like it was in dram you know it's
like because the nvme drives
being the you know it's off the sata bus
and onto the pcie bus it's one step
closer to the processor mm-hmm and
we can that's why like dram is the best
because it's on the processor right
sure even the you know i guess the cache
and the processor
is on the processor but it's also not
connected to your
uh display and and all that so
dram is sort of the king and which we
also make
there's all these um kind of irrelevant
almost benchmarks of
people turning on their computer and how
long does it take to boot and it's
and it's it's kind of irrelevant in so
many ways and it makes me think about
those spinning
those drives spinning up we have such a
uh
we have a tendency to look at okay when
i click on something how
quickly does it happen how quickly does
that application come up
and for me in this scenario how quickly
am i able to open
large video files in my editor and right
that's like where yeah i'm not having to
wait for
for that that moment is just an instant
moment for me
i would do uh so i a lot of the i would
create demos for when we go to trade
shows like nib
the broadcasters uh north american
broadcaster show or ibc
in amsterdam uh i'd create some demos
with adobe
and uh you know one of the things that
we'd have to do there is like if we're
editing 8k or you know 4k or 8k video
you have to make sure that the clips are
long enough to blow out any
dram that you have you know because if
you know like if i'm editing and it's
really small files they could all just
live in dram
or you know and i wouldn't know the
difference you know it's like it could
be
coming off a hard drive but the first
time i read it it's really slow but
after that it's
nice and fast uh because the if the
files are tiny
but if you are trying to pull like 4k
still frames rather than an avi or a
quick time
uh you know that because the avr
quicktime might be able to
be stored in if you have 64 or 128 gigs
of memory in your
system right you might be able to store
most of the video there
but you don't really see the performance
of the ssds until you
have something that sort of outmatches
the amount of dram that you have
available to you
mark if i may change directions just a
little bit
as we approach closing our interview off
one of the things as a business user
that are that's really important to me
is knowing that i can get support when i
need it
and throughout the course of this
process in upgrading my server one of
the things that
really stands out to me is the fact that
your team was there for me
every step of the way is that
is that pretty typical of kingston uh
before i worked here i
i didn't know that much about kingston
i've worked here for a couple of years
now
and one of the things that really blew
me away was the level of support so
uh if you have a whether you have a
problem with like a
hyperx microphone like this or a headset
or a keyboard or dram or uh
an ssd if you call our support number
we have people here in southern
california in orange county that answer
the phone there's not a data center
somewhere around the world so during the
day
it's going to be people in orange county
if you call it three in the morning it's
going to be people in england
so we've got a really great support
where
if you have a real problem that they
can't solve with uh
you know the all their known database of
issues
uh it ends up to me in the engineering
team for ssds if it goes to us
um like within
a half an hour it's in our inbox and
and you've got like a whole engineering
team from
uh southern california to europe and
and taiwan that are all dealing with it
uh personally so
fantastic i think that's one of the big
differences like i i've had problems
with uh
drives from other manufacturers that
i've worked at other manufacturers and
and i couldn't get anybody to support me
at the manufacturer that i worked at
previously wow
that's great and there's something to be
said for good support
absolutely now you mentioned the hyperx
line of consumer products of course i've
experienced it from the enterprise
kind of level um is this
you know level of support something that
can be expected from
consumers as well as business users
well absolutely like i was saying like
uh we've
we've actually had people you know like
with broken keyboards or
you know it's a it's uh you know it's
it's all one number every
kingston uh you know has the hyperx
brand for
gaming but we also do you know high-end
uh server
products dram and ssds for the data
center
as well as you know consumer dram and
consumer ssds and
usb sticks from consumer ones to all the
way to the encrypted ones with keypads
on them
um one of the other things that also
surprised me coming from
another uh company to kingston was
uh the level of testing so a hundred
percent of
our data center uh ssds and and dram
they're
they're they're as every piece is tested
uh they've you know like they've uh the
server stuff goes through a more
rigorous
test uh but they simulate like three
months worth of uh
uh use on the d
on the dram side and and uh
uh like all the ssds are tested at
uh in an oven basically while they're
when they're being manufactured they're
all tested
at a high temperature to make sure that
they are uh
functioning in an optimal fashion
fantastic
big thanks to our guest mark noland who
joined us from kingston today
to talk about those drives really really
exciting stuff hey um
make sure you subscribe to us on youtube
linuxtechshow.com
is a great way to find us there also if
you love what we do please become a
patron patreon.com
category5 but that's all the time we got
so we're out of here take care we'll see
you again next week
[Music]
[Applause]
you