covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias while we're
still waiting for the mainstream
transition to 5g
samsung is already beginning to discuss
6g which the company expects to be
commercialized as early as 2028.
in a white paper published tuesday
samsung has said it expects the
international telecommunication union
to begin working on 6g in 2021.
the amount of time and work dedicated to
developing each generation of networking
has shortened as time passes
samsung said in the white paper that the
company expects the earliest
commercialized date for 6g to be 2028.
it also states its belief that mass
commercialization will
or could occur by 2030. samsung believes
6g will equally serve humans and
machines
as the main users 6g will be will reign
in an era of advanced services for truly
immersive extend of reality
high fidelity mobile hologram and
digital replica
6g's performance requirements of much
must reach a peak data rate of 1 000
gigabits per second
and air latency of fewer than 100
microseconds
for comparison's sake that's 50 times
the peak data rate of 5g
and 1 10 the latency the company has
identified the three major pillars and
requirements that will make up 6g
in order to fully realize 6g performance
architectural and trustworthiness
requirements must be met
5g was mainly focused around increased
performance
samsung's whitepaper notes that 6g
architectural
and performance requirements will
overcome hurdles made by the limited
computational capacities
of mobile devices trustworthiness will
address
privacy and security concerns
you