covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias apple has
unveiled the first mac computers powered
by its own
m1 chip in june the company announced it
would transition away from the intel
processors it had used since 2006.
apple said the advantages of using the
m1 chip included better battery life
instant wake from sleep mode and the
ability to run ios
apps it added it had optimized all of
its own map apps but now needs to
convince other developers to do likewise
the new computers include new versions
of the 13-inch macbook air
which no longer requires a fan to keep
its processor cool
the 13-inch macbook pro also will also
receive the new
processor and apple says it can now play
video for 20 hours on a single charge
twice as long as before the mac mini
will also receive the m1
it did not unveil new versions of its
imac or mac pro computers
suggesting apple might be waiting for
more advanced versions of the chip with
more memory
and greater graphics processing
capabilities to use
in those the new macs are available
immediately
they run the new mac os big sur
operating system
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias and if you appreciate what we do
become a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you