[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today we're not going to talk about
numbers and the reason very simple by
the time i'm recording this year
uh the u.s election is still going on
and therefore i've got no idea what the
price
of our beloved cryptocurrencies are
currently doing
and so uh we'll focus on something that
is also very important
which is scams and if you're the owner
of one of those ledgers
you might have received an email asking
you to upgrade something
and i hope you didn't do that because it
was a scam
and there are plenty of those currently
in the market
this is coming from the website of
ledger
that are listing a few of those scams
sms messages or so just be very careful
in what you're doing just make sure that
the domain or the website that you're
using
is a legitimate one um never ever
enter those 24 words that you use to
open a wallet
into any other place um because that is
guaranteed a scam
uh just keep those 24 words or those 12
words
secured um and nothing will happen
same with private keys just keep those
private keys on you
because it won't be the last time it's
not the first time it won't be the last
time that try somebody's trying to scam
you
it's very easy to just copy a website
like the ledger website
it'll take an expert probably less than
a day to do that
and then just uh they changed one of
those letters in the name
and you don't even notice that and poof
uh your funds are gone
so be really careful with that and just
to show you
i mean this email that went around uh
came from
a hack that happened probably six seven
months ago
where somebody hacked the ledger
database
and they sold now those names over to
some
scammers and those cameras were the ones
that emailed
you or sent you that sms and those
people in the last three days
they made 107 bitcoin so um
it's not small stuff they made good
money by just scamming
uh people and i hope you're not part of
that
the other one where you have to be
careful is and this is also really
important
is exchanges
two weeks ago bitmex the co-founder
was um uh held and put into custody
i think he's out at the moment but
nevertheless there's huge problems with
bit max
they're still trading uh different to ok
x uh you cannot withdraw any front still
after two weeks from okay x the owner
is uh in custody in china uh kucoin
they lost 200 million dollars in a in a
hack
um and the latest one is here one that
is
uh huawei where the ceo
is also on the police investigation at
this time you still can withdraw funds
but i don't know for how long so if you
go on to
coin market cap and you click on
exchanges in coin market cap you get a
ranking of
the largest exchanges you see huobi is
number three
bigger than kraken and down here uh
place nine you've got kucoin in place
eleven you've got ok x
all those exchanges are not small
exchanges they're big exchanges with big
volumes and nevertheless
legal scrutiny and suddenly can
something can happen
just don't forget also exchanges like
quadriga
two years ago where the owner suddenly
died
and a lot of people lost a lot of money
mount gox 2013 another one
that spectacularly went down under
so just be careful and just to highlight
that
we're going to implement a little image
into our
uh video which is not your keys not your
coins just to remind you
in bleak big black yellow
um letters that you should not leave
any funds on an exchange just take it
off put it on a wallet
uh things can happen and you're not in
control of what the
law is going to do in those countries
all the owners are going to do with
those exchanges you're simply not in
control
things change very quickly here and it's
very easy for an exchange just to close
things down
so um yeah i i hope
i hope you learned something i hope
you're not falling into those scams and
i hope you're really removing
all your funds from those exchanges if
you haven't done so already
and yeah thank you very much for
watching and please leave us
a like it helps us we need to grow and
so just leave us a like
that would be highly appreciated anyway
thank you very much for watching
and i'm looking forward to see you next
week again bye bye
thank you robert just a reminder that
we're not providing financial advice
but only sharing what's happening in the
cryptocurrency markets always remember
that the cryptocurrency markets
are ever-changing and always volatile so
only invest what you can afford to lose
[Music]
[Applause]
do
[Music]
you