covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias you may
remember the pocophone f1
now the poco f2 pro has launched
complete with the qualcomm
snapdragon 865 an impressive 8k video
recording
the pocophone f1 was a rare beast and an
actual example of a flagship killer
now almost two years later it's finally
time for an upgrade
the poco brand began as a sub-brand of
chinese phone manufacturer
show me but with the success of the f-1
it was decided that it could stand on
its own
and they broke it out into its own
independent company based in india
following the f1 they rebranded the
mid-range redmi
k30 calling it the poco x2 now the new
f2 model is essentially a rebranded k30
pro
the poco f2 pro brings a long list of
improvements compared to the f1
starting with the latest chipset the
snapdragon 865 is the best chip from
qualcomm yet
and one of the first to feature gpu
drivers that can be updated
which might improve the phone's
longevity
a lot of emphasis was placed on the
liquid cool 2.0 tech
with a vapor chamber that in itself is
larger than competing phones
poco says this will enable more
efficient cooling
the f2 pro runs android 10 out of the
box with poco launcher 2.0
dark mode is available which looks
gorgeous on the upgraded
amoled screen storage now starts at 128
gigabytes
there's also a 256 gigabytes option
which we'd recommend since they've
removed the microsd
slot and the 8k video can eat up a lot
of space
the storage is fast uf ufs 3.1 up from
2.1
on the f1 the new camera on the on the
poco f2 pro may be what pushes die hard
pocophone
f1 fans to upgrade the phone has four
rear-facing camera sensors
the setup includes a 64-megapixel pixel
sony imx 686 sensor
it supports three-time optical optical
zoom as well as dual optical image
stabilization
there's also a 13 megapixel ultra wide
angle camera
an 8 pixel mega and eight megapixel
telemach
telemat this is a tongue twister an
eight megapixel tele macro camera
and a five megapixel sensor for selfies
you get a 20 megapixel camera on a
motorized pop-up mechanism capable of
just a
1080p video that's the one thing we'd
really like to see improved for vloggers
who are forced to use the rear cameras
if they want to shoot in 4k or 8k ultra
hd
speaking of ultra hd the more powerful
chipset enables 8k
recording at the full 30 fps and 4k
videos can now be recorded at 60fps
the switch to amoled also allowed the
fingerprints reader to be hidden in the
screen
the screen refreshes at a standard 60
hertz but the touch sampling rate has
been increased to 180 hertz
the poco f2 also has widevine l1
certification
so it can play hd content from netflix
amazon prime video and other services
the capacity of the battery has
increased to a 4 700 milliamp hours with
faster
30 watt charging and a headphone jack is
still included
the poco f2 is available now through our
partners
head over to cat5.tv f2 to check it out
[Music]
you