[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today i'd like to focus on something
that a lot of people are asking us
i'd like to get involved in cryptos but
i have no clue how to do that
so um let me focus on that today let me
show you some ideas on how to get
involved
and so there are a few components that
you have to think of the first one is an
exchange in other words
you've got your cash and you would like
to convert it into
cryptos and uh for that you need an
exchange
and the one that we recommend is
uh kraken so this is the kraken
exchange kraken.com k-a-k-r-a-k-e-n
dot com they're by far the best um they
also accept uh u.s uh residents
and uh they have got also the cheapest
rates
um or fees and also
they have got the best service so this
is the
exchange that i recommend others like
bittrex coinbase and so on
but kraken is from my point of view the
best one so
you can wear transfer money over from
your bank account
into kraken and then you just have to
select
the cryptocurrency you want to buy there
are a few categories of cryptocurrencies
basically three
the first one is bitcoin which is the
old the grand ad
that's the most stable one that's the
one that just went
well above all-time high and you cannot
make
big mistakes there so the fluctuations
of course
will exist there and as you can see
currently we've got a dip of 25
which is absolutely normal in this
market but you will not have those
10x or 100x that you might
have heard of the next level is ethereum
and then the rest falls into the third
category so i as a beginner
never get involved in a third category
because you have to learn first how this
market
works it's a little bit like horse
racing yeah so if you go
to a horse race um and you start betting
on a horse
then of course you will lose your money
if you have got no clue
hosts horse performs which way you can
bet
on any horse and the hope that that
horse will win but
the likelihood is very small and for
that
you have to do some research and the
research is also very simple much
simpler than
with traditional uh in the traditional
market with stocks and
and so on and so if you go into coinmark
gecko.com which is our favorite um
directory where you
find all the the big um cryptocurrencies
and then you select one that you like
let's say you've heard of
um let's take here celsius network
and that they've got a good potential
and so on and so you've got two options
here you first you can listen to all
those
experts that are not real experts yeah
i mean you've got a few people that have
got insider knowledge
but you'll hear also opposite of opinion
from other people and there's nobody
in this market that can predict how the
the values are going to behave in the
near future
so you need to rely on your own research
and that's really really simple
so first part what you have to do is you
go on to gecko.com you click on the
favorite
um currency that you're interested in
and in here you've got all the
information that you need yeah so if you
scroll a little bit down you see of
course
the the trading view and then you've got
here the all-time high so all-time high
on celsius was 6.82 on the
third of january uh 2000 was eight days
ago and the all-time low
is beginning of to the end of 2018
so about two years ago that was the
all-time low
which is interesting to know that so you
know if there is a big potential
uh in regards to the price then here
a little bit further up you've got the
markets
and the markets just tell you where you
can buy those and this is also important
so for example you've got uniswap here
you can go
of course directly to unit swap and buy
it there
you run risk that you fall into a hoax
because not everybody uh i mean you can
launch a celsius network token on
on unit swap so the best way is to get
to coingecko you click on this
field here that will redirect you to
uniswap and then you can then exchange
your ethereum for example against
celsius tokens so that's one way the
markets
is where you find the liquidity
next one in regards to your research is
you go onto their website and just check
on how this looks i mean is this
something you would like to get involved
in
is this something that appeals to you
personally
do some research what are the people
that are involved are the developers
all those things next is you go into
twitter or telegram
both not so much facebook not so much
write it but twitter is definitely
important and telegram is important
telegram
is people like you and i that
telegram is a group where they we meet
and
we discuss things yeah so if you've got
a question around the celsius network
regardless of what question that might
be you go into telegram you ask that
question you'll get
for sure a very swift answer
so that's telegram twitter is more of
well i mean you know twitter so i don't
have to tell you anything about that
so that's basically the research so the
research
revolves around um the product yeah does
the product appeal to you
then the users how many users are there
is this a coin
that only a few users are interested in
then i would be careful because
you know that if there are not many
people involved then
it's unlikely that this thing will go uh
10x 100x or whatever
and then the utility of the coin yeah so
you can what can you do with it is there
already an example the sample
so this is different to the traditional
market because the traditional market is
always around
the valuation of the company management
and also key figures of the company
yeah and you buy a share in the company
that's
completely different in this market here
this market is built on hype
uh we're currently in a bubble uh yes it
is a bubble
and it will burst at one day like they
always do in the crypto market
and so you only work towards this bubble
yeah and once this bubble burst the
equation is a different one
you have to change your mind shift uh at
that
stage when will that be nobody knows but
until then
this is what we recommend to you so get
an account on kraken
buy with your fiat uh the currency that
you like
do a research beforehand if you're
complete newbie
uh focus only on bitcoin and ethereum
don't touch
the others um because you might make big
mistakes like withhold phrases yeah so
you can
make big mistakes there too if you bet
on a horse that nobody ever heard of
so that's um that's basically
it from my point of view just showing
you a little bit on how to get involved
in this
i didn't touch anything in regards to
wallets or other things
that will come at another stage so focus
on
the exchange get your tokens currencies
purchased on that exchange but do your
research beforehand
so that's it for me um it's an exciting
market as you can see
we've been saying that all along the
time so i hope
i hope you get involved um not financial
advice of course
anyway so thank you very much for
watching please leave us a like
and subscribe and come back soon next
week
thank you bye thank you robert just a
reminder that we're not providing
financial advice
but only sharing what's happening in the
cryptocurrency markets always remember
that the cryptocurrency markets
are ever-changing and always volatile so
only invest what you can afford to lose
[Music]
[Applause]
you