welcome to
uh category five tv coffee break
it is the uh it is october the fourth
um sunday and i'm bp nine hello
and uh i see doug over there on um
uh on the other screen and
uh well peter was here but he's dropped
out so i i guess he had some microphone
issues
he didn't have any he didn't have any
video and then he uh
he he dropped out so i'm guessing he's
going to call back in again
shortly so all right so um
uh what i was going to say what and
peter won't hear it but um uh
please understand if i have to mute you
it's because you're making um a bunch of
noise on the
on the microphone and you're distracting
from the audio
so um uh if if that
you know if it if i have to mute you
it's because
um uh it's because the uh um
[Music]
uh it's because the audio has been too
distracting and i have to
to do something about that so it's no no
slight on you or anything like that it's
just that
i have to do my best to make sure we we
uh have good
uh good video and audio on the uh
uh on the mic on the on the recording so
so i appreciate your understanding with
that so
hello robbie greetings hey robbie hi
everyone
hi guys um
i haven't been able to join you yet in
season two
yeah you too how's my sound i heard
you're you're talking about sound issues
uh you're overdriving the mic just a
little bit you're a little
a little hot on the microphone but uh
otherwise you're
yeah that's much better yeah that's much
better
oh who's good i'm gonna have to run it
through the compressor
yeah that'll be you that'll be me
so i've done this and i
so i've done the intro but i'll do it
again real quick so i'm bp nine
and uh on my left that way
is doug give us a wave doug hey
and then below him is peter and then
robbie give us a wave sir uh-oh we've
just lost peter again
give us a wave robbie and then sober
hello welcome
glad to see you so i was just explaining
uh
when you all uh when you all dropped in
thanks for the royal wave there robbie i
saw that
so i was just explaining i was just
explaining that uh
if i have to mute you which please don't
take that as a
as an affront or an or a insult it's
just that i have to do my best to
keep the recording as clean as i
possibly can so so
so i appreciate your understanding with
that so thank you
so bp nine i should say to the viewers
then
that if suddenly i'm like if my mouth is
moving
but you're not hearing anything just
know that bp9 has shut me up
because i wouldn't necessarily know i
wouldn't necessarily know would i
why would i would i do that to you
robbie would i do
that to you we should you probably i've
already won
[Laughter]
we've gone through the it's it's it's
all good it's not a problem
so here's here's what i've been doing
i don't know you've seen this before
right
you've seen this device prf-80 yes sir
candy trs-30 model 100 and seen one of
those in about 40 years i
know i know well it runs its own doug
where to date me
[Laughter]
this was manufactured in uh i believe it
i want to say
late 80s but i can't find a if i
if i'd remember no no it was it was
later than that as i recall but
in any case 83
my cats my cat's messing with us
um so the the bitter news that i have on
this
is that what i did was installed
a thing called an option rom on this
thing
and what it lets me do when i do that
and i'm just going to pop it open so you
can see
what it lets me do is it lets me run
cpm on the machine
nice so if you can see i don't know if
you can see that
it's got okay what it is oh there we are
so what it is is that there are two uh
uh sockets in in the um
uh in the back of the unit that allow
you to plug in what's called an option
rom
and what i put in its place is a device
that replaces all of the memory in this
thing
um because as delivered this thing has
32k
of 32k of rom and 32k of ram i'm gonna
say
all of the memory oh 32k
all of the 32k yes
so it lets you replace
it lets you replace the um uh
uh all of the all of the memory in it
and give you 64k
of memory and then it um
and then it's uh
also has enough space on that dinky
little device
for a four megabyte hard drive
wow
that's why i did it because my capra
you've seen me use the capro before
you've seen
if you go back to the earlier coffee
breaks you'll see
the the um the uh uh
you'll see the capro that i was using
previously
and it only allows something like 390k
on the um on each floppy disk
well with this i have a four megabyte
hard drive and i can go crazy with it if
i want to
so i'm really chuffed about that um
that came to my mind when i heard you're
talking about the 32 ko memory
is uh does anyone even have a document
smaller than 32k
the answer to that is yes because i've
been transcribing a lot of documents
for um for um
uh uh for cpm uh the cpm
uh a lot of the uh uh
and also for this model 100 as well
applications for this model 100
there are a lot of programs that have
user manuals
that are that are pdfs but they've been
scanned in
so they're not searchable and they're
just images they're just
images of pages so what i've been doing
is transcribing them into a
document processing language called tech
for latex
use some kind of recognition
i tried i did try that but i can't
i just don't get good enough um
i just don't get good enough uh uh
character recognition by the time i go
back and correct
all of the issues i may as well have
just typed the thing in from scratch
so i take one chapter at a time and i
type that into
yeah we hear you peter um
taken off the pdf file if you've done
braids already
the recognization will not work very
well
yeah well the original the original
image that was that was stored in the
pdf is pretty crappy anyway
it's pretty poor so ocr
that's what i was just explaining that
the ocr is just not very uh strong
it's it's not going to be very
successful so you end up having to just
type the whole page in anyway by the
time you get around to
trying to correct all the mess that you
get from from attempting ocr
so that is what it is that's how it
works
so the other thing that i was going to
show you
if any of you are familiar with palm os
at all we're going back in time here do
you remember
we are i'm i'm such a geek today
remember
and also all the participants of the
coffee breaks are old farts anyway
yeah come on now
come on now so here is what
here is what my uh um what my phone
now does i can now if i can get that
lined up properly
i can now instead of using the keyboard
on the
um on the uh
instead of using the keyboard on the the
k-pro
um a correction on the k-pro i really am
retro today
instead of using the keyboard on the
android well the screen just went blank
uh like the on-screen keyboard you mean
i can now
it's yes i replaced that on-screen
keyboard with
an application called graffiti pro
and what that does is it lets me i don't
know if i'm going to be able to demo it
but what it does
if i uh if i literally type
in this is a test and i do it over
graffiti
i don't know if i can easily do this but
i say this
is a test
and what will happen is that it has
you know i've done that through the
oh it just says this is a test on the
screen
and i did that through graffiti not on
the keyboard
it's j i i i just trying it out for a
while to see if it works and i'm finding
it works pretty well i can actually
you know type notes in pretty quickly um
using using this so it's just a bit of
fun
it's just a bit of fun so that's what
i've been up to
so long
coming on to f right there
f droid where have i heard that before
what does that do
it's on a on a
free it's an uh alternative to
al alternative to the google store and
they have only free software open source
software
oh okay that's okay that's where i've
heard it before
got it okay probably by me all right
let's go around the room
let's go around the room doug what
you've been up to sir
well i've been sick since uh late monday
evening
um oh no apparently
it's food poisoning
and i've had oh no yeah
not to be in delicate but i've had uh
diarrhea uh dry heaves
um i had a fever
and extreme chills i mean uncontrollable
shivering
violent uncontrollable shivering and
loss of appetite
yeah and i went to my doctor and he put
me on clear liquids
and it helped
um my fever went away
he had me calling back a couple of days
later and
he said okay try solid food very bland
salad food
so i was eating stuff like
cold cuts um
yeah bread or toast with just a little
bit of jelly
stuff like that yeah
[Music]
i was using the bathroom like every half
hour yeah
so i
[Music]
so i've stopped uh stopped eating it and
back i put myself back on clear liquids
and
i got to call them tomorrow we'll see
what happens but
how's that ham sandwich going good
i'm sorry i should not make light of it
doug
i hope you get to feeling better soon
yeah
i i keep up those liquids because
something i did not know is that or i
found found recently well a while ago
was that a lot of the liquid a lot of
the moisture
uh that you absorb into the body is
through them absolutely
yes i did not i knew that i didn't yeah
so you've got to keep you've got to keep
the liquids up because that'll
keep everything let's say you're moving
shelby
[Laughter]
robbie stop laughing making us
yeah diced carrots don't just go right
through i'm just looking forward to
seeing your description for today's
episode of bp-9
uh i i don't know how i'm gonna describe
this one
[Music]
oh man we should not we should not
stop stopping now but
i i say enough and then i laugh i'm so
sorry doug this is not
this is not professional it's all right
we can't
we can't help ourselves but robbie we
haven't seen you in a couple of weeks
what have you been up to yeah
oh nothing i've just been relaxing bp
night
[Laughter]
yeah right see what they did there yeah
i believe that i believe that
yeah so today i've got the server yeah
i've got the server
all torn apart drives everywhere
oh so i'm pulling all the i'm pulling
all the drives running fio test
gotta run some tests and then i've got
ssd's data center drive to put in there
so you're going to see some nice
improvement in performance right there
a little bit of a performance
improvement yes
lucky nice now you do know how to use
dvd in linux
you you do know how to use db in linux
right
well yes what do i need that for my
transfer
to transfer all the data from the
spinning drive to that
no no i don't need to do that um because
i've
uh i came in i've spent the last three
days running redundant backups
so i've got full images of the entire
system on separate drives
um
it's at 96 doing an offline rebuild
right now
so um so while i'm running fio tests to
get the
benchmarks um so i'm benchmarking the
spinning drive and then once i upgrade
to the ssds i'm going to be benchmarking
those to see what the difference in
performance is
and i got um
one of these like decibel indicators
that show you the ambient noise
nice so i i actually took a reading
before
so i took a reading before so that i
could hear because you know that i've
been trying to cut down on the noise in
the studio
or in the on the bridge but i'm curious
to know
if getting spinning drives out of the
server because there's six of them right
if that's going to make a difference um
on noise because spinning drives do
generate a little bit of motor noise
it should be should make a little bit of
a difference eh yeah
right oh absolutely that's what i meant
today guys
the capro had uh the capri 2x the cpm
machine that i
that i demoed several several months ago
in the
in the previous coffee break had two
floppy drives in it
and they generate a huge amount of noise
exactly and i pulled those out
and put in an sd card reader in in their
place to emulate
flop yeah i recall it's dead silent now
no fans no nothing so you turn it on
and you hear that zip you hear nothing
it's amazing
so i remember watching a video of
someone
yeah a video redoing um
um a rec server i think it was off of
uh two unit um uh wreck server
and he was um taking out the um
france uh wreck mountain service uh
the fans are not uh particularly quiet
here they took those out and here uh we
did
um the um um without
few with our pliers and and he mounted
the
um standard uh silent desktop fans
and he connected those to the um and all
of a sudden
it went from very noisy to is it on
yeah yeah it is amazing that the amount
of noise these machines can make it's
quite surprising
and i guess you're right i guess they
don't care if it's a server a rack
mounted device
i guess they don't care too much about
noise but there must be all kinds of
noise in a data center as well yeah i
often wonder that
oh yeah like when i walk into the data
center where our server's co-located
um it's like you walk in and it's just
nasty and i just wonder like why don't
dell
and the the big server companies why
don't they
reduce the noise like it makes sense
right like
they're not cheap fans that they put in
it like it's it's not like they're
cheaping out and going with
noisy fans like they could put silent
fans in their servers and it would take
the levels from here to here
yeah just to make it more pleasant and i
think
maybe we'll start to see more of that do
you think we'll start to see more of
that because uh we're gonna have so many
more
uh work from home environments where
people have to have
servers like my my boys from uh from the
oroville
uh brandon fayette is his setup is like
he has
um petabytes of data storage sitting in
his living room because
he's doing the video production for the
orville it's like
so like they need to make them quieter i
got a
i'll just uh put the rest down in the
basement and then i won't hear it from
up here so that'll work for me
yeah and eric moved when we
upgraded our servers from an old uh
system to
a newer system that we bought from the
data center
and we went to the data center and they
had it lying on a desk
helping us to install the drives it
turned out one of the drive was bad so
they had to
and get a new one and i remember when
they had to go to
get a new drive and then we had to wait
for uh half an hour before he came back
yeah and then they shut down the server
in the uh small uh
room yeah we were
three people in the uh room and when
they he shut down the
um when the fourth guy shut down the
server all things simultaneously
yeah yeah yeah i'm not surprised oh you
wouldn't believe
in here when i turn that thing off it's
just like this place just becomes like a
sound booth
yeah you know that that where there's
just nothing there's no ambient noise at
all which is like
brilliant but it seems like doesn't that
alcove doesn't that alcove help
to i guess it acts more as a amplifier
it might
it might separate yeah yeah so what i
did is i put the server on the very
bottom of the rack so it's close to the
carpet
and then i was going to i was going to
put some sound isolation foam around it
just to
help yeah i was going to say
that nice so real quick robbie anything
anything else you want to add
before i hand it over to sober
no hand it over to soldier but i just
wanted to stop in i'm literally waiting
for fio tests to run they're going to
take hours
so i thought and it was it was five
minutes before noon
that uh that i started the fio test so i
thought oh i can make it to coffee break
today so
good to see you so glad you made it
robbie yeah i'm glad you're helping in
man
yeah sober what you've been up to
nothing much just being uh home alone as
usual
um i did one run to the uh grocery store
and yeah i'm just just looking at home
outside a few a few minutes every day
and
the post office is still working i'm
still getting bills in the mail so
uh you know it's all working people seem
to be coming
no the people people keep complaining
that
uh the post the u.s postal service is so
messed up but no no no i'm still getting
bills so that's working out just fine
you know
how about you peter what uh what sort of
trouble have you been getting into
um
you know i've been having a bad arm and
i playing there on the uh
young lady in the role dead by the way
trying to strangle me
well i went to the doctor today i heard
bad
i peter i heard bad arm and blamed it on
somebody but
i'm not sure that's the first thing
we've heard of at least
i think he blames it on you bp9
okay fine i don't care
um oh yes yes
well i um
[Music]
now peter slow down wait wait for some
reason
your audio has just blown right through
the roof i don't know what you think
what you changed i
i i found a large
lump
under his arm is that right peter yeah
preliminary oh my god you're having a
preliminary uh
like the doctors are going to give you a
prelim to see what's going on
yeah yeah uh
uh give me the treatment and the role uh
which i knew about so i got to go
through
therapy yeah
how do they think that your valve change
how did they think that your valve
change has anything to do with this
peter the good they got because the
woman got me bothered
[Music]
it's only been two or three weeks into
surgery though hasn't it so
it'll take a while yeah
i think he got me to learn about why he
went
to the hospital afternoon
they gave her a couple weeks away they
sent her out and they said well that's
it
all we can do you just gotta sit down
and she didn't sit down
and uh they came running after that they
got round and
uh from the old table a toilet chair
she broke she broke that bone aren't
now they're talking about another
opponent and then they talk about their
vote
and they're all in the same area they
don't really really
really know what they're doing and uh
uh so they just arrested
[Music]
i like sitting down and watching tv and
watching youtube and stuff so i would
have no trouble at all doing that
well yeah going to have trouble healing
up if she doesn't uh she doesn't rest it
though
i told her that one and i'd give her
we're running out of time now we're
running out of time now later but but
let me say let me say peter my thoughts
are with you are
all of us so our thoughts are with you i
hope uh all goes well
do keep us up to date with that uh with
that lump in your arm and with your wife
and the same thing for you doug keep us
keep us posted on
on how you're progressing keep those
yeah it's all it's all good it's all
right
all right we're up to we're up to 30
minutes now so
i'm i'm gonna uh i'm gonna get ready to
shut this down so
thank you all for um for for joining and
having some fun with us
um and uh for keeping it keeping it
geeky because that's what we do that's
that's how we roll folks so um
thank you all and uh have a great day
take care everyone bye-bye thank you see
you guys
get healthy