what i like about minecraft and i mean
yes i'm an adult and
you know probably oh you shouldn't be
playing video games and stuff that's
what your life sounds like
but no the the truth is uh i i love that
minecraft is such a creative atmosphere
it's it's an open world
where you craft whatever you can come up
with based on the elements within the
world but the cool thing is
as a dad during this lockdown it's
an element where i can connect with my
kids on a personal level
where because they're you know they're
not hanging out with their friends they
don't have the same social
interaction uh you know with the server
that that you know we set up
they can connect with other kids
remotely yeah they're building
relationships it's a social thing
yeah absolutely they're building
relationships which is which is cool but
at the same time
i can be sitting at the kitchen table
take a you know 15
20 minute break from my work when one of
the kids is like oh i'm going to go on
the minecraft server
and i'll join them got to check out the
episode if you haven't seen it you got
to build the server and download it for
your kids yeah i'm not going to pretend
that i use it for
um educational purposes um
i am i'm the minecraft noob among us
so this is the first experience that
i've had with mine you've
previously been with mind test correct
yeah the open source kind of alternative
um minecraft i've never played and
i'm just finding it so much fun but and
as an adult like that's kind of
surprising to me i didn't realize how
much i was going to enjoy it but the
other thing too
is i mentioned that it's social but i'm
finding that it's
quality time with my kids yes so we're
collaborating and we're working together
my my youngest who's 10
he and i this past weekend spent a good
couple of hours anyways
mining together so we found a mine and
we're looking for
different uh ores and then we're
smelting things and
we're collaboratively working together
to to uh play this game and it's just a
boatload of fun
and at the heart of it is this little
raspberry pi
micro server that that we created on the
show and it's just a blast
of course a lot of folks are like me
never played minecraft before
let's take some time to show those
viewers um how to play the game
sure absolutely so i have my laptop here
oh fantastic oh look at that it's got an
hdmi cable going into our broadcast
server
imagine that so hey stick around right
after this quick break we're going to be
firing that up and jeff is going to be
teaching you
how to get started with minecraft don't
go anywhere
[Music]
so
all right we're back we're talking about
minecraft uh before the break
and one of the things we want to show
you tonight is kind of how to get
started
because you know our last episode we set
up the server
and now if you've never played minecraft
you're like i don't even know what to do
so that was me jeff it was you and what
i'm going to do is take five minutes
just to kind of walk you through
your first couple of minutes in a
minecraft world to get you started
and then from there you can start
exploring because when minecraft when
you load in
you have nothing you're in the middle of
wherever the game generates you
and you have a portion of a day
to get yourself set up before the night
hits and all the bad guys come out
so you got to be ready for that
otherwise like me you'd just be running
around with
a stick
yeah and i had to laugh the first time
uh
my youngest son loaded minecraft he
didn't know what he was doing and then
it came to night
and i heard this blood curdling scream
from down in the basement nobody got
hurt i go running down there i'm like
dude what's up and he's like it's night
and the is gonna get me
and he needed me to rescue him sure i
you know in a matter of like 30 seconds
built him into a little block and waited
for this
hey whatever it takes yeah exactly so
i'm just going to walk you through so
uh we're gonna switch to my computer
here sure and uh we'll go from there so
as i said i've already set up a new
world i'm gonna load right in
i'm in the middle of a forest so i've
got nothing going on i have full health
i have full food so i'm not hungry
but i'm in the middle of nowhere
[Music]
the first thing you want to do is take
down a tree
you don't need any tools to take down a
tree
you can just use your hand but the
reason you want to take it down is
because
you can instantly create you see i've
got a new recipe unlocked because i have
the wood
you can instantly create some tools that
allow you to get started
uh so i'm taking a couple of blocks and
with you know we talked about the
educational component of minecraft
minecraft works in a lot of mathematical
formulas and so for every raw piece of
wood
you can produce it into four planks so
by pressing the e button on my computer
i bring up my inventory
and you'll see here i have seven spruce
logs i drag them over to crafting
and each log is going to give me four
spruce planks
so at the end of the day i've got 28
planks so you've just clicked on those
i just click on them and now you see i
have a whole whack of new recipes
wow so from here i can then take my
spruce planks
put them in and i'm not seeing anything
other than a button
so i don't want a button that's not
going to help me but if i click this
green book
i now have recipes that i can make so
i'm going to click this box so i could i
don't see
all i see the ones i can make there's a
crafting table a stick a pressure plate
and a button well a crafting table
sounds like something i'm going to want
so i click it and it shows me that four
spruce planks gives me a crafting
table so i'm going to pull that out of
my inventory
and now i have a crafting table
so as you can see where are we i want to
see if i can find the sun
you're kind of in the middle of a forest
here jeff yeah it's kind of hard to see
but um so i'm going to put the crafting
table down to place an item
it's a right click whoops wrong item
that's a wooden plank right there there
is a wooden blank i'm going to go to my
crafting table
there now my crafting table's down and
to use my crafting table i right click
and now i have different items available
to me i can make a door stairs whatever
in this case i'm going to want a couple
of sticks and the reason you want sticks
they are the building blocks of life you
need sticks for tools you need sticks
for torches
all that kind of stuff
so now because i've collected sticks i
have a bunch of new recipes
again i go back to my crafting table and
now you can see
i can make a wooden axe a wooden sword a
wooden hoe
a wooden uh pickaxe a wooden shovel uh
as well as a uh some ladders so to get
started i'm gonna need a sword
gotta defend myself it's a wooden sword
and i'm going to want a wooden peck axe
so why do you need a pickaxe when you
just break things with your hands
because you get to the point where you
see over in the mountain how you got
that gray
yeah that's actually stone you're going
to get getting into harder and harder
elements and you need a more robust
tool so the the pickaxe
you'll see has two attack damage 1.2
attack speed so it does
double the damage that your hand does
okay
now granted attack is more so for bad
creatures
but in the case here a pickaxe is gonna
a wooden pickaxe is gonna do more damage
for mining and ore than my hand would
okay
so i'm gonna pick up oops i don't wanna
use my
uh sword to pick up my because they have
a finite life right that's
the more you hit with it the the shorter
it lives
that's right so now that you've gotten
started you've got your wood
before it turns to night one of the
things you want to do is find
shelter now i always recommend heading
towards
some sort of a hill because
they generally have some sort of
uh cave system like this
where you can get deeper and deeper in
now it does get dark
and the darker it gets the more you're
going to see
uh mobs and whatnot so over there is
iron that's lava don't touch it you'll
burn
but one thing i want to point out that i
saw in the hill just above me
is coal oh
where did i see the coal somewhere over
here
and you're going to just learn to
recognize these blocks
just by the way that they appear so i'm
going to show you here i'm trying to
mine with my hand
it's taken a while to get through the
block but you can see it's slowly
cracking
okay so that's with my hand now if i go
to my pickaxe
that was so much faster yeah
so you can see how much faster it goes
well there's cool there's coal
and why you want coal is you're going to
be able to use it to make
torches as you see as i'm grabbing these
elements
i'm getting more and more recipes you
also saw
that i earned an achievement where i got
the stone
yeah and so when you start off quickly
get your wood tools
and try and find coal and the reason you
want to find coal is that you can have
torches because torches are going to be
the lifeblood
at night because it gives you light so
in my case i've got some coal i am now
going to head down here
to this little hole okay perfect spot to
get started
so as you know i have some wood
uh planks i'm gonna make a little
doorway
so one two
three four
and this is where the building elements
come in
five six
and seven so now i have that blocked off
other than
a doorway and i'm gonna put my crafting
table down
so i've got something to work with
and you see here i have new recipes i've
got a lever i've got andesite
diorite there's a bunch of stuff i can
work with but i'm running low
on wood so there's some of my recipes
have disappeared
oh okay so as you use up your resources
you need to come back and get more now
again i'm using my hand i could have
made a wood
um pickaxe or sorry a wood
axe which would make mining a tree that
much faster
not to work because i still have enough
daylight
but what i'm going to do is collect all
that wood
i'm going to come back down here to my
crafting table
and i need to make these spruce planks
again
so if you have a lot of resources you
can make things go faster by holding
shift and then click the resource and
all of it will carry over into the
crafting section
and you see here i've got five um spruce
logs and
each one produces four spurs planks
again if i hold down shift
and then left click all of it instantly
got all 20.
so it's much faster very good so now
because
i have that doorway i want to make a
spruce door oh
cool so there's my door
[Music]
and a little tip because this is outside
and we still have enough time before it
turns to night when you place a door
you want to go outside your place
and place the door from the outside i'm
going to break this door and you're
going to see why
because if i placed it from the inside
it goes to the other side of the block
layer
and if there is a mob which is what they
call the like the creatures that attack
you
it's going to want to get in the door
and it's going to stand here
with a block above it to protect it from
the sunlight so things like zombies and
skeletons
will survive at night but they burn up
during the day oh
so a little safety tip when you're
building a house is build the door on
the outside so that it's standing in
this direct sunlight
yeah so come morning time it will burn
up
and then anything that's at your door is
going to go away perfect
so now that we've got our door
i'm gonna go back inside and you're
right-clicking to open the door i'm
right-clicking to open the door
and now i'm gonna do something with the
uh coal that i had
got my sticks
my coal and you see i have torches
so i'm going to collect my torches i now
have access to 28 torches
and what that's going to do is provide
light for me
so now when it comes night time this
area is lit up
and you're not going to have mobs spawn
in here and kill you
which is generally avoided to die so if
you're just getting started with
minecraft
that's a quick tutorial on how to safely
get started
in a way that allows you to survive and
explore from there
the one other thing i'll mention is
you're gonna need
food so if
you get started and you're lucky enough
to have animals around you like i see a
pig over there
awesome because that's going to give you
access to
food some pork right away can you eat
that without cooking it
i can eat it without cooking uh it's got
better nutritional value
if you do cook okay so i take that pig
oh poor piggy he even has hearts
he does have hearts oh he loves you jeff
i know he does
he's not happy with me anymore uh so now
i have access to
i just i just want to put out there
hashtag bacon
[Laughter]
uh i did see a fox oh look there's a fox
can you eat it
uh i don't know if you can eat fox i
can't say it as i've tried
but um the sun is starting to go down
and you can see in the horizon we're
getting that
like dusk color nice or sorry uh
yeah dusk um so it's kind of got that
pink tone to it when that happens
you want to get back to your base of
safe operations
uh otherwise what's gonna happen is mobs
are going to spawn
and when it comes to torches one thing i
will mention is they produce light
um for an area of
six blocks that will prevent a mob from
spawning
so if you put a torch down nothing will
spawn within six blocks so one two three
four five six this is a safe zone for
light
this is not it doesn't look like much of
a difference but the mechanics of the
game
says that this is dark enough something
is gonna spawn
okay which you don't want to do so yeah
and if
if it does spawn can it walk into the
light it can walk into the light once it
spawns yes
and so you want to have enough light
around your base area that nothing is
really going to spawn
near you if you are comfortable enough
doing that especially at night now you
see there's the moon the moon's coming
up
there is a creeper i want to avoid it
over there
so i'm going to run down to my base open
my door
close it now they do not open doors
unless you build your game into hardcore
mode
uh then they will break down doors and
come in but right now it's nighttime
i'm effectively safe here okay and so i
think that's a great spot to stop
fantastic yeah a good start for sure so
what's next in the game like what what
happens next for us
so at this point you start exploring
you want to explore you want to
understand the achievements you want to
take it to the next level so
you saw that i started to collect some
stone yeah when i was looking for the
coal
so now you have the ability to make or i
have the ability to make stone tools as
opposed to wood tools
and then obviously stone tools are
stronger than wood tools
right then you're going to want to start
exploring and mining because the deeper
you go
into the earth the more you're getting
getting valuable resources and a little
bit there when i was looking into the
cave
i said oh there's some iron yeah iron is
uh
obviously stronger than stone right okay
so an iron pickaxe is gonna do
go a lot further for mining than a stone
pickaxe would
and so you're going to have to
continually re um
you know stock up on some of those base
resources like you're always going to
need wood
what is a core component of just about
everything in there
stone is used in a lot of things then
you're going to get into the more rare
ones like iron
uh and then diamond diamond spawns
most common spawn isn't the right word
but it generates most common between
blocks 12 and 14
uh when you're playing your game all
right this will all make sense to you
later on later yeah but when you're
playing on your computer
f3 is going to bring up the
game kind of stats you'll be able to see
the blocks you're looking at
tell where you are in the world if you
need to find your coordinates that kind
of stuff and so when you start mining
down
you're going to want to go down to block
12 to 14 to get those diamonds again
that's more advanced stuff
but we're not even going to get into
that stuff right now but that's the
basics if you're getting started so
you've just set up your pie your
raspberry pi
uh minecraft server and you're like what
do i do yeah
get some wood some torches that gets it
gets you going and then from there
we will be over the course of the next
while um getting into some more advanced
builds
yes jeff what is the most sophisticated
build that you've done so far on the
server
i would say actually would be the
collaboration with you
excellent we generated a
villager spawning section where
the villagers when they have enough food
they'll breed and have more villagers
and then we used a train track system to
transport them from one village to
another to create a villager trading
post
yeah which then gives us access to a
whole bunch of new resources that
otherwise we'd have to go exploring to
find
but they'll trade with us so that's
probably the most advanced thing we've
built
i'm glad that i was a part of it yeah
yeah i mean and me being the noob like
i'm learning the mechanics and so
the the basically the ability to have
villagers
um uh breed is like part of the
mechanics of the game and so i created
a system that would allow that to happen
automatically yes
um so that's that's been a lot of fun
and it's a lot of fun to to do these
builds
and we'll show you that build down the
line as well so you'll get to see that
yeah do check out the entire series on
minecraft
you can see the links below or if you're
watching this on cable tv or some other
way where you don't have those links
just head on over to category5.tv
and do a quick search in the search bar
at the top for
[Music]
minecraft
[Applause]
[Music]
so