covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias microsoft has
submitted a series of patches to the
linux kernel with its aim being
to create a complete virtualization
stack with linux and microsoft
hypervisor
the patches are designated rfc requests
for comments
and are a minimal implementation
presented for discussion
the key change is that with the patched
kernel linux will run
as the hyper-v root partition in the
hyper-v
architecture the root partition has
direct access to hardware
and creates child partitions for the
virtual machines it hosts
microsoft principle software engineer
wei liu says
just think of it like zen's dom0
hyper-v's architecture is more similar
to zen than it is to kvm or to
esxi and leo acknowledged that they in
fact draw
inspiration from the zen code in linux
until now the hyper-v root partition had
to run
windows microsoft has also ported
intel's open source cloud hypervisor
a virtual machine monitor that normally
runs on kvm
which is built into the linux kernel
with these changes microsoft likely has
its azure cloud
infrastructure in mind azure runs more
linux than windows as
acknowledged back in july 2019 by
microsoft engineer sasha levin
who said the linux usage on our cloud
has surpassed windows
linux already runs well on hyper-v with
a windows root partition
but making this a complete linux stack
may improve performance
microsoft is also working hard to
improve linux support in windows 10
with sls or sorry wsl2
and they even ship a linux kernel with
windows
gui support has been promised wsl-2
also uses hyper-v and windows 10 is on a
path to becoming a hybrid windows
linux system though as of now this is
mainly of interest to developers
microsoft's ignite virtual conference is
taking place next week
and we can expect the company to say
more about his linux plans then
you