[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today we're going to talk about
confusing things and we'll have a
solution for you
confusing things are those influencers
that are constantly bombarding you what
to buy and what not to buy and
they all say it's not financial advice i
know
now let's take a look into that to
explain what i'm talking about
so i opened youtube because most of the
big influences are all in youtube
i uh searched for crypto i did
a search and i selected those that
appeared this week
and on the top list i see
bitcoin tops easy six figure bitcoin in
isn't that interesting next one here is
crypto market dip ether and ada network
updates coming
bitcom you and this one is live at the
moment prepare yourself somebody talking
about again bitcoin
fifty thousand and sixty thousand in one
day
um market crash uh coming soon here's
somebody
uh cardano price prediction and an ad i
mean
this is really confusing if you're not
deep
into uh researching uh cryptos
so many of us and i include myself in
this year in the early days
then start hopping around so if some
influencers start selling
or recommending coin a then you jump
into coin a and suddenly the price does
go up
but it doesn't isn't usually not very
long lasting after one day or so they
come down in price again
um and you lost money because the fees
are high
and and yeah you buy high and you sell
low the typical problem of a beginner
so my recommendation is twofold one is
stay cool and i'll show show you some
ways how to do that
and the other one is do not trade yeah
trade is something if you're really deep
into this year
and you have got um the knowledge
on how to trade and what to trade uh so
knowledge in projects
then yes you might trade but my
experience i've always lost money when i
started trading
and following these people in regards to
recommendations
so what do i recommend yeah it's
you have to listen to yourself first
research the coin
token that you want to invest in i've
shown a few videos on how to do that
and just be sure that this is a long
term project you want to invest in
if you don't find anything use bitcoin
that's the safest part
but on the other hand
and you've seen these trading charts
well chart analysis with fibonacci
and so on and so on bollinger bands
where people are going to come up with a
four hourly chart and a 12-hour child
wow
blah blah blah which is that that's
really confusing and that's i think
somehow now starting to be applicable
because we're getting old
world people into our industry but not
so much
the beauty of this year is that we've
got also statistics that are coming from
unchained data so
for example how many people are taking
their coins off exchanges
why is it important because if people
are taking the coins off exchanges it
means
they don't want to sell it if they are
on the other hand
returning coins onto the exchanges
that's usually a sign that they're about
to sell something
so those statistics there are few around
and i just want to show you a few that
are really
really compelling and the website is
look into bitcoin.com
so the first one we're going to look to
into mvrv
so market value and
realized value and it takes a second to
load
but i'm sure we'll see that in a second
here we go
so the this is the the chart of the of
this uh this indicator and the blue line
is the
price of bitcoin and as you can see when
this thing peaked
the price price of bitcoin also peaked
when this was
the price was low the indicator was low
so it's a pretty good indicator
to tell you when to buy and when to sell
at the moment as you can see it's here
in the middle ground
so it's not in the red it's not in the
green area and there are few others like
those around
so they are holding ratio and you can
this website is really good
uh because it also explains to you in
detail
uh how what this indicator is and how to
read it
and again here this hour holder ratio is
something completely different to what
we saw before
but here price high indicator high price
high indicator high price low indicator
low
so a pretty good correlation between
when to buy and when to sell or here's
the next one
the new unrealized profit and loss ratio
here when things go into the red it
means it's danger zone
at the moment it's already in red but i
would say that those real peaks here
is about 70 80 percent that's
uh when the danger zone is here and
again when the
price peaked this indicator peak yeah so
you see
that there are a few of those indicators
that really make sense
uh to follow and to study and that will
give you the confidence whether you're
investing in the right thing or not
so yeah that's it for me uh today
i just um wanted to make sure that you
don't get confused and you don't start
trading
and moving around your coins in case you
have got some investment because that
would be
um uh not good for you not good for your
money
so um yeah that's it for me so thank you
very much for watching and hope to see
you next week again
thanks bye-bye thank you robert just a
reminder that we're not providing
financial advice but only sharing what's
happening in the cryptocurrency markets
always remember that the cryptocurrency
markets are ever-changing and
always volatile so only invest what you
can afford to lose
[Music]
you