hello welcome
to category 5 community coffee break
i'm bp 9. this is the first coffee break
for
2021 so happy new year to to everybody
who's here and who's also watching after
the event
um above me on this side oh i got it
right for once look at that there's doug
on my screen so say hello doug give us a
wave thank you sir
and then peter's up on this one hello
i'll have a go i'll have a go at
figuring out what it is later but anyway
this is my handy dandy you butte whiz
bang
garage door opener sequencer card
and i have made some progress uh first
thing i did was build a component list
of all of all the components and
uh peter you were right in that
one of the components that i was that i
was looking at
is a um
an opto coupler yeah that's right yeah
you you and i looked at that
and we we i couldn't figure out if it
was a voltage regulator or or what it
was and he said no it's an opto coupler
it could have been elective no no no no
yeah no it's
definitely looking at the part number
it's definitely enough though so
so um the other thing i did was
i drew a really really crappy don't
laugh
peter okay don't laugh at my crappy
handwriting and and
and and uh ugly american
circuit diagram yeah make my mind
this is only this is only part of the
circuit because
the first thing i needed to do was to
figure out
what um uh what is the
power doing on this thing and here is a
much better representation of it
i put this in kicad ki cad
and what i can do once i've finished the
circuit diagram
this is again this is only the part i
initially drew that's why
yeah i use software okay
yep once i finish that then i'll be able
to
um you know redraw the pcb if i want to
or whatever i want to do but primarily
i'm trying to understand what
it does so i've figured out
the interesting thing that really struck
me with these
is that only one of these relays
actually switches
the active side of the um
of the the power the other two relays
switch the or route more specifically
the neutral side for the
um for the uh for the motor
um the the motor that that drives the
garage door
up and down these two work together to
switch
effectively to polarity although don't
think it's a dc motor
i believe it's an ac motor but somehow
these two relays and i haven't figured
out the ins and outs of it yet
but the two relays uh uh control which
direction the two what's the voltage on
the on the mag ladder magnet yeah yeah
sure
yeah yeah like it would on a dc motor
but
the ugly you know the 600 pound gorilla
in the room
is this this i see this special this
specialized ic
that i gave you that y part number for
yeah yeah
there's no nobody knows anything about
that part i can't find any
data sheets or anything what happens is
manufactured
and their others don't mark them or they
give them funny numbers right
they're one-off shirts i mean by that
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
well the so you know what i do not know
at this point
is whether that i see is good or not so
i'm basically down to
square one again and that is component
level repairs for the
replacement for the components that are
obviously bad
uh like this big big old resistor this
big two watt resistor which you can see
right there
um because you can you know as we showed
you in previous
coffee breaks smoke all over it and all
kinds of burn marks and all kinds of
stuff
so there's some resistors that are
definitely going to top bread
yes exactly yeah so that's it
that's that's what i'm faced with doing
right now i'm going to have to do that
um it's going to be fun uh
i've got it sucks that i'm going to have
to get like one or two parts
as like a one-off robbie and jeff were
talking about the other day
using a laser printer to make pcb
there i wrote some comments in um
discord i don't think it's a good idea
because the chemicals they were using
were nasty
um they were using waterchloric acid and
uh argent peroxide which i produced in
the
exothermic reaction and it tends to go a
bit busy
and the other thing chlorine gets comes
off and he's not very nice
nasty so you think you're in the first
world war again you know
yeah yeah yeah yeah no no i
if i would have done it i would have
done it outside in in somewhere where
friendship ventilation yeah i pointed
them to
i pointed them to osh park for um uh
for some and i'm not advertising or
anything like that but
you could there's half a dozen you know
pcb
uh manufacturing houses that will take
gerber files
and build you job lots of pc
pcbs right could you there could you
send that to me somewhere
because i i went to one in england and
they ripped me off basically
and uh they told me 50 quid for doing a
uh pcb and they wanted more money after
that as well it's
literally poshpark.com oshpark.com
um hold on come come back i'll look for
a penalty okay
yeah or i'll put it on discord it's no
big deal it's no problem that for you
i'm just actually glad to pull right
things down quickly
yeah that's fine um i've heard
advertised
you know one company has been
advertising all over the place called
pcb
way as well but i have not had any
experience with them
so i do not know what uh what what
they're like
um i have i have worked with osh park
and i do
do they do one off because i'm making
the bulldogs the uh
um i think there's like a minimum of
three or something you'd have to get
three of them
because what they do the minimum
manufacturing size for the pcb
is i don't know eight by 11 or some
whatever the minimum size is
they put your part in your board in with
everybody else and try and fit it in as
close as possible
to reduce the the waste so they don't
waste a lot and then after the
manufacturing is done they'll
obviously break all the boards apart uh
to your individual spec board and then
send you
just those boards so they have to have
i don't think just one will work very
well for their manufacturing i think
it's got to go like
three or somethings a minute yeah
yeah i i built a track we know
um which is an aprs arduino unit
it's a shield that goes on an ap on an
arduino
um and i think that was a nosh park i
had to
had to buy three of them um i
had to have them make three of them that
was the minimum they would number how
much how much
honestly i don't remember but it was it
was less than
less than twenty dollars that's about
twenty including shipping
no that would be about that would be
about fifteen quid i think okay
yeah i'll tell you why because um i
played duck um i ordered it from
uh uh china they switched um a coaxial
switch
a three-way one uh switched my intense
to stop the
vent uh vandalism again and uh i got a
very
funny email from them in a in a very
funny english
that i couldn't anybody read properly
yeah it was you flung you know
you found english things
legitimate or what so i bought some
relays and
on the use and relayed out of a car you
know three uh
a jewel relay thing to switch the
collection with that
uh with some transistors in the bottom
in the box
there's over a few ham radio places here
in um
here in the states one's called
hamradio.com it's called ham radio
outlet
um there's another place called mfj
enterprises
which um which makes a lot of that kind
of gear
um maybe you'll maybe you'll have some
luck with that but you still got to deal
with shipping from um
uh from the us over to
ireland so yeah that's the problem yeah
yeah yeah but
but they'll weave gold a bit ordered and
uh and uh
some friends of my friend of mine's got
some pcb that belongs to me
yeah i'm doing the youtube in the
mountain on some pcb balls
and uh hopefully we're trying to get the
thing to work
with three aerials too similar to that
to the uh
yeah i saw it similar to the dark the
car door thing
you know same
seven degrees of frost today by the way
and we have a celsius
yeah celsius yeah yeah and wet snow as
well
everybody we had snow for one nice
nice one day and then he got very eyes
and he got black eyes and he couldn't go
i'm very i'm very surprised at how
quickly
the days are getting longer
because a week ago um
in central time zone anyway the
sun would go would go down around uh
you know 4 35 o'clock now it's only a
week after
is it a week yeah pretty close well two
weeks now i guess
two weeks after the shortest day of the
year which is what 21st of december
and it's already 5 30 before the sun
goes down it's quite surprising
so um yeah
it's uh dark and now 5 13 is dark now
i'm surprised
i'm not surprised so doug what have you
been up to sir
peter and i have hogged the conversation
all this time i'm sorry about that
that's what you've been up to well i
attempted to use my raspberry pi as a
an entertainment center or um media
center
and um i bought
a little keyboard oh nice
okay yes keyboard there was a company
made fab
called fabi favi okay used to make a
keyboard just like this
and it worked with pretty much anything
i put it into yep
i put it in my laptop and it worked fine
i put it in my raspberry pi and it
worked fine
this won't work in the raspberry pi
it'll work in my laptop but it won't
work in my raspberry pi
okay wow did a little online research
and found out that it might require
a powered hub usb hub
so does it not have batteries inside it
yeah there's a battery in this huh
oh hello cat hi
it's maddie maddie you're from man i'm
maddie
hi gorgeous
well i went out and paid 20 for a usb
hub and it still doesn't work
oh dear well it's a wireless thing
though is it not
that's that keyboard that keyboard's
wi-fi is it not or bluetooth or what
i i'm not sure or is there actually a
wire that runs from it to the raspberry
pi
no it says mini wireless keyboard mouse
combo
okay but you you have to know whether
it's bluetooth or whether it's
i'm guessing it's bluetooth
we have to talk to robbie about that one
because i don't know how a wi-fi
keyboard well actually i have heard
i i know my roku remote controls
operate on 2.4 gig as well
on the on the wi-fi frequencies so i
guess it's nothing stopping it
from happening i would have expected it
to be bluetooth though
but oh well it probably the raspberry
i wonder if it's just not showing up as
a raspberry
as a uh as a keyboard on the network or
something yeah
not picking it up and i'm thinking it
there somehow the raspberry pi
well yeah somehow the raspberry pi you
said
you said that keyboard unit won't work
on the raspberry pi but it does work on
your pc
is that true correct
that is correct so the pc
what's the pc running windows
or linux yes um
i might try windows 10 i might try it
well i'm not surprised because windows
is loaded full of drivers for all kinds
of
esoteric um devices
uh i might try a linux distro
something not raspberry pi do you have
any pcs or laptops that run linux
yes i might try that keyboard on
on that linux distro
okay i might try that and see if your
keyboard
is recognized by the other linux distro
that's running on the pc
before you try it again on the um on the
rush
i have a keyboard running linux mint i
have a keyboard
or a laptop rather running linux mint
i have one running point linux and one
running ubuntu
okay um
[Music]
yeah i would certainly i would certainly
try running
um
he's back i would certainly try
um uh checking everybody
uh sorry but i think it's at your end
doug because
you're frozen but everybody else is okay
so
um oh you're back okay okay
so it's probably it's probably your end
at this point i mean the first thing i
checked was my internet as well but
mine's okay and everybody else in the in
the meeting is moving okay
so you were the only one who was frozen
doug yeah yeah yeah
i see you sober
that's what i would try i would
definitely take that keyboard that the
raspberry pi does not recognize
and see if your linux mint laptop will
recognize the keyboard
then you'll know if it's a linux versus
windows yeah that makes sense
yeah well i was gonna i was gonna say
solder how are you doing but he's walked
away
he's probably off making a ham sandwich
or something
or some kind of a sandwich he's got all
kinds of food stacked up on the
counter back there oh yeah he can hear
us all right he's just getting coffee
but oh yeah oh you're just coughing
you're muted your microphone's not
working
it helps if you plug it in
yeah there he is
until i need them so wow
just in case anybody's listening huh
yeah
now what's all that stuff stacked on the
back counter there is that your
remainder of your christmas and new year
uh no
it's um
[Music]
late last year i had the mice in my
cupboard
oh no yeah you got more
you've got more mice problems no it's
it's the same but um i haven't
figured out how to stack it after um
yeah see don't you wish you'd put a back
screen on your
uh behind you now
well silva what kind of trouble have you
been getting into you turned to perfect
because
because peter has talked for a while and
doug has talked for a while now it's
your turn
oh well uh um same olds i'm all just uh
being home and uh watching a lot of
youtube and
a little tv and yeah
been there done that i got twitch
working on the roku again which i was
pleased about um
because the official the official twitch
app
doesn't work anymore on roku if i try
and start the official twitch app
it just crashes out and it just crashes
back to the main menu
yeah yeah but there is now
an app that you can in android world we
call it side load um
it's a it's a so-called unauthorized
channel it's called tuoku
t-w-o-k-u
which seems to work okay so um
so you know i think getting down what
what what's that question what
okay so the the the website
is called twitch twitch.tv i believe
and the the roku the app
on the roku is spelt tuoku
t-w-o-k-u it's a
it's important in tow of the two words
so
the first two is tw from twitch and the
rest is okay you from roku
okay t-w-o-k-u you have to log
into your twitch account uh your roku
account
on on the website um to add the channel
you can't add the channel just
on the roku menu
you have to actually
yep yep you have to actually connect
you have to actually add the channel
from the
ah i keep saying twitch from the roku
website
yeah so since the last time i was here
um
you slept a lot that's for sure yeah
i actually did that uh just now uh
i'm not surprised uh
yeah today with a night for them
so what time is it what time is it over
there is it really ten o'clock over
there
it's uh six uh 24 pm okay so peter lied
or or he rather he uh stretched the
truth a little bit
because he said it was like 10 p.m over
there no i
i did it dark i did it dark over there
i apologize i thought you said it was
like 10 o'clock at night
the sun is here going down um 3 0pm
so yeah you're a long way north aren't
you
yeah that was getting up in the morning
it was just i was just commenting that
it was uh that here
um the the sun on the
shortest day of the year on the 21st of
december
the sun would go down about it looked
like about 4 30
p.m and not two weeks later now
and uh it's it's it seems like it's like
5 30 now
so it's surprising how quickly
go ahead since the last time i was here
um i
am some of you may have noticed that
i have actually started to use uh a few
of the
[Music]
discord channels and not just the irc
bridge
i found a
client that is free software that
connects to uh
discord and um so come over to the dark
side
come over to the dark side
oh that way oh wrong way there we go
there we go there we go
yeah so now um i found that
light cord is um a client on the drive
found on the
github so it's their work engine and and
uh just fine so what does that what does
that do
it logs into an uh discord without me
having to use a
firefox or another
web browser okay and why
why do you use it if you're using a web
browser
oh okay do you get all the same
interface like switching channels yeah
the only difference is that um
some on some of the discord servers that
i attend
um
[Music]
i am in the discord channel over
um some a youtuber called uh
switched to linux and he have a few
icons
right next to the channel names and the
icons then
doesn't show up in colors but that's i
can live without that
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah i i still need
to pick your brain sobu
about um um
tls specifically yeah um
making making tls connections because my
client
is really starting to annoy the crap no
not i don't have a client for this
program but
the the client that i'm writing
for the server that i'm writing is
really starting to
give me um give me heartburn because i'm
having trouble
trying to figure out how to how to make
it work so what i'm almost tempted to do
is just keep you know start moving
forward with the
protocol and you know and just do it
over an unsecured connection initially
and then just plug in the ssl connection
um
over the top of that because it it one
way that looks like
there is there is something called um
um okay yeah um
i tested it 10 years ago for something
and it works but i didn't use it so
but it is possible to have a client that
is
not using ssl or tls or anything and
you have this um
that you used to start a thing with and
it
tunnels the traffic over rtls
okay yeah okay or i could just use ssh
because i already have ssh working
between um
i only ever log into the main machine
from a laptop even on my internal
network over ssh
so i mean i could just use that ssh
connection
tunnel over the ssh connection if i
could do that so
i haven't figured out how to do that
either so
i mean because if i do a if i do a open
socket and create connection
by default it's just going to make a
direct connection between the client
and the server it's not going to use a
tunnel of any kind unless i
tell it to so yeah
um i've been working on password
generator
and uh yeah yeah and what i'll be doing
is
uh over christmas i've not been well i'm
probably
reading medical reasons but uh we won't
go into that
and uh so i decided to pick up a
computer a doctor to write this thing
and basically you create a 64-bit patch
code
and and use that to create the
uh the user pass phrase you know like a
bb-9
and they created the x-codes then from
their code you create the uh
the text from that uh
you can change it from um uh
uppercase lowercase letters numbers
mixture of letters um and uh both cases
i integrate 76 uh
um between 50 and 76 characters
per password not it on the password
testing it was billions of billions of
years
to break it he couldn't break
never occurred to me to build a password
generator because
uh my password manager i use uh keepass
the standalone version that runs on
linux
um it generates passwords for me
so it never occurred to me to to
write a program to generate passwords
but it works well that would work very
well though
it does work out good i think i would
talk to
my and these are the mathematicians of
my younger brother
and it was working out how many times
that uh
that we could divide well to to get
the number of the characters out because
it was out there
because they did in another river so we
would just talk to frequent now and she
did
that she worked for well off the
government
produced because of the i'm not saying
more about that okay
and uh she said that that would work
very well
we also just we also took the table
which is all the other letters in that
you use and
mix them up as well so it makes it more
more difficult to
uh them to break so yeah that's it so
you have two things you have a password
and the number which is the big sub
value you know we mixed up the thing
then perspective um
i've got the tools code if you want to
see the source code in pasco or
they're dropping in on on that within a
zip code for everyone
and they're sure yeah yeah and and the
the uh
the other comments about the other thing
was that uh it was just a name i thought
of at the time
it'll go at microsoft a wee bit about
the um
oh yeah the uh what is it network
hack.xy or something like that
yeah yeah yeah i get that yeah yeah i i
knew it was but
you you said you could have called it i
hate windows but there are so many
executables called that
that it won't matter anyway it'll get
lost
[Laughter]
but i wouldn't repeat it but
have a password uh generator uh that i
use
uh it's called apg it's a linux based uh
command line uh something but it's it
that generates a
uh a random password that you can
actually
pronounce um oh yeah yeah yeah well
again my password generated that my
password manager does the same thing you
have an option when you generate a
password to say do you want the thing to
be pronounceable
and if so it will generate passwords
like that
yeah the the the benefit of that is uh
it's easier for you
for you to remember and it's still a
good password mind uses a clipboard to
transfer this from the password you
wanted to
to that to the to the device you want to
put the password
i think i have some uh between 20 and 30
and a different password i have a
different password for everything
and i have everything in in my head
because i have a system for how
how i am yeah yeah absolutely
well i'd love to keep talking but where
we are over time
i'm going to edit some of these
we're going to edit out some of the
stuff from the beginning because we had
some sound issues but we'll get rid of
that
hopefully that'll cut the time down for
the final recording
and i have no idea whether robbie is a
sleeper awake at the moment
because i guess he's spinning up for the
next um i guess he's spinning up for the
next show
so um he'll have a chance because my
friend called me and
he called me five minutes after the year
the coffee break started and he looked
real
well but i'm glad you made it anyway so
boo so well
good to see you again album yeah
absolutely absolutely
i mean this year this year we can
actually say that uh
houston uh looking back to history is uh
2020. yeah that's true that's true
all right let me let me close this up
because we're done let me let me close
it up i want to say thank you all for
uh for all your um participation over
2020 and hopefully a lot more
over 2021 hopefully sobu will stay awake
for the next
few uh
[Laughter]
merry merry christmas to all i know
we've all gotten through christmas i'm
glad you all had a good christmas and a
new year
and let's hope for a really good uh
2021. so
thank you and it's actually a
merry christmas and not just another
holiday but
yes i agree i agree i agree
all right take care everybody see you
see you next week
bye buddy wait a minute there we go bye
[Music]
oh