covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias single board
computer fans especially those who love
the raspberry pi are ecstatic at the
surprise release of the new raspberry pi
with a whopping eight gigabytes ram yes
eight gigabytes that's double the max
memory they had until now
been available the raspberry pi 4
launched just under a year ago and is a
very powerful little spc
but two things about it were really
lacking no emmc
storage capabilities and a maximum of
four gigabytes ram
though four gigabytes is still quite
impressive for a little sbc
while emmc is still not available on the
raspberry pi it
boasts double the previous maximum
amount of memory
that said gone are the days of the
raspberry pi being the 25
sbc the price is now 75
u.s and up here in canada it cost us 110
to order one
plus shipping this makes it the most
expensive raspberry pi
ever released so why the surprise when
the raspberry pi 4 was released and 8
gigabytes ddr4 package wasn't available
but micron stepped things up earlier
this year providing the necessary
component for the upgrade
unlike its predecessors whose soc can
support no more than four gigabytes ram
the processor used in the raspberry pi 4
can technically support up to 16
gigabytes of memory in total
so while 8 gigabytes is incredible in
this space it's not the absolute max
you