covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias the
collaboration between lego and nintendo
will go beyond the lego super mario
series of playsets
set to launch in august lego is also
making a brick-based version of the
classic nintendo entertainment system
on twitter the official lego account
posted a darkened video of an upcoming
set with the words
are you ready to play like never before
the five-second teaser shows what is
clearly an
nes system a controller and a crt
television
which would logically be composed of
plastic lego bricks
can't quite see it here's what the video
looks like after we brighten it up and
resolve
the 2600s piece lego nintendo
entertainment system set will feature an
elaborate build for the brick based
television
a crank on the side of the tv will make
an on-screen mario jump up and down
and make the on-screen play field scroll
right to left the set also appears to
work with the lego super mario sets
clear photos of the lego nes were also
leaked
showing the 8-bit console with its
controller a super mario bros cartridge
and a vintage tube television and on
tuesday nintendo posted a video to their
youtube channel which shows the set
being built
it'll be pricey listed at 300 euros
lego and nintendo have not officially
announced a release date for the lego
nes set as of yet
but we expect the announcement soon
[Music]
you