covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias if you enjoy
your weekly tech news with a slight
linux bias
become part of our fleet choose your
rank at patreon.com
category five let's get into it debian
officially supports the pine book pro
that's coming up but first prepare to
find your next distro centos
sys admins there will not be a centos 9.
for years centos has been a stable open
source release based on
and functionally compatible with red hat
enterprise linux
that all ended this week in what some
users are calling a betrayal to the foss
community
when red hat announced it is severing
support for centos
and the centos team simultaneously said
they're moving to a rolling release with
their centos
stream distro a user commented on the
centos blog post saying
this is dumb the entire premise and the
only reason
anyone uses centos is because it's a
rebuilt red hat enterprise linux
congratulations on undermining that
nitwits
the op received many plus ones for their
spot on insight
will this mean transitioning to a centos
stream
will the shift to a rolling release
result in more admins looking at trusted
alternatives such as
ubuntu or debian red hat said in their
announcement tuesday
we believe that the real value of open
source lies in innovating and solving
problems
and have learned that a rebuild or clone
doesn't provide that opportunity
are you a centos user do you feel
betrayed by your trusted distro
or are you excited to see what's next
with a centos stream
comment below updates for the centos
linux 8 distribution will continue until
the end of 2021
centos linux 7 users will thank the
stars they chose the lts
since support will continue until june
30th 2024
centos stream 9 will launch next summer
i am not a red hat user
um so it doesn't impact me
uh but i know good for you but i can
i can see how this would have a
significant impact
to just suddenly walk away now
thankfully they're taking a year to
transition
but how do you just cut ties like that
yeah and now i am
i'm also not a red hat user centos user
i'm
very much a debian baby as our viewers
know absolutely yeah i love debian and
debian derives
um but in this case now who does this
impact i mean i've got customers who
uh who do use centos i know some
sysadmins who use centos
and in fact my church uses centos as
their email service
um server okay and so it leaves them in
a
weird situation where okay you know hey
i've been trying to transition them over
to
you know some some other service for
some time but now it comes down to okay
now
the varied operating system the very
distribution that you are
using for your main server is no longer
supported
right and is being cut off and and all
ties are being cut off from red hat so
i mean it is really a burn um you know
we're gonna see in the next
coming months because uh you know a lot
of stuff right now
is what is the reaction of the user base
and so
some of the news comes from that
reaction
yeah so what's the response of the
sysadmin well the response is like
we feel betrayed right but the one thing
and i do
somewhat agree with the comment from
from
red hat is that you know the community
is about
advancing and growing and developing as
opposed to just
building off something that's older so i
get why they want to make this movie i
don't even know if that's the point it's
more like
centos is basically an
alternative to yes red hat enterprise
linux
red hat enterprise linux of course
requires the purchase of
licensing yeah so
does that come into play where well we
don't really want to support
the clone that everyone is using
because we don't get paid for it again
you know don't
shoot the messenger i'm you know a lot
of stuff right now it's very very fresh
in the news
comes from the reactionary response of
the assisted men
and and right now it feels like red hat
has
pulled the plug on something great and
it's gonna hurt a lot of people
and and not only like hurt but like it's
really tough
to suddenly have support yanked out from
under you
on a distribution that you've been using
for 10 years and how easy
and i say that kind of tongue-in-cheek
how easy is it to walk away from that
and switch to a new system like i think
like for anybody who's using it
i'm you know thinking your church they
have to build a whole new system
essentially like that's what simple
here's the choice the choice becomes do
we
now transition to centos stream
which is a rolling release which is what
sent os
that that was the appeal of centos is
that it was
not a rolling release yeah so now do we
go to
uh centos stream and become a rolling
release or
do we start looking at debian which is
going to fall under that category ubuntu
is very well supported by
canonical so it opens up
now now we need to start looking at okay
well if
if we're no longer going to be on this
what we what we're going to call a
stable release and what i mean by that
is not
not that anything else is unstable in
the traditional sense but
we've got two different release models
yeah you've got that like
here's a distro that you can install and
it's just going to continue maintaining
itself
for years versus the rolling release
cycle where you need to keep it up to
date all the time you need to upgrade to
the next distro
or the next version of the distro and
could have some breakage in the
in the meantime yeah and so there's you
know that that kind of support issue as
well
so do we start looking at other distros
it'll be interesting to see and only
tom's going to tell so
i wonder too how much this might drive
and not just the thought of moving to
debian or moving to ubuntu
but does this also drive us to think
should we
consider some of the cloud options i
mean if the church says okay well our
mail server is no longer supported
so are we going to transition this old
mail server to something new or
are we just going to scrap it all
together and say you know what let's
just buy a nas
and use that for file sharing and go
with
one of the cloud options for email that
might be the better solution
so i'm eager to hear your comments below
i'd love to know how this affects you
how it impacts you what your thoughts
are do you fall on
the side of the sysadmin who is kind of
feeling betrayed right now by red hat
and even so much as to say feeling
betrayed by centos
um or do you fall into the the camp
where it's like okay well i'm gonna have
to
transition to something and it's
exciting and it's a chance to
try something new and fresh where do you
fall comment below
love to hear from you on the coattail of
ubuntu's announcement of official
support for the raspberry pi 4
it seems debian doesn't want to be left
out their next release contains a debian
installer enhanced for arm devices
with official support out of the box for
among others
the 200 pine book pro pro linux laptop
from pine 64. an alpha version of the
debian installer for buster successor
bullseye
has added support for the linux 5.9
kernel series
and improvements to the rm64
architecture support
along with outcome support for the new
arm devices including not only pine 64's
pine poke pro
but also the original 99 pine book
support has also been added for the
friendly arms nano pi neo air
and nano pi neo plus 2 as well as
several other single board computers
from a variety of manufacturers
could we be starting to see the
transition to an arm-based server
room post your thoughts in the comments
below
we've still got a half a year left
before debian 11 goes stable
but bullseye is available now as debbie
and testing so if you're particularly
adventurous or just really want to get a
debian powered pine book
pro for christmas feel free to give it a
try now
becca raises an interesting point in
that you know
could this be the start of a transition
in the server room we were talking about
centos
and the transition there but could this
be the start of a transition not only to
new
distribution but also new architecture
i think it could i mean i i have i have
watched
arm grow and gain more um
user base in the last probably year it's
been
pretty significant it's happening
quickly very quickly and so i'm very
intrigued to see
where this takes things because i do
think
arm could really become the new standard
it's fast and it's cheap yeah and not
only that but to think
of all of the single board computers out
there that are arm based
i mean maybe there's still a hesitation
to put
at least to rely and depend on single
board computing
in the in the data center right and that
there is some truth in that
and and part of that comes from the
reliability of storage so you think
about a raspberry pi with an sd card
well do you really want your entire
infrastructure housed on an sd card
probably not
no but arm is a lot more than just
single board computers and it's not
limited to sd cards
you look at things from you know boards
from odroid you look at boards from pine
64 and other competitors to raspberry pi
and they all support emmc yeah and in
fact a lot of them
from both of those manufacturers and a
lot of other manufacturers are
supporting
um m.2 yes so you can stick an nvme
drive
on your single board computer yeah and
now you're running like something that
is screaming fast
super super fast super reliable and uh
that belongs in the data center if you
ask me i completely agree
and i mean right now you know in
my day job we're dealing with servers
and
you know all this kind of stuff and one
of the things we've been talking about
lately is getting
our own server and so what you know with
this story makes me think
are we at the point where we could run
uh you know take like a hosting server
or you know you know a cloud server and
run it off you know a rock pro 64 or
something sure why not where you've got
it hooked up
to you know a whole bunch of terabyte
hard drives through
usb or something for the storage space
but that not even usb
like i think well and it has usb 3 but
think about um
iscsi yeah sure right good example
um but the data center isn't i mean sbcs
flip the economics of the whole
situation on its head
because rather than having one intel
server with two
xeon processors and 32 cores and
and which are like gigs of ram power
hogs
and super expensive yeah rather than
having one of those to do 10 different
things
you just have 10 single board computers
doing those 10 different things and your
cost
not only up front goes way down but your
cost ongoing
for the you know the actual power that
you're using
the heat that you're generating and the
noise
from those big old servers i mean it's
really flipping it on its head
but keep in mind mac apple
are actually pushing their macbook pros
and the macbook air
and yes and their mac lineup of
hardware into the arm architecture as
well that's right
run processors so we're really you know
it's not just
single board computer hobbyist stuff
anymore we're talking max
yeah which is huge and if we're talking
max which are
you know they have that kind of aura
about them of being
an innovative company and they push
trends and and
and they kind of shift the industry in
in so many ways
um when are we going to start seeing
real good
solid servers like 1u
2u3u servers that we can stick in our
server rack in place of those intel
equivalents that absolutely happen well
we want to hear your thoughts let us
know
would you use an arm based
single board computer to run your server
where do you think this is going to take
things let us know comment below
send us in your thoughts don't miss the
other stories we're following this week
first the eu is pushing for home workers
to have the right to disconnect
plus scientists have created a plane
that flies
without fuel subscribe to our youtube
channel to make sure you catch the full
stories
from the category 5 dot tv newsroom i'm
becca ferguson
thanks for watching
[Music]
you