this week i'll compile debian bullseye
on my pine book pro with the desktop
environment
chosen by viewers i've also got my hands
on the new eagle moss die cast model of
the orville
and i'll crack into the box and get a
first look at our favorite union vessel
becca's here with the top news stories
we're following including nvidia's
acquisition of arm
microsoft's underwater data center and
an ai that'll kick your butt
in gran turismo sport crypto
correspondent robert koenig is here to
help us understand what
impermanent loss means as we learn more
about
investing in the cryptocurrency market
don't miss a moment
it's time for the tech
[Music]
our live recordings are trusted only to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
revive your computer with improved
performance and reliability over
traditional hard drives with kingston
ssds category 5 tv streams live with
telestream wirecast and nimble streamer
tune in every week on roku cody and
other hls video players
for local showtimes visit category5.tv
well welcome to the show it's so nice to
have you here my name is
robbie ferguson and i'm the host of
category 5 technology tv have done
for oh let's figure carry the 1
13 years 13 years this
my friends is the end of season 13. can
you believe
that lucky number 13 which has been
filled with no problems has been
just a perfect year all around
that has finally come to an end
our next broadcast will be season 14.
so do get involved in our community make
sure you
subscribe to us on on youtube in
particular make sure you click that bell
so you get the notifications anytime we
post anything
but also get involved in our community
so that means getting onto our discord
server
getting into irc if you're more into
that kind of thing
or getting onto our book face i mean
facebook or twitter
so you know on facebook we are cat5 tv
on twitter we are category 5
tv uh so if you follow these or get onto
our discord which is available
on our website if you click on interact
and
you go to category5.tv as our main
website so these are all different ways
that you can kind of follow along with
the show what's going on
because the next few weeks are going to
be weird
they're going to be really really weird
i have
consistently been about
consistency i am very keen on making
sure that we do a show every week but
what i've realized through the course of
season 13
lucky 13 2020 we'll call it
dun dun
well i've realized that you know i'm
just one guy and i do a show
for you through the interwebs and uh
sometimes i need a little bit more time
to get everything together so what's
happening
is that as we transition into season 14
there is going to be a short break
and that short break is going to allow
me my
my staff my team the opportunity to get
everything set up the way that we
want to be for season 14 and that means
putting all 2020 behind us even though
it'll still be 20 20. don't you worry
i'm not talking
next year i'm talking next month so
we're going to put it all behind us and
we're going to say look we are strong
we are stronger than ever and thanks to
our community who have carried us
through this time we're going to make it
through and we have
so now it's just putting our you know
the elbow grease in and getting
the final touches done up so when i come
in every wednesday to do category 5
technology tv live
it's a mad dash to get everything wired
up
everything's set up and everything ready
we record the news we put together
crypto corner with
robert koenig and i get all those files
prepared and we're ready to go
out the gate and then you know a
microphone doesn't work
or some crazy thing like that so all of
these things need to be worked through
before we kick off season 14. so again
get involved in our community get
involved in the various chat
areas like the irc or discord
following us on twitter or facebook is a
great way to
be kept up to date as to what's going on
and when we will be live
or just go to our website category5.tv
and i will endeavor to keep the calendar
up to date which if you scroll down on
that main main page
you're going to see a google calendar
embed and that's going to show you what
is coming up
so i want to say hey hey
to our discord i see you all i see bp9
and soul boo
and marshman and ubu and hj
thanks good sound tonight they say that
is fantastic
what a difference a week can make you
know what i'm saying
uh it is so nice to see everybody
myordix is joining us as well nice to
see you noman5
and our discord is a great way to
interact not just with
our staff but also the community
themselves and they'll probably be up to
date on what's going on
um speaking of community also there is
some transitioning going on with the
community coffee break as that kind of
winds down its original intention
it is becoming its own kind of separate
community uh
event that we're going to be holding
hopefully every week
as we have done in the past so keep an
eye on our website
everything is so up in the air during
the time of transition folks i'm going
to call it that the time of transition
and uh we're we're kind of evolving into
what
everything is going to be come mid
october-ish
so keep an eye on our website you're
going to be kept up to date but i do
believe
uh there will be a category 5 community
coffee break this coming sunday
at noon if all goes well from a
technical standpoint it should be there
i will be posting links on our home page
and making sure that you're ready to go
all right i have my pine book pro
this my friends i'm gonna i'm gonna move
this out of the way
we're gonna save this for later
i know you want to see what's in the box
i'm going to just set that
right there i have my pine book pro
this sleek little machine is
absolutely stunning look at the like
do you get the sense for how lightweight
this
is for how
sleek and slimline it is one of the
other things is there are no moving
parts that means
no fans no active cooling there
is therefore no noise
none have you ever held a laptop on your
lap
that generates absolutely zero
noise that's the pine book pro the only
reason i have it plugged in right now is
so that i can bring up its screen
for you that's the only reason otherwise
it's completely wireless
i get about six hours battery life on
this thing on a single charge
and there are some hacky little things
that you learn about your pine book pro
as you go so i'm going to tell you one
of those
i lost my power adapter i lost my little
barrel plug
to be able to charge it and i was like
what am i going to do
and then i got into the forum and there
were people in the chat
speaking about the ability to charge it
with usb
c so i thought what
wait a minute so um so i started looking
through the thread
and wukash who has been on our show was
uh talking about the fact that yes with
a standard phone charger
you can plug usb-c into the pine book
pro and charge it so that
that's crazy i'm using usbc for hdmi
output
but you're saying i can plug in an hd a
usbc
power adapter and that's going to charge
my pine book pro so i took the risk
the risk i mean mukash arkinsky was in
the
forum saying uh you know he's from
pine64 and given the thumbs up and
saying yeah you can use your usbc phone
charger
so i did it and it charged quickly
very very impressed so that's one little
hacky thing that i didn't realize
out of the box i could do with my pine
pinebook pro
i thought i had to have that adapter i'm
sure i'll find it somewhere and i'll be
like what is this for
i don't need this anymore but one of the
other things that you can
hack on a pine book pro is the operating
system now understand this little guy
as sleek as it is as beautiful as this
is
as a laptop it is
i'll call it a developer system so
where something that is this sleek and
this powerful would
you know maybe you would expect to pay
six eight hundred bucks
um ten thousand if it's an apple product
with this it's only 200 bucks so what do
you get for 200 bucks i mean that's
the temptation is oh wow a 200
linux laptop it's so sleek and it's so
great and it is
but i want to be clear that the pine
book pro is not for your average
everyday user it's for
the tinkerer it's for the people who
like me
want to be able to find hacky little
things and build my own operating system
and
figure out how to make things work and
it's a it's really
a development platform laptop it's
amazing for programmers
i mean i program in bosch all the time
i'm also a php developer
who uses nano as my ide so you know like
i
i love this kind of form factor in this
lightweight
long battery life but it's not for my
kids
because they can't you know it's not a
gaming system it's not meant for that
and it's they're they're gonna it's
gonna lead to disappointment so if
you're looking at the pine book pro
we need to look at it with that kind of
just going into it you need to
understand that it's not
the same as the three thousand dollar
laptop or the two thousand dollar laptop
or the one thousand dollar laptop this
is
basically the power of a really good
high-end chromebook
but with genuine linux on it but it is
open source
and it's continually growing so um right
now you may install
an operating system and find it's a
little buggy or you've got problems with
this or that but then it'll
get better and better or you try a
different distro and because it's open
source
you will find you know maybe you'll find
one that you'll love
but i want to you know i hope that
that's clear because i don't ever want
you to go out and buy something like
this
a pine book pro and then be disappointed
i
am very impressed by contrast
but the average joe user somebody who's
not a computer guru or
you know you don't have to be a guru
don't get me wrong but you've got to
want to tinker you have to have that
desire
to mess around and and play with it
if you don't have that desire then maybe
the pine book pro
isn't for you um and so i want to give
that to you up front because i don't
want you to be disappointed with that
purchase
if you love to tinker if you're like me
you love to hack
and and program and get into the linux
terminal and compile things yourself
this is probably for you it's got a
1080p
screen it's again super super sleek
great battery life it's got 802 eleven
uh five gigahertz so it'd be like
a c n g
b i don't know it's got
it's got five 2.4 gigahertz bluetooth
and
everything else but again like it's it
is what it is it is fantastic for what
it is
so as i seek to
kind of customize my pine book pro it
came with manjaro linux
and i love what the manjaro team are
doing with the pine book pro again it's
open source right so
so this team is creating a distro that
pine64 has said okay well this is
probably
the most rock solid right now so let's
put that on as our
default and so that's what they're doing
um
but i'm not an arc fan and that's what
it's based on
and and i am very much a debian fan so
debian can be any derivative of debian
so that can be ubuntu
on my desktop computer my production
computer
i'm actually using linux mint which as i
understand it is based on
ubuntu and ubuntu is based on debian
so it all comes down to for me loving
the debian distro so my servers run
debian pure and i wanted to
i wanted to seek out being able to
install
debian on my pine book pro like legit
debian and then lo and behold
community member daniel thompson got in
there
and uploaded a script that allows you to
compile
upstream debian 11
on your pine book pro so that means
that it is debian
as if it was debian downloaded from
debian.org
essentially there's a couple of tweaks
there with the kernel
and things like that and daniel's done a
really really great job of
making it really really easy to do and
really really easy to get through
but uh it is bullseye at its heart so
you're ending up with a true debian
operating system on your pine book pro
well why would you want that other than
just
the bragging rights to say hey i
compiled my own operating system so i'm
talking like you're not taking an
image and flashing it to the emmc no
we're actually
creating the image ourselves why would
you do that other than the bragging
rights
there is that but when you download an
operating system manjaro
or any other distro you're basically
taking
what the distro developers have said
this is what we like or this is what we
want our distro to look like
and feel like and act like these are the
the included pieces of software that we
want in our distro and that's what's
included
so when you install a true
base raw debian upstream
distro you are getting basically just
a bare shell that you can now decide
how do i want it to look how do i want
it to
function what office suite do i want
what browser do i want i get to choose
all of those things so how easy can it
be
well all you need is now i'm running
from my micro sd on my pine book pro
so i need an sd card because if i'm
running from
pardon me i'm running from the emmc so
if i'm running from the emmc i can
create my image on an sd card a microsd
if i'm running my operating system from
the microsd
i can similarly create the image on my
on my emmc internally so i don't
actually have to take that chip out
that's pretty cool so all you need to do
is just insert
your micro sd card into the side of your
pine book pro
and just give it a little push and now
the first thing that happens is these
windows will pop up for the partitions
just make sure you eject
those all right so we want to basically
unmount those so they're not
actually mounted on our uh
on our operating system and then i'm
going to go into applications internet
and firefox on my system whatever
browser you're using
that's fine chrome whatever and i've
made a little shortcut for you cat 5 dot
tv slash pbp
deb and that's going to take you to this
page by daniel thompson
that has a link to well it's got some
great information about any bugs that
are outstanding
things that you can come to expect from
this build
but it's got the link to the github
repository so let's copy that
by right clicking and copy the link
location
and then we're going to jump into our
terminal so on my system here
it's system tools mate terminal
and git clone is going to clone that
repositories and
and then paste that link but i haven't
installed git yet so sudo apt
install git and just enter your password
that's going to install the get
program to be able to synchronize
our get repositories and download this
uh
installer script so now just run that
again git clone and then the paste
and now go into the folder pine book pro
debian installer and sudo dot slash
install dash debian is all we need to
run
so hit enter so now it's actually
going through and get cloning
all kinds of stuff
directly from the repositories that uh
that
uh that daniel has set up so let's just
let that go
and for the most part i'm gonna do this
in real time i'm gonna speed it up a
little bit for you just because hey
this is tv and i don't want it to be you
know 45 minutes of just watching a
compiler on an arm
processor let's see here so this is now
creating the file system on my drive
that's the sd card
now you see unable to resolve host
robbie dash pvp do not worry about that
that is
my distro i'm missing the host entry for
uh one nine
uh sorry to be uh 127.0.1.1
should resolve to robbie-pbp but i
haven't added that entry to my host file
yet
so just keep that in mind that is not an
error that is just a host entry that is
missing from my host file
so this goes through you can see there's
really no questions here it's just
going through doing its thing it's
installing all the components for debian
and getting our base installed there you
go i see bash i see calendar i see ncal
and busybox
look at that
all right so now we need to enter a host
name so i'm going to call this pine book
pro you can call it whatever you want
and then create your user i'm going to
use
robbie and enter a password to create
that user so this is what i'm going to
use
to log into my computer enter your name
if you want
and this is just the typical user
creation process on linux
say that's correct and let her go so
that's now
installed and ready to go so now i've
got to go through like the keyboard
setup this is all pretty straightforward
you've seen this before
i'm selecting the us keyboard layout and
the default i don't want to mess with
that and no compose key is fine
now this is very important make sure you
select your locale this does not include
any locales
out of the box so i'm going to scroll
down to en
us utf 8 and hit space
to include that and then tab and okay if
you don't include a locale you're going
to have some missing language support
and make sure you set it as the default
as well okay
that is very very important
all right wait for it
here it goes all right we generated our
locale now it's asking us for our time
zone
standard debian installer right so i'm
going america and we'll go down to
toronto hit t
there we go toronto america
and this is very important now this is
pretty cool you can select what
desktop environment you want now first
of all i want to say
i jumped on twitter and i let you decide
so i said let's pretend i'm going to
install debian on a pine 64 pine book
pro tonight on live tv
which desktop environment do you
want to see me install from 311 votes
11 said lxde
lxde is a very lightweight desktop
environment so
if you want incredible performance it's
probably going to work really really
well it has a
similar kind of interface to like
windows 98
but a little bit streamlined not quite
as many features as mate
but it runs really really fast and
doesn't take a lot of system resources
18 of folks said they want to see me
install mate
i love mate that's what i'm actually
running normally on my pine book pro
that's what i run on my uh on my linux
mint system i use the mate version
and anytime i install ubuntu guess which
version i install
zubuntu no i'm just kidding it's ubuntu
mate uh
32 percent speaking of jubuntu uh
32 percent of our twitter uh poll
uh respondents voted for xfce
maybe even more lightweight than lxde
but
a lot a little less like the paradigm of
that kind of windows
operating system i'm going to use that
as like my example for the paradigm
but you know like the start menu the
applications menu of
lxde and mate xfce is a little bit
different you kind of right click on
things
and bring up pop-up dialogues by doing
it that way
and 39 for the win
said they want to see me install gnome
gnome it's like a klingon word it needs
an apostrophe after the g
so gnome is
quite the contrast to lxde
it's heavy it's
it's it's pretty heavy i'm gonna put
that on a 200
pine book pro are you sure is this
to challenge robbie and see if this will
work
well let's go through so i'm going to
select debian desktop environment
followed by
what gnome
you can install multiple if you want and
then you can select it at
your profile selection and i'm going to
select laptop that's just going to
install some
tools like my battery manager and things
like that and hit ok
and here we go thank you to everyone who
responded to my twitter poll
311 people
voted and 39 of those voted for
gnome so we're gonna see how that
performs
on a pine book pro this is going to take
a little bit of time
there's really no more interaction
required
at this point it's just going to go and
it's just going to install
remember i'm installing to my micro sd
card right now
i could then from the micro sd card turn
around and install by doing the same
process
to my emmc and now i've done it without
having to open up the
pine book pro so when we come back
from this short break this whole process
will be complete the installer will be
finished
i'm going to fire up my pine book pro in
the shiny new
gnome desktop environment using debian
11 upstart stick around
[Music]
welcome back this is category 5
technology tv and today we're looking at
gnome on the pine book pro 200
pine 64 linux laptop and it worked
i can't believe that here we are in
gnome
and it's running at least now
first quick question from our chat is
bp9 wants to see me open
a terminal and drag it around on the
screen just to see what the performance
is like
oh i just maximized it unmaximized
all right let's see uh
my mouse seems odd
there we go all right so there i am
moving it around
apparently i'm in like left-handed mode
on the mouse though
that's strange so let's see if there's a
quick way to fix that
it's a little bit slow too so i might
want to accelerate the mouse
so let's see if i can just like turn it
up a bit
there we go
i'm using the touch pad so it seems a
little janky out the box
so you can kind of see what i'm talking
about how hey maybe you got to kind of
play around with things a little bit and
i'm doing this
on the fly oh that feels a lot better
okay is there a way real quick does
anyone know to
reverse okay there we are primary button
left yes does that fix it
that's just maybe no maybe i'm not used
to gnome do you right click to move
things
but there you go hey performance is all
right of that
okay click we've got firefox what else
have we got let's check out the apps
performance looks like graphic
performance you gotta
admit that's pretty sleek for
gnome on a pine book pro
holy cow got to get used to the mouse
though
i'm going to want to tweak that and
right out of the box here i
am and thinking you know there are some
things that i would want to tweak for
sure
i don't have wi-fi so i can't bring up
the internet to show you
uh the internet just now but obviously
we've got firefox
hey play with this this is just a really
quick demonstration to see
hey can we compile debian linux
upstream on a pine book pro
and does it perform this is performing
really well
yeah i know look at that
so we've got libreoffice writer
libreoffice suite
already pre-installed out the box and
you can bring up synaptic package
manager
i presume is included yes synaptic
package manager is a place oh
it's not in installed i can so it
actually took me to
the installer to install it that works
for me
so hey with synaptic package manager i
can install things but it looks like
it's got its own
crazy package installer too i admit
not a gnome baby i'm a mate baby so i'm
old school so those of you who know
gnome
are like that's this and that and yeah
so but hey it works out the box
very cool so why do i want to do that
because i want control
over my environment over my pine book
pro i want to be able to control it
am i going to run gnome on it myself no
am i going to run mate yeah that's my
choice
but it goes to show how if 39
of our community who responded said i
want
gnome that's not my choice
but it goes to show that hey you can
customize this
make it the way you want your pine book
pro to be
and it gives you that opportunity to
really play around and make it your own
and then you can copy it dd it to the sd
card or onto the you know
make a backup and then you've got your
own distro that you can flash on to it
reinstall if you need to if you break
something and all that kind of stuff so
that
is a fun project don't forget i set up
that quick link for you at cat5
dot tv slash pbp deb
and that will take you right to daniel
thompson's repository the information
there
about the script that he's created big
shout out and kudos to daniel for
submitting that to the community
that is a big thumbs up from category 5.
thank you everybody i hope you enjoy
your pine book pro
and we've got to jump over to the
newsroom so here is
becca here's what's coming up in the
category 5
tv newsroom uk based computer chip
designer arm holdings
is being sold to the american graphics
chip specialist
nvidia microsoft's underwater data
center has resurfaced after two years
a deep learning model has achieved
superhuman performance at gran turismo
sport
microsoft has submitted linux kernel
patches for a complete virtualization
stack
with linux and hyper-v and google says
it has wiped out its entire carbon
footprint
past and present stick around the full
details and this week's crypto corner
are coming up
this is the category 5 dot tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
uk-based computer chip designer arm
holdings is being sold to the american
graphics chip specialist
nvidia the deal values arm at 40 billion
dollars
four years after it was bought by
japanese conglomerate softbank
for 32 billion arm creates computer chip
designs that others then customize to
their own ends
it also develops instruction sets which
define how software controls processors
arms technology is at the heart of most
smartphones among many other devices
including a majority of single board
computers such as the raspberry pi
odroid xu4 or roc pro 64 which also
makes it the heart of pine 64's pine
book bro pro
arm will also power apple's new macbook
lineup
nvidia has promised to keep the business
based in the uk
to hire more staff and to retain arm's
brand
it added that the deal would create the
premier computing company for the age of
artificial intelligence
california headquartered nvidia overtook
intel to become the world's most
valuable chip maker in july
until now it is specialized in high-end
graphics processing units
these are commonly used by gamers to
deliver more detailed visuals as well as
by professionals for tasks
including scientific research machine
learning and cryptocurrency
mining in our case we render all our
video in real time using nvidia's
cuda platform nvidia is also one of
arm's clients
using its designs to create its lineup
of tegra
central processing units under the terms
of the deal nvidia will pay softbank
21.5 billion dollars in its own stock
and 12 billion dollars in cash it will
follow up to a further
5 billion dollars in cash or stock if
certain targets are met
nvidia will also issue 1.5 billion
dollars in
equity to arms employees
two years ago microsoft sank a data
center off the coast of orkney in a wild
experiment
that data center has now been retrieved
from the ocean floor
and microsoft researchers are assessing
how it has performed and what they can
learn from it about energy
efficiency their first conclusion is
that the cylinder packed with servers
had a lower failure rate than a
conventional data center
when the container was hauled off the
seabed around half a mile offshore after
being placed there in may 2018
just 8 out of the 855 servers on board
had failed
that compares very well with a
conventional data center
ben cutler who has led microsoft's
project natick says
our failure rate in the water is 1 8 of
what we see on land
the team is speculating that the greater
reliability may be connected to the fact
that there were no humans on board
and that nitrogen rather than oxygen was
pumped into the capsule
mr cutler says the nitrogen atmosphere
reduces corrosion
and is cool plus the absence of humans
aboard with the absence of humans aboard
it means there's no movement or things
being
banged around orkney was chosen for the
trial by microsoft partly because
it was a center for renewable energy
research in a place where the climate
was temperate
perhaps even chilly the idea was that
the cost of cooling computers would be
lower
if they were underwater the white
cylinder emerged from the cold waters
with a coating of algae and barnacles
after a day-long operation
but inside the data center was still
functioning well
and is now being closely examined so
that the research team can learn more
project natick was was partly about
working out whether clusters of small
underwater data centers for short-term
use might be a commercial proposition
but also an attempt to learn broader
lessons about energy efficiency
in cloud computing the overarching goal
of project natick
is to evaluate the feasibility of
underwater data centers
phase one was just to be able to figure
out can we get computers into a
container and can we deploy them in the
water without it leaking and
do the computers survive and how well do
they last phase two
was to show that we can make it in a
manufacturable
uh production scale component so
the container behind me it fits on a it
fits on a trailer it fits on a cargo
ship and it
allows us to actually build up this data
center to any size that we want
orkney is a great place for this
partnership because
they've got renewable energy for 100
and more of their grid power computers
are not designed to work in the
environment that we humans operate so
things like oxygen moisture in the air
that is really bad for computers it
causes corrosion on the components
you also get temperature fluctuations so
the heat from night to day and summer to
winter can cause those components to
fail and so we have this theory that if
we're in a really stable environment
we're in this cylinder we've taken all
the oxygen out we've controlled the
humidity
no one's walking around there's no
nobody bumping things or causing any
additional failures that we'd see better
reliability
this project gives us the ability to
feel like we're working not just on
computers not just on data centers but
on sort of moving forward environmental
responsibility
as a company and as individuals i mean
everybody uses the cloud everybody needs
data centers this
this need isn't going to go away we're
going to continue to build larger data
centers and use more electricity because
the demand is there and the
demand keeps growing how can we do it
that's better for the environment
and that's just better for us as a
people the experiment on orkney is over
but the hope is that the result will be
more environmentally friendly data
storage
both on land and underwater microsoft is
cautious about saying when an underwater
data center might be a commercial
product
but is confident that it has proved the
idea has value
a deep learning model has achieved
superhuman performance at gran turismo
sport
over the past few decades research teams
worldwide have developed machine
learning
and deep learning techniques that can
achieve human comparable performance on
a variety of tasks
in order to further assess their
capabilities and performances
some of these models were also trained
to play renowned board or video games
such as the ancient chinese game go
or atari arcade games researchers at
university of zurich and sony ai zurich
have recently tested the performance of
a deep reinforcement
learning based approach that was trained
to play the car racing video game gran
turismo sport
their findings further highlight the
potential of deep learning techniques
for controlling cars in simulated
environments
yon longsong one of the researchers who
carried out
the study says autonomous driving at
high speed is a challenging task that
requires generating fast
and precise actions even when the
vehicle is approaching its physical
limits
autonomous car racing where the goal is
to complete a given
course in minimal time features some of
these difficulties of controlling a car
close to its physical limitations
to address these challenges and advance
the frontier we consider the task of
autonomous car racing in the top selling
car racing game
gran turismo sport which is known for
its detailed physics simulation of
various cars and tracks
the key objective of the study is to
develop an artificial neural network
based controller
that can autonomously navigate a race
car within a simulated track
without requiring any prior knowledge of
the car's dynamics
to perform well at gran turismo sport
the controller should be trying to
minimize the amount of time
in which it can complete a given track
the researchers first defined a reward
function that formulated the racing
problem
as a minimum time problem as well as
outlining a neural network policy that
directly mapped input observations to
car control commands
subsequently they trained their neural
network's parameters
using reinforcement learning maximizing
the reward that their model would
receive when
when performing well the researchers
trained the neural network on four
playstation 4s and a desktop pc
remarkably after less than 73 hours of
training
their model had already achieved
superhuman performance
outperforming the best known human lap
times in all three reference settings
including two different cars on two
different tracks
the results highlight the incredible
level of precision that the model can
achieve
and its ability to consistently execute
optimal actions
even in scenarios where these actions
are risky and might lead a human player
to push their car
off track so what exactly would you
reward
an ai with chips
what i really love about this story that
becca is sharing with us is that
when i think about ai technology up
until this point when it comes to that
machine learning
it's very like step based
so you think about chess for example so
when an ai
plays chess it's planning out the next
move
and then it makes that move and then it
plans out the next move and then it
makes that move
what's happening here in gran turismo
sport is that
the ai the machine learning algorithm
the the brains of the operation
has to continually be
planning ahead and figuring out how to
make those moves
and and it does it so very well so
it makes me think okay first of all this
could be a really
really great way to improve the
computer players in online games or
in offline games imagine being able
like to play a race car game with
opponents that match
your level of skill and
maybe even surpass it but
by using those computer games as
simulations they're training
the ai even further to learn what works
in a simulated environment where
human lives are never at risk so
would they then be able to take that
learned
methodology that learned intelligence if
you will
and move it over to true autonomous
vehicles that are going to operate
on the road and are able to
basically think for themselves and plan
how are they going to pass a car without
actually hitting that car
and those kinds of things that right now
we're just not quite there yet
with autonomous vehicles but could this
be kind of a precursor to the next step
of artificial intelligence-based uh
autonomous vehicles and then that leads
to everything else
i think about space flight and and
everything that is to come
it's really an exciting time hey we've
got to take a really quick break though
microsoft has actually submitted linux
kernel patches for a complete
virtualization stack with linux and
hyper-v
and google says that it has wiped out
its entire
carbon footprint both past and present
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert is here with the crypto corner
so don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
i hope you had a fantastic week and as
you know
there's always something exciting
happening in crypto so let's take a look
into it
the market has recovered a little bit
it's not at the 400
billion us dollar we had almost two
weeks ago
before the correction but it's
recovering nicely and as you can see
we see a lot of green in
in the market cap but if we start after
our seven days
we see the usual picture d5 d5 d5 d5
and so on and so on and if we sorted by
the negative
it's similar also d5 d5 d5
and so we get a lot of questions in
regards to d5
as one can imagine and i'd like to dive
a little bit into
how to be safe when investing in this
famous yield farming
market so let's take a look into that
you probably saw this tool here from me
last time we spoke about this here
yieldfarmingtools.com
which lists not all of them but some of
those
yield farming opportunities that are out
there and i explained in the last video
why an apr of 889
is possible and if you click on this
uh option here then you see that the
smart contract
risk level is high and the impermanent
loss level is high
and so i explained to you that smart
contract that's something that you can
check by going into d5safety.com
that will explain to you which protocol
is safe and which one isn't
so if it's something in red i would
definitely not touch that
if it's green then yes it has been
audited and it's
probably safe the other thing is the
impermanent loss and to explain
how that one works because everybody has
got a question what is impermanent loss
just those two words are really weird
anyway so if we look at the traditional
market
yeah like here i pulled up binance uh
with exam
and bdc then you see here
that you've got the order book people
want to sell and people that want to buy
and in the middle somewhere they find
the mutual prices acceptable
but you've got people that have got
different price views and they're just
willing to wait or not wait
and that's not the case in protocols
like uniswap
as you probably saw in uni swap you
don't have an order book
and the way that that's set up is
explained through this chart here
so at the beginning when you build up a
pool in uniswap
you decide how many ethereum in this
case how many die you're putting into
the pool
and that's the ratio that's fixed and so
of course the prices are changing and if
the prices are changing a little bit
it's no problem but if the prices are
changing a lot
it is a problem and that's called
impermanent loss
and what i've done here for you is um
i set up a calculation as an excel
spreadsheet
so you can see here for example when we
have got a protocol ethereum and sushi
i also a pool we provide liquidity for
pool ethereum and sushi the price
when we opened that pool is 386 and the
sushi price is 504
and today the price went down a little
bit
in ethereum it's now 375.65
and sushi are left here at 504 so the
impairment loss is about zero percent in
other words
you have not lost any of your money but
if this price changes significantly then
at the moment
it's are it's around three dollars then
there is an impermanent loss of 2.9 so
you lost 2.9
of your assets in this in this case
if we make that difference bigger so
let's say
say that this is not three this is
0.4
then you see you lost 47.2 percent it's
not
that you lost the sushi part of your
portfolio because remember
there's always this balance you lost
47 of your whole pool so the good
money that in this case is theorem that
stayed stable
you lost 47 of that one too and that's
the risk that you're carrying here
and that's a problem with all these d5
protocols like here
moon which is another similar to sushi
you have got an apy
of three thousand percent sounds
fantastic but have you checked the
the moon price now so let's do that we
if we go into here and say moon
then you'll see the risk that you're
carrying by just investing in this pool
yeah so let's go 14 days so at one stage
it was 12 and now
it's around 2.90 so you will have lost
significantly amount whether it's go up
or down doesn't matter it's always the
relationship
the relation that is important so you
will have lost a lot of money by
investing in this pool
and that's exactly the risk that you're
carrying which is called
impermanent loss yeah so that's where
you have to be really careful
you have to check if you invest in one
of those crazy pools
you have to be really on top of that and
check it every hour
even during the night that the price
doesn't change because you know
in cryptos those prices can change in a
second
so i hope you understood what um
impermanent loss is
and how risky that is if you invest in
these coins and they all are risky so
there is not one
where you can say um that this is a safe
bet and you'll get your 199 percent
just do the calculation this formula
that i had here
in this spreadsheet is is available
and if not just send us an email and
we'll send
the spreadsheet to you but anyway
so that's it from me this week again i
hope you enjoyed it i hope you learned
something
this is the solution to the impermanent
loss or the answer to the question
what's impermanent loss
and yeah i wish you a fantastic week and
thank you very much for watching and
i'm looking forward to see you next week
again thank you bye bye
now i can't pretend to know
cryptocurrency in the marketplace as
well as robert koenig
but if you're like me you're probably
craving sitting down on the moon with
some sushi right about now
that is crypto correspondent robert
koenig robert thank you so much just a
reminder that we're not providing
financial advice but only sharing what's
happening
in the cryptocurrency marketplace always
remember
that the cryptocurrency markets are
ever-changing and they're always
volatile
they never close you should only spend
what you can afford to lose
now back to becca in the newsroom thank
you robbie
microsoft has submitted a series of
patches to the linux kernel with its aim
being
to create a complete virtualization
stack with linux and microsoft
hypervisor
the patches are designated rfc requests
for comments
and are a minimal implementation
presented for discussion
the key change is that with the patched
kernel linux will run
as the hyper-v root partition in the
hyper-v
architecture the root partition has
direct access to hardware
and creates child partitions for the
virtual machines it hosts
microsoft principal software engineer
wei liu says
just think of it like zen's dom0
hyper-v's architecture is more similar
to zen than it is to kvm or to
esxi and leo acknowledged that they in
fact draw inspiration from the zen code
in linux
until now the hyper-v root partition had
to run windows
microsoft has also ported intel's open
source cloud hypervisor
a virtual machine monitor that normally
runs on kvm
which is built into the linux kernel
with these changes microsoft likely has
its azure cloud infrastructure in mind
azure runs more linux than windows as
acknowledged back in july 2019
by microsoft engineer sasha levin who
said
the linux usage on our cloud has
surpassed windows
linux already runs well on hyper-v with
a windows root partition
but making this a complete linux stack
may improve performance
microsoft is also working hard to
improve linux support in windows 10
with sls or sorry wsl2
and they even ship a linux kernel with
windows
gui support has been promised wsl-2
also uses hyper-v and windows 10 is on a
path to becoming a hybrid windows
linux system though as of now this is
mainly of interest to developers
microsoft's ignite virtual conference is
taking place next week
and we can expect the company to say
more about its linux plans then
google says it has wiped out its entire
carbon footprint by investing in high
quality carbon offsets
it became carbon neutral in 2007
and says it now has compensated for all
of the carbon it has ever created
chief executive sundar pakai has also
announced
that they intend to run all of their
data centers and offices on carbon free
energy by 2030
they'll do things like pair wind and
solar power sources together
and increase the use of battery storage
and bakai says they're working on ways
to apply artificial intelligence
to further optimize their electricity
demand and forecasting
while carbon neutrality demands a
certain level of scrutiny
the fact remains it is becoming
fashionable for large companies to work
towards sustainability
reducing their own impact on the
environment
microsoft for example revealed plans to
become carbon negative by 2030 back in
january
and both apple and amazon have plans to
become carbon neutral in the next 10 to
20 years
google's endeavor will also create
around 12 000 jobs over the next
five years big thanks to roy w nash and
our community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what appreciate
what we do become a pre
patron at patreon.com category 5.
in the category 5 tv newsroom i'm becca
[Music]
ferguson
welcome back this is category 5
technology tv
but we're not doing tech because
sometimes
what we feature here on the show isn't
necessarily tech
sometimes the things that we feature are
just things that we think
are cool here in our studio i mean we've
got to decorate right
and on the bridge i wanted an orville
model
and sure enough we got one eagle moss
uh is selling these right now you can go
to cat5
dot tv slash orville model and that's
not an affiliate link or anything it's
just
so that it's really easy for you to get
to the website where they're selling it
there are two different versions of this
there's a 10 point some odd
inch version and then a 5 point somewhat
inch so
basically half size and then the full
size the xl
which is what i'm about to unbox so i
had to
here in canada call up a local
comic book store because they wouldn't
ship it from the website
to us here in canada so i want to tell
you if you're unable to order it direct
give a call to your local comic book
store i called big b
comics here in barrie ontario canada and
they were
incredibly helpful they told me that it
would probably ship around october 31st
and here i am it's september 16th and i
already
have it so it's way ahead of schedule
and i don't know if they did that on
purpose just to impress me but i'm
impressed
and very very happy so just an
encouragement that if you can't get your
hands on one of these and you want to
make sure you give a call to your local
comic book store
because they're able to pull it off of
their order list
again i've got that hotlink for you for
eaglemoss at cat5.tv
orville model but let's get in here
first of all the box
says ecv197
orville the uss orville was designed
to explore great distances and map
uncharted space while the ship is an
example of the superior technology of
the year 2418
its ragtag crew are a little less
advanced nice little summary there of
the orville let's get
into the box so this is a die cast model
from
eagle moss the official ships collection
with the orville here we are okay so it
starts out with a
16-page color booklet it's got the
design
specs ship profile right up about the
ship
exploratory class vessel uss orville
investigates the mysteries of the alpha
quadrant
it's got some great pictures from the
show nicely printed
nice little keepsake there that's a
little bonus
cool
all right so let's get into the box and
see what do we have here
oh before i get right in here remember
back on episode number 628
tom costantino and brooke nazca showed
us a 400
000 model of the orville ship
there you go oh my goodness so this is
the actual model folks that was that
that was used to shoot those
400 000 worth of fun kids wow
well this one is a little bit less
expensive
and will fit on your desk it's only 75
bucks for the xl about 30
for the small one and there we are
[Music]
wow i am such a geek
i have this shirt i mean come on
and i didn't even have to buy this
special you know
okay so here we've got a base it's just
a black base i have seen some pictures
on
twitter uh with a glass base and i
really really love
that idea but i haven't been able to
find it so i think that that might have
been like a custom base that was
like for maybe for tom or something like
that so that just kind of
snaps together presumably and into the
box
it's cold the metal because it's a
die-cast model
the metal is actually you can feel that
it is a metal model
that's cool it's got metal parts now i
can feel these are plastic
i want to call them the cells we're
going to call them engine loops
the lower two are plastic and the top
one is metal part of the die cast so
this is
the cast model here and then the
attachments are
the lower two engine loops
and there you are
ecv197 from cat5
dot tv slash orville model again that's
just to get you there really really
quickly
and there you have it that's going to go
on our bridge as a little ornament and a
little bit of a
homage to tom and brooke and everyone
else who put the show together
and uh that will represent on our
on our bridge there you have it
beautiful
very nice well folks it's been
really nice having you here thank you
for joining me for season 13 which has
been an absolute nightmare
but we made it through and you know what
category 5
is stronger than ever it really is but
we
have these growing pains here as we are
in a new studio space
and working our way toward basically
being ready for season 14
so i'm very much looking forward to
season 14. i've got a lot of stuff
planned out
just a reminder if you are a supporter
from our kickstarter campaign
or if you are a supporter currently on
patreon
you will receive some vlogs over the
course of the next few weeks
as we'll be showing you what is actually
happening behind the scenes
leading up to season 14. if you're not
currently a part of
our patreon page you can join that at
any time
and you're not missing out because if
you join today you're able to actually
watch the previous
114 vlogs the most recent vlog
is here at studio e me setting things up
getting the acoustic tiles in steaming
drapes and talking about all the things
that are to come
putting some leds behind a tv to make it
look cool and that's a full half hour
of behind the scenes video hosted by me
right here
at the studio so if you're a fan of the
show please support us on patreon
patreon.com category5
and you're going to have access not only
to those past vlogs
but also everything that's going to be
coming in the coming weeks
to show you our supporters what's going
on behind the scenes
thank you so much for carrying category
5 through this difficult time i know
it's
been a challenging time for all of us
but it could have gone all sorts of ways
for category 5 and i know that in season
14 we're going to be strong
possibly stronger than ever we've got a
great space
we've got a great backing and we've got
a great team and i'm really looking
forward to bringing you the show
in october keep up to date folks
i will see you soon check in on the
discord i'll be there
take it easy good night
you