covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias sony has
delayed hosting a showcase event for his
next games console
sony did not directly mention the civil
unrest in the u.s but alluded to it
saying we do not feel that right now is
a time for celebration
adding it wanted more important voices
to be heard
the firm had been said to unveil some of
the games and development for its
forthcoming playstation 5 on thursday
hours later activision delayed the
release of new call of duty content
the firm said now is not the time to
launch new seasons for modern warfare
warzone or call of duty mobile
it had been expected that both
free-to-play products would launch this
week presenting the firm a fresh
opportunity to sell character outfits
and other
in-game items other technology firms
have also canceled planned launch events
games publisher electronic arts
postponed its reveal event for its
latest sports title
madden nfl 21 and google had earlier
delayed an online event for the next
version of android
sony's move avoids the risks inherent in
trying to promote games likely to
involve violent combat at a time when
standoffs and clashes
are occurring across the u.s other game
companies that are planning launches
over the coming days may now come under
pressure to reconsider their plans as
well
you