when we had to upgrade the storage in
our dell r510
server earlier this year i decided to go
with kingston dc 500 ssds
they've got a killer warranty and the
specs make it clear that they're going
to breathe new life into this old
machine
i ran some fio tests and the performance
increase that those bring over the old
spinning drives
is insane i mean the random read iops
alone
180 times faster
so it was time to install them and i
bought eight 2.5 inch to 3.5 inch
adapters
that'll match up nicely with the
server's backplane since the dell trays
only support 3.5 inch drives
firing up the server with the ssds and
all appears to work great
but all the drives are flashing in amber
light
i asked mark from kingston if this was a
concern well
with dell where did you get the drive
sled
wait a minute so you're telling me these
fancy expensive drive adapters or what's
causing this
it's the drive sled the drive set has a
chipset on it
all right let's try a different approach
then commander muffet posted thing
1830990 to thingiverse which looks
promising
i've got the link in the description
below let's give it a shot
[Music]
success the kingston dc 500s connected
directly to the backplane using 3d
printed adapters
did the trick this is another testament
to the cost
savings of owning a 3d printer
now i paid 16 dollars each for these
adapters
the ones i printed myself
these worked better and now while i used
expensive pla plus filament which costs
40 per kilogram each tray adapter
which is 14 grams uh price that prices
it at only 56
cents each so the material cost being 56
cents
i saved 15 and 44 cents
per tray adapter that's a grand total of
123.52
saved to print eight adapters myself
if i did that just two more times i've
already offset
the upfront expense of buying my 3d
printer in
savings alone hey thanks for watching
remember to subscribe to us on youtube
give this video
a like and click that bell to be
notified when we release new videos
check us out on patreon for exclusive
behind the scenes and early access to
our videos
and i'll catch you next time
[Music]
you