good morning
or afternoon or whatever it is in your
time zone uh i'm bp 9. this is category
community my
if my grid view looks correct then
that's doug
and that's solberg
[Laughter]
so sobu give us a wave you just did but
that's okay yep
good deal thank you sir and hello doug
thank you for the wave
and i'm bp9 hello so
let's see um not much going on in
in my world i um i have not made a lot
of progress on that client server
although
i think i reported last week that i
did make a successful connection between
the client and the server and made them
exchange
uh credentials back and forth uh you
know made them solve a problem back and
forth
and sobo i still agree with you sir i i
absolutely agree that those
encrypted packets should be signed um
and i do plan to implement that and try
and figure out
how to how to make that work reliable at
the moment
i cannot make that work reliably and i
don't know why so
i even used you suggested i go talk to
somebody
in chat or whoever who has used
this packet you know these packets
before this
crypto library before yeah um
and i used the uh test cases that are
actually
shipped in the source code with that
program
so uh with that library so hello peter
welcome peter
i used the test cases that came with
that library and they
fail in the same way they usually work
but sometimes they don't but i have to
run the thing over
and over and over again to see that
failure you run it once
it's a good chance it'll work but if you
if you run the tests over and over and
over again
they sometimes work and sometimes they
don't i'm sorry i'm probably
having to do the probability curve on
the i need to say
uh take whatever the probability of them
they're failing
to give a mathematical idea what's going
on you know
it really just random or that as they're
fixed
i don't think it's random well
i don't know if it's random or not um
i just know that it um
[Music]
is that most times it works i want to
say probably 60 or 70 percent of the
time it works
yeah you know every time what the
percentage will work or would you
i want to say about 60 or 70 of the time
is is how how often signing works in
conjunction with encryption
um but you know the rest of the time
it does not so when i figure that out
i will continue to figure it out but i
still have to write the um
the code that actually performs the
exchange of data between the client and
the server
and i feel like that's more important
right now than
than um uh uh than
encrypting and signing the packets
because i'm still in development
so uh doug something for you to see
i've shown this off last week i showed
this off last week and
did you see did you see the um coffee
break from last week or no
i read it i didn't listen to it yet
okay so that's the keyboard okay
thinking
think white keyboard it is think outside
is the break outside keyboard
okay it's a bluetooth keyboard and i did
prove that it does work against the
raspberry pi with the raspberry pi
awesome so you pop open that
which is useless for a raspberry pi but
in a minute i'll show you what it's
really useful for
and then you open it like that
and that gets you a pretty much
well i won't say full size keyboard yeah
pretty darn close the spacing's pretty
good
it's it's awfully close to my to my
regular keyboard it may only be like 10
percent smaller
might be three quarters i don't think
it's that small
now my regular keyboard has function
keys and um
and numeric keypad that this does not
have okay
to get to the numerics you have to hold
a function key down and use the new
merits along the top row
right right but when i got it working
with the raspberry pi i thought oh
i'll i'll do something even better i'll
make it work with
this ah which is the
portsmouth and of course it works
perfectly well
no problem at all it it registered
immediately as a
as a um as a keyboard on the on the
phone
and then as soon as it connected
so what you do i'm going to try and do
this toward the phone
there's the uh there's the keyboard and
then you just rest the phone
on top oh sure sure and you have a
perfect perfect terminal just like that
well
i actually found this
you found it nice i got this off of
amazon
and i went in and i entered in the
search bar
something like mini keyboard for
raspberry pi
okay and this is what popped up i don't
know if you can read the name on it
ipad's part ipad port yes
and it does work with raspberry pi okay
it said that it did
and it really does oh good works
it works well now now i'm having it what
is it bluetooth or wi-fi uh it's wi-fi
okay 2.4 gigahertz okay
but now i'm having issues with um
chromium
what kind of issues well i'm using a drm
version of chromium okay because the
uh version that comes with um
raspberry pi doesn't automatically have
the drm
capability okay and so i went on
a search engine and i went and looked
for
how to resolve that and i found a
version of chromium that has drm built
into it
okay now it says it needs to update and
it can't
so drm for um digital rights management
right is that so you can play like
youtube videos stuff like that
yeah basically whatever i want um
if i go on amazon it says that it
doesn't have drm if i use the standard
chromium
interesting and i need to update
chromium but
when i try to update chromium it says
it's already updated
it's got the newest version so doug why
don't you try to
install um
another one and update it from there
then swap back again something depends
on
depends on if it'll run on the raspberry
pi peter um
i would have called um uh the one i used
um
firefox yeah that's the one there
i know it's got it's little funnies
about issues and things but
uh firefox if you're on firefox baby i
i'm not a
computer really and try around firefox
and then try to
uh get it running on firefox and then go
back to
drm diversion it may not might be wanted
utrm2 registry so
yeah i was about to suggest the same
thing and uh one thing about the
firefox and the drm on the linux systems
is that it is
it is included but it is
[Applause]
disabled but whatever by default as
opposed to in windows or on mac
so you have to but when you go to a page
that uh you
need you to activate the drm um a bar
on the very top uh comes along and says
that you need to activate drm to play
the content
well maybe i'll try firefox then
you might also find that the drm support
is supplied by a common library that
both firefox and chromium uses
um i found that to be the case but
sometimes
you're right there peter
what i found was that the library um
uh uh uh the library provides the
support
for both uh for both
have i have i lost myself
can you all hear me okay yeah we can
hear you now you did stop
for a second you stuttered yes probably
my internet
um my next call is going to be to my
internet provider because i'm
i'm done with this crap anyway so excuse
me i should not have said that
no problem um
yeah well here in the us your choices
for internet
uh what sucks and what sucks less
basically
so that's pretty much the only choices
that i've got
so it's okay nobody understands
frustration better than me
oh yeah
so um yeah what i found was that the
um that the internet i'm not internet
the the drm or whatever functionality i
was looking for at the time
um i installed chrome and then that
installed the library and activated the
library made firefox start working
so you might find something similar to
that
yeah okay i don't know how well that
works but you know you might be you
might be okay with that
i'll have to search it out and report on
the next episode
sure oh yeah i don't know what else to
suggest uh
i have not had that problem one of the
problems i have with this
is uh this is the pine phone
the problem i have with the pine phone
is that it um
it uses or particularly the ub ports
edition
uses its own software center and you
can't install software from anywhere
else so i can't just no you cannot
sorry loading huh no you cannot go to
uh the command line or i can go to the
command line but if i try and do app
install it just won't work it just if
there are
or perhaps app is pointing to
the uh uh to the on you know to the
software center
but if i um
if i try to install something like
evolution or if i try to install
something like
firefox it's just not found can't find
it you know
it doesn't say doesn't say command not
found use apt install
to install it it just says i can't find
it are they using a debian
uh descendant of linux ubuntu is based
off of debian yes oh it is ubuntu okay
okay yeah yeah that's what ub stands for
in
ub touch ub ports is ubuntu ports
edition
function that tells you what package to
install
that is itself a package that one can
uninstall and i
think that some distributions
don't include that by default so you
have to install the um
okay but i can run i can do app search
for the for the package name
and it just the package i'm looking for
just simply does not show up in the list
you know so i can do that on the command
line and i the package i'm looking for
like firefox or evolution or whatever
it just doesn't show up in the list what
i would investigate is
um in the etc in in the apt folder
check the
maybe a little google search about the
distribution you you're using under me
and then let me get my handy dandy uh
fountain pen and let me check let me
write that down
let's see
apt it's literally in slash apt
it's the apt okay yeah
got it got it and in that there is a
file called
sources.list and there is also a folder
called
sources.list.d yeah
the configured servers that it is
looking for for
packages from so the problem there would
be
finding packages that will work on this
distribution
and this cpu yeah um
i think yeah google is your friend in
this case
but i think that the
pine book not the pine book pro
but the pine book uses the same cpu
as this pine phone does and if that's
true
then theoretically i should be able to
use the same packages that are in the
pine book
in the pine phone theoretically we'll
see what happens
you watch me you watch me crash it big
time so
i better make sure i keep i make a copy
of a recovery image because apparently
if i
stick an sd card in there with a with a
bootable image
it'll boot off that instead of the
built-in nvme
so what browser does the pine phone use
no idea oh
it's yeah it's um
i think it might even be uh
something some webkit-based browser
and i think it's a gtk
um specific included in the
included in the gtk package list
in the distro wow i've run ubuntu before
and i've never seen that
no nor have i um i expect expected to be
able i did get ssh working on this by
the way
with private public private key so now
i can from my laptop on my desktop or
whatever i can
ssh into it using my private key
to this machine to this
but it will only keep the screens alive
if the screen's lit up
lit up then it just won't work
it there's all kinds of caveats to this
thing i mean i expected
particularly a fairly basic linux box i
knew it would be
um i knew it would be pretty basic i
expected to have a fairly basic linux
box
with a phone attached and what i was
trying
what i'm trying to do is to solve for
allowing it to sync with my local cal
dev and card dev server
i think i finally found an article
online
that talks about how to do that and so
i'm going to try that probably this
afternoon i meant to try it yesterday
but i was just too
too lazy um
that plus my my internet kept
all over the place so i
it is because not much else to do and i
think it's just died again has it
no oh it's fantastic
see what i'm talking about and today it
[Music]
well yeah i don't want to jinx anything
so anywho so that's what i've been up to
um so boo what well sober what have you
been up to
i've been to a funeral this week i'm so
sorry
yeah it's one of my uncles and he had
their cancer for a few months
or maybe no so
they were hoping that he would last
until and uh
till the summer but no my condolences
so the good news is
my side of the family and the rest of
their family on
their generation uh it's not always been
um there's there's not been an uh
contact between the families yeah but my
aunt who is now the video
and she wants uh contact so okay and uh
us cousins and uh nephews
on the delayed uh down we where we uh
it turns out that people have always
wanted contact but uh
didn't know how to start and
yep well i'm sorry to hear that solving
um i would like to go back to australia
to visit to
visit family but um not able to do that
just right this moment but i'll do that
before you know once uh travel opens up
so
i woke up at
5 45 in order to if i had to drive
before
almost four hours oh no
what you need to do is get you an
airplane and then you can
fly it rather than driving it'll take a
lot less time i'm telling you yeah and
then
the funny part is that um that place uh
uh it's out in in normal times it is a
huge uh winter destination and they have
a local air
uh airship for sure
not a problem at all yep no worries at
all i just needed a few millions
uh for 10 million
millions for a plane and then a million
for
learning to use the thing well i don't
know what your i don't know what your
currency is and i don't know how that
compares against u.s dollars
um but you can buy used planes here that
are in good condition
for i don't know price of a car about 30
40 000 dollars
oh they cost more they cost more yeah
here in the states if it's if it's
tagged with the three letters faa pma
you can charge 10 20 times more than
what a
what a regular rubber band would cost
and that costs
significantly more it specifically
uh that's a license to print money right
there you know so yeah
absolutely and
that as well are rare
now how's your um how's your antenna box
coming along peter
um we uh where the
point of uh making the pcbs at the
moment we're designing
are um we're using chemicals at the
moment and my friends out and uh we're
deciding
uh uh uh that uh
how long do we have to put in this stuff
so how did you
how did you draw the pcbs did you use
some sort of a
program to do that or did you just uh i
i used two programs and the one i didn't
like
was the os one which was a load of um
yes thank you good job i was about to
warn you about that
okay i could use some of your australian
words and nobody understand me
no no you're doing just fine nobody can
understand you now it's all good
and uh so so we hopefully try and get it
get it quite soon this week we hopefully
if we don't get any problems but the
problem is that uh
the board is quite got a lot of these on
and
uh got a lot of small connections
between them there was a thing
and they got a chance of the leads
coming off because of the legend
of experimenting with that we got him
well you probably want to uh yeah well
i thought if you were using rf um with
lots of
lots of amps and lots of watts you
probably want thicker wire than that but
i guess the control circuits don't need
such heavy gauge wire correct
only 150 milliamps per coil that's not
bad
okay yeah all right yeah not a problem
at all and uh
um um
a difficult i put the picture of it in
this called
i did yeah i saw you i saw that you
i it looked like a laser print was it or
an inkjet print
yeah it was a picture of a
of the um of the box that i painted at
the end i put the wire in it i think
that's why i left in
oh i thought you were talking about the
circuit die the
printed circuit board that you were that
you printed no no no
okay uh i would have been to the dentist
expensive uh uh
major prominent dancers that uh of
course do my teeth
oh boy because again
and they took a tooth out there
and uh they they bought it up
they cooked it up i used another word
i wouldn't now and uh and
they broke the tooth off and they chose
the
oh man oh man
we gotta we gotta stop talking about the
pressing stuff we're gonna talk about
fun stuff instead
anyway they did they that they did okay
now and i told them they have to get out
because they pulled it up
they're the ones too much bugs
and the other one on the other side has
started as well but uh
i'm trying to hold on to uh
i get uh same problem i got no doubt
about them i think they've got just the
roots and it's gone wrong again
so i just have to wait too and i'll go
get the injection
by the way talk about injections my
mother got the injection
on wednesday okay
yeah that thing that we're not supposed
to talk about yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
okay
and what and what the let's go it all
was
and it was okay fiasco
didn't turn up to uh to put her to
together ready i'd like to get ready and
couldn't find anything it was moaning
anyway when they're like bless them it
really was like brethren nobody knew
what left what they're left and they're
right and doing
well that place her how is her hip is
she all healed up now or is she still
wearing a brace or what
her pelvic bone i should say
oh i'm so sorry okay
okay
on the 31st of march she gets the second
one
well when i get you know when when it
becomes available for me it's going to
actually disqualify me from flying for
two weeks
it's actually i'm i'm also on the list
that will not be the next uh
in the list i think i could do it
because yeah because
you know right right right yeah okay
yeah all right mr doug what's uh what's
going on with you sir
what sort of trouble are you causing
well um i told you about
i told you about one thing with uh
raspberry pi
yes um that's pretty much it okay
well good luck with your um good luck
with your uh
uh uh with your keyboard adventures
yeah and good luck with your
entertainment center adventures
what did you decide you were going to
put on the raspberry pi for your
entertainment
device i'm just using raspbian
right but what software package like
plex or something
did you decide oh um
i haven't done that yet i may i may do
that
okay okay but you got a couple of
choices i've been telling you in the
united states
um excuse me
if you crack the drm
to copy anything to a hard drive or
something like that you've broken the
law
right right and that's not something i
want to do
fair enough fair enough so
outside of that plex doesn't really
offer you much does it that's true
you're right yeah that's true
um one of the things that go ahead peter
anybody used matt that before anybody
have used a piece of topic called man
lab
no i have not no okay
no okay um
what i'll probably do in the next i'm
about to close this down because we've
been on for 25 minutes already
so what i'm going to do probably in the
coming weeks is uh
invite probably i've got some questions
about uh
cryptocurrency um and how we would use
it
in everyday life and so
i think what i might do is see if we
can't get uh robert k
um in on on the coffee break or
something we can quiz him about
about crypto how would you guys feel
about doing something like that
that would be cool yeah and i was
thinking maybe um hook up with
ameridroid and talk about some of the
latest and greatest and doug you could
you could ask amira droid about all
those uh
about all those various options for your
uh raspberry pi
because i've thought about using
something like an old droid4
yeah he'll show you one yeah i'm sure he
would
what's the worst could happen right
he'll say no right
like he did to me i remember at an
earlier coffee break he was involved and
we we
joked around about having him supply
some um
some uh raspberry pies for educational
purposes or so and he didn't bite we
tried but we
didn't bite it's okay it's all good it
was all good fun
but then
i found something uh on another discord
server that i thought was a humorous
um oh boy oh boy i saw that
i did see that yes yes yes i did see
that
yep yep yep yep i did see
that yeah mine is not mine is not so
complicated that uh that it has a
warning panel like that it doesn't have
a master caution
alarm like that so maybe maybe voyage it
does i see you've got your illusion is
is more complete than it was last week
there's so boost so nice job
okay again a second can i uh i want to
tell you something we'll play you're
quick
if you're quick because i'm about to
shut us down
go peter
i guess he doesn't want to talk after
all can you hear that
i didn't hear anything
all right i can't hear anything so i'm
gonna go ahead and shut us down
all right thank you all for uh thank you
all for joining in with uh category five
tv coffee break enjoyed it
and have a a good week and we will catch
you next week
take care everybody bye
[Music]
oh