covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias the raspberry
pi foundation has launched a compute
module with the specs of a raspberry pi
4. the raspberry pi foundation launched
a new product monday the comp
the compute module 4. it's hard to
believe it's been so long but the
raspberry pi 4 was released in june 2019
the compute module 4 brings the pi 4 to
the industrial
iot space featuring the same processor
packed in a compute module just begging
to be integrated into powerful iot
appliances
if you're unfamiliar with compute
modules you can think of them
as single board computers without all
the ports and gpio pins
they allow the computer components the
brains of a raspberry pi to be
integrated into robotics
smart devices maker tech clusters or
anything you can come up with that
requires a tiny low-powered linux
computer at its heart
since the compute module 4 shares its
spec with the raspberry pi 4
developers can do all their prototyping
on the pi 4
sbc but then order a bunch of compute
module 4s to integrate into their
commercial product
just like the raspberry pi 4 the compute
module 4 features a 64-bit arm based
processor
with video core vi graphics this is
going to represent a huge upgrade for
previous compute module customers
and with 4k video output output at up to
60 frames per second
plus the ability to decode h.265 video
the compute module for the compute
module 4
could be a game changer for multimedia
driven devices such as smart tvs or
set-top boxes
the compute module 4 is available with
your choice of 1 2
4 or 8 gigabytes ram and 8 16 or 32
gigabytes
on board emmc flash storage
wi-fi and bluetooth are also optional
the price ranges from just 25
to 90 usd now imagine that jeff
the raspberry pi compute module 4
yeah in one of your sbc projects or
something like that powering it like the
brains
this is a pretty soon as becca said
h.265
decoding so that's like video that is
very cpu intensive
yeah that's awesome like it says a lot
that's more power than my plex
server yes which is like
who knows where that's going to take
things i like the idea of
cluster computing and that's where you
take
several computers connect them together
through networking
and basically install um
software beowulf or something like that
that clusters them to make them be able
to perform
tasks together in such a way that it
basically makes a super computer
right out of several computers so you
think about these raspberry pi
cl uh cluster or the modules
and and put like 10 of those together
in a a cluster and you'd have like this
compute module
cluster that'd be nice computer with
that much power
when you can have eight gigs of ram on
each
board times that by ten a lot
can do a lot it's changing things folks
the world is changing
that's for sure what would you do with
all that power
and silence he's waiting for you to
answer i i'm
thinking i'm like what would i do with
that how many people just went
bitcoin mining sorry guys
it's you know what's sad my first
thought was
could i automate like some of the
utilities that i have in the kitchen to
make food for me
that was my first thought with a with a
compute module four
yeah takes more than that but i know it
could be the brains of such an operation
clearly i'm hungry though
well your thoughts comment below we'd
love to hear what uh what you would do
with a compute module for
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category 5. from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you