[Applause]
covering the week's top tech stories
with the slight linux bias if you enjoy
your weekly tech news with a slight
linux bias
become part of our fleet choose your
rank at patreon.com
category5 let's get into it
intel's newly announced 12th gen chip
hybrid is set to compete with both arm
and apple silicon that's coming up
but first mozilla's privacy vpn service
is now available on mac os and linux
mozilla vpm launched in july but only
for windows 10 or android or ios devices
the new availability on linux not only
opens mozilla vpm
up for linux desktop users but is our
hope that this will also mean the
service will be available in the budding
linux based smartphone market
with devices such as librim 5 and pine
phone gaining in popularity
for now though the system requirements
seem to hint to linux compatibility
exclusive on ubuntu
we'd love to know what the appeal of a
vpm is for you
is privacy of ultimate interest or are
you hoping to gain access to services
that aren't available in your area
or maybe a little of both comment below
and let us know
mozilla vpm users uses wireguard to
encrypt your network activity and hide
your ip address with no bandwidth
restrictions
they also boast that unlike some vpn
services they do not log your internet
usage
mozilla vpm costs just five dollars per
month and allows you to use it across
up to five devices the service is
available in the us
the uk canada new zealand singapore and
malaysia
with more regions coming soon it's
amazing what you can get for a fiver
these days
it's true no that wasn't quite a plug
but yeah it kind of is
um yeah five bucks that's pretty
competitive so and mozilla is obviously
an uh household name that yeah that we
can all know and trust
so it's pretty great but i think the key
thing here jeff
and becca touched on it but the real
sense that i get from mozilla vpn is
that
they are aiming to be truly private
yes if you will in that they are not
collecting the data of
what you're using the vpn for correct
and so
you know that that has all kinds of
you know that can be good and that could
be bad however from a privacy
perspective because vpns are meant to be
private
it's important to realize that a lot of
the affordable
or free that's even better air quotes
free
uh vpn services that are out there a lot
of them track you
and monitor what you're doing and log it
and sell the data
and and so when you're using a service
that's meant to give you
anonymity and they're logging it
that kind of defeats the purpose if yes
yeah so and that's something that
mozilla has really
uh stepped up to to say hey for five
bucks a month we're going to give this
to you
and we're not going to monitor you we're
not going to lose what it is that you're
doing
um vpns can be very very helpful um we
talked about proxies on the show before
um and it's sort of a similar idea but a
vpn allows you to basically place your
ip
elsewhere in the world so that means
even though i'm here in barrie ontario
canada
i can go on the internet and any website
or service that i use
will think that i'm in sunny california
yes and
so that can be good from and like a
privacy perspective because they can't
tell that i'm from barrie ontario canada
but also it can allow me to access
services that i can't normally access
yeah up here in canada for example um
we have different services than
in america yes so and sometimes it
is crippled services and so that that
can kind of stink and
and you know maybe there's a gray area
there and i don't want to get too far
into that because
it is a little bit of a legal gray area
but we understand what it means and
um but where it can be helpful as well
is if by um
an incident that is not malicious you
get blocked on a service
yes then you can change your location to
that service
using a vpn or a proxy but using a vpn
in order to be able to continue using
that service
and a good example of that would be even
so much as where i myself
from home have been working on category
5 tv
and accidentally put in the wrong
password yep
my firewall says oh somebody's trying to
hack in block that ips address
so then i'll use the vpn service in
order to
to actually do my work so that's a good
example of where i don't want them to be
tracking
how i'm accessing my back end yeah i
want to be able to log in even though
i'm locked out because i'm going to have
to go into the studio and unlock my
my ip from the firewall because i just
lost access
or i can use the vpn to get in unlock my
access
see and that's there's a lot of good use
cases i i've
i mean with my work i view a lot of
training videos and whatnot and
and there's a couple times i've tried to
view different training videos on
different services
yeah and sometimes it goes sorry this is
blocked you can't view it in your
country
sure and i'm like why it's a training
video it's not like it's a
so i've had to use vpn for that but as
well interestingly enough at our church
uh we bought uh our internet services
and lte
um but the modem that we got
is uh or sorry not the modem the um
router uh no the sim card that's in our
modem
uh because we can take the model
wherever we want is a us-based sim card
oh so even though it's it's operating in
canada it registers as an american
device oh wow
and so we need to use a vpn to access
some of our services and campaigns in
canada
wow even though that makes it even
slower jeff
it really does that's another thing
about mozilla's vpn is they do boast
that
it's fast yes i mean i have there was a
vpn service
you know you're talking about free
services i purchased one
a couple of years ago that it was um i
you know
paid some money for it but it was a
multi-device vpn so i could use it on my
phone i could use it on my
android box all that kind of stuff and
uh
great why would you want don't answer
this why would you want to put it on
your android box
carry on um
yeah not for that yeah um but uh we're
strictly above board
well for me it's about i just don't like
to be followed
you raised a really interesting comment
about business and i'm thinking
immediately international business yeah
and
how some services that may be in use by
a uk partner i can't access from here in
canada correct
so there's another legitimate i'm not
being blocked from it because i'm a bad
person or a bad guy
no i'm being blocked from it because
it's it's like region-specific that's
right
and so with an international business
that can cause problems
absolutely yeah interesting yeah
let's check it out it's really
interesting to see i wouldn't have
thought of mozilla for this kind of
thing though yeah well they're kind of
expanding
the line you know stay competitive stay
competitive that's right
uh check out the link below if you want
to check it out here's becca intel's
newly announced 12th gen chip hybrid is
set to compete with both arm
and apple silicon intel announced at ces
just this week that its 12th generation
chipset hybrid
alder lake will integrate big little
technology
placing it in its closest yet
competition with arm
and apple's m1 with big little
technology
processors are multi-core with some
cores being high performance while
others are high efficiency this enables
the device or desktop to efficiently
utilize performance cores versus power
saving cores
depending on each specific function
while
intel's forerunning lake field ships
also use technology similar to big
little
they were only for mobile devices what's
so significant here
is that the alder lake chipset will take
the next major leap by becoming the
foundation for
intel powered desktops and laptops as
well
this is definitely an exciting step for
intel
but it has a bit of a feeling of being a
follower rather than an innovator
how is your faith in intel these days
are you considering amd or arm or will
you hang tight for the coming alder lake
performance numbers
post your thoughts in the comments below
just like intel's 11th gen tiger lake
chips
the 12th gen alder lake chips will
feature an enhanced version of the 10
nanometer superfin designs which will
include new high power cores called
golden lake
and gracefont while some of the some
people see this move strictly as a
competitive one by intel
others speculate that the move is to
appease stockholders who might be losing
faith in a company
that seems to lag more and more behind
with each passing year
though delays and long waits are
anticipated alder lake chipsets may
possibly be available as soon as the
second half of this year
now before we comment on this story i
have to give kudos to becca for making
it through
because our cottage is on eagle lake
okay and eagle in german is
adler oh okay so with a little bit of
dyslexia you're gonna take that l and
move it before the d and now it's
alder right alder lake oh my goodness
she hit it every
time didn't once say adler lake good on
her
so well done big dot little in an intel
processor i mean that means
so we were talking multi-core processors
becca really broke it down and you know
i'm
i'm impressed that big.little is
is really revolutionary in that when i'm
doing
really intensive tasks i want my system
to be performing
at its best i don't care in that moment
about energy con
consumption or reduction in
energy however when my computer's idle
or i'm just surfing the web or whatever
i don't need all that power i don't need
the heat that it generates i don't
so big dot little means rather than
throttling your processor which is the
old traditional intel way
which is you know take a three gigahertz
processor and when you're using it
at its max it's going to be 3.2
gigahertz but then
when you idle it's going to go down to
one gigahertz
and and so you know that's the old way
throttling
this is multiple cores and some of the
cores the little ones
are simply more energy efficient so it
will choose based on the task
which cores are being utilized for that
task
it's quite interesting and that's
something that that you know
arm has been doing for a long time we
see it on single board computers we're
talking about the rock pro 64.
the rock pro 64 has six cores
it's a single board computer with two
big cores
and four little cores yeah and so it's
able to
really perform well when it needs to but
then when it needs to be energy
efficient or
just being used as a you know an idle
server it's going to utilize it's going
to
use a very small little trickle of power
right but that you know that alludes to
what beck asks
uh you know in the news there about are
they just kind of following suit
or they're being innovative yeah and i
have
felt it that way for a while with intel
like for
mac as well well yeah exactly but
for the longest time intel was like
the one to watch it was like if
something new was coming out it was
intel
and i feel like that's shifted lately
and they are playing ketchup
but isn't it interesting who it's
shifted to right
do you know arm yeah so
the new m1 chips from apple arm-based
arm-based yeah intel's new chips
are utilizing a similar technology to
what arm is already doing
and we covered this like a month or so
ago
like is we've had this talk yes we see
this coming
arm is already huge but they are taking
over
they are and i can't wait to have
arm servers and this really we have the
discussion about armed servers in the
server room yeah i
it never even crossed my mind about
big.little no
and so now i'm thinking oh my goodness
for my debian web server running on
these extremely efficient cores
and then suddenly there's a burst of
traffic and mysql goes crazy and so it
needs to use the big cores
that's a fantastic scenario absolutely
i'm loving where that's going
but is you know where where is intel
going to fall into all this it's an
interesting thing
and then amd is doing their own thing
and they're doing really really well at
it yes
so it's a very competitive market we're
going to see a lot of change in the
coming years
what do you think hey becca mentioned it
but do comment below we'd love to hear
from you
don't miss the other stories we are
following this week first the first ever
super nintendo world theme park is set
to open in february
plus microsoft has fixed a bizarre
windows 10 error
subscribe to our youtube channel to make
sure you catch the full stories
from the category 5 tv newsroom i'm
becca ferguson
thanks for watching
[Applause]
[Music]
so
you