do you ever
sit there some days and i i realize i'm
like going off on a tangent out and just
wondering already
we're not even a minute would you ever
wonder what's going to be like the next
iteration of the internet
the next iteration of the internet yeah
i think the next iteration
as we see the technology progressing as
far as bandwidth
capacity goes okay and we're going to be
learning a little bit about
some of the advancements there uh with
the newsroom today
because there's such a high demand for
bandwidth right now
yeah people who are working from home
understand
that your your you know your dropouts
may be the result of
all of a sudden the isp is handling a
lot more traffic
because people are now working from home
you think about an office
so let's say we've got an office with 50
people working
that's one internet connection that
everybody's sharing and so if there's
problems it affects that one office
right if however you've got now all of
those 50 people working from home
we now have 50 internet connections and
those internet connections are doing
what
any guesses when i work from home what
do i do
stream netflix i do that
game but i tend to remote
in yes that's right so that one
internet connection now at my office
that used to have
50 people sitting there has now got
potentially up to 50 people remoting in
from home
accessing that same internet connect
connection to be able to work from home
and remotely access their files and
their computers and things like that
so you've got this whole kind of like
bottleneck happening on the internet so
what's next for the internet
as as things get faster as things get
like
richer as far as the available bandwidth
goes
are we going to see improved
well improved performance automatically
turns
more impressive services yes when
high-speed internet came along changed
the world
yes but netflix that you used to be able
to order a dvd and they would mail it to
you
and you could you would rent movies from
netflix this is how they got their start
so it was it was like a website that you
would order
a dvd and they would send you that dvd
you would watch it just like you rented
it from blockbuster
and then you would return it that's
right then
then high speed internet came along and
you know what netflix is now
yeah so what is going to progress
how are things going to change how are
things going to improve like what is
next
it's all you know who knows what's going
to improve
what's going to change i keep thinking
it's going to go completely
wireless if you can remove that
physical cable uh are we
there yet are we already there
to some degree i mean i use the wi-fi
yeah the tech is there but i think from
an infrastructure standpoint
we're not there there's a whole lot that
would have to come in place to make that
more reliable but at the same time
you've got
um is it a tesla working on their
satellite network it's going to hit the
globe not tesla but
spacex yes spacex sorry yeah same
same ceo yeah that's right same same
twitter
same shenanigans that's right but yeah i
think it's gonna be wireless and i think
it's gonna
allow bandwidth to go so much faster uh
it'll be interesting to see how it
progresses over the years and and what
it changes
what's uh what's really kind of catching
my my eye is this covid app
that we've got in ontario actually i
think it's across canada
for that randomly connects with
bluetooth
so that if you've walked near somebody
that has tested positive for covid you
get an alert that goes
hey you don't don't interact with that
person well no you get an alert that
says you recently interact with somebody
who's been tested
positive oh wow so this is happening all
in the back end on your device and i'm
and so i was thinking about that going
this is just with bluetooth is there a
way to have
almost like hot spotting as you go
with mobile phones that would allow this
constant wireless network to be like
so interesting i mean a couple things
come to mind jeff first
first of all when you start talking
about wireless i start thinking about
man that would be so expensive
but the interesting thing is that with
the progression of technology
and the the betterment of the underlying
infrastructure the cost to the end
consumers goes down
yeah so we're going to see that price go
down so
maybe my my smartphone and the ability
to connect to
five 6g internet is going to drop
and when that happens now all of a
sudden autonomous vehicles become
much more autonomous that's right
because they're internet connected
all the time with a high-speed internet
connection yeah
and and then we've got all these new new
technologies that can just open up
that's right and things like these apps
that communicate but then the second
thing that comes to mind is
now you've got everybody calling big
brother well of course
you're there to help yes yes but
where is the line where we say okay well
we want big brother to some extent
i want google to be able to tell me if
an earthquake is going to hit
in california absolutely if i live in
california it's smart
and and so there comes a point where you
say okay well i'm gonna i'm going to
allow google
to have access to my telemetry yeah
but then how much trust are you putting
in this company
so so there's there's yeah there's there
are all these considerations
i think in general the human race uh
as as a broad brush stroke so not
everybody but as a broad brushstroke
i think we're always gonna go with the
times of advancement i mean you look at
when
as a whole as a whole yeah i mean you
look at when facebook came out and it
changed the way that we do online
permissions
it used to be you had to give permission
to access your information
yeah and with facebook they said no no
you need to give us you need to tell us
what you don't want us to share
and now and we're gonna and we're gonna
change that every six months exactly and
you're gonna have to be on top of that
because otherwise you've
basically opted in because you're using
our free platform that's right and it's
changed the internet now everybody does
that where it's like you tell us what
you don't want us to share
you tell us what you don't want us to
have access to and i think in general
most people
again general broad breaststroke uh most
people are like you know what it's the
convenience of it
i'll deal with it and they just they
they seem to want to ignore it that's my
sense of things so i think
if we get to that point where it's like
all of that information is just kind of
bouncing between phones i don't know if
too many people are going to care
it's going to be interesting so i've
often been of the mindset where
it's like i don't do anything that i
would be a afraid for somebody to know
about right
but there's also like identity theft and
and tracking and and the ability for
you know the big brother to see you know
the trends
of my lifestyle where i go where i buy
my coffee at what time
which then boils down to okay well now
you know where i'm going to be
right now all the data would say wow
that guy sits on the couch a lot
oh yeah i practically get up and
stop at starbucks and and sit at my desk
for 10 hours
ever since my day and then i'm at the
studio work and work and work
yeah yeah yeah anyway didn't want to
take us on a tangent what are your
thoughts i mean it's
it's an interesting discussion i mean
because this is it's a transition that
is happening and is going to happen and
i think
the pandemic has also kind of pushed us
to need
change in regulations in the
infrastructure and in the technologies
that are there
and so you know how is that going to
impact
us as a society as as people as
individuals and and
you know what are what are your thoughts
comment below it's a good discussion to
have with the community
oh for sure absolutely
you