hello good afternoon
good morning wherever it is in your uh
in your time zone
it is uh category five um community
coffee break i'm bp nine
um and i'm in the middle of the crowd
here so we'll see if i can point
correctly there we go
way up in the top left hand corner is
sasha hi sasha give us a wave
good there's so boo right above me i
think i don't know how this is going to
work but
i think there we go that's that's uh
doug over there give us a wave doug
good job and then down there is i think
is is peter but he's not there
i i he's his camera's on but i don't see
him or hear him so
i don't know i saw a shadow i saw a
shadow i know he's there somewhere
all right good reminds me of the anode
uh
joke i heard uh i think it's um from one
of the
black other episodes um
i just had the the audio portion because
we used it in uh
in uh in ioc chat 20 years ago the eyes
are open the mouse moves
nobody's home yeah yeah lights are wrong
but nobody's home
oh this peter hello peter
there we go hello peter
uh-oh he must not be able to hear us yet
so we can still talk about him
oh crap there he is
that's uh there we go that's peter bob
uh down there let's see if i can do that
there we go that's peter
welcome peter good to see you yeah yeah
yeah yeah
so uh let's see we've talked about we've
talked about this
um and i'm pretty much resigned to doing
a uh component level repair on this
i am not going to um i'm gonna finish
the circuit diagram just because
uh just because i want to and sasha just
to show you my handy work
that is part of the circuit diagram
oh no well i started with yeah way yeah
yep yep that's
that's only part of it there is a whole
bunch of um
there are connectors and all kinds of
stuff there but this thing
right here
is a thing called an integrated circuit
or an ic
and and it coordinates all of the
different signals and controls and all
that stuff
um and uh that i don't know if that
i see is any good or not so this is part
of my garage door opener in case you're
wondering what it was
and these these relays here
what they do is they can they control
the um
the power to the garage door opener
motor
that brings the door up and the door
down so what i'm trying to do is to
figure out
i know this got struck by lightning
and i know some parts got got burned and
i
don't know if that's easy to see because
my big old fingers in the way
but there's a there's a resistor here
and
other resistors here as well that are um
that show obvious burn marks
so anyway that's my next thing um
so i may have to i mean i don't know yet
if that i see's any good if the ic is
bad i may replace it with an arduino or
something put a socket in there and
put an arduino in its place
you just need to add a bm something
and then you have an icbm yeah
true enough yeah that's true yeah you're
right
um so i wanted to to touch base with you
about my client server um that i'm
writing
because i cannot get signatures to work
reliably
i can if i can all i can do all day
i can encrypt a user i can encrypt the
payload
so say the client has the public key
of the server and has its own
private key and say the server has the
public key of the user and its own
private key
right so the private keys belong to the
to the um parties that they they should
belong to
if the client encrypts
uh uh encrypts the payload with the
service public key and then the server
encrypts the reply with the client
public key would that be enough in your
opinion
to prove that this is the right person
that this is the correct
correctly i mean that would correctly
encrypt
that would allow proper encrypt and
decrypt across the wire all the time
but would that be enough do you think to
identify that person
i'm not sure that is how it's supposed
to work and
that kind of setup indicates that
the client sends some a message
somewhere
and then later on maybe an hour later
then
the reply is coming back but it's an
instant connection
where he sends the server message a
command to
do something and then get an instant
replay
then only the the service uh and
the key is is all that matters your
client doesn't have need any
kids with them yeah but that's that but
but
apart from encrypting the communication
i
also want to prove that the person
who i'm asserting i am is that
you know is that person to the server
right
so if i want to if i want to say i'm
user id123
right i want to i want to prove to the
server that i'm user id123 but all i
have is my own private key
and the service public key and the
server
has its own private key and my public
key
so it can encrypt with my public key
and i can decrypt with my private key
see what i'm saying
yeah in order for you for the server to
know that
the message is coming from you and not
someone else then you in addition to it
and then
encrypting the message you have to
assign the message with your
publication yeah unfortunately signing
isn't working
because i am not able to
uh i am not able to reliably sign every
time
for some reason using the using the
gcrypt library signing does not work
every time
anyway that's that's something we can
discuss later if you like
um but i was i wanted to get your input
on that and i agree with you i would
rather sign
that sign and encrypt but i don't think
that's going to work so
this one can't do it this is to
come into the end of the kind of uh
advice that you need you need someone
who actually works
with the uh encrypting
in order to yeah yeah okay
maybe you are using their own
encryption tools oh sure it's certainly
possible
it's certainly possible um i thought i
was using the same library that tls is
using
but uh um what is it called open ssh
i think that's right open ssl is the one
that everyone is using finish the show
yeah okay yeah but um implement that
there quickly and
oh sure oh i absolutely i absolutely
admit i may have implemented that
incorrectly i'm more than happy to admit
that
it seems to me that that whole note of
the uh
that seems to be the tone of these days
to
admit being wrong right yeah yeah
we're not going there we're not going
all right
okay uh sasha what have you been up to
so good to see you
what have you been up to real good to
see you too
i've just been working and fixing up the
house and
more working and so nice to know that
you've got
the weekend off i think i saw that in
discord just before you popped up
oh goody we get to chat with sasha today
yes and for christmas dave got me a
kitchenaid stand mixer
and so this weekend i've been
attempting to bake
how's it working out for you well i made
pizza
so that was good yeah yes that's true
later very exactly yes so
my end game goal by the end of the
weekend is i'd like to figure out how to
make little donuts like the little
doughnut hole donuts
are you gonna are you gonna deep fry
them
well i have a cast iron pan so i think
i'll just throw some oil in there and
like do
like a light little fry of them because
i would like to bring those to work
to share with my friends um they're not
as interested in my healthy options as i
am so i need to learn how to make junk
food and win the hearts and
minds of all my people
your healthy options what are your what
are your healthy options
what are your healthy options well i i
for example like i also got a soda
stream
and like that's a healthy option instead
of regular pop i boiled down my
blueberries
and made a syrup so now i have some
blueberry
well i made homemade ginger ale
yesterday and that is my favorite flavor
now
oh i've got i've got to get it i've got
to get that recipe i love ginger ale
yeah and if you make it by yourself like
make it at home it's healthy right
so i have a stream as well so um
i'm i'm already i'm already pretty tired
of the sodastream
yes but i'm tired of sodastream flavors
i'm i'm ready to try something else so
you can pick and choose among all kinds
of different flavors
um whether they are made for the soda
same or not you can
take some custom
flavors or sure yeah or do like sasha
did and
do like sasha did wherever she is
and uh and make your own what did you
say you used blackberries
blueberries so we have lots of
blueberries on our on our property
and we picked we only took one day and
picked as many blueberries
as we could one day and we have enough
to lost this a year
um and so all i boil down a bunch of
blueberries with some honey and some
lemon peel because lemon peel i guess
has pectin in it
which automatically makes syrup syrupier
um
yeah and um yeah you just mash up the
blueberries strain it and then you have
blueberry syrup to add to your soda
stream it
does that preserve it or you or do you
have to freeze it as well
well um i
didn't it didn't uh last long enough for
me to even worry about preserving
i'm on my was supposed to own a whole
year
and it lasted how long a week
oh wow
that's too bad nice well i'll get your
antioxidants up for
sure i think blueberries yeah absolutely
yeah
so instead so yeah instead of healthy
healthy things this weekend i'm going to
learn how to make donuts
i'm impressed nice job sasha nice job
now um a little funny that uh david gave
slash or something
for the kitchen for christmas i'm not
going there i'm not touching that i'm
leaving um
she probably asked for it did you ask
for it sasha
yeah nice nice
stereotype for a reason then yeah
is the house all ready for winter or did
you not get ready did you not get it
ready in time for winter
no you know what is funny is we got it
ready for winter and then
winter so far has not fallen upon us
oh really we have no snow so
last year i don't know if you'll
remember i don't know if it was
international news but we heard about it
in ontario
newfoundland had snowmageddon in january
shut down like the whole island it was
insane
yeah um and this year we still have
green grass outside
wow wow so i keep walking around making
fun of everybody i'm like oh yeah
this is your first winter though isn't
it and yeah
yeah okay nice wow wow
it'll come don't worry it'll it'll be
here before too long don't you worry oh
well you know i'm sure it'll be here
it'll probably show up in april because
this april is my 40th birthday and i
want to have a nice
i want to have a nice big shindig and
it'll probably be like
seven feet of snow or something you
should just
you should just hijack the whole garage
and just make it a big party room for
you
for your birthday that's right big
birthday there you go
we gotta let some other people talk
sasha i'd rather just chat with you but
we're gonna let some other people talk
too
i'm so sorry a great listener
and the phone sounds great even without
the headset by the way so you've done
done a great job with that well done
thank you
doug what have you been up to sir hey
well um the saga of my raspberry pi
continues
i was going to ask about that keyboard
yeah
well the that uh little keyboard that i
showed you
um wasn't working so i bought a
bluetooth keyboard and connected it to
my raspberry pi but that kept losing its
pairing
so i had that like a day i sent it back
two days after i got it
um and i've got another keyboard that i
got this morning
and i'm going to see how that works oh
wow i'm charging it right now and
it didn't do anything when i first got
it so i figured
no luck with keyboards are you needed to
be charged
well it's because it's a raspberry pi i
think
well maybe what you need to do is get
you one of those raspberry pi 400s with
the keyboard and everything all built in
well then i did yeah i could do that i
suppose
i don't know if there's any way to
connect it wirelessly to my
tv though i believe it's a standard
raspberry pi inside um
that would be another question for
robbie but you know he keeps
i'm trying to not have to run cables to
my
computer or anything other than
you know from the computer to the tv and
i guess you want the raspberry pi to be
near the tv because it's going to serve
as the media center right
i'm sorry i think it's uh you want the
raspberry pi to be near your
um uh near your tv because uh
it wants to serve as a media center
right yeah yeah the raspberry pi
is under the tv so the keyboard has to
be separate
and you don't want wires strung across
the room too right
connect to it got it right from from one
side of the room to the other
oh bluetooth should do it bluetooth oh
yeah
yeah yeah it should be okay i think it's
like 15 feet or something isn't it
30 30 feet no problem at all you'll be
fine 10 meters
i i always forget how to do that
conversion yeah okay i'll take your word
i'll take your word for it
it sounds about right a meter is a meter
is 39
inches oh okay okay
so it's roughly right okay i need to get
out my wiz wheel for the airplane that's
probably okay
you know what the dog is doing i'm
curious about the
[Music]
steam or smoke care coming up i think
that's a vaporizer of some sort
oh yeah yeah that mist coming up back
there that's a vaporizer
not it's not smoke just in case you were
wondering
is that for essential oils or just to
humidify the air well i can put
essential oil in it but i have a cat
so essential oils and cats don't agree
ah-ha i did not know that i'm glad you
said that
so i have a cat too and i don't have an
electric vaporizer like that but
many many many years ago i got one of
those clay ones that has a little tray
in the top
the diffuser yeah you put a candle
inside it
and you put the essential oils in in the
top i think with water as well
and that that does that but i did not
realize that
that cats and essential oils did not mix
well there are certain essential oils
that can
harm your cat others are okay but
some of them are not good i'm so glad
you said that because
uh because that would have been very bad
and i the last thing i want to do is
is harm the cat so yeah if you were
going to use essential oils i would
research it first
absolutely yep yep yep okay well thank
you
so what was the what was so
you're charging that last one and you're
hoping that it will work
correct that one you're charging is it
bluetooth or is it uh wi-fi
it's wi-fi okay
it comes with a dongle right
okay uh do you do you still know
how confident are you that it'll work
with a wi-fi keyboard but that raspberry
pi will work with a wi-fi keyboard
um well the last time that i did a
search on
um amazon i typed in raspberry pi
mini keyboard for raspberry pi okay and
this one came up
so it says it will work with a raspberry
pi
specifically mentions raspberry pi okay
doesn't work um i don't know where i'll
go
yeah yeah well i have any comments
did you read the comments and reviews
because a lot of times if people
have a complaint they write it in the in
the reviews
right and that's when you find out
whether or not it doesn't work
i didn't read those to begin with i was
kind of in a hurry
but i can check that out
well i have a um yeah always trust uh
you have to um if there is no negative
uh comments or review or something then
my advice would be to
check um other things that that they are
selling uh
and and see if there's anything that has
bad reviews and if there is not
chances or they are deleting bad reviews
right right okay yeah
yeah i i i don't know how much i trust
anything that i
did i see special comments and stuff on
on amazon yeah but it would be nice to
be able to trust them for the bad and
good reviews
not a particular product but if the the
platform have a mixture of good and bad
reviews and
um average um reduced and um
it's not a platform who's doing
something nasty and
to hide the comments
okay okay well um doug all i can suggest
is i have a think outside the box
folding keyboard
it is a bluetooth keyboard and i i would
suggest
using that except i don't know that i
have tested it
with a raspberry pi so i will do that
i will test it with a raspberry pi and i
will let you know what it
what what how it works what brand is it
the brand is literally think outside the
box
that's that's actually the that's
actually the brand of it
and the thing the thing has two aaa
batteries inside it and you you
unfold it and that opens up to a
fairly decent sized keyboard but it does
not have
i noticed on your keyboard so all the
ones that you've shown us
have the integrated mouse pad and and
yes a little joystick and stuff that
this keyboard does not have that
so if you need that that those mouse
controls
then this keyboard won't work for you so
well i suppose i could get a bluetooth
mouse or something
wireless mouse you could but then you
need a platform to actually
drive the mouse on right well i've got
you can't see it in my frame but i've
got a
what i call a um a remote organizer
and it's got a flat area on it that i
could use a mouse on
it's right here on the my right side
just out of shop yeah
just take my word for it yeah there you
go
all right peter what sort of trouble
have you been getting into uh
did you see that yeah i spoke about
thank you
so what about what the uh the
password program did you download today
uh i did not try to download it um
because you said it only will
only compile on windows uh and i don't
run windows here
okay okay okay
uh i could probably make it work on the
linux if i try
which is uh sorting out some of the
libraries and things you know
well if you want to you could stick it
up on github um
you've already done that you created a
github account didn't you
yeah but i've got a problem like i'm got
a machine that will work
i could go and kick up a bit um it's a
bit of a problem
and uh the other problem was was um
the the aerial problem with this swedish
box well
the chinese decided to cancel it so nice
back and that was a bloody problem
because the uh the
mistress said let's say them they're a
little bit green
and a little bit precious against people
who come from my country
understand well yeah i mean i have a i
have a parcel that was
that was shipped over from uh california
and from uh chicago illinois
it took two days to get to the central
post office
in my city and then it took three weeks
to get from
that central post office to my local
post office
it's crazy local [ __ ] which is a bit uh
um well a bit funny that's right yeah
yeah because i've gotta
you do have a talent for uh choosing
people off though
[Laughter]
don't worry about it anyway i got my
money back okay
so i'm gonna end up doing what you're
doing with uh
relays and uh on the huge relays and uh
i've ordered another box from merv and
got me a box uh yeah
from the local uh electrical uh
districts are going we are on that
in in the next week or two is to rebuild
it again
on amounts of ones in the relay and use
them uh
some uh dining and transistors to switch
them on we've got about we've got about
one minute to
go and then i have to close it down
because we have to stay to about 25
minutes
yeah yeah yeah but anyway um you
remember i said about the aerial
people that uh tried to bother you yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah
good
if it's less than one minute it's going
to be about 30 seconds
okay uh i was on a cap and uh i worked
into the old man
o am the end down in uh
saudi arabia attraction and uh i called
him first time worked him the guy i
lived through said that by
all no good and you did the world in
said that uh
i need this little thing looks like a uh
well i think uh
i think sector would use it for a
clothesline particularly
uh that's been very rude about it and uh
uh he called involved that didn't work
him i went somewhere else and worked
into the salon
and who had the same things i've proved
that i was right
that he he talked a load of uh well you
know
yeah okay so by by saying he worked into
for everyone else who's not familiar
with this that means he
he worked his operation his ham radio
station and talked to stations in ceylon
and then where was the other one oh man
okay so that's what he means when he
says he worked
all right let's um let's close this up
anybody have any final
comments real quick comment sasha you
want to go first
um i'm just so excited to see y'all
yay me too
[Laughter]
so
i think it's ten years ago there's an
island uh outside of this country and uh
in on the coast of
uh uh norway uh along uh uh uh where i'm
living
where mail from the uh uh local uh
authorities
to to the inhabitants of the island it
took two weeks
to be delivered so they got eventually
they got tired and
they started their driving and the mayor
started driving around the island
himself and delivered mail
in the tournament it was a
meeting and calling for meetings for the
uh
mayor and his staff
but after the meeting was supposed to
happen then the
invitation came in the mail so yeah how
about you any final comments
have a nice day all right enjoy enjoy
your keyboard i hope it works for you
this time
thank you i hope it does take care
everybody
have a have a good night
[Music]
you