covering the week's top tech stores
with a slight linux bias virgin
hyperloop has trialed its first ever
journey with passengers in the desert of
nevada
the futuristic transport concept
involves pods inside vacuum tubes
carrying passengers at high speeds
in the trial two passengers both company
staff traveled the length of a 500 meter
test track
in 15 seconds reaching 172 kilometers an
hour
you may recall from our past coverage as
far as 2018
that the top speed for the hyperloop is
said to be a thousand kilometers an hour
and while this is only a fraction of
that ambition it's a big step toward
hyperloop transportation becoming a
reality
virgin hyperloop is not the only firm
developing the concept but nobody has
carried passengers before
sarah lucian director of customer
experience was one of the two on board
and described the experience as
exhilarating both psychologically and
physically she and chief technology
officer
josh geigel wore normal clothing rather
than flight suits for the event
which took place on sunday afternoon
outside of las vegas miss lucian said
the journey was smooth and not at all
like a roller coaster
although the acceleration was zippier
than it would be with a longer track
neither of them felt sick she added she
said that their speed was hampered by
the length of the track and acceleration
required
the concept which has spent years in
development builds on a proposal by
tesla founder elon musk
some critics have described it as
science fiction
it is based on the world's fastest
magnetic levitation trains then made
faster by placing the train
inside vacuum tubes the world record
speed for a maglave train was set in
2015 when a japanese train reached 374
miles per hour
in a test run near mount fuji the
hyperloop has already exceeded that
speed but never with passengers
critics have pointed out that hyperloop
travel systems would involve the
considerable undertaking of both getting
planning permission
and then constructing vast networks of
tubes for every travel path
miss lucian acknowledges the potential
difficulties saying
of course there's a lot of
infrastructure to be built but i think
we've mitigated a lot of risk that
people didn't think was possible
in speaking about the infrastructure
challenges she pointed out
that while governments can continue
building up yesterday's transport
systems
people are looking for new solutions the
transportation of the future
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us
this week thanks for watching the
category 5
tv newsroom don't forget to like and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
[Applause]
so
you