if you click on subscribe on our YouTube
channel unfortunately that bumps our
numbers up and as our numbers go up I'm
honorbound to do crazy things so I have
my first choreography lesson thank you
very much
and it it will say it's I'm learning I'm
gonna progress as we go so we hit and
surpassed 25,000 subscribers at Linux
tech show comm and of course that means
I got to do a funky dance for you and so
I'm working on it and I got my
choreographer helping me out with that
and it's a surprise who's going to be
helping with that so make sure you keep
watching category 5 TV and it helps if
you're a subscriber because then you're
going to get the notification