covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias the government
in alberta canada is backing the
development of a high-speed
hyperloop between edmonton and calgary
albertans could be among the first
canadians to travel by high-speed pods
between cities
after the government of alberta signed
an agreement with canadian
transportation tech company transpod
to develop and test a high-speed
hyperloop between edmonton and calgary
though no financial commitments have
been made by the government alberta will
support toronto-based transport
by sharing data identifying land and
participating in discussions with
potential investors
according to the news release the
project involves a short-term
feasibility study ending in 2022
research and development ending in 2024
test track construction in use between
2024 and 2027
and the construction of a line between
downtown edmonton
and downtown calgary to begin in 2025.
there are a handful of companies
developing this technology
which allows pods to travel at high
speeds in a low pressure tube
with various projects in the early
stages around the world
this would be the first such project in
canada
the vehicles would travel up to a
thousand kilometers per
hour with an average speed of between
and 600 kilometers per hour alberta's
hyperloop line would stop at the
edmonton and calgary
airports as well as red deer he said and
the total moving time of the full line
would be
a half hour the system would be powered
by a mix of solar panels and electricity
and would mainly transport passengers in
time-sensitive goods like
mail or e-commerce products the 6
billion to 10 billion dollar project
would create
jobs in a province where many oil and
gas workers have lost their jobs in
recent years and position alberta as a
potential hub for technology
you