i wanted to show you how to plot because
that is the most important thing
to get you going with chia now we talk
about using nvmes why
well you've seen videos that say oh you
can plot on a standard spinning drive
don't worry about it don't get an nvme
ignore those people
because i'm not telling you it's
impossible
you can take your bicycle on the highway
but you're not going to do 120
kilometers an hour
great technology don't get sidetracked
by people saying oh you can do it
no listen to people who understand the
technology behind it
and and you're you're gonna want nvme
because it is significantly faster at
plotting and the key
thing is you need to get your drives
plotted as
quickly as possible otherwise you've got
a couple of plots
and a whole bunch of empty space and
that empty space is doing nothing for
you it will do
nothing for you until it's plotted