covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias minecraft is
making the jump to playstation vr
minecraft is already available in vr
forum for windows 10
with the oculus rift and windows mixed
reality plus there's a samsung gear
vr version minecraft playstation vr
is based on minecraft vr tech from these
other vr
platforms mojang studios executive
producer roger carpenter said
everyone who has minecraft on
playstation 4 will get that patch
automatically
download that patch and you'll get
access to the new microsoft vr
functionality
of course you'll need a psvr setup in
order to use it
the ongoing covet 19 pandemic forced
them to adjust how they develop
minecraft
carpenter added but the process was
relatively drama-free
skybox labs also working on halo
infinite
helped mojang work on this release the
minecraft playstation vr experience will
retain
everything from the base ps4 version and
we'll add a bunch of new settings
this includes two ways to play the game
immersive and living room
mojang didn't expand on what that means
but if we were to guess
the letter the latter may feel like
sitting in a virtual room and playing on
a giant screen
mojang didn't reveal whether minecraft
playstation vr will work with the
upcoming ps5
sony has said their playstation move
motion controllers playstation vr aim
controller
and playstation camera will all work
with supported ps
vr games on the ps5 but it's not yet
entirely clear what that means
get your playstation vr ready the free
update drops later this month
you