here i am on the bridge
of the category 5 tv network this is
where it all comes together
this is where the magic happens this is
where i do all the editing of category 5
technology tv and everything else
that goes into such a broadcast we've
been on the air for now
well this kicks off season 14
and from seasons one through to season
we used a track called cupid's migration
by my buddy mick rippon
as our theme song and for season 13
mick himself remixed it for us but here
we are season 14 kicks off today
and it's time to spice things up a
little bit
so what are we gonna do we're gonna get
on fiverr and find ourselves
a remix what i've done is i've uploaded
it to
my github so i've created a new
repository called cat5 tv underscore
theme
song and it has the original dot mp3
from nick griffin
and i've then cloned that to my server
so
category 5 dot tv slash cat 5
tv underscore theme song original dot
mp3 happens to be
that same track so we're going to be
able to send this link
to to anyone who is going to be
producing
on fiverr let's get a peek here okay so
i've created
a file here that is going to tell them
that's where the file is
all right couple of key points here
let's jump back over to gold wave
as far as the intro goes
backing up all right that's cool so
key points
kind of builds right here this is where
it starts
[Music]
but i want it to i want our focus to be
on this guy
all right so that melody comes in at
29 seconds okay so i've
asked for that to be emphasized um okay
i'm looking for
a remix that
uh makes you want to
uh that puts a spring in your stack give
it a good groove
breakdown starts at 1 14. it'll be for
our intro of the webcast
so the build should be pretty pronounced
but happen rather quickly
i can always cut pieces up and move them
around but imagine a quick verbal intro
where we say here's what's coming up and
then our logo flies in and the melody
drops
etc all right
now if you're not yet familiar with
fiverr think of it like an
online classified service but instead of
buying and selling goods
we're buying and selling within the gig
economy so you're
hiring freelancers who will share their
talent and their skills with you
or if you want to sell your talent and
skills within the gig economy
fiver's a place to do that now as a
partner of this video
you can actually use our link and i
would appreciate it if you would because
that will give us a bit of a kickback
but go to cat5
dot tv slash fiverr and that will take
you to their website and you will
receive
20 off when you sign up and place your
first order
if you use our link cat5 dot tv
slash fiverr so let's head there
[Applause]
and i'm going to do a quick search
because i know what i'm looking for
i want chiptune oh i accidentally put an
s in there but it corrected it for us
first option is 6.99 let's give it a
listen
that is not a chiptune uh gangnam style
uh here's one for 50 bucks
[Music]
okay that's pretty good but let's say
our budget
is 50 altogether so let's say
we want to spend because i want to have
more than one to choose from let's say
between one and 18 dollars
this is 14 bucks
and this is lincoln park in 8-bit
get ready for it my very first collab
with
osison because this is happening
it starts with one thing i don't know
why
it doesn't even matter how hard you try
that's cool
let's skip up to the chorus
you hear that
that is awesome let's check out what
else they've done here
[Music]
definitely a good vibe not what i'm
looking for but
[Music]
all right
oh that slide
[Music]
nice
okay i don't know how you're gonna get
that on an 8-bit computer
that kind of flanging going on
so not quite authentic but that is
let's just meld two eras together here
[Music]
and beautifully done really i mean so
what i'm sensing from
ausaisin aussiezin
is a real understanding for that
chiptune
feel but then has kind of adapted some
more modern
uh effects and some of the things that
couldn't have been possible back in the
chip's tune days
um and i'm talking like the early days
of 8-bit nintendo and things like that
but i love that first track so i'm going
to set this one aside definitely for 14
bucks that's worth going back to
this this one we looked at yeah okay
and this one's got mario bros not 8-bit
that is so again we're melding two
different
eras here and i'm not i'm not digging
that
oh i love what emment has done here
is that there's an echo that gives the
sense of a more modern effect but
it is still using what was possible at
that time
so we've created something they've
created something here that
i haven't heard before but surely is
authentic
[Music]
okay what else have they done
i love that that
insane vibrato
[Music]
oh
they did it again that like bringing in
this echo
that is so authentic but yet
so fresh
[Applause]
well done
now we've got some stereophonics going
on here
that we didn't have in the 8-bit days
but i do like it
[Music]
oh i could totally groove to that
see that's got that you know you're
walking
and you just gotta spring in your step
it's a little bit low tempo for what we
want but
it has that
[Music]
okay now we're getting into elevator
music but what i'm hearing and what i'm
liking is the ability to take
authentic sounds and put a spin on them
like that echo
effect it's not delay it is
actually the the instrument being
re-resampled re
repositioned and and put into the
sequence
in such a way that it sounds like an
echo but it is just part of the sequence
i really really like that and while i
want this to be an
authentic 8-bit chip remix
i kind of like what they've done there
with adding some
stereophonics to it i think that works
really well and it brings it into
2020 in such a way that it still
sounds authentic but it has a bit more
fullness than just being straight down
the middle
monophonic so i dig that a lot i'm going
to keep that one open
i like that
so authentic but yeah it has like a
really good groove
very modern sounding that's awesome
oh halftime breakdown
yes dude you are a time traveler
where were you in the mod cracker day
seriously
oh oh i just want to hear through to the
end
okay literary squirrel knows what
they're doing
definitely a musician all through and
through alright what else you got for us
[Applause]
[Music]
all right not into that
that first track okay this has got more
more of a vibe
[Music]
literary squirrel again has put one
instrument
fully on the left and then the rest is
kind of
in space here but that base is
now it's moved into the middle okay
that's pretty neat
lots of demos
[Music]
i love the arpeggio
am
[Music]
it kind of felt like it was going to
build and then it dropped off into like
a churchy
kind of sound to it which i didn't
really like how it dropped down rather
than building up
okay we've stepped too far outside of
the genre that
first track from literary squirrel
though was so good
that i and the price is seven dollars
that i have to hear what literary
squirrel is going to do with our
with our uh theme song let's move on
there's such a fine line between
fidelity
and authenticity and i think that that's
what i'm hearing is that
i i'm looking for something with higher
fidelity
higher like production quality but the
authenticity of that is fantastic it's
just
too like ultra compressed it's
like the levels are just straight across
the board just
it doesn't have the dynamics that i hope
for
it's so cute
[Music]
i wasn't looking for cute though
wow he's playing it
[Music]
i just imagine that most of these folks
are sequencing but he's actually playing
it
hello hello my name is gabriel perez
gabrielle
nice to meet you pose and produce music
for your video game thank you
play it for me okay that is
way too epic
can you imagine category 5. all right
there we go
[Music]
was that super tax
i gotta back that up is it just me or
was that super tux let's jump back on
that
hello
[Music]
what's that watermarked in the
background that is
super tucks nice 10 points for open
source
but not quite the sound i'm looking for
sorry but it was nice to meet you
gabrielle
no i don't need lessons for you today is
to create a
fabulous video game free mix of your
song
sounds good it can be a 16 bit remix or
an 8b
rings i'll go with apex i will show you
now thank you
[Music]
do
i kind of dig what nico's doing
[Applause]
yeah not into that one
so those first three are kind of what
i'm
you know thinking but niko is
seven dollars so i want to give niko a
chance to
try this out and see what he can come up
with
so i'm going to go about placing the
order let's see what these
four musicians can come up with
[Music]
[Applause]
uh okay this is one that has basic
standard
and premium so basic is high quality
audio file
commercial use one instrument
one instrument isn't enough standard
a one minute long track unlimited
instrumentation
commercial use one revision
35 bucks though it's going to push us
over budget
i can't wait to hear what eminent comes
out with though
let's do it
okay and on to aussies and
i think with azazen they've nailed it
they've nailed that
like creating a track that has that
authentic feel
and i don't really need to make much as
far as comments go i like what they're
doing
so let's just move forward
if you're enjoying this so far please
give me a thumbs up i'd appreciate that
very
much and in the meantime i've placed all
four orders
and when we come back we're gonna hear
our first results stick around
[Applause]
[Music]
um so let's take a quick look at some of
the ones that have been submitted so far
so literary squirrel you remember
has an exceptional demo track
and has sent me a couple of demos so far
and let's give a quick listen to the
most current because the first one that
he sent the melody was a little bit off
and i had said
um maybe take a look at the melody give
a listen to my track and then come back
to me
with uh with a new demo and see how
things look so let's give a listen here
to what we've got so far from literary
squirrel
[Music]
you feel that it's got that bob
definitely nailed that kind of
groove that i was looking for
[Music]
now the intro is getting a little bit
long but i can cut that up
nowhere oh okay
so what i'm hearing there is we're still
having trouble nailing that lead melody
and what i realized through my
conversation with literary squirrel
is something that i never thought of
before because i very much
hear music by ear i'm not a sheet music
person at all i don't understand
notation at all but when i hear a song i
can
tinker it out on the on the keyboard and
come up with a melod like i can recreate
the melody because i play by ear but
i feel like literary squirrel is not one
of those people who plays by ear but
rather plays by sheet music by notation
and so
i had suggested maybe what i can do is
i'm gonna i'm gonna
film my hands tinkering this out on the
piano at home so that you can see the
notes that
that it should be because we're not
quite there i can i can hear that he's
he's hitting the the the right like
timing
but the notes are off so let's let's
listen
[Music]
see what i mean
so he's just not hearing it the way that
those of us who
uh play by ear hear music so it's just a
little bit different and it's kind of
interesting isn't it
but he's nailing the the the overall
kind of concept of what i was looking
for i
really dig that groove it feels good to
like i'm just kind of i want to go like
this as i'm listening to that but as
soon as the melody comes in it should be
the
uh so in his case let's see let's hear
because he's playing it in a minor
[Music]
i'm going to play it on the piano
tonight let's switch to that clip
so the next one in line let's see here
and i'm just on fiverr here so
mnet has submitted a couple of versions
of the track as well so let's give a
quick listen
[Music]
so
again we're just a little bit off on
that melody
just a touch
nailed like everything else i'm really
kind of digging that
um i am hearing it's a little bit too
full for a chiptune like to be genuinely
8-bit we were limited to four tracks
back in the day
so there's a lot going on there when the
beat comes in there's like
that just feels a little bit too much
for the
for that era i feel like there's just
too much going on
so i'm gonna request that uh that mnet
kind of pulls that back a little bit i
feel like
he's really nailing kind of the
reminiscence of the original but it's
gotta have something a little bit fresh
there like it's a little bit
i guess i would say on the fence of
being a little
too close to the original like if you
listen to that
i'm just gonna push play again here
like that just feels a little bit
too close to the original almost like
it's like a
like just a a one-to-one
kind of recreation i'm looking for a bit
more
of a remix so we'll see what
what mnet can do with that all right so
let's move on to our next one here
and that is nico igorovich
nico what do you have for us here we are
here is nico's
submission let's give it a listen
[Music]
get off
nico took me literally and put footsteps
so we got literal footsteps there not
exactly what i was talking about when i
said like
picture yourself taking a walk um
nailing a lot of it but that lead melody
there was just that one point where
it was just a little bit off so i'd like
you to kind of rework that a little bit
nico
um and and maybe what we'll do is
instead of fading out
the end there just kind of end it on
like a
or some kind of a downbeat of some sort
i'm starting to hear that where
you know so i'm envisioning how this is
going to be as like an intro video or
something like that so
i kind of want a little bit of a quieter
intro and then the
melody and then a so that it's right
into
all right welcome to the show and we're
we're ongoing so
maybe if nico could implement a couple
of those things tweak that melody just a
little bit we definitely have that 8-bit
vibe going
and i love that niko agorovich is
charging me
in total after all my fees and
everything else 9.77
canadian which blows my mind
let's give a listen to nico's latest
submission
here it is
much more reminiscent of the original
yet
very much 8-bit
[Music]
yes
nice so then it's straight into the show
welcome to the show
i'm robbie i heard one off note there
in the melody line
see what he's done there he's gone
[Music]
so going down on that note so i'd like
to have him
take a quick peek at that that's a
really simple revision though i would
expect
dragging one note down as long as he's
not actually playing this out
on a keyboard and having to redo entire
bits but it seems to me like that's
probably something that he can just
pull together in the sequencer if he's
sequencing
so here's hoping uh all right i've also
got another submission from
emnet and emnet um has been a joy to
work with
and uh all of these gents have been um
but eminent is like so like
right in tune with my mentality as far
as like good customer support he's
always like
thank you so much for your great
feedback and
all this kind of stuff so like over the
top really good customer service as well
as a very talented musician
let's give a listen to what he's done
after i've kind of
so my requests have been with regards to
like really kind of pulling back
it was a little too busy because it felt
like even though it had that 8-bit sound
it was doing so much that it was like 16
tracks versus the four that we were
limited to so let's see
how he's been able to simplify that pull
it back this is eminent's new submission
for us
[Music]
oh nice
[Applause]
[Music]
staccato
[Applause]
[Music]
oh i love that arpeggio
that's fresh
[Music]
sweet
so like nailing the nuances of the
original track while bringing it into
the 8-bit era
[Music]
i just want to see that hear that ending
changed
to end on a downbeat no fade outs
i know the original had that and maybe
that's unfair because that wasn't part
of my original specs
but i'm going to ask eminent to do that
anyways and see what he comes up with
because now as i'm hearing these demos i
start to understand
more of what i'd like to hear because
i'm hearing some of the things i like
and some of the things i don't like so
it gives me a chance
to really evolve my vision for this
well i'm sure you can feel it as well as
i can we are so
close now i haven't yet received a
submission from jose's and
however he has been in communication
with me just to let me know that
life is a little bit too busy right now
and he's
asked for an extension so i'm fine with
that i understand that you know it can
be
really really busy and i would rather
lean toward
quality than speed so let's give him an
extra day
and see if he's able to come up with it
for us i'm perfectly fine with that so i
think as you go into fiverr
you know use use those dates that they
give you initially
as a bit of an arbitrary date unless
you're really really in a hurry
then make sure you are very very upfront
with the artists
or whoever it is that you're hiring to
say look i really need to achieve this
deadline can you do it because
i have found i mean like these are
freelancers people that are working from
home
in a lot of cases these days and uh and
so it's a
you know you've got to be upfront and
honest and i think i've been that and
i've let jose's know
hey if you need an extra day take it i
really would like to have it done by
then because i'd like to do this feature
uh but if you need more time i'd rather
lean toward quality so take your time
take all the time you need
and keep me posted basically so but in
the meantime i've received
three other submissions and revisions
since the last time i checked in with
you
so first of all nico igorovich has
submitted his revision which is
super super simple you remember this is
the one where he went up one note where
i wanted him to go down
so let's give a listen and just see if
he nailed that
see such a
simple little thing one note and now
it just feels like he has nailed it so
i'm going to approve that one
literary squirrel um i'm
curious if my clinking around on the
piano
is good enough and he actually replied
back and said yes
i needed this thank you because i'm not
able to notate music i can't write out
like the notes on
sheet music because that's not me and as
i explained previously
like the best i can do is just tink away
on the piano
and hope beyond hopes that that's enough
for you
who plays by sheet music to be able to
translate that
and i think you're able to see which
keys i'm hitting just enough
that you'll be able to nail that so
here's hoping now let's give a listen to
literary squirrels new submission
utilizing my tinking around on the piano
to see
if we've nailed that melody
[Music]
nice i love also what literary squirrel
has done there
i hear it i don't know if you hear it do
you spot this
um i was very much on the like on the
beat
he's kind of like it added like a dance
like it's a bit more like a bit i don't
know like
skippy uh i don't know the technical
terms because
i'm not a professional musician but it's
got that kind of like
swing to the to the melody a little bit
listen again
[Music]
see he's hitting those like notes in
kind of the in between spots so that it
gives it a bit more of a vibe and i
really dig that
finally the uh oh and so i've approved
that
of course i mean he's nailed it well
done um
emnet has also submitted his ending
to kind of wrap up our
view of these three i said to eminent
like
everything else is perfect but i just
really want it to feel like it resolves
and right now it's just kind of
you know fading out dying off and not
really having a
firm solid ending i really want that so
let's hear what emnet has come up with
with no other direction than that
here it is
[Music]
yes oh that is so
authentic like i just beat the boss i
beat the final boss
and we're at the end of the show and
[Music]
game over i love it absolutely
absolutely stellar well done gents i'm
also looking forward to jose's and
submission
and i'll come back with that as soon as
it's in the final submission from azazen
is
in let's give it a
[Music]
oh listen welcome to the show this is
what's coming up blah blah blah
kind of a little bit of a lull there
[Music]
you touch that
you know what's awesome now you watching
this you've seen
that i love that halftime breakdown
and i let literary squirrel know that i
loved it when he did it
i didn't say any such thing to joseon
and yet he's picked that up
in the song and and done that kind of
halftime
beat and i just absolutely love that
[Music]
haha
and there's that breakdown from the
original
[Music]
so just kind of changed it a bit but i
like it
oh nice that is jose's in submission
uh you know what's really been a lot of
fun throughout this process is having
the opportunity to hear
how four talented musicians on fiverr
have taken the same song and interpreted
it
ever so slightly differently and each
track is
the same it's got similarities it's from
the same original track but
it's completely different in so many
ways as well
i don't think that i personally feel
that there's a clear winner
i feel like i'm going to get use out of
all four of these versions
of our theme song and in fact as i went
into this i thought we were getting
a new theme song for the intro of the
show but now i'm picturing like
a new version for the extro with the
credit roll and a new version when we
transition and
we've got four different versions that
are brand new
for our theme song but which one is your
favorite we had nico agorovich
litter a squirrel
[Music]
m-net
[Applause]
and of course mosasan
comment your favorite below and don't
forget to give us a like
big thumbs up and to subscribe if you
enjoyed this video i greatly appreciate
that
and don't forget if you are thinking
about trying out fiverr whether you need
a new logo
or somebody to design something for you
create some music
there are just unimaginable amounts
of talent as far as like the level and
the eclecticness of the talents that are
available on fiverr
if you'd like to give it a try you can
save twenty percent
on your first gig by using our link cat5
dot tv
slash fiverr and of course that will
also throw a little tip
in our tip jar for us as well thank you
so much for watching hope you enjoyed
you