here's what's coming up in the category
5 dot tv newsroom
arm plans to spin off its iot businesses
under the softbank banner as it focuses
on
core chip design business autonomous
driving startup turns its ai expertise
to space for automated satellite
operation
a new chrome experiment may boost your
laptop or device battery life by up to
28 percent user profiles along with
parental controls are
finally available for amazon prime video
and sega's next retro hardware retro
hardware
is a 1 6 scale multi-game arcade cabinet
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner
are coming up this is the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
arm has announced plans to spin off its
two iot businesses
a move that would effectively transfer
the divisions under the broader umbrella
of the softbank group
which purchased the chip designer back
in 2016.
the move comes as rm seeks to to focus
its efforts exclusively on the
semiconductor business
that has made the company a ubiquitous
presence in the mobile world
the transfer is pending additional
review from the company's board
along with standard regulatory reviews
though arm says it expects the move to
be completed before the end of september
of this year
while it would effectively remove the
iot platform and treasure data
businesses from its brand
the company says it plans to continue to
collaborate with the businesses
the company will retain the chip aspect
of iot while leaving the data software
and services aspects
as their own spin-off businesses arms
iot business has seen quite a bit of
success
with its technologies shipping on
billions of devices and the planned goal
of one
trillion expected next decade
hungarian autonomous driving startup ai
motive
is leveraging its technology to address
a different industry and growing need
autonomous satellite operation
ai motive is teaming up with c3s a
supplier of satellite and space-based
technologies to develop a hardware
platform for
performing ai operations on board
satellites
their ai wear neural network accelerator
will be optimized by c3s for use on
satellites
which have a set of operating conditions
that in many ways resembles those on
board cars on the road
but with more stringent requirements in
terms of power management
and environmental operating hazards the
goal of the team up is to have
ai motives technology working on
satellites that are actually operational
in orbit by the second half of next year
the projected applications of onboard
neural onboard neural network
acceleration
extend to a number of different
functions according to the companies
including telecommunications earth
imaging and observation
autonomously docking satellites with
other spacecraft
deep space mining and more while it's
true that most satellites operate
essentially in an automated fashion
already
meaning they're not generally manually
flown at every given moment
true neural network based onboard ai
would provide them with much more
autonomy when it comes to performing
tasks
like imaging a specific area or looking
for specific markers in ground or space
based targets
also ai motive and c3s believe that
local processing of data has the
potential
to be a significant game changer when it
comes to the satellite business
currently most of the processing of data
collected by satellites is done after
the raw information
is transmitted to ground stations that
can actually result in a lot of lag
time between data collection and
delivery of process data to customers
particularly when the satellite operator
or another
go between is acting as the processor on
behalf of the client
rather than just delivering raw info
there is also more
value from a business perspective in
selling process data
ready to be consumed ai motives tech
could mean that processing happens
locally on the satellite where the
information is captured
single board computers and other
disruptive tech have shifted toward this
kind of
computing at the edge in ground-based
iot setups
and it only makes sense to replicate
that in space for many of the same
reasons
including reducing the time it takes to
deliver the process data
which in turn means more responsive
service for paying customers
the latest experimental addition to the
chrome browser promises to save
a ton of power usage a new flag in the
canary version of chrome
called throttle javascript timers in
background
will cut down on the processing that
normally happens in background tabs
and it could add two hours to a laptop's
run time
javascript's timers often track user
interaction with a web page
checking things like the scroll position
and ad interaction while the tab is open
this also happens on background tabs
which really isn't useful since by
definition a background tab
isn't being interacted with when you
have a bunch of tabs open
these timers can chew through a good
amount of battery for no reason
normally background tabs can trigger a
wake up once per second
now in canary if you turn on the new
throttle javascript
timer setting any tab that has been in
the background for more than five
minutes will have these timers disabled
with wake ups limited to once per minute
google ran some to sorry google ransom
test
to see what kind of impact this would
have on battery life
for the first test they used a 2018 15
inch macbook pro and loaded up 36
background tabs with a blank foreground
tab then let the laptop run
until it died with the feature turned on
the laptop lasted
two hours longer or 28 percent longer
than the default settings that's a huge
improvement and it still can't get cr
but it still can't get chrome up to the
level of apple's safari
which bested chrome by three hours with
the default settings and by
one hour with the new throttling flag
the first test showed just how much
power can be sucked up by background
tabs
but the next test was more of a real
world use case
it swapped out of the blank foreground
tab for a youtube video
with an actual foreground task going on
the difference was less dramatic but
still significant
without throttling tabs chrome lasted
4.7 hours
and with throttling it got an extra 39
minutes
lasting 5.3 hours safari was not
included
in the second test while these are
promising results google says they are
still investigating how limiting
background timers will affect web pages
while google says that the work done
from these javascript timers was often
not valuable to the user when the page
was in the background
they also don't want to break web pages
which provide valuable background
services
like incoming chat and video messages
media playback
and notifications after a 50 percent
rollout on the canary version google
plans to gather feedback from web
developers before the change hits the
wider chrome
user base you know that's an interesting
story because
for my wife and i who are both chrome
users um
we often have a ton of tabs open i mean
if i'm doing
you know research for work or she's
doing
you know different things at home or
we're helping the kids with school
between their school work and
and the research that they're doing and
the the work they're working on on their
google docs we could
at any point have a couple dozen tabs
open and i mean
with my uh with our family computer
we've got the dual monitors
and it's not uncommon for me to have a
browser off to the one screen with
two dozen tabs and then my main screen
where i've got a couple of main tabs and
so
to to have an integrand it's not a
laptop but to have
that power saving is huge because not
only is it
less power on the computer that's being
used but over time you
could see some savings in your sure you
know you mentioned it's not a laptop
and and one of the things that becca
didn't touch on jeff was performance
yeah and i do think about how even on
our desktop computer at home
my youngest will have that same scenario
20 tabs open and then he'll switch user
oh right so which is great
because linux mint allows us to have
multiple people logged in at once but
now we've got
somebody else logging in and double the
tabs yeah
so his java javascript timers are still
going off
in his browser on his profile yes
so i wonder how it would affect
performance as well
yeah i i'm very interested to see i mean
i i know it's a small change
going from one second to the one minute
but i'm really looking forward to see
the impact because
i i do think it's going to be
it will have that you know performance
power but and especially for older
devices
uh like if you if you've got an older
laptop that's already struggling
i mean not just battery saving but if it
does improve some of that background
performance
uh you know that could breathe you know
a little bit of extra life into those
devices so i think it's a great great
idea great feature
yeah totally agree user profiles along
with parental controls are finally
available for amazon prime video and
sega's
next retro hardware is a 1
6 scale multi-game arcade cabinet
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert is here with the crypto corner so
don't go anywhere
welcome to the world of cryptos and
welcome to the crypto corner
this week we had again a stable market
uh
not not huge change in the overall
market cap
so from 266 billion we went up to 272
billion
but again if we thought after those
seven days we'll see some significant
changes like here v
chain went up by 75 percent in just
seven days
or well it's 57 in total we have got
over
uh 30 coins that went higher than 15
and on the downside we've got only four
coins that lost more than 15
so some interesting dynamic happening in
this market as usual of course
now this week i attended the cardano
summit
and when you attend the summit then this
is how it will look like because it has
to be virtual
you've got the tracks where you can go
and listen to the presentations you have
got the exhibit
exhibition halls where you can go and
even talk to exhibitors they have got
some people on the other side of the
computer
and you can interact with them and then
the agenda and
this is um something interesting in
regards to cardano
because it highlights the difference
between something like like
uh ethereum and cardano cardano as you
can see here is
full of academic people that did the
presentations
and um and
in you see doctor doctor doctor
professor and so on
and ethereum is more the environment of
geeks so
fantastic programmers world best
programmers
that are coding on the ethereum
blockchain and coming up with new ideas
of what to do
like the default market uh just as a
late
development and in cardano they're
coming from another
angle they're coming from the
intellectual angle from the theory
the theoretical angle and that's why
also took them much longer to go live
uh rather than um like a theorem they
went live very quickly in that sense
so it's interesting to see which one of
those two blockchains will
have the upper hand long term
now going into detail of what has
happened
i want to show you some presentations
that i really like
this one here is called beef chain which
is a supply management
supply chain management protocol
together with a legislator from wyoming
and it highlights the difficulties that
exist in this market
like here if a salmonella breaks out in
one of those factories
the recall can be really devastating
yeah like here peanut corporation of
america
that company doesn't exist anymore
because of the salmonella outbreak
and executives were handed 28 uh
years of prison and so it's important to
really have
an end-to-end uh tool
that you can rely on and that's what
they developed on the cardano blockchain
and i hope they one day they will also
do that on the medical side
because i i heard that uh 10
of all medication that you can buy is
fake or substandard and so such a tool
would be fantastic also in the medical
sector
next is onboarding so
um i mean in the western world we don't
have huge
problems in getting access to banks or
loans in other countries like here this
is africa for example it looks
completely different
but how do you do that you need to make
it in a way that it is secure
and that's exactly what they developed
here with a project called atala prism
and it's a big deal because it simply
will open up opportunities
like lending payments insurance banking
uh so in total they calculate over 400
billion globally
in d5 payments and in africa that could
benefit for
from such a tool it's just to make sure
that
you're in a secure way are able to
access
these finance tools in this case
yeah so it's a fantastic
product for the unbanked next one
is cardano aims to be extremely
decentralized at the moment it's a
little bit decentralized
but if you want to have something very
decentralized
then you need to offer also tools in
regards to the governance
and they developed this year with
um on the cardano platform and how the
governments look like
it looks like it's fantastic and it's
well
thought through so it's worth taking a
look at so how is the voting done what
can you do with your coins and so on
then part of the decentralization will
be also
um a fund and this you remember probably
ifund which was created by apple
to get apps onto into the app store
cardano is doing a similar thing now
so they launched um a fund
with over 30 million uh us dollars
in it already uh to fund developers
coming up with new ideas and will be
then the chain
governance decides whether those
developers will get those uh grants or
not and
they will also be linked to deliverables
which i find
fairly attractive so that's a new way of
of governance of
a company or in this case a project and
the last one that i saw
is also that coinbase custody
which is just the department of coinbase
will support
uh secure stating secure staking
of the cardano the ada in future so
in total some really interesting
developments on the cardano platform
which i found interesting because it
will shape
the industry as we are in so that's it
from me uh this week
i hope you enjoyed it and i hope you
learned something
and please let us know if you've got any
questions so thank you very much for
watching
bye-bye thank you robert just a reminder
that we're not providing financial
advice but only sharing what's happening
in the cryptocurrency market
always remember that the cryptocurrency
markets are ever-changing and always
volatile
so you should only spend what you can
afford to lose now back to becca in the
newsroom
thank you robbie at long last
amazon prime video is catching up to
competitors like netflix hulu and disney
plus with
with a key feature user profiles
the feature began rolling out in the
mobile and set top box versions of the
prime video app beginning tuesday
the feature allows multiple people
sharing on amazon prime's
prime subscription to maintain separate
watch histories
and watch lists additionally amazon has
made a distinction between user profiles
for kids
and profiles for adults with different
rules
users can configure up to six profiles
in any mix of children's and adults
adult profiles all this is rolling out
immediately but it will take time to
reach
all users multiple user profiles were
supported in india and africa previously
and they are only now making their way
to the rest of the world including the
united states
the rollout brings amazon closer to
feature parity with
netflix and other big streaming partners
players
the bulk of major apps in this space
offered this feature but there are some
outliers who still don't
like cbs all access some of those other
streaming services
offer robust parental controls so amazon
is leaning into that with these changes
as well individual profiles can be
flagged as a kid's profile
that profile will only see
recommendations or search results of tv
shows and films that are age appropriate
12 and under and kids won't be able to
make purchases
amazon is including a number of other
options for filtering content like this
including the ability to restrict
content on a per-device basis
amazon is making these changes amidst
rising competition
disney plus has seen massive growth in
the recent months and netflix seems to
be faring well
also large new entrants to the market
with massive libraries of exclusive
content like hbo max and peacock
are also hitting the scene which puts
pressure on prime video to offer
competitive features and content
in terms of content amazon is working on
a lord of rings tv series and it just
released a new season of hannah
the industry giant is also developing a
tv series based on the video game
franchise fallout
from some of the writers of behind hbo's
from some of the writers behind
hbo's west world what i do like about
amazon prime video is as an
amazon prime member i have it right
so while it kind of seems like okay well
these there's all these services you've
got to subscribe to 10 different
services
in order to get the shows that you want
well amazon prime is part of my prime
service right which i get for free
shipping yes
and priorities and stuff like that on
amazon so it really is cool
what i don't like about the profile
system on netflix because there was a
time when
even netflix didn't support profiles
yeah it's relatively new with like the
last six months to a year isn't it uh
it's been a couple years i think jeff
yeah i remember reporting on it when it
was new but
what i don't like about it is that there
are no pins
there are no there's no protection on
the profiles
so i'll give you an example when i first
set up profiles on our family netflix
account
i had one for each of my children and
then one called
parents right and i had it set up so
that it was
like adult con not adult content but you
know what i mean
grown-up shows yes uh for uh the parents
and the kids were limited to stuff that
was age-appropriate well
it didn't take long before i started
hearing from
our our child that oh so and so
changed my name to butthead you know
they changed my avatar to something like
whatever
so it and then it became like fight
moment that was you doing it at night
wasn't it no
you got me no so now it's like our pro
i've given up our profiles are all
ridiculous
yes but i i really wish that
netflix and amazon prime maybe they'll
maybe someone will clue in and say okay
well
the parents should be the only ones who
can set those settings
yes the parents should be the ones who
can configure them and maybe
they they have a pin based system so
that my
like each child could make changes to
their own profile like changing their
avatar changing their name
but not allow trolling within the family
yeah so that's the only biff that i have
with it it's
it's a nice feature that uh that they're
rolling out with because
um that's been one of the challenges
we've had
like we have uh we have an android box
at home for the purpose of being able to
get
disney plus and amazon prime tv
on our home tv because it's not a smart
tv or anything like that
so we needed a way to put all those kind
of in there and um
and one of the things that i've
struggled with is
whenever we've gone to amazon uh to
watch their content
there is no way to separate between the
kids and the
and the adults and so this is a nice
feature they're rolling out
but up until this point i've not allowed
our kids to
go on to the amazon content because i
don't want them just opening up
something and being like
oh that's that's different yeah or
there's the other side of it where okay
well
each of the three kids is watching the
office but they're
watching it at different places right
right it messes up this
queue so yeah so one of the nice things
about online content and streaming video
is that you can keep track of which
episode you're on well you lose that if
you don't have profiles yes
so that's another thought all right
we've got a throwback to becca
after the release of the genesis mini
and the recent announcement of the game
gear mini
sega doesn't show any signs of slowing
down its plans for miniature retro
hardware releases
the company's next entry in the space is
the newly announced astro city mini
a tiny arcade cabinet set to sport 36
sega arcade titles first released to
japanese arcades in 1993
sega's astro city was a successor to the
smaller 1988 arrow city cabinet
the astro city mini will launch by the
end of 2020 in japan for an
asking price of 12 800 yen which is
roughly 119
the chassis itself will be at one sixth
scale to an actual astro city cabinet
standing a little more than six and a
half inches tall
based on this scale this suggests that
the original cabinet's
29 inch screen will be reduced to
roughly 4.8
inches the joystick and six button
control however will be half scale
and that joystick will sport an
eight-way digital switch which should be
a huge improvement over the
squishier analog joystick found on the
neo-geo mini from 2018.
sega has announced 10 of the system's 36
games with more announcements planned
throughout the summer
so far the list contains alien storm
virtua fighter
alien syndrome golden axe altered beast
columns 2 dark edge golden axe revenge
of death adder
tant r and fantasy zone the unit will
take micro usb
power and will even support hdmi output
to a big screen tv
it'll have basic emulation functionality
such as save states
there will also be attachable usb
control pads sold separately
which allow up to three people to play
on the same mini cabinet
any plans for release outside of japan
have yet to be announced
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom
i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you