Hi and welcome to new everyday.
My name is Kerry and my name's
Jen. And on today's show we're
going to talk about a man named
Phil.. So stay tuned. We will be
right back. This is new every day
with Jim Bakker. And Carrie. Hey
everyone thank you for tuning in
again to news every day. We're
so glad that you've tuned in. And
maybe this is your first time joining
us. And John and I have been friends
for a number of years. We sit down
here and we record this show and
just talk about life stuff we talk
about God we talk about the Bible
we talk about how it applies to
our lives. We talk about Jesus
and what he has actually done and
changed our lives and given us
a new perspective. And so we just
kind of engage in conversation
and pull you in along with us.
So thanks for tuning in. So we've
talked about the book of Acts Jan
and then we've kind of strayed
off a little bit and now we're
headed back. And what are we going
to talk about today. Well today
we're actually backtracking because
the last time we talked about the
book back we talked about Saul's
conversion and as we thought OK
we need to get back into the into
the book of Acts where are we going.
And we're like well we're going
for after Saul's conversion and
when we said wait a second we skipped
over a man named Phil and for some
of the way you might be thinking
will do.And what's interesting
is that the author of The Book
of Acts who is the doctor Luke.
Actually gives. Almost a full chapter
to a man named Phil or Philip.
And you might be thinking Well
who is what he is. Phil OK. So
according to the commentary it
says he is one of the seven chosen
to oversee the ministry of distribution
distributing aid to the needy in
Jerusalem church. Now he has become
an evangelist spreading the Good
News about Jesus. He wasn't one
of the 12 disciples. But and we've
talked about this in previous shows.
Basically the ministry was getting
so large that the Apostles could
no longer give attention to just
preaching and praying the gospel.
And so they were through the power
of the Holy Spirit. They were told
to set aside a number of men to
look after the waiting tables that
means the care of the church. And
so we talked about Stephen a little
while ago and how he was one of
those seven. And so Philip was
one of those seven two. And Chapter
8 the story as you say the story
of Stephen ends at the beginning
in verse 8. This is on that day
a great persecution broke out against
the church at Jerusalem and all
except the Apostles were scattered
through the Judea and Samaria.
So that's all. So the only ones
that remained in Jerusalem were
the Apostles godly men buried Stephen
and more deeply for him but Saul
began to destroy the church going
from house to house.He dragged
off men and women and put them
in prison and then we went on to
talk about Saul's conversion. Now
coming up to verse 4 is this man
named Philip who we you know we
first saw back in chapter. Well
let's just see. We saw him around
chapter three when they actually
laid their hands on people and
they actually listed off the number
of people the names of the people
of who would participate in this
ministry. And and Philip's name
was mentioned around those seven.
So here we go verse 4 starts off
like this. Those who had been scattered
preached the word wherever they
went. Philip went down to the city
of Samaria and proclaimed the Christ
there when the crowds heard Philip
and saw the miraculous signs he
did. They all paid close attention
to what he did with shrieks. Evil
spirits came out of many and many
paralytics and cripple's were healed.
So there was a great joy in that
city. I just I love the fact. Of
this passage but as I read that
what caught my eye was so those
that have been scattered preached
the word wherever they went. Like
even though they were scattered
because of persecution. It's not
like they said okay. To lay low
for a bit. Got to lay low let this
thing pass over or I can't talk
to Jesus he's going to get me killed.
And what's interesting is that as
one of the apologetics or arguments
that they that Christian I want
to say speakers are often used
when they say well we know Jesus
actually rose from the dead because
his apostles and those who saw
him proclaimed him because why
would you be willing to die for
someone or something if it wasn't
real that you didn't believe in
your Noer that it was real. And
so like Philip Here's Philip after
having been scattered from Jerusalem
continues to preach the Word of
God of the Christ. That's what
it says. It says the Christ or
the Messiah. So he was claiming
that Jesus is the Son of God. It
didn't matter that he had been
scattered it didn't matter that
Steve and his friends had been
killed. He was willing to lay down
his life for the sake of the gospel.
Like now it says to me that's real.
This is real and what I also respect
about the apostles here and about
the bonus ones like Philip is that
even though Stephen was just killed
like the Lord used that for his
purposes because in scattering
then the word was spread and we
talked about that when we spoke
about Stephen but they didn't sit
in mourning. They realized the
value and be had the eternal perspective
of the kingdom of God. This is
not all that there is. Yes. And
if you feel if you think that way
that this is it that this is all
that there is to life then.It influences
how you respond to tragedy and
how you respond to persecution
and people commenting or you know
saying harmful things to you then
it's much easier to internalize
it because you don't have an eternal
perspective. But it's like these
guys knew where the game was at.
Yes. Like you're going to run hard
until you finish and Stephen finished
seemingly early. Yeah but it was
just the start of their ministry
going forward and you know as you
were you were saying this is so
easy when the hard knocks come
when the challenges of life come
just like you said. I'm going to
lay low. I'm going to lay low low
I'm just going to take it easy.
And as you were speaking you really
how is speaking to my spirit. My
sister passed away almost a year
ago now. And you know it would
have been easy at that point in
time just you know oh this is so
sad. And yeah I saw it as an opportunity
of proclaiming the good news of
how faithful God was like. Even
though from a very earthly perspective
it you know her life might not
have been seen seemed as successful
or a benefit to those around her.
And yet I know that God used her
to do so much in my life and and
to the people that interacted with
her. So at her funeral I was I
actually had to share the gospel
story of how you know I don't understand
why all this is happening and and
here's Philip who's thinking Oh
he's the Messiah.He came to the
Jewish people why are these people
rising up like he very well could
have been like was what makes this
doesn't make sense. But he said
no. I know who Jesus is. I. Am
going to proclaim him and I am
going to continue to go out. And
it was just you know a real opportunity
for me to share. Like I don't understand
what's happening. But I do believe
in a God who is faithful. I do
believe that Jesus really did die
on the cross for our sins so that
at the end of time at the end of
our stories here on Earth that
were going to be you know renewed
with him and like Face-To-Face
glory. And my sister is going to
have a new body and I'm going to
get to see her again because those
who have faith in Jesus Christ
will be reunited. Yes. And it's
just that's part of the like the
yes story. Yeah. And that's what
Peter Philip is proclaiming. He's
proclaiming that yes yes like this
is who Jesus is. And what's interesting
is that part of to be a group part
of the Group of Seven they had
to have be like godly men and full
of the Spirit and had you know
been a part of that group who followed
Jesus. So I just I love the fact
that it said Philip went down even
though they had been scattered
they preach wherever they went.
So he went down to the city of Samaria
which was a big no no for Jewish
people Big no no. We saw that in
John Chapter Four when Jewish stuff.
Jesus he was Jewish. Jesus stopped
at the well and was speaking to
the Samaritan woman and everyone
was that one he was speaking to
a woman in that time that was a
no no. And she was a Samaritan
which was also the Jews did not
associate with Samaritans So it's
very interesting that that's where
he goes. Yeah it is. And it goes
on when the crowd heard fill up.
So he's preaching and then saw
the miraculous signs that he did.
They all paid close attention to
what he said and was shrieks. Evil
spirits came out of many and many
paralytics and cripple's were healed.
So there is great joy in that city.
So as we go to commercial break
what I want you to think about
what part of the gospel message
brings you great joy. That. Right
that Produces whether you shop
on geek your best be in a photo
or video eBay or Amazon or even
if you want a free trial of audible.
You'll find the best deals and
support the shows we produce by
simply visiting the shopping sites
you already frequent by using the
links on our Web site visit Category
5 dot tv slash partners for the
full and evergrowing list and help
us create more free content like
this show.Thank you for shopping
with our partners. And thank you
for watching us. Hey everyone and
welcome back. You're watching you
every day with John Kerry and we
just want to thank you again for
tuning in and thank you to all
of our wonderful partners. If you
go to our Web site new everyday
dot tv click on the partners tab
and you can see all of the organizations
Businesses who are supporting us
to help make this possible. Thank
you also to Category 5 TV and Robbie
Ferguson who hopes to produce this
program. So we're back with a man
named Phil Phil. I know it's it's
it's early. What I love is that
it's there's one chapter in the
book of Acts. You know he doesn't
have a book named act he didn't
write a book. Yeah. I don't actually
think he's mentioned in any of
the other. Like many of the other
writers write about Phil. And so
what was it about his life. That.
That Luke wanted us to hear. I
think it's just this. He was a
man who loved Jesus who was part
of that group of seven who were
set apart by the Apostles who when
persecution came he just kept going.
He just kept going. And that's
an aspect of his story that I hadn't
thought about before. And I wonder
when he was actually murdered I
would have to look that up I for
next show.Maybe that's why he's
not mentioned later on. I don't
know. But it's that tenacity in
that kingdom perspective. Yes.
That this isn't what life is about
is knowing Christ knowing that
we're loved by him that he was
risen from the dead and that this
stuff is real. Yeah. Motivated
his actions. Well because it says
they all paid close attention to
what he said. Why. Because he spoke
and then the miraculous signs happened.
So I don't think he's like Ben.
I think it's like oh you're sick
in the name of Jesus be healed.
Right. So he was aware of what
was going on. He saw the need and
he prayed because he believed.
And so they're watching him they're
watching him just be a real believer
in Christ. Yes like like this is
and I know a lot of churches and
I know I've spoken with other people
who say that they're Christians
and say that the Book of Acts is
not for today that the signs and
wonders done like the healing in
the casting out of evil spirits.
That was for that time and it's
not for today. But I got to believe
that this is for today because
Jesus commissioned them to go out
and this this whole movement was
just to continue continue continue
because Jesus prayed when he was
in the garden or when he was with
his disciples the night before
he died he prayed for the people
who are going to come to know him
through the apostles he was praying
for us.I think to live this way
to have the fullness of the knowledge
of God and The word also says that
the signs will follow those that
believe the healing of the sick
the raising of the dead. Yes. The
casting out of demons and the lame
walk the blind will see. Jesus
said you see me do these things
and you will too even more. Yes.
And John I've just been challenged
lately just to Pray. Crazy prayers.
Now what I mean by crazy is like
believing that God can do miraculous
things and for a people and generation
like in western society where we
rely so much on ourselves or technology
or whatever in our lives I think
that God can speak to people by
doing the miraculous through his
church. And that in the last time
that people will be turned to him
because of the signs and wonders
that will follow those that truly
believe. And. You know we had a
woman in our church who had hurt
her shoulder and she messaged me
saying can you put this on the
perch. And that's what we do. We
have a prayer chain at church basically
sending the email is sending a
text message it goes out to a group
of people they start praying. And
she said to me after that was sent
and after I received prayer on
Sunday morning my shoulder felt
miraculously better. Yeah. And
I was just like yeah like and it
shouldn't shock us but sometimes
it does because not always.Do people
share with us how they feel healed
or they are healed after we've
prayed for them. But it was just
like yeah god like why wouldn't
you do this. We asked and we ask
in faith. Yeah. And it was just
so cool. Like when you said this
is for today. This is for. It is
for today. And that question that
I asked before we went to break
said you know so there was great
joy in that city and so what is
it that brings me joy about the
gospel. What is it. And it's probably
hearing God stories about how when
people open themselves up to Jesus
being changed by him and and hearing
them just share the stories of
how they are transformed. I used
to do this but now I do this. I
used to do this and now I do this
I used to you know like my marriage
was just falling apart. And then
I came to know Jesus and he healed
like that's probably one of my
greatest joy is just seeing the
power of Jesus Christ working in
the lives of people. Yeah. Like
that's my yay. God yeah. That's
what brings me great joy. When
I think about the Gospel message
is just how lives are changed when
they meet Jesus. Yeah. And I'm
more and more convinced that he
really is the answer to every problem.
Like there is no problem too big.
And it's sometimes like if I pray
for someone to be healed and then
I healed. It's easy to think of
all the reasons why and that all
the reasons why not to pray in
the future. But if I'm not praying
that nothing's going to happen.
So why not just pray. I know I
got to share a story so my mom
was at a parent teacher. Night
I guess and the school for my little
brother and the custodian was there
and she was complaining of back
pain. And my mom just went up and
she was like I would pray for you
back. OK. And then she just put
her head on her back and prayed
for her that she would be healed
and that was it. And my mom walks
in faith believing that God can
do like all these crazy people.
And then he does. And then he died.
Yes. So anyway is the custodian
a couple of days later I spoke
with another teacher at the school
who knows my mom and said. After
that lady pray for me my back gets
Better. Yes right. Yeah. I know.
Lord priest or like I just believe
that he can he can do these things.
We're out of time already. We're
out of time. Read that passage
about Philip. As a. How can I look
like Philip or what part of Philip's
life can I be a part of in the
sense of like maybe you're feeling
opposition but you still need to
step out in faith or maybe God's
call you to pray for someone or
to do a miraculous sign and you're
just like whoa that's not for me.
We would say ask the Lord about
that. Like ask him to convict you
to give me the courage that you
need to step out in faith and just
continue to preach you know whatever
the words are that he's given you
to share. So and I just got to
say pray and ask God to show you
something about that person that
he would give you even like a word
of knowledge for them something
that you could share with them
and pray specifically for them
because he already knows he already
knows them. He already knows them.
So we're going to sign off. May
the Lord. Blow your socks off this
week when you think about what
is it that you would have me do
if you asked him that question.
And then just wait. I mean I'm
just thinking that the Lord is
going to have you do step out faith
in a miraculous way. So may you
be strong and courageous knowing
that God is love. So until next
week. I. Find. I reckon that. Said
Catch an episode of new every day
every Friday morning and new everyday
TV We are also on Codi Roku plague's
YouTube and Facebook for it here
in the Southern California. Tune
in every Sunday morning at 6:30
Pacific on channel 33 television