[Music]
welcome to the world of cryptos
welcome to the cryptocorn how was last
week
well last week we had a slight increase
from 276 billion to 283 billion
and mainly because bitcoin increased in
price
and if we sold this year by the seven
days we see a few currencies increase
quite significantly like swipe with 152
overall over 18 18 coins increased by
more than
uh 15 if we sort by the negative
then only one coin lost more than 15
percent
now at this stage i'd like to um
we need to talk and the reason is
something is happening in the market as
you can see i mean we've been reporting
about this increase
for some time mainly in the default
market but something else is happening
in there
and before you make those mistakes that
i made during my time
in cryptos i'd like to show you those
mistakes that i made now what i'm going
to show you of course is not financial
advice
please i'm just a techie guy
so let's take a look another directory
this one is masari.io
which i find fantastic so get an account
there it's better than
coingecko and coinmarketcamp because you
can select
all different types of
data that you can't select or find in
other
browsers directories so this one here i
selected and sorted by
all time low or up since low time low in
other words
aver for example increased since uh its
all-time low by
ten thousand percent ten thousand
percent
it was this year that they had the
all-time low and so if you would have
invested one thousand dollars you would
yeah you can calculate
yourself how much money you would have
made and there are few that
increased significantly i mean all those
are big
uh chains here harvest big chain link
kyber those serious projects so these
are not scams or anything
and so what i'd like to show to you is
those mistakes that i made in those
uh many years that i'm in this industry
and uh
here's a small list um that i will refer
to
so the first one is those famous pump
and dumps and we had recently the pump
and dump
in dogecoin where somebody
decided on tick tock to make a video uh
saying let's promote uh
dogecoin to one dollar and poof the
price went up like crazy but
the same way it went down again and by
the time you'll hear this year
the price will be already up here so you
only can lose money
another one is this one here where an
expert started working with one of those
projects together
and it looks like it was back here a few
days ago
they bought some tokens as you can see
and but that no significant
and he announced it this morning and as
you can see woof the price went up like
crazy
and if i take a look at the 24 hours so
this is
the last six seven hours by the time you
would have heard it
it's too late the price is going down
again so don't fall to those famous pump
and dumps
next one is scams in uh in general terms
uh so we've got this one we reported
about this on a few times
already um there are many others where
you just
they ask you to send you some uh
bitcoin ethereum or whatever and they
sent you the double twice the amount
back or whatever
but there's nothing free on in crypto so
forget about
participating in this year you saw that
already many times that you will lose
money
it sounds tempting don't do it even
worse is those where
there are some people promoting special
currents like here
this one was very big in 2018 and 17
where people were promoting and pushing
bit connect
and creating videos and everything it
was a ponzi scheme
and so 2.6 million billion dollars were
lost that way
here one coin 400 million dollars it's
incredible the money that is being lost
by just people
listening to other people to invest
money don't do it
next one is experts and as you everybody
here in this industry is expert you
you've seen that by now
and if this morning i searched here for
all kind and old coin and youtube and
you can see a few of those already here
like this one here urgent
update these all kinds will pump
thousand percent top secret all coins
that will pump into 2021
1000x altcoin gains these are just the
first three four
in this list and so i know i will
i have listened to those and then i
invested accordingly to those hoping
that one day the coin will go
to those thousand percent it didn't
happen so
don't do that either don't listen to
those experts i know it's tempting and
now
we're all greedy and we'd like to become
billionaires
in in a week it ain't going to happen
so there might be some movement but it's
not what you're expecting it's not those
thousand percent guaranteed not
find your own strategy next one is
trading
um so um
that's where i lost money um
when i take here whatever any any coin
let's take bitcoin and i start trading
so
moving going in because i think the
price will go up or moving out
i can guarantee you will also lose money
there because you are not able to
predict what the price is going to do
nobody is
there a lot of people that pretend to
know what they is and they do technical
analysts and analysis and it shows
everything perfect
and reality is and gonna happen
last one is participating in these
uh lending platforms now as you can see
here currently
um this one here curve.fi is offering an
apy of 246
which is incredibly high it doesn't make
any sense uh so i don't
go into this either unless you've got a
lot of money that you can lose
because first you don't know how they're
doing this year so you need to learn
that first and secondly
the fees are also incredibly high so if
you go in with hundred dollars you will
lose that by just
uh participating in these uh lending
platforms so you will not be able to get
that find your own strategy i think
that's the best way find your goal and
do your own research
and and do your own uh homework
anyway so that's it for me this week i
hope
you learned something i hope you don't
fall into the same traps i did
uh it cost me a lot of money
so and i'm looking forward to see you
next weekend thank you very much for
[Music]
watching
you