[Music]
covering the week's top tech stories
with the slight linux bias the world's
very first 3d
bio print lab-grown rib eye steak
i'll tell you all about it in a moment
but first if you enjoy your weekly tech
news with a slight linux bias
become part of our fleet choose your
rank at patreon.com
category5 also make sure you subscribe
to
our youtube channel and click the bell
to catch the stories we cover each week
i'd also appreciate it if you'd give
this video a big thumbs up to show us
that you like what we're doing
on with a story a little more than a
year ago
robbie jeff and sasha stood in studio d
and talked about a plant-based pork
substitute by impossible foods that was
unveiled at ces in las vegas back in
january 2020
it was created in a lab using extracted
soy protein and heme
a plant-derived iron molecule that
provides a meaty taste and scent similar
to animal derived iron
and while this food tech breakthrough is
indeed a promising
product for vegetarians and vegans alike
meat eaters worldwide are still not
ready to trade in their beef and pork
for a plant-based alternative
but what if the meat alternative was
also made of meat
huh well the world's very first lab
cultivated 3d bioprinted ribeye steak
has been unveiled in israel
this month it was created by aleph farms
ltd
and the faculty of biomedical
engineering at technion israel institute
of technology
unlike regular 3d printing which uses
plastic or ink to build an
object 3d bioprinting uses cells
and in this case actual cow cells
we've successfully produced the first
pieces of beef steak
grown from natural cells without harming
any animals
meat is a complex tissue this
breakthrough includes various cell types
found in conventional cuts of meat
grown together outside the animal
to form a 3d structure similar to meat
but using more sustainable safe and
ethical
these first cell-based meat cuts
demonstrate
our capability of achieving our vision
of growing
sticks this meat had a great look and
the original texture of a steak
finally meat you can enjoy that's good
for your health
and the planet from aleph farms our 3d
bioprinting technology is the printing
of
actual living cells that are then
incubated to grow differentiate and
interact in order to acquire the texture
and qualities of real steak
olive farm said in a recent statement a
proprietary system
similar to the vascularization that
occurs naturally in tissues
enables the profusion of nutrients
across the thicker tissue
and grants the steak with the similar
shape and structure of its native form
as found in livestock before enduring
cooking this specialized process of
literally growing steak in a lab instead
of on a farm
uses only a fraction of the resources
needed for raising cattle
and doesn't require any antibiotics or
fetal bovine
serum natural pluripotent stem cells can
be grown in larger quantities
didier tubia the co-founder and ceo of
aylef farms explains these cells can
multiply efficiently and can
mature into the cell types that make up
meat like muscle
and fat cells it is enough for us to
harvest the cells once from a cow
and the procedure we use is non-invasive
in scale the alf farms cultivation
facilities
aptly named bio farms will be similar to
yogurt factories
though their goal is to have a wide
variety of bioprinted state cuts
available in the marketplace by the
second half of 2022
they will first need to acquire approval
from the fda and the u.s department of
agriculture
before they can sell in the u.s tobias
said
we believe the u.s is well positioned to
be one of the first countries in the
world to clear cultivated meat
we have had interactions with the fda
and the usda
in an interview with the washington post
toubia also had this to say
with cows the breed has a role but the
quality comes from the feed
with our cultivated meat it is similar
we control the cultivation process and
we can design
meat specifically for a market adjusting
the amount of collagen
and connective tissues in fat to tailor
meat to specific requirements
last month ayla farms and mitsubishi
corporations food industry group
jointly signed a memorandum of
understanding in japan
the plan is for the two companies to
work together once market approval is
procured
with aylaf farms providing its biopharm
technology
and mitsubishi handling the
manufacturing and distribution
3d printed steak like we're talking okay
we've talked about it in the past becca
mentioned that
last year we did talk about a
plant-based
simulated pork but this is completely
different this is legit beef
this is real meat that has been
basically grown in in a way that has not
harmed any animals and then
3d printed so they can create
the you know the right marbling the the
texture the flavor it is meat
yeah and if you're somebody who's
conscious about how animals are treated
it's done in an ethical way non-invasive
they've cultured some cells
and now they're growing it yeah and so
what comes after that is like
you know that cow's walking away happy
eating in the field doing this thing and
his
cellular offspring are there now being
3d printed into stakes
3d printed think about it which is crazy
3d printed steak
but what i was blown away by with this
story is the fact that
it looks like a steak it tastes like a
steak
it feels like a steak that's at least
that's what they're saying yeah
and so i mean time will tell i i would
sign up to try it
absolutely i mean it's it's me i gotta
try i mean and they can create
i wonder what this is going to do to the
industry at large
because the immediate thought that comes
to mind is like wagyu
right beef right so if they can create
that
perfectly simulated marbling not
simulated
i'm using the phrase simulated but it's
not simulated no it's it's
real yeah it's but it's designed by
humans
based upon the how meat
what meat is what the chemical makeup
and an actual
makeup of meat is mm-hmm but the fact
that you can custom order
like that's what they want to get to is
custom ordering your steak so it's like
oh i like mine with extra marbling i
like mine
you know in the shape of my favorite
cartoon character you know like that
will happen
i want a cat five marbled steak oh my
goodness that's the next step
folks yeah but the one thing about this
that
maybe it's just branding for me that i
kind of went oh
is the fact that it was mitsubishi
they're the ones who are doing the
technology the printing end of things
and i was just like
so take it one step further and you
think about well that's weird that a car
company would be involved in this right
i am wondering if tesla might take
notice and by tesla
i mean i mean the ceo of tesla elon musk
and the reason i say that is because you
start to see
connections between his companies oh
sure absolutely you see
the boring company and tesla with its
batteries and
and solar cells and and the um
uh spacex obviously yeah like all of
these things come together for what
a mission to mars right so thinking of a
car company like tesla picking up on a
technology like this
imagine being able to 3d print your
meat right on mars well and mars is like
what a one-year journey
they say or i think tesla's made a
little bit faster now with their spacex
but you know you've got that long
journey you can only have so much food
on board
but think about the fact that if you
could now print
your protein for astronauts yes
yeah all you have to do is have a diet
yeah balanced diet you can have a
cultured factory
so to speak that reduces so much weight
because you don't need all that extra
dehydrated protein whatever yeah we're
approaching the technology that is
absolutely out of sci-fi
totally just incredible stuff i love it
so how do you feel about lab-grown beef
and 3-d bio-printing do you think such
advances in food science and technology
are necessary
for the future sustainability of our
planet
do you envision a future like in star
trek where food replicators everywhere
will be able to print
not just steaks but any type of food let
us know your thoughts in the comments
below
from the category 5 tv newsroom i'm
becca ferguson
thanks for watching
[Music]
[Applause]
you