covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias after the
release of the genesis mini and the
recent announcement of the game gear
mini
sega doesn't show any signs of slowing
down its plans for miniature retro
hardware releases
the company's next entry in the space is
the newly announced astro city mini
a tiny arcade cabinet set to sport 36
sega arcade titles first released to
japanese arcades in 1993
sega's astro city was a successor to the
smaller 1988 arrow city cabinet
the astro city mini will launch by the
end of 2020 in japan for an
asking price of 12 800 yen which is
roughly 119
the chassis itself will be at one sixth
scale to an actual astro city cabinet
standing a little more than six and a
half inches tall
based on this scale this suggests that
the original cabinet's
29 inch screen will be reduced to
roughly 4.8 inches
the joystick and six button control
however will be half scale
and that joystick will sport an
eight-way digital switch which should be
a huge improvement over the
squishier analog joystick found on the
neo geo mini from 2018
sega has announced 10 of the system's 36
games with more announcements planned
throughout the summer
so far the list contains alien storm
virtua fighter alien syndrome
golden axe altered beast columns 2 dark
edge golden axe revenge of death adder
tant r and fantasy zone the unit will
take micro usb power and will even
support
hdmi output to a big screen tv it'll
have basic emulation functionality such
as save states
there will also be attachable usb
control pads sold separately
which allow up to three people to play
on the same mini cabinet
any plans for release outside of japan
have yet to be announced
you