[Music]
welcome to category 5 technology tv it's
so great to have you with us
you know jeff some christmases some
holidays we go all out and do all kinds
of fancy things we've done a musical
yes you have we've done all kinds of fun
christmasy things this year 2020
we decided to take a different approach
as we wrap up
the year here on category 5 tv it's
about just taking
a break sitting down just together as
kind of our cat 5
family and hanging out and just having a
nice time together
and and kind of reminiscing a little bit
and i was saying before the show here
i've got my phone i'm not being
anti-social i promise you
i'm being very social because i'm
watching our discord i'm watching our
irc chat server
and encouraging our viewers to get in
there while we're live
while we're recording the show uh it's
an opportunity
for you to to say hello to tell us a
little bit about uh
maybe reminisce with us tell us some of
the things that you've enjoyed with
category five this year
and uh and and hey interact with us we
don't get to interact
with the viewers as much as we used to
it is true
and i miss that i really do um and
that's part of the evolution of a
program such as ours
is that we don't always get to sit down
and just have a one-on-one with our
discord and our our viewers it's true
we've done zoom meetings and we have the
community coffee break which
happens every sunday and bp9 has been
great to take that over for them yes
um yeah and so that continues and it's a
great opportunity for you to sit
down with uh with our community um
now the whole studio is shutting down
for the for the rest of the year
like the end of december makes sense and
coming back in january and so it's
it's a really really neat time uh for us
we've never ever done that before i know
i mean
we've been through a heck of a year it
really has been a year i mean like i
think about when this year started
and a new studio was not on the mindset
like covid was not on the mindset it was
just like hey we're really excited about
you know the season and the things that
are coming and then march hit and it
just kind of went
and uh here we are we're i mean we're in
studio e
i love the studio i love all the changes
the things that are happening
really excited about 2021 and what it's
going to bring for cat5
and uh yeah it's going to be good to
just kind of wrap up on a positive note
i know it's been a tough year for a ton
of people but we've tried to
you know keep cat5 as consistent as
possible and as fun
and you know social as possible and so
yeah if you are watching live
get in the discord not only have we
tried to keep it going and and
keep the show um consistent as you say
but also to try to find our new
selves right because our show has gone
through such a time of transition
yeah so as jeff mentioned at the start
of this year
2020 we were gearing up for all the
features that we had planned we were
getting everything set
um we had just finally purchased a
server rack
yep for our old studio d because uh you
remember jeff
um we had that big uh 3u
dell r510 server massive sitting on
a desk yep we didn't have a rack for
that so we just got a server rack we
just got a new isolated audio console
it's a tascam 24 channel console which
is a big upgrade for us and we were
finally ready to do that
and then um we lost our studio yeah
because the landlord decided that he was
hoping to re-use the space for something
else
yep but just after giving us that news
so we were just
humming and han and trying to figure out
okay well where does this leave us
as a show that's when the pandemic
started
yes so we moved
and we lost sasha and we lost sasha i
mean she's
she's still with us she's still part of
our community and part of our
our crew so for those of you who wonder
you know what what
has happened with sasha um she is still
very much a part of
this family and and our staff but
life has completely shifted for her as
well so she's had to move across the
country yep
she does have a dream and we support
that dream uh
of uh renovating um her attic space
into a pseudo kind of remote studio
which would be so cool
and it would be really cool so that
she'd be able to remote in and come on
and be a part of our show once again
in some fashion it's not going to be
like it was back in studio d
when she was there in person but but
we're still looking at ways to have her
here and some people have said well why
haven't you had her here why hasn't she
been on on a wednesday night when you
guys are live and you could have brought
her on by zoom or something like that
and as i say life has happened for her
too so
having moved across the country she got
a job and she is working
like mad and much so she works wednesday
nights
yes and also the time change so and the
time changes
much later try to get sasha to
explain to us what time it is and and
what time she's going to be here
it's just not happening that was a great
episode but yeah
i mean i like when sasha would he was
here for studio d
like the show would end she's like i'm
going home i got to go to bed because
she always had
the word more in the morning yeah and so
i mean to then ask her to do cat five
when she's in a later time zone and it's
gonna
you know be an even later night for i
mean she'd be going to like what 11
o'clock at night 12 o'clock maybe
and it's like oh my goodness so yeah
uh nomen5 wants to know if this is our
opportunity to see robbie dance and it's
not yet
that's a funny story too because now i
don't know the story okay well we
we were approaching we were at 24
000 subscribers on our youtube channel
linux tech show that's right yeah yeah
okay
and i kind of uh off the cuff jokingly
said hey if we hit
25 000 i'll i'll i'll do a dance for you
and then all of a sudden we hit 25 000.
oh and i got called out on it and it's
like you need to dance now
so i had i i got a choreographer to put
together a dance for us
yeah and then the the city went to
lockdown right yes and so
that is still happening apparently that
is something that i'm planning to do but
like so many things with lockdown kind
of
you know we're locked down okay now
we're not locked down we've even
been even i guess sunday was it that i
messaged you
and said i don't know if we're going to
be able to sit down in the studio
because
monday monday our city was moved to
red zone they call it so we weren't even
sure if we were going to be in lockdown
by wednesday
but here we are we're not in lockdown
yet again
but it keeps kind of going that ebb and
flow and we do need to keep everyone
safe that's
very very important so is the dance
happening yes well the other thing
that's got to happen
yeah is the simulated labor that's
happening too
so i had somebody ask me about that this
saturday like hey what do you do with
that labor thing i know
how do you know about that to like
people talk man yeah
so your wife is spreading the word yeah
so that with that
so and and a lot of the kickstarter
perks as well
um these are all things that are that
have
because of the pandemic had to just be
put on pause
that's right they're not canceled
they're not put on
indefinite hold or anything they're
we're just in this pause motion where
so for your labor and i don't even know
how much you know about the coordination
that's gone into this
i don't know i just know to talk about
this
yeah you get to prepare you do not
prepare
i want this to be completely legit i
told you if you're not allowed to do any
sit-ups you're not allowed to
to work those ab muscles at all so been
faithfully staying at it that's
fantastic
so with regards to the to the labor so i
started working with a company at the
start of this thing okay um
for the electronic component so they
sent me
um what they created which is an eight
electrode device that goes on your
stomach
okay um and that device is connected to
an electronic piece all right that
electronic piece
i'm working with omslo so elaine from
omslo those of you who follow my nems
linux project
you're familiar with them they create
raspberry pi
accessories p hats um
connections electronics for raspberry
pi's that can be controlled
so elaine is well was i mean
again everything is just on pause all
right so know that all these things are
being coordinated and and just had to be
like okay well we can't proceed
so what elaine yeah what elaine is
working on
is a raspberry pi gpio
circuit connected to a raspberry pi zero
with the with the wi-fi and
uh the gpio okay that is connected to
these eight electrodes
and there's a web interface for this oh
come on
and with that web interface our viewers
when this happens and it is happening
are going to be able to push the buttons
are you serious
yes in real time live
so that's all happening however i don't
think that was part of the kickstarter
that's not happening
well we got to go all out we got to make
this happen
now the other thing that we need to make
sure with this jeff is that you're safe
of course that's sort of important to us
[Music]
like i'm the resident guinea pig we want
to hurt him
but that's as far as we want it to go we
want to safely hurt him yes
and with that i actually have a
volunteer organization called st
john ambulance who we were
coordinating with them they have
nurses and they were going to send two
nurses that were going to oversee this
entire thing
there we have a defibrillator we have
all of these you laugh but it's all
for safety's sake so all of these things
are in line
all of these things are in the works and
happening and then we went into lockdown
so st john ambulance comes back to me
and says
okay well get back to us once this
once we're through this pandemic because
right now we cannot send the nurses
right
our volunteers cannot enter your
building right okay
so that's where that's at so everything
is happening but paused
all right all the perks are happening
but paused
we've got we've got people who are going
to have one-on-one
zoom calls with myself with sasha and
it's happening but it's paused because
like with sasha's schedule she's i was
talking to her this week as well
she's just not sure she can't commit
because she's on call yeah that's right
so
that makes it tough it's and if that's
part she's a psw so she takes care of
uh folks in a in a home and with that
she needs to be available all the time
and uh doesn't know when she's going to
get called in so she can't really commit
to
uh you know a full day of being a part
of category five
so so know that so yes the dance is
happening yes we're going to shock jeff
really really badly to the point where
it is indeed
uh necessary to just have a
defibrillator on hand
we also have to do the paintball thing
the paintball thing is happening and
jeff you suggested well why don't you do
something with that
where sasha can remotely control that
right because the deal was with the
paintball thing that
uh whoever donated the most it was what
10 cents a ball
whatever it is exceeded ten dollars a
ball whatever it was
to a max of 500 paintballs and sasha
would get to shoot me yeah so this was
the kickstarter
and uh that was just for anybody who
donated
and then because we had that five
thousand dollar donation come in
sasha gets to shoot me with 500 balls in
the name of the donor
but then sasha moved away so i said to
robbie
there's got to be a way where sasha can
do this remotely
i have a 3d printer now yes you do and
you're using it
so well yes so what are you doing with
that so that sasha can shoot me from
across the country well we talked about
this
and the decision was made internally
that we cannot do that
yes and and that's an unfortunate thing
so that
we're still going to shoot him but we're
figuring it out
and here is the solution first of all
the reason we cannot do it
is because everything that we do is to
be open sourced
so when we create this circuit for the
the uh the false labor that's going to
be available on our github and people
are going to be able to
access that and see how it works and
that's cool
we do not want to be um
a part of distributing a system
a system that can connect to a weapon
that can be controlled remotely that's
fair
right so because we don't want to give
sasha remote access to a paintball gun
we're going to get sasha to come in to
studio e
and she is going to actually shoot you
with a paintball gun
she will be here for that
so is that happening tomorrow no
we're in red zone but it's happening and
it's just on pause
500 paintballs five so many welts
oh my goodness are we gonna do that the
same day as the labor
no no you'll definitely need to use the
defibrillator if that's the case
i know oh my goodness oh that's
nuts some good has come out of
um the whole situation the pandemic if
you will
not the pandemic itself but right with
having um
the need to move into a new studio space
we're in a better studio
we're in a better space and we're in a
better place as far as the company goes
uh to grow and expand and move forward
as a show and and get better and better
and i think you've been finding too that
the content has been getting
um i guess i don't know if more
thorough is the word i would say more
robust
i i wanted to take category 5
to the next level in that when we do an
unboxing
i wanted to get out of the old style of
unboxing where we
open a box take it out of the box
connect it
maybe fire it up if we have time right
but with a one hour show you don't have
a lot of time for that kind of stuff
that's true
so one of the things that we introduced
this year is
production week and production week is a
time when we take
the week off of the live broadcast so
that we can instead
work behind the scenes on doing some of
those extra videos so
that is like filming and unboxing that
we can then
speed up in post so that it only takes
three minutes five minutes out of the
video and then we can actually
demonstrate the hardware right so you
know that's a really really neat way for
us to be able to do a better show for
you
and it changes kind of the paradigm of
how we shoot things and and that has
uh has worked fairly well that's
something that we're still evolving and
come january you're going to see that
our schedule is changing again
production week is going to actually be
every two weeks
so that is uh going to be something that
we're experimenting with and maybe
if it works great then that's what we're
going to do if it doesn't then we're
going to adjust things and
we're still figuring out what it looks
like to produce
the new category 5 tv right it is a lot
of work it's a huge amount of work
how much work jeff two hours do you see
the bags under my eyes
so production week sometimes viewers may
think and maybe we fall into thinking oh
well they're not on the air this week so
they're taking a break
no i am he's not
so when that happens i'm usually here
till about midnight
oh doing video production and in fact
last night i was still here
um producing last week's episode
right and worked until one o'clock in
the morning getting
the videos up just the the one video
mind you um
of the interview that happened last week
yes so you know all these things there's
a lot of
thank you and yeah i was really excited
about that and and thinking of that
interview
that's something that we started working
on in the old studio
i don't know if folks realize like this
is something that we have been working
on
for over a year yep that's true you know
that
yep because we had that server sitting
there and you know that i was working on
migrating and getting everything
switched over and and filming everything
the whole process
but then we had to move so then we had
to kind of start over
and get everything redone and re-shot
and
everything else so pretty amazing yeah
so but
we've we've had some good come out of
this with sasha having to leave um that
left a vacancy in the newsroom and we
had an interesting situation
we were um trying to hire somebody we
did some interviews you
you know this yeah he's nodding yeah i
was there so we did some interviews
uh for for somebody to help out um on on
air and uh we had some great prospects
lined up
and then the pandemic happened it was
like the week after i was like oh
yeah so so we had i mean we
had to put all that on hold yeah and we
couldn't have
any new staff start with us because of
the pandemic and lockdown
but my wife becca who you know as our
news anchor now
um said that she would be willing to to
do it as a
you know temporary stop gap we don't
want to cancel the news we want
to continue on with that so she decided
that she would take a go at it and
temporary stop gap she's phenomenal
she's been doing a great job
and i think she's really found her own
and figured out that hey this is
this is a lot of fun yeah but she's
doing so well that i want to encourage
her as well that
hey like uh do you want the job
so but it's been amazing um and you need
to realize too that having becca as part
of the news has been
um has been what helped us to be able to
carry on with that feature
that's right because you guys are in the
same home so you don't have to worry
about the social distancing
exactly yep so she came in and we would
shoot
every week so we start shooting the news
at four o'clock in the afternoon and
we're live at seven so
uh and that's how it works but because
social distancing was not an issue with
me and becca it made things a lot easier
a lot safer
and uh and legal as well so that's
always a plus
now let's just tell the truth you just
want to spend more time with your wife i
always want to spend more time with my
wife
and and it's funny too because i do all
the editing right now
right um we don't have another
person to do editing at this point
so i'm spending more time with my wife
than she's spending with me
because if i'm doing post-production
like she's on my screen and i'm doing
all the editing for
many hours um and so that's been kind of
a neat experience too yeah because i
kind of feel like i'm spending more time
with my wife which has been cool
yeah that's right so yeah so today i
mean just kind of go back to the
beginning of the episode if you're just
tuning in now today we're kind of just
chilling out reminiscing about the last
year as we look towards uh
you know kind of that holiday break so
if you are in our discord irc
like drop us a message wish somebody
merry christmas
or uh you know give us your favorite
memory something about cat5 from this
year
you know let's keep it uh you know happy
and positive and forget about that covid
thing
and uh you know just what's some good
stuff that happened this year speaking
of
great content on category 5 tv that has
worked out
throughout this situation and yeah it's
all here
i know where you're going with this one
uh robert koenig yes
with the crypto corner phenomenal has
been doing an
exceptional job and he produces this
himself yeah
and sends it up to us and robert i i see
you in our
in our discord and you know on behalf of
category five like we appreciate you so
much absolutely
and you know you you folks at home who
enjoy
robert's feature i encourage you like
hey get on to linuxtxshow.com
give them the views give them the thumbs
up post your comments
really show some love to this guy
because he's been there faithfully
every single week with that content and
keeping us surprised so that we know
when to buy when to sell that's right
much content too
absolutely i've learned so much and i'm
still learning so much
like i got to tap into this guy's
knowledge for sure
yeah i totally agree so that's really
worked out well but please yes give him
the thumbs up
we're we have this interesting situation
where we're we're trying to figure out
our youtube as well
yes and if you subscribe to us on
youtube you see that like we're
constantly evolving the content and
trying to figure out
uh what's the best way to release this
content
and and by doing that we're trying to
figure out
you know it's tough because robert's a
part of linux tech show
right but then all of a sudden we're
doing a review of a raspberry pi
so i think from a viewer's perspective
it's like well is this
is this channel about cryptocurrency or
is it about
single board computers or but we're all
a team working together just trying to
bring you
exceptional um tech centric content
and and robert's a big part of that so
so get on there and don't just pay
attention to the the raspberry pi stuff
give him a thumbs up as well
uh okay bp9 says you guys moved into
a smaller studio how is the new space
working out for you i guess let's let's
ask jeff that question first because
my perspective is going to be very very
different as kind of the manager of the
whole thing
right i i think uh
the two studios can't be compared
they're not apples to apples
because they're different like this is
the first studio we've had
a fireplace well yeah fireplace but this
is the first studio where we've had dual
rooms
like all the other stretchier rooms well
that's true yeah there's three rooms
so our other studio was all one room it
was a big open area
this studio is totally different like
the fact that we're in an
isolated room that's just for filming
you know you've got the the lighting
rigs the boom mic or the boom camera all
the kind of stuff
and it's separate from the server it
changes the dynamic
because the uh the the that background
white noise of the server running is
different
you can have your production studio so
on that end absolutely love it i do feel
like it's a little bit more work for you
going back and forth
yeah like with studio d you could sit
right there
yes and oh let's do a mic check let's do
an audio check oh something's wrong okay
and you could do it while almost still
being on camera here it's like okay hold
on i gotta walk around there
so it's a little bit different it's a
little bit more steps for you which i
think works because you know you can't
your steps the closest thing i get to a
workout that's right
um but personally i i love this studio i
think there's so much potential in it
that will make cat5 a much better more
well-rounded
product it is smaller i do wish that
there was more space just because we've
got
so much stuff packed into here yeah
because gear yeah not just junk like
between like gear
well yeah like lots of cameras lots of
lights goes into making a show like this
it's not just a single dslr
and a computer like there's a ton of
work that goes into this
i mean even move day like we had to rent
a pretty decent sized truck just to move
the studio yeah
so i mean i love the studio i'm excited
about it i love the cool little things
you're doing
that the other studios you couldn't do
like you know you walk in you've got
your 3d printer
yeah and you've got that rig set up
where it's filming it and all that we've
got
the cables run through the wall that
ameri droid hooked us up with that wall
the easy portal yeah yeah the easy
portal like
all these little things that we would
never have done in an open-air studio
where it's like hey how can we evolve
this and make it better
it's just it's it's so cool because
we've had to change the dynamics of what
we do and how we do it
and it just takes it to that different
level i love it yeah and this is the
first time we've pulled down the green
screen but it seems to be working really
well
and so we actually have like a proper
system where we can pull down different
colored drapes and things like that
that's pretty neat
the space for me is brilliant and you
mentioned the sound in here like if
we're quiet
what do you hear jeff nothing it is
absolutely silent because we actually
have a policy here that there are no
moving parts allowed in the studio
so that means no fans no um
computers that have moving parts so
these are the only things that move
everything is solid state so it's
absolutely silent in here
if there's anything that has a moving
part like the 3d printer it's in a
different room
right so and that isolates all the
sounds so sound is
uh completely different here than it was
at the old place
very different um and i love the space i
love having
um the production room separate from
the tv studio yes here because i'm
when i'm on the air for tech tv um
it's a little different because i am
also the producer
yes so there's nobody in the producers
room right now right
and when jeff says i'm getting my steps
it's because i have to actually walk in
there
push a couple buttons and then come back
if we need to change
yeah to to a different shot or something
like that
we do use a stream deck in order to
change camera shots but i mean
like when we're switching between the
news and things we want to be able to
hear it so i go in there and turn on the
speakers
but when uh when the pandemic was at its
peak
here in barrie uh before the churches
were allowed to open
my church actually used this space in
order to do their their church broadcast
and your church used it a couple times
as well yes yeah that's right so
from that perspective in that
environment
they were in here doing their thing i
was not even in the room i was in the
other room
running the the board making sure the
audio was good making sure the stream
was live
and completely separate so socialize
social isolation
if you will was brilliant it was really
really a lot easier for us
uh in this space and it's a wonderful
space oh totally absolutely
i also the one other thing that i love
is
because you have your own separate
production studio
you can have all those monitors
you couldn't at studio d because you'd
be blocking they're
just at the edge of the camera so yeah
like you i think you just had two
monitors and now you've got like
six it's amazing i i walk into the
production studio every time
and i get just a little bit jealous not
gonna lie
bp-9's question going back to that
asking about having a smaller space i
should just say
the space appears smaller because it is
three rooms right so it's
it's almost the same amount of space
that we used to have in one big open
room
okay uh but it's split into three rooms
right so it
the studio space is smaller than our old
studio space because
there's also a production space so do
keep that in mind but the space itself
our floor space
is only i think 10 square feet smaller
it's really minimal
as far as that goes but the interesting
thing
here and this sort of segues into noman
five's question as well which we'll
touch on
um the neat thing here is that we're in
a mall yes
and in a mall if
the company grows and if we say okay we
have outgrown
this small studio space we can actually
there's another unit right on the other
side of this wall
we can rent that unit we can take out
one of the walls put in a door and
expand
because it's that's what they do they
sell square footage
that's right when we signed up for this
place they put up everything and painted
and
got it set up for us like this is set up
for us that's right
so we can we can expand we can grow we
can do that
and nomen5 asks well i hope that you
don't lose
your heat or your air conditioner like
you did at studio d
so studio d our previous space was
an industrial unit who
they worked there during the day and
then we would come in the evening and do
our show
we had our own separate space with
locked doors and it was completely
separate from the business
but there was nobody else in the
building yeah
so if we tripped a breaker which i've
done once here
i uh i turned on the vacuum i plugged it
into the wrong outlet and tripped a
breaker
if we did that at the old studio space
we would have no power
that's right and we would have to wait
till the next morning when someone came
in in order to get power back
we did have problems with heat and we
did have problems with ac
because again it's a unit within
a giant building and if somebody was
cold that day and cranked the heat
in their unit they didn't realize that
now our unit was a sauna
yeah and they would go home and the heat
the
the big blowers in the ceiling were just
pumping out heat
all night long yeah they were loud there
was that too
but this was the problem right we didn't
have our own thermostat there was
nothing like that
and we don't hear either but there it's
climate controlled yep
i mentioned i tripped the breaker when i
tripped the breaker
i walked to the mall office and i said
hi i tripped a breaker and they said oh
no problem we'll be right there
they came they went into the electrical
room uh which is not in our unit
and flipped the breaker back for us
which is awesome done problem solved
if the heat ever stopped working if the
ac ever stopped working here
it's a big professionally managed
building and
i am fully confident that they will
not allow it to
be like if the climate control was down
it's down for everyone
so it just wouldn't happen here it can't
happen
it's true yeah exactly professionally
managed space
what a difference that makes yeah that's
nice this is category 5 tv we're
wrapping up the year
2020. we're saying farewell to the old
and in with the new
i'm looking forward to the new yes hello
to our discord
uh hello to our irc please jump in
say hello if you've got questions for
jeff or i uh or jeff or me
i should say i always go back to when
eric was a co-host he always corrected
me on that one
now now i get it right most times eric
was the worst for that
it's always correct it's so and so and i
in school that's how i learned it it was
always and i
but no it's not always that way when do
you use me
um it depends on the context and and how
you would say it if it was just you
so really yeah huh
so if i would say i am sitting here then
it's jeff and i
versus like hand that to me so hand that
to jeff and me
yes exactly good example yeah yeah well
you learn something new
every christmas episode wow no tech here
today folks
well speaking of tech we do have our
phones out we're not being anti-social
uh we're actually watching talking to
all of our wonderful fans and viewers
and the community
so if you are not part of our discord
you need to get involved so go to cap
absolutely
all the information's there uh the great
thing about
discord i mean i love the irc
but the irc is one channel with discord
what i love
is that there are so many channels like
i look down there's got to be
30 channels within this discord server
that's always hopping there's always
something new popping up you've got the
general chat
that just never seems to end because
we've got viewers from all over the
globe
but if you've got a tech issue you can
post questions all week long if you
if you've got recipes we've got food
channels in there if you want to post
pictures of bacon
that's right there's a channel there's a
channel dedicated to that
i love bacon and for the vegans there is
a channel for you too
that's right yeah i may or may not throw
meat pictures in there just because
oh jeff you didn't i i think i did once
oh jeff
i i banned i love my meat what can i say
there's a reason i like the bacon
channel oh dear
but yeah even behind the scenes stuff
like we've got i mean when the show's
not happening there's
so much going on so you can get in there
yeah we post pictures all the time yeah
absolutely
but uh yeah so if you're in the discord
by all means say hi
throw out a christmas greeting let us
know kind of what your
highlights have been for 2020 so uh
is there any sneak peeks or sneak
like uh teasers on what's coming in 2021
what is coming in 2021 now yes the i
mean
you want teasers i want teasers
well i mentioned that part of the idea
behind
production week is to be able to do
proper unboxings proper testing um
and and sometimes that means weeks of
testing sometimes that means
having a product here set up and we've
been using it like the 3d printer is a
perfect example yes well how did we
review that
well the unboxing took a long time
because it had to be assembled so
we put that all together for you and
then i learned how to use the 3d printer
at least
at a rudimentary rudimentary yeah no now
i just
it's a constant production run yeah it's
amazing um
so with the 3d printer like so
production week makes it so that we can
do
much bigger features so we're doing
things like
we have uh an open source nas unit
that's single board computer powered
and i've wanted to do this for some time
you remember i actually started a series
where i was going
to make one from an odroid xu4
and that's still coming as well but
that's a perfect example of
a feature that we really wanted to do
but because we were limited to just one
hour per show
and we were shooting everything live no
b-roll
no like pre-production or anything like
that it made it impossible for us to get
through those types of series
so now we've already shot the unboxing
and assembly of this
open source nas unit we've done some
testing i have a couple more weeks that
i'm going to be testing it and
setting it up and installing software
and putting it through all the paces and
then we're going to be demonstrating
that
here on the show which is going to be
amazing because you're going to get all
of the benefit of
many many weeks even so much as probably
about a month and a half worth of
testing
all compiled into one single feature so
that's exciting looking at the 3d
printer
one of the things that folks have been
really intrigued by
are some of these what i call a hyper
lapse it's not quite a time lapse a time
lapse i picture like
stick figures moving back and forth but
most most people
call it a time lapse but it's a hyper
lapse which is
um where you see the thing growing out
of the 3d printer and it just
grows you showed that two weeks ago i
think on the show we use it all the time
ever since i got the 3d printer and
created it was when you showed the uh
the
christmas ornament that you put things
in bo's christmas ornament
at yeah if you haven't seen that
linuxtechshow.com click onto the
the uh uh there's a playlist for 3d
printing hyperlapses
that was cool but also uh even in the
interview with
uh with mark last week that's right i 3d
printed some parts for the server
in order to allow those drives to
connect directly to the backplane
and you saw the the pieces just kind of
growing out of the build plate
and so we're going to be demonstrating
how i do that
which is so amazing and again going back
to i i don't want to just show you i
want you to be able to do it yourself so
we're releasing all of the source code
the designs we're creating videos to
show you how to do it yourself
because what i did is i 3d printed and
soldered a switch that connects to my 3d
printer
and then wrote a perl no pardon me a
python application
that in injects code into my g-code
that tells the extruder that in between
each layer
as soon as you finish printing a layer i
want you to go push that button
and so this is all programmatic and and
so this whole thing is open source and
available to our viewers
and uh and that's something that i'm
looking forward to doing as well so
we're gonna be demonstrating how to
actually do those hyperlapse videos
which is just a lot of fun that's
exciting it's a lot of fun and i can't
wait to see what our viewers come up
with
as well so cool i love the evolution of
the show in the fact that
you know you go back to the beginning of
cat 5
uh what 14 years ago and like you had
that
um fundraising software that you made
express the sharathon express you know
and it's like that was the big
thing yeah and and then uh when i came
on
what five six years ago like 3d printing
was still coming around but at that time
it was all about drones
yep and like as the show evolves and as
tech changes it also
kind of drives the dynamics of the show
and then we had this
push of cryptocurrency and and now we're
like maker projects and i love that i
love how the show keeps evolving
with tech as it evolves and it's like
five years from now
when this is like a full-blown thing and
like we're we're
filming 180 hours a day what is the tech
that we're going to be covering are we
going to be covering
yeah you know nano oh yes
everything everything jeff it's going to
be
that is you know it's the fun thing
about working at a place like category 5
is that
there is always a an assortment of
content available
it's really just what do we have time to
produce yes and that's as the company
grows that's where we want to be we want
to be able to produce more and more ex
excellent content and so you know your
support of category 5
throughout this year and moving forward
through patreon is just a way that
um you're helping us to grow helping us
to stay strong and helping us to get
better and better uh nolman5 is
looking at our discussion about 3d
printing and saying he's actually
3d printing a bunch of stuff for
stocking stuffers right now it's a great
idea i've been doing the same thing
yep and it's it is really cool i'm at
the point now where i'm designing
my own stocking stuffers yeah
you've seen some of it unfortunately i
can't show you yet this is one of the
things
i can't show you because my kids might
see it that's right
but there is some really cool stuff
coming off the printer
um and i've been saving money on things
that i would normally have to buy
yep but uh and some things you can't
even buy because they don't exist that's
right
which is even cooler it's funny
i every week i say to jen i'm like i
want a 3d printer
i have no legitimate use for it but i
and every week i come home and i'm like
robbie did this robbie made that i'm
like this is so cool she's like robbie
has a use for that
i'm like but i could yeah but some of
these some of these stocking stuffers
and and i do save money too like i'll
just say um one of the things that i 3d
printed for one of my children
uh was 40 on amazon right and it cost me
60 cents to make myself
well look at the the rack for the
servers uh or for the
hardware example yeah like i mean that
last week you saved yourself
half the price of the 3d printer oh only
yeah like that's funny and i needed them
i needed them
and now it's like if someone else wants
them i know hey i can print you some of
those yep
yep so ten dollars each the fact that
you know like why not
exactly but the fact that luke uh our
middle child is getting into soldering
and all that
and he wants to get into maker projects
it's like
i could totally pair soldering with a
with a 3d printer and he could do some
really cool
stuff so yeah yeah absolutely i'm making
cases for my single board computers
yep and starting to do some really cool
designs
nems linux is a tool that i've written
that
monitors your network and gives you the
state information so if
a if a hard drive is failing it will
warn you
um so the case is actually kind of neat
it has rgb leds in it
okay and the case will light up based on
the state of your network so if
something is wrong
the light will turn red very cool and
that's all part of the case that i
designed
that's it
um ameridroid wants to remind you that
you can let your wife know that the 3d
printer is not for you
it's for the it's the education of the
children you know what ameri droid you
are absolutely correct
yes my kids love it and even so much as
just printing a dalek
oh yeah you know just to have that
figurine and it's as good as something
that you get in the store
yep and it costs 10 cents to print well
like okay so going back to luca because
he's
he's our creative kid yeah every time we
buy a game like it could be
clue it could be monopoly it could be
settlers of catan whatever
he like we're done and he's like oh i'm
kind of bored with that game i'm like oh
okay he's like can i make a game with
that
like what do you mean make a game and
he'll literally take an existing game
come up with a whole new set of rules
and and develop his own game using the
board and the pieces
and i've said to jen imagine if he could
3d print his own pieces that's what i've
said again many times i'm like what if
luke could make his own game like yeah
he makes his own comment
this kid's 12 11 12.
somewhere around there uh but like he he
makes
he's asking he makes his own comic books
he solders he wants to get into
programming 3d printing he comes up with
games i'm like
you know what you just keep coming up
with stuff because later in life when
i'm retired at 50 because you're paying
for everything because you're a genius
then it'll all pay off that's it too is
you want to encourage
creativity yeah and i'm always looking
for
i guess you'd say i'm looking for ways
to encourage that creativity in my kids
and you know i've done the the raspberry
pi's and they
assemble it and then they don't know
what to do with it right and
then i try to find projects it's like
okay well now you can program
stuff and it's like well but i can
program on the computer and it's faster
and so it's like okay well i tried with
that so but the 3d printer is something
that yeah i'm finding that
the kids really do enjoy it they're
they're coming up with some neat ideas
it's here at the studio so they you know
they have to now come in to the studio
in order to 3d print something right
but you can get one at home or someone
in the garage or whatever else
yeah yeah that's cool i'm trying to
watch the discord here as well folks
hey if you got a memory or something
some question for us uh
anything about category 5 tv over the
past year we'd love to hear from you
absolutely so what's on your christmas
list
my christmas list actually consists of a
lot of accessories for the 3d printer
because i have to keep myself creative
too absolutely
and so i i find that it's it's a hobby
for me that it's
it's become a hobby for me to be able to
tinker and play around
and i'm at that point now where i am
doing my own designs and so it's like
i'd really like a nice metallic filament
and you know these kinds of things i'd
like to
be able to do more with the 3d printer i
like that you're getting into the
dual color printing i am programming
that is so neat to watch
well the the ender 3v2 has only a single
extruder
so that means that you can only have one
color filament coming out of the
extruder
at any one time but you can change the
filament
mid print so i tried that that was my
first step so i printed
an ornament just a plain red ornament
and then i printed on top of that
so i in in cura i then took text
and turned it into a 3d print and i
elevated it
five layers which was the height of the
ornament and actually printed directly
onto
the ornament with white text right so
i've got a red ornament with white text
on it and it worked perfectly yeah it
looked great yeah so then i took it one
step further
and i took my text and i turned it into
a hole they call it so basically it's an
inverse of
something that you would print it it is
anti-print right so i took
the thing that i was printing and i
pushed the text
down into it okay so that it would
create a hole
in the first print so then when i
printed the red thing there's a hole
and then i switched the filament and i
put it inside of the hole
so i put my 3d printer inside the hole
so then i printed the white
into the hole and so it's
perfectly flush that's how you did it
yeah very cool but but it looks like a
multi-color print yeah it does
really i'm just changing the filament
and programming the g-code in such a way
that it that it actually prints in the
right spot
that's so cool make sure you line things
up just perfectly kids i love that
so good uh so bp9 wants to know about
learning
uh lua on mind test for
for luke uh might be fun lua is a
programming language
oh okay and mine test is a minecraft
like
yes yeah um mango fox used to do some
mind test stuff
yep yep yeah so i do remember that we
had a program uh
here on category five the pixel shadow
yes which she did when she was younger
yeah
and uh mind test is a really
really great version like a open source
version of
what you would say is like a clone of
minecraft it's not really a clone of
minecraft
they come from the same base but um but
they're very very similar
yeah but with lua you could be
programming your own modules for it
creating very very customized
um worlds right okay yeah that's cool
i'll have to take a look at that i know
luke plays mind test sometimes oh yeah
yeah
we should do like a mind test lan party
oh my gosh
parties we need to do oh yes yeah so are
you in
all right folks well it has been
fantastic
having you here jeff what is what is on
the horizon
for you as far as like what do you look
forward to with category five
so we're coming up on 2021 where we know
that it's going to be better than 2020.
what's on the right honestly for me i
want to expand
my knowledge base to the point where
it's not on all on your shoulders that's
my i
like the way this is going yeah uh like
i watch you do the features and i mean i
i love being here i love being co-host i
love just being
a mouthpiece that can add banter but i
don't have a lot of time in
my life to learn these things because my
job doesn't
go into the realm of tech that often i
mean it's starting to now but
i want to be able to know some things
where it's like hey
robbie i can do the feature this week
and we're like hey this is great i'm
going to sit in the production studio
and produce things
that's what i'm hoping to do uh it's
just it's a matter of time that's cool
so yeah henry bailey brown really hit on
that yes
when he brought in his feature which was
um
when he 3d scans using his drone so he
shot all that and brought it into the
studio
ready to go and then we sat down and and
kind of added the bumpers on either end
and talked about what it was we were
seeing
right but that was all something that he
brought in and that that's really really
cool so yeah that's why i'm working on
uh the circuit boards with luke
yeah so that we you know we can go down
that road get you some b-roll and then
we could
just build this circuit board it's uh
you know so it's things like that where
yeah that's what i would like i'd love
to see that stuff too
and and i looked up when you were
talking about creating your own pcbs
and you mentioned using a laser printer
and so i'm like what are you talking
about
so i actually looked into this and it's
a way to like use the ink from a laser
printer to actually
like dissolve parts of the pcb yeah
so that it actually creates yeah the
circuit
it's so neat how does that even work i
don't know and
but magic well yeah and that's the thing
like i didn't what seems like magic i
didn't want to look into the chemistry
of it because i'm like i just don't want
to like
this is cool enough but advanced enough
as it is yeah but when you print the
design on the paper and then
and it has to be laser it can't be color
and then when you put it on the board
and then there's the chemicals that you
use that are just the chemicals you can
get at the store interacts with the ink
yeah and then it creates the actual so
conduit that the
electrical signal passes on and then
it's just a matter of drilling the holes
and then you put your various components
in and solder them and so
so neat it's a way to make circuit
boards at home
without having the professional circuit
board printers because
you can just design it on i think what i
think it's kcad is the program i've got
okay um where you can design your
circuit board and
you know each of the you know the little
modules and components that go in it
that you solder it's like okay well this
resistor's here
and this is going to be there yeah and
then you just print it off on paper and
do it and so
it's it's pretty pretty neat it's
impressive and
blew my mind when i came across it i
think the search term in
in your search engine is going to be
pcb laser printer
method yeah and if you do a search for
that
your mind might be blown too has anyone
in our community ever
done that before i'd be interested to
know and i think jeff would probably be
interested too yeah as well we'd love to
see pictures
yeah so yeah that's for me that's what i
would love to do for cat5 it's just a
matter of the time to do it
so but i'm slowly learning cool you know
community joining us in our discord on
irc um
real quick and and you don't have much
time is there something that you're
looking forward to
with 2021 and how category 5 is a part
of
your life during that time i think for
me it's
it's going to be really cool to see how
the show
evolves post pandemic yeah because
right now we've been working so hard to
pull everything off amidst the constant
threat of lockdown the
occasional lockdown right now red zone
and not being able to have people into
our studio
including um the lighting installers
you know the people that we're supposed
to be installing our new led lighting
panels
have had to cancel so you know
i'm looking forward to seeing what the
show
can do in 2021 when these types of
things are not
a consideration or at least not uh
not holding us back yeah in a way
so that's that's something i'm really
looking forward to
i love the way that you know the
community is going and
the way everybody supports us it's so
great to have uh you know you guys are a
part of this
yep soul boo saying he would love to see
sasha
do something on the show even if it's a
little bit pre-recorded and i mean
that's totally the plan i mean as robbie
mentioned earlier it's just a matter of
her schedule and getting her available
and finding times at work and i mean i
pre-recorded probably would make it
easier but uh you know with her
being in the iceberg capital of canada
it's uh it's a matter of
with poor internet well yeah it's a
matter of internet it's going to be
tough
so we're going to figure it out but uh
yeah
it's uh it's good it's going to be good
norman 5 would like to actually come and
visit us post pandemic
and be in the studio and i think that
would be really great too we've never
obviously we've not been able to have
any guests
here physically in the studio yet that's
right and that's going to be really
really cool
this space i mean um boleknowski
and and bill marshall have been to
our studio space some of our community
have been to our studio space in studio
d
to to be a part of the show we've had
others as well
and um that place was
you know we made the most of it we made
a great space for what it was but those
who were there
know that it was just a big open room
with horrible floors and an industrial
bathroom
yes it was some heat that you couldn't
turn off
yeah but now it's like okay i'm going to
be proud to have you come and join us
here so i hope that those who have
already been up to join us
yeah bo from ameridroid wants to come
and see us as well i'd love to he's got
to bring up the ameribus
can you imagine the gas i don't care i
want to see the mirror bus
yeah um we'd love to we'd love to
have you come to the studio and join us
um i'm thinking
in my head uh one of the things i do
want to do in the new year when
it's possible is to host um
uh tours oh that's just fun a tour to
have people in
right now i've considered like do we do
it during this time and
everybody just wears a mask and we allow
two people in at a time and
have to redundantly explain everything
over and over and over again for a day
i thought maybe that would work but i
think maybe if we just wait things out
and then
come in and and have like an open house
which is what we had originally planned
when we first started thinking about
moving we we had october
something was our open house that had to
get cancelled
yeah um so that would be uh that would
be really cool and then
i thought about shooting a 360 video for
those of you who can't travel to
canada oh that'd be fun um so that you
could have a virtual tour as well
so if that's something that you would
like a 360 video that will cost us some
money
um so become a patron yeah it's been a
long time since we've done a 360.
yes the last one was uh
oh man episode four uh
yeah i don't know that's when we had all
the past co-hosts and yeah
it was that was fun yeah but a huge
amount of production
oh my goodness yeah so much so you know
we really need to have
we'd need to step up our equipment a
little bit as far as the 360 video goes
yep yep is there okay so i know we've
got to shut it down because we're kind
of
at the point but is there anything we
haven't
done with the show that's always been on
your dream list that you'd love to do
with cat5
that's a big question to spring on me
jeff i don't think so
i'm sure there are as soon as we sign
off the air i'll think of something and
i'll post it in our behind the scenes or
something
there's one thing i've always wanted to
do with cat five and i
don't know if we'll be able to do it
just because we're
not levitating using ions
i would love for us to be able to get on
this
on studio behind the scenes
yes for star trek discovery that would
be neat it's filmed an hour away from us
yeah that's what i want so if any of
y'all watching
or oh the orville that would be fun do
it oh yeah
let's go down to california bo you want
to put us up for a week
yeah let's do that see that would be
neat
yeah like i would love to see cat5 go
like
and and hang out behind studios with
that kind of stuff could we ever do that
yeah
so you ask it's totally doable well it's
not
what because and you say like
do you dream robbie yeah i dream but
category 5 is a part-time gig for me
yes part-time i work my butt off
that's a lot of work but to do something
like traveling and things like that that
means like this would have to be a
full-time job
you know i will travel on your behalf oh
thanks jeff you know
you know what i would really like to
have this as a full-time job
this is a great place to work yeah so
can we just like work toward that
and maybe robbie be able to do some
traveling oh yeah
yeah but i've always wanted to see cat5
do that because then that would be neat
yeah that's just
the closest we ever came was to send uh
henry bailey brown
down to um he went to
i think it was in toronto for the vrto
yeah that's right virtual reality
toronto yeah that's right
so uh he went down there and again shot
b-roll put it all together for us that
was pretty cool that would be soft
yeah yeah so i'll hook you up with
tickets to the next one
if things like that happen anymore no
not right now
like we were looking at ces well yeah
what are we gonna do with ces this year
exactly yeah we can go virtually there
yeah yeah all right
oh well sky is the limit yeah
that's good all right folks well it's
been great having you here and
and i'm not just saying that to the chat
but those of you who are watching
as well thank you for a wonderful year
it's been a roller coaster ride for all
of us
here at the studio it's there have been
good weeks and bad weeks and it's been a
real roller coaster of like not really
knowing
what is going on sometimes but
we're here we're faithfully putting
together shows and we're going to
continue doing so
really excited about what's to come in
january so
watch our website category5.tv scroll
down on the homepage you'll see a google
calendar embedded there
that's going to give you the up-to-date
calendar as far as what our production
schedule looks like
so we are going to be off for christmas
break over the next couple of weeks
so jeff's got time off i actually will
have time off
so it's not production week there will
be
family time and and actually taking a
break um
i didn't really get the vacation that i
normally would take this year
yeah um because what do you do for
vacation
so i but i was looking at my vacation
days that are left over it's
we're here at the end of the year all my
vacation days have stored up because i
didn't use them so
so i'm going to take some time off at
christmas and just take a break with you
deserve it with my immediate family
because we're in red zone that's right
we can't visit our parents or anything
so
yeah so it's you know there's there's
good and bad but um
so we will be back in january second
week of january
and uh really looking forward to having
you here first week of january is
production week that's right so we'll be
here as well but
it just won't be on the air if you're a
kickstarter supporter
or a patron just know that over the next
couple of weeks
even though we will be off the air you
will be receiving content this is
something i should really quickly touch
on
because i want our kickstarter
supporters and patrons to know
that even though the vlog has fallen
behind
i'm going to explain that a little bit
there are some vlogs coming over the
next couple of weeks
awesome with the way the production has
been going we have one production rig
right and so there have been two
attempts to produce a vlog
first one was the led lighting install
which they didn't show up and canceled
so you know i produced the first part of
the vlog and then it's like oh
it's it's not happening so and the
second one
um got everything together and the
production rig is in use
producing the um the um interview that
you saw
last week yeah so so with having one
production rig it's
it's posing a problem where i can't do
additional content because
that rig is constantly putting out video
or editing video
any moment that i have i'm not looking
for extra things to do
right and so i'm having that little bit
of difficulty where i
and i don't have another editor who can
put these together for me it has to be
me right now
so there's just not enough time in the
week so um
so during this downtime it gives me an
opportunity to vlog
i'm going to be coming on and talking
with you having some nice
conversations about what's been going on
i'm going to show you some of the things
that you haven't seen yet
but you have to be a kickstarter
supporter or a patron in order to
to see those bits of content so looking
forward to
sharing those with you over the next few
weeks all right folks
well have a wonderful christmas a happy
new year 2021 is going to be better than
2020 i promise absolutely
and uh hopefully it doesn't take long
before things shift in the right
direction and we have
you know see some light at the end of
this thing so but thank you for
supporting us and being a part of this
community
throughout the course of 2020 it's been
up and down
but you've always seen us through so
thank you yeah take care everybody take
care jeff
you too see you christmas bye
you