[Music]
welcome to the category 5 community
coffee break everybody
it's the 19th of july 2020. i'm robbie i
see seoul boo
and peter joining us as well so far
hello i if i seem to be looking
up i might do that by accident because
our contractor has been here spent one
morning so far
and so now the tv the tv is mounted on
the wall instead of on the floor so i'm
actually
kind of looking up a little bit so we've
got
uh i don't know maybe 10 or 12 foot
ceilings here and it's
down a few feet from the ceiling so
cameras here
tv's there just so you know
so lots of exciting things happening
around here though too guys like
so with the studio of course we've been
working on
like waiting and waiting for the
contractor to be able to get in
so check this out check this out
how do you like that yeah nice
gonna be fantastic what a difference so
that frees
up all the floor space that our drapes
were taking up which was about four feet
out from the wall
and i can have multiple drapes on the
system
at a time and just choose which one i
want to come down i agree
and now you can have a different
background using the green screen
in the show or in the coffee breaks or
yeah
exactly so and i thought um so we've got
the green screen already
i've got a black screen as well that we
haven't used
um and then you know maybe a white
screen so that we've got those three
kind of infinity
infinity screens hi bp9
so we've got bp9 joining us as well hey
buddy yeah
maybe he doesn't hear us
yeah so peter you were saying you got a
new work bench do you want to show us
your your new work space here
oh okay he's got to find us specs folks
so this is this is the work area for our
resident
guru of electronics and
power supplies yeah and everything else
yeah and everything else
oh so is this like a garage
yeah yeah oh nice okay good
and turn it into a workshop
and
get the press soldering station yeah
cool that's uh that's an app before that
uh
yeah you probably could can you say
i'm proud of me that i recognized as
soon as you pointed the camera at it
that that's a tube amp
yeah yeah you did that yet and uh it's
not written
at the moment uh and uh i've got a few
uh
i need to work sort of things like that
that's awesome
[Music]
so i can um plug more things into the
plug in multiple drills and power supply
yeah right
oh cool and everything i've told you on
that everything else
very good it was just a normal um
that's that horrible stuff uh they make
speakers off of
calling the neighborhood again
um you know stuff that makes speaking
like a neoprene or something oh
like a like a particle board or
something yeah
yeah yeah it was not good even though
really good because uh
like a punch in here but i'm not careful
oh yeah okay
so we've got i think play rain metroid
uh uh playing very little for that's the
second hand
oh yeah hey that works yeah it's it's
harder to drill into the concrete block
so you may as well put that up and then
you've got something you can screw into
eh
we we actually uh uh have actually
screwed into the
what we got is uh um
blocks and then uh and then we
put the balls on top then we screwed in
with um
wall plugs and and then yeah
i guess that that can make it more solid
too like i know when
uh when the contractor was putting
everything up here he had
like quarter inch thick boards that he's
mounted on the wall
first and then he's mounted our things
onto that so that it's not putting too
much of a load on this
the single stud it's kind of spread out
yeah these things you'd think and they
were
done at the moment i'm looking for
another picture
to go underneath oh yeah that's great
man
yeah yeah that's great i i i'd love to
have
a space like that
it was brilliant yeah yeah i'd love to
have a space like that but my garage is
like
it's my storage room like we don't we
don't have a lot of storage at our house
we don't have
a crawl space or anything like that so
it's like that's where
stuff gets stored so but but i have that
dream of
having workbenches all around in a clean
area in the middle where i can
oh dude
that's a real soldier
plumbing that's for doing plumbing not
not the electronic stuff
no no that would
yeah it's got level it got quite warm as
well
it is hot
i did that once um uh
i was there soldiering something and
then um
for some reason uh i think i must have
had a brain fart because
i was i was up um i needed to support
the soldiering for some reason yeah and
without thinking
i was supporting it with my thumb oh oh
oh yes
okay so here's i had that mark on my
thumb for a million yeah
i think i thought that robbie oh wow
a tesla coil
a homemade phaser
circuit oh yeah so
you think you know wouldn't touch it
i'll tell you my story is that i would
never i would never be so dumb as to
touch
the hot tip of a soldering iron but what
i did
is like you store it you know how you've
got your helping hands with the little
like wire coil thing that you stick the
soldering iron in
so i have it sitting in there running at
400 degrees
whatever it is and super super hot and i
take out the soldering iron and i'm
doing my soldering
and then i grab the coil to move the
helping hands and i go
because my iron had been sitting in that
so it's like yep
live and learn so i had like i had rings
on my finger for about two weeks
i let go pretty quick i'll tell you that
much yeah
yeah you don't hold on to those things
for too long
yeah sober you've been up to anything
these days getting a lot of drumming in
yeah a little and they're playing some
guitar and yeah
i mentioned my garage my drums are kind
of tucked in the garage right now
because i don't have a spot for them
even now that we're in the new studio
space i just don't have a spot for them
so yeah the only reason that i have the
drums in my living room is that
i live alone so i have this is my drum
kit
and then i have the uh living room uh
the the dinner table
yeah that works yeah
i got i i i obviously have the three
kids and the wife at home but
it really comes down to if i tried to
set up the drum kit in the living room
my wife would not have that
not even for a moment
[Laughter]
hi bp9 cannot imagine why yeah
i'll have to ask her why
you've been vp9 all right thank you how
about you
very good been a busy week my friend
very very busy by the way thank you for
uh fixing the uh
the website i appreciate that yeah i'm
working on it uh and so but it wasn't
it's fixed it's working now great um
solebu was mentioning though that also
the
discord irc bridge is down so yeah
after the coffee break i'm going to do a
quick reboot on the server
which i hate to do because that takes
everything offline for about five
minutes
one of these days peter's going to learn
about that mute switch and he's gonna
yeah no he's not
no he's not i found me
by the way i'm glad you did we were
along for the ride
so uh so i talked a little bit about
what i was up to last week and i've been
doing some more work on that
there is a um there's a
a package i don't know if anyone's heard
of it but keeping track of to do is
called task warrior
never heard of and okay i find it
i find it to be very helpful for keeping
track of on my to-do list
um one of the things i really like about
it
is that it lets you sync to a task
warrior server on another machine
so all of my machines my android my
phone
my tablet my laptop the pine book pro
they can all you know deal with the same
task list
and sync to the server periodically oh
well
um last week when when i talked it was
you know i was trying to find ways
i'm building another application that
works in a similar way
and i was trying to figure out what is
the best way to keep the data in sync
because i don't want to have separate
sets of data on each device i don't want
the laptop to have
one set of data the android phone to
have another set of data
the main machine to have another set of
data that won't work i really
need them to sync up and last week i
talked about well
one of my options is to have
the device or have an always
on connection to the server all the time
well great a great idea but not so smart
especially if you're not at the house or
or not in range of the network or
whatever the case may be
so i'm working right now on um
on that on implementing the same
protocol that task warrior does
and that's a batch that's that's a batch
process the idea is that
you collect all your data in a local
file on your local device then whenever
you get ready to sync you send that data
to the server
then it plays it back along with all the
other updates that everybody else gave
and then you build your database with
that uh
you end up having a set of server
requests
you store and that's how you build let's
take you keep your database in sync
so i would imagine the deduplication
occurs on the server
to make sure that it's not adding
duplicate data
and then sends out the consolidated
information
yeah yeah that's if you do an ad of an
item that is already there
um yeah the impact really is do you want
to just add it or replace it and
as a designer i could say well i could
just replace it
with the with the old palm pilot um
applications what would happen is you
would get two items
in your database yes the hot sync
protocol
you actually ended up with two duplicate
items that you'd have to delete one of
them
so that would be another way to go so
also if you go to delete an item that's
already gone
how do you treat that do you treat that
as an error or do you
uh or do you just uh uh treat it like oh
well it's already gone i don't have to
worry about it just acknowledge it and
be like all right done
yeah yeah these are these are the
questions that i'm
designing through right now that's
awesome very quick
trying to make decisions about what's
the most intelligent yeah
and maybe make it configurable or
something i don't know i haven't
haven't decided that yet this is a
one-off thing i'm not going to sell it
so yeah i just checked uh
noticed that i knew i heard the uh about
this before um is a free software
project and it's in all the major
distributions
is a what software project task warrior
yeah i know but but what was it you said
selbu about
uh task warrior you said
that's one of the reasons i like it you
don't have to have x running or anything
to make it work it's just
it's all it's all command line based
yeah and that means
that that makes it makes it so that if
you're out and about and
you don't have it on a system that you
yourself
the video you can
you can always build a ui on top of it
if you want to
but you don't have to right it's always
nice to have that common denominator
that command line at the
at the at the you know at the least
um uh you know as your base
requirement oh someone turned on their
speaker
that's me sorry oh one sec i wanted to
show you guys something
but i gotta figure out how to mute this
there there ah that's better
okay now how do i turn on my camera
there you go oh i bet you're gonna show
us the the new um
the new studio yeah some of the stuff
here we go
okay there can you see what i'm looking
at now
no we're just we could just oh wait i'll
have to open i have to
look at the other screen so this is this
is my view
right so so it's coming together like
this is
obviously still a mess right here
because i haven't done the cabling or
anything but
um they've got the tv up on the wall
we've got the
rack uh the the rail system for the
drapes
that's what it looks like so there's a
like a pulley over here
to bring the drapes down or put them up
um and there's room
i'm going to put a black drape and
possibly a white one
so then we can just change the
background we're going to use a i
thought you're going to use a brick
backdrop or something
uh i probably will for nelson's sake
okay
he's nelson nelson's a guy who hates the
bricks
a viewer you've seen him on the show
nelson hudas
there you go those are our up lights
very very pleased with those
nice so they look really nice yeah but
they don't really provide any ambient
light do they they just
provide accent right okay that's it yeah
it's about it's about giving a nice
nice kind of look to the set for for
dirt
cheap so yeah i think it adds a lot um
yeah those uh and the pulleys reminds me
of a video i saw yesterday
give me a high five for the screen
um it is a norwegian uh
tv show uh it's uh similar to the uh
american
cops on only a local for
norway um the police chief in one of the
counties uh um was
featuring in one in one of the shows he
was going to join
uh one of their patrols because he likes
to uh
he likes to periodically
join uh his staff to see
what they are doing in their daily life
and he started by
joining one of his colleagues in her
office and
sitting down on the chair and
immediately as he
sat down and in the back the uh
elected there was elected curtains on
the window
and they closed just as he sat down and
the the switch for those turns
it was right behind the uh armrest
and so he bumped it by accident yeah
and they lost them because
i figure you could use like a motion
sensor like a pir
or something and as soon as you trip it
it like closes the blinds for you
that would be neat i i have a pir that i
was thinking about
connecting to an arduino uh maybe like a
digispark
and with the pir send a keystroke
to usb which would be like a keyboard
keystroke which would trigger a camera
shot
do you guys remember me talking about
this at any point so
if i put a camera say in the producer's
room
i could set up a pir sensor that as soon
as i walk in that room
it would turn on that camera so that if
if i was doing a presentation
and i didn't have somebody to do camera
switching for me it would automatically
switch based on the pir
i have done something similar with uh
with cameras but they
use motion detection not sure what par
is is that uh infrared passive infrared
yeah like
like motion sensor yeah what i've done
with any regular webcam in a
fairly basic project uh package on
ubuntu is it will it will
sense any kind of change in pixels on
the camera
and only then will it fire up a shot so
it's not a time lapse
it doesn't do it every time yeah you
know at a regular time but what it will
do is
whenever um any motions detected
based on pixels changing on the uh
on the um on the camera then it it
preserves your shot so the difference
the difference with pixel versus pir is
pir is actually sensing the heat
so if a human walks in the room it will
set it off
but not an insect or a shift in the
lighting
those kinds of things smoking what about
if we were smoking
well if someone was smoking in our
studio i'd tell them to get out
[Laughter]
the cigarette sure would yeah the smoke
probably would as well because
uh the the the heat uh the moisture
droplets which we've all learned about
we've got our masks right
yeah if you ever wonder if mass make a
difference just watch people at a
smoking section
tested motion cameras as a security
feature
about if you can fool them in some way
um and they test that fulfilling their
room completely with smoke
it had no effect yeah but um holding up
a curtain and then walking
slowly past the camera that worked
because it sealed that right
the heat couldn't get so that that drape
would have to be thick enough
that it would it would block the heat
because infrared is detected
really all it would have to do is stop
movement of air robbie because uh
because this isn't that well infrared
but you are still generating a certain
amount of heat so that sheet if it was
cold would work
but i would think if it was too thin it
would still allow some of that heat to
be visible to an infrared sensor
i would expect i don't know because it's
not it's not
visibility it's heat yeah yeah
yep and they also tested the
fingerprint sensors um in order to open
uh
locks in secure areas
um every lock they tried and all you had
to do was
getting a fingerprint or someone and
scan a fingerprint and then printing it
out and
holding that yeah i heard about that um
3d printers um printing to like uh
like a rubber filament or something like
a yeah
they could actually they could make
gloves that would work with
the thumb print yeah they tried that but
they
couldn't make them uh reliable the most
reliable
method was to do to print it on a piece
of paper
really so it was optical not touch
that's surprising that doesn't surprise
me at all you just push the finger out
over a glass pane then effectively take
a photo of it
but on my phone is it is it optical or
is it an actual touch sensor
like that is reading the actual
fingerprint i don't feel like it's
optical like it's
completely opaque
do you think it does wow
but you look at a laptop maybe a laptop
is a better example where the laptop has
a
finger sensor and it's just a strip of
metal
yeah that can't be optical is it no no
no not obviously so there must be
various technologies to be able to read
the fingerprint
i i feel like it's like those touch
lamps that you touch them
and the light turns on religious
capacities that's all like right right
but combine that with some form of a
sensor that reads the
so it only triggers it when you touch it
i don't know i'd have to look into how
those work
yeah i'm not sure yeah another
technology they wanted to to test was uh
uh rfa or
id tags yes how hackable they were
and they contacted a firm who
specializes in those tags and they had
scheduled a meeting with
someone uh adam savage told us at uh
one of the conventions he had he
attended um
in one of the last years of admit
posters
and he said that he was not sure how
much he was allowed to say but
he told everything in you um
in that phone call there was the uh
chief of
the production and one of his team
members
um and on the phone it was the guy they
had contacted
along along with the legal the chief
legal advisor for
are a mastercard and a huge list
and they were told in their uh point
like that if they
if they did this they would sue the
discord channel
oh wow the bank the bank
outside uh next to people doing that
thing and
uh the signal coming off the tailor was
there
to go in the van somewhere and decoding
it
and reading the numbers off of it yeah
i've seen rfid
i would imagine that our cards must be
encrypted they have to be right come on
tell me they are
but rfid itself is completely unsafe
oh okay well we won't talk about it but
i'll just say
you can buy an rfid reader for a couple
of bucks
and you can read anyone's rfid
so as long as you know how to interpret
that data if you have the right reader
yeah then yeah you can
put it in in your pocket and it can scan
the
that's it it happened at a christmas
parade here in canada
where somebody had walked around and
rfid tapped everybody's back pocket
and just taken a bucket of time
from people's wallets and uh
and they walked away with you know who
knows like twenty thousand dollars
whatever it was taking ten bucks twenty
bucks at a time from people's wallet
with just touching them with the sensor
it's just scary so i disable rfid the
tap
feature on all my cards but
we're coming up on the end of our our
coffee break today but i just want to
acknowledge uh rd blair
who's just joining us hi rd blair
hope you can hear us
we can't hear you perhaps your
microphone is muted i know
zoom when you first join there's a
little mic icon and you might need to
tap that to turn on your microphone
but we can see you and it looks like i
want to be where you are
yeah it looks real nice well we're
you're here just in time for us to leave
bye
yes exactly yeah i want to go where you
are
actually that reminds me i am going to
take some vacation time and head up to
the cottage which
is very similar kind of surroundings so
this week was
crazy i know you guys were hoping for a
live show on wednesday and
with with what happened with microsoft
yeah how long
did you work for on that day i worked
until
about 6 30 and
um so keep in mind that normally we
record the news at four
so and i was stuck at work until six six
thirty
and i did come to the studio but then
that is about the time when jeff would
normally arrive
now that we're back to having a co-host
and uh
and then we would get started on the
shoot but uh
we hadn't even recorded the news yeah so
so we did pull something together for
you guys um so jeff and i decided
all right even though we haven't done
the news even though nothing is prepared
we're going to sit down and do a show
so we did we recorded something for you
then becca came in the next night
and recorded the news and i've been
putting it together so i just finished
editing it this morning
and i'm uploading it to the category 5
youtube channel so there will be a show
this week
it's just that it wasn't live and it's
completely uh you know it's a little bit
different
format so but there's something there
and there's something
you mentioned mythbusters you heard
about grant umahara didn't you
yeah i posted a link i posted the two
articles on the uh
uh the cat five irc challenge and i
noticed that uh some moderator
deleted those links in the uh discord
channel
that may or may not have been me yeah
okay i yeah i couldn't handle it that
day soldier
yeah that was wednesday yeah yeah
uh that's that's like yeah i don't even
want to get into it
that's tragic i know there's a lot of
that
you know yeah i didn't know him
personally or anything like that but
it's like
okay two of my grandfathers died of an
he was aneurysm 49. crazy
on the up and up and yeah so and
it seemed like a healthy guy from
everything i could tell i know yeah
you just never know do you yeah yeah so
wednesday
yeah but but hey i mean let's let's
just trust that the next few weeks are
going to be great um as i say i'm going
to take some down time i'm going to
get some rest and you're making progress
that's a good thing
i'm making progress i'll just tell you
you came in a little bit late but once
the coffee break is posted
come back to it watch it on demand
because i did demonstrate the back
drapery system as well okay yeah so i
i i couldn't remember the password for
the um oh yes
for the zoom meeting and it's on the
website and the website was down so yeah
we're having a couple issues today so
i'm working through ready to go oh yeah
i'm ready to go
zoom automatically generates a random
one so it's a little bit different now
because they're enforcing passwords now
i thought i remembered
it but it didn't so remember
before before you could choose if you
wanted a password and you could type it
in and everything
now because of the fallout of that
situation where people were using no
password
um they are just enforcing random
password random passwords
i don't have a problem with that i'm
perfectly fine with that
they may allow me i might be able to do
a vanity password but i've never looked
don't worry about it
i've recorded it now i know what it is
even if the website's down i know where
to find it it'll
probably change before the next coffee
break that's fine then i'll do it and
i'll reverse that too
just so just search on the website yeah
it will be on the website and that's a
keynote too because
as i'm going to be away for vacation
time which is just like relax
and also this place is going to be under
construction so i can't
really do much from here so
i'll post information on the website
about the next coffee break
and i'll be on discord and everything if
you can't find it or you need an update
but there probably won't be one
there i i can't guarantee if there's
going to be one next week and
over the next few weeks so we'll see
right all right guys sounds good not a
problem
yeah yeah just try to join and if i'm
not here it just won't be on so
yeah all right guys nice to see you all
and
to everybody watching nice to see you
and i'll uh i'll
see you after i've had a bit of a break
so take care
sounds good take care cheers bye guys
bye
always always fun guys
i'm sorry that you didn't get to say
anything sorry about that but
we see you over there
and i'm still not hearing anything so
yeah oh uh another note guys did you did
you notice that there was no
there should have been no static off my
microphone this time
yeah it sounded good so that's so i i've
started working on that because i had to
work out what was going on there
and turn turns out uhf
is line of sight and it prefers not to
have to go through stuff
so because because the studio is in the
other room
yes it was actually the wall in between
us was causing some interference so
you know if you have metal studs in the
wall we do yes that's
what that would be we determined that
with the contractor here so
so what i did is i got on amazon and i
bought um
i bought four 25 foot length cables xlr
that i can run into the studio through
the conduit and so
today i'm just doing a test i've just
draped it along the floor and
i moved the antenna receiver into the
studio so
perfect should be a lot better yeah a
little bit it was really nice
great very different but i couldn't
put my finger on them so that's why the
mics were dropping out and why you
needed to know my extent
exactly yeah i don't care so i'm not
that was interference
yes i thought it was because the the
band is so crowded here
and it is but yeah it still should be
pretty good with the
mic kit that we have so by the way i
noticed that
someone had uh typed something in the uh
yeah it was rd blair he said there was a
hardware issue
that's why his mic's not working well
watch for it watch for the next coffee
break and try to join us arty blair
all right thank you guys see you
bye
beat me up
[Music]