[Music]
greetings and welcome to the world of
cryptos
and welcome to the crypto corner i hope
you had a fantastic week
well the cryptos had a fantastic week
too as you can see
the market is now over 400 billion
dollars which is fantastic news
and we see a lot of green uh in in the
charts
mainly here ethereum that went up since
yesterday by 10 in seven days by 15
but the crazy stuff is happening if we
sold by seven days
here we've got even a few coins which is
new that went up by 300
in seven days 300 percent in seven days
all these are d5 tokens by the way d5 d5
d5 d5
and so on so we have got 28 coins it
went up
higher than 15 percent and so the
default market as you can see is
absolutely on fire
which is also reflected in the fees that
we have to pay for an ethereum
transaction
so just to give put that in perspective
about uh march of this year we had to
pay
around 20 cents 30 cents for
a transaction now we have to pay around
six seven dollars for one transaction
which means
on more complex transactions like the d5
ones
it can be that you have to pay twenty
thirty forty dollars
uh if you uh want to participate in uh
in the default sector and so on um as
you see here
these are the charts of the fees and the
last
bull market we had in 2017 where we
thought this is outrageous we were
over four dollars at peak now we're
6.50 that supposedly is going to be
eliminated
with theorem 2.0 but nobody knows when
that will be exactly implemented so
until then we will have to pay higher
fees
that means at the same time if you're
investing in this segment you cannot go
in there with just hundred dollars
because it will eat up
the fees really eat up your profits so
let's take a look closer look at this d5
market and this is here on
d5 polls.com and last time i showed you
this year we were around one billion
dollars
locked up so this is the money that
people are putting into
these protocols to participate in this
market
and it's currently at nine billion
dollars so it's it's
growing like crazy uh and uh
you can see here in in closer detail
how this is happening what's happening
and so on so yeah
default market is is where you have to
be
but be very careful because if you want
to participate in here
you need to know what you're doing i am
not participating in that i think it's
too hot
and too risky you need to be
in all the telegram groups you need to
be in contact with the people
you need to know which program which
protocol was audited
where is the music happening by the time
you hear it by the way from all those
famous youtubers
it will be too late and you will lose
money
or there's a chance you will lose money
so
if you participate in d5 just be very
careful
now i've been asked a few times what do
i do
with um with taking profits
yeah so it's very it's easy to buy
tokens you hear that on
youtube channel or wherever you you hear
that
somebody recommending something you say
yes fantastic that's exactly what i want
to do
you buy those tokens but then what yeah
and
um so that you don't fall into the same
mistakes
that i fell into in 2017 this
is what i'm now currently doing so as
soon as a
coin went goes up by
um 200 or doubles in price i mean 100
percent
what i do then is i take 20 out and put
them back into ethereum or
bitcoin depending on what your favorite
uh flavor is
40 i then take out and invest them into
a new
uh token and 40 percent i keep
in that token so that's my strategy
that's what i do
if a token went goes higher than a
100 percent why because with all those
tokens that go up crazy in a few days
they'll come down again it's it's always
the same
case now there are some special moments
uh where i also plan to take out money
and these moments are the elections in
the u.s nobody's got knowing
what's going to happen and it will have
an impact on the market
so at before election i'll take uh 20
out of my portfolio
and put them into uh fiat so us dollar
euros uh
canadian dollars whatever that is uh
when btc
bitcoin reaches an all-time high so
around 19 000
i will take also 20 out into fiat
when btc reaches either thirty thousand
and forty thousand i take twenty percent
each time and and put into fiat just
take out your profits you know just to
be on the safe side
because this thing comes down like a
rocket it goes up like a rocket but it
comes down
in in a matter of hours from an all-time
high to
a normal number so you have to be
prepared that
when the market comes down that you have
taken out your profit and you don't
uh well cry about uh non-taken
gains now last one is if bitcoin reaches
50 000
then i will take 40 out into into feared
um all this this is the strategy that i
will be following
uh what happens after 50 000 well nobody
knows because we've never been there
we've never been
at 30 000 either but this is said this
is the strategy i follow
um i recommend you you create your own
strategy
um and you follow it it's important but
you'll see that
once this market goes up and comes down
a lot of things uh will happen anyway
that's as usual for me so thank you very
much for watching
and i wish you a fantastic week thank
you bye
you