covering the week's top tech stores
with a slight linux bias having trouble
sleeping the latest windows 10
cumulative update
breaks sleep mode causing laptops around
the world to become insomniacs
we have the fix to yet another microsoft
update blender
microsoft september 2020 optional update
seems to be causing some trouble for
those who are running windows 10 version
while the update comes with fixes for
critical issues and improvements
like many of microsoft's previous
cumulative updates this one is far from
perfect
some users are reporting that the
optional update broke windows 10
sleep mode with the update installed
some users are reportedly facing an
issue where their pc keeps waking up
from sleep mode
one user states on feedback hub when i
close the lid press the power button or
select sleep
in the power menu or the win x menu
instead of sleeping the screen
simply turns off and my laptop does not
go to sleep even after leaving it alone
all night similar complaints can also be
found on microsoft's forum website
what's worse is that at the time of
broadcast there isn't a fix available
from microsoft there's a temporary
solution available if you're affected
though it's a bit
hacky and reminiscent of the old up down
down left right
game hacks of the 90s first you need to
stop the windows update
service then start it again then
restart it then do a check for updates
and install the pending updates
once they're in reboot your computer and
you should be good to go
with a working sleep mode
you