hello welcome to
category five community coffee break uh
i'm bp nine how are you and way up on my
top left on my school
well that way is robbie
the bald nerd himself hello robbie
and then we've got right nick
and then we've got doug right to him uh
hello doug
thank you sir and we've got marshman
give us a wave marshman
hey how are you sir and then peter
on the road uh on the bottom row give us
away peter
today yep well except for me
no no beard for me so mr
robbie so good to see you what have you
been to
look at all those greats how did all
those upgrades go
actually it's funny that um can you guys
see my screen at all
no not really yeah well then following
the upgrades
uh our iso audio recorders record
nothing but screeching noise
i've got i've got uh tech support
working on that
issue they've never seen before i told
you the average would go well didn't i
didn't i say that yes what could
probably go last week
last week on live sessions for patrons
uh
we were fortunate that we had broadcast
it live
obviously to youtube um
and by doing so youtube recorded it so i
had an audio recording
that i was able to use as the audio
track
not ideal but it worked oh well nothing
though right saved the content
i had to figure out i should look at you
with a big look at you on the phone
because it's uh
i look like i'm looking away from when i
um when i look at you
on the big screen hello boo nice to see
you uh away
good job you're looking a little your
back
background's looking a little fuzzy
though sir yeah
totally i was completely occupied by
writing
[Music]
writing something and the time oh
the coffee break started three minutes
ago i told
oh you're cutting out again yeah oh boy
take it away it's all i'll let robbie
take it
oh yeah well hey good to see you guys
nice to see a small selection from our
community
uh be nice for those who are watching on
demand
to uh hey think about joining uh coffee
break
uh which happens i guess every sunday at
noon eastern time
but uh i hope everybody's been well it's
been pretty crazy around here
so yeah i've heard about that yeah i'm
at home
today doing editing remotely
fun project that i've been working on is
i got a usbc
uh 1080p monitor which connects to the
the pine book pro so now i i now have a
a dual screen pine book pro linux
so you guys may have seen yeah
and uh it's all powered by the pine book
pro
so it's just so i have a usb i have a
usb usbc dongle
from pine phone which
has an api output wall
but um unfortunately the phone will not
um activate the usb dongle
because the main board in bone has fault
in it
um in that it needs it it needs to have
certain
components in order to make work and
energy
or remove those components
any device that has usb otg should have
the ability to output hdmi so i have a
an hdmi dongle for the find book pro
which
is how we bring up the screen on on the
air but this is like just
two monitors side by side i got i made
sure it was the same size as the pine
book pro monitor
so it just looks like a dual screen
coming book pro it's quite nice
but i'm having to do the editing on the
desktop computer because
pine book pro is not going to cut
i i was
uh producing 4k videos i'm actually
doing that
verification not actually doing that on
the pine pro are you
doing this on a
yes sir absolutely welcome thank you
let's see have you have you met
everybody
in the introduction or can you see the
label i've not met the folks
here i i've just seen robbie on the
channel so
okay well clearly i apologize
apparently my own playing out though
apparently um
uh i'm bitcoin welcome uh
on my top left is the bald himself is
robbie ferguson
and above me is uh doug
and next to him
is man no you should be saying that hush
man
thank you sir and then the next row will
be peter
and then here again and then next year
solving
over tonight everyone
this is dave he just joined he's a
member hey dave
good to see y'all yeah so we're going on
the um
it's going really uh to tell you what
all for people i mean
for all the fun things they've been
doing so
i've been talking a bit about the pine
time and the uh
and the pine cone um
anything from me or uh shall i move on
to this one
oh hey and next next up can take it away
unless you guys are all right
for me directly i'm i'm here for the
half hour so
oh i'm sure the question will pop but
we'll just we'll just go around
and see what people can i raise one
thing can i raise one
yeah uh doug you were mentioning that
you had
problems with um certificates on your
raspberry pi and the first thing that
came to mind that i don't think actually
came up
it was ssh keys yeah and did you fix
that
no um i actually can't get it to connect
to wi-fi
which i think is the whole problem oh
okay
just i i wanted to know because the
raspberry pi doesn't have a real-time
clock i just wanted to know if you
had set the date and time on your
raspberry pi because if you haven't
then all ssh keys will be invalid
because the date and time don't matter
that i was not aware of i'll i will have
to
google how to do that yeah you could you
could actually go to my blog
if you go to baldner dot com slash nerd
gasms
okay you'll see a tool there that
is how to set the linux date and time
and it gives you a quick little copy and
paste command you can throw in there and
it'll automatically set it for you
all right your raspberry pi because it
doesn't have a real-time clock
you need to have ntp installed once
you've got it up and going with the date
and time set man
okay so in order to automatically
synchronize it
raspbian must have that in it it does
come with it yeah
okay okay i think it's literally
a man isn't it i think it's literally
the command date
is it not you're choppy
oh he's asking he's saying that
the command is dead is asking if date is
the command to use
i'm not sure oh yeah yeah yeah but
there's
there's like syntax and you've got a you
have to use like the rtc
standard time stamp so just if you jump
on my blog i've written a tool that just
makes it easy you choose your time zone
and you copy and paste and you're done
so hopefully that'll fix it fix it for
you doug and if it does
uh make sure you let the team in in the
community know here on the coffee break
next week yeah
yeah i'll post something on discord cool
excellent um baldnerd.com nerdgasms
if
[Applause]
if peter looks confused then you know oh
he he's always could
talk no worries
when peter does smiling yeah
good yeah there you go so dagger from
the raspberry pi
issues you had what was going on with
um well i've tried uh using ubuntu
instead of raspbian
because i was having problems getting
wide vine to load into raspbian it
wasn't updating
so i found ubuntu was updated
um through another ubuntu machine that i
have
so i downloaded ubuntu for the raspberry
pi
but then i started having the ssh key
problems which robbie
i believe just solved um so i will
fix that and we'll see what happens i
will let you all right
okay well thank you i appreciate it yeah
do let us know how it works out so
definitely
all right marshman you're muted so i
can't
oh there you are okay what time what's
going on with
the oh good what's going on
[Laughter]
say what they've reopened ripley's
aquarium
i could change that if you like
something else but then then
then we get demonetized i have things
that have been monetized
i like that i like the uh that that
fake real bird that you flap oh he's
gone
no he took out he took out his video
okay
uh let's see yes well later dave because
news so
there we go that's what i love to see
and let us know what sort of uh sort of
fun you're having
tick if you like go ahead
i have a a small hobby channel on
youtube
i'm calling myself geezer geek and
i'm doing videos to help folks
accomplish things with everything from
windows to ubuntu
to the hardware that they're using and
you know for example i've done a video
on
making a recording appliance and i did
that for a 501c3
that i serve in fact i'm the pastor of
it
and okay i made this recording appliance
so that our pianist
could come in and do recordings he's not
a tech guy so all he has to do is
start it it'll record for an hour
he goes over turns it off and then i go
in and i collect the video
and then i process it yes one of the
videos that i did how
how to make this one touch recording
device
very nice channel that's my hobby
channel
and then over the last uh pandemic
year year right i have done all kinds of
videos
for the church that i serve so okay
that's what you know that's the new way
yeah
that's what i do here coffee break every
every uh sunday i do the cop right
the royal video we're doing we're doing
fellowship like this with meetings
and we're doing um doing a little bit of
um
business meetings like this but um
for the the basic worship and faith
support it's it's all
virtual via youtube so yeah yeah yeah
that's the that's the new normal right
that's how
it is right now these days yeah so i do
the same in this video i feel like we're
so very fortunate
that when this happened we have the
technology that
absolutely services can continue yeah
and continue
years ago we couldn't have done this
yeah yeah it's amazing although my
church is meeting in person
i'll be there tonight yeah yeah mine too
really
wow okay now do you doug do you tuck the
beard into the mask
no no he
well that would make it hard to talk it
would get in my mouth
you guys all kinds of things that be
experienced
so another short video on the twitter
two weeks ago uh someone was there
working uh
if you're on a on the airport and
someone was yelling at him to uh put put
on his mask and then he
pulled the mask down he has
made the mask
with his face printed on the mask
now robbie you had a mask on at some
point there's like a
mouth like a duck's mouth or something
was that a green screen or was it an
actual printed mask i did was it i think
you did
i think i saw on one of your no i i got
the
led mask that you can program with
bluetooth but other than that most of my
masks are
like just like i've got one that's the
binary one that that folks saw last week
but okay
okay yeah i thought i'd i've i must have
been a
picture that someone said on discord
they haven't seen those
yeah funny yeah i wonder if that was
some zombie teeth
and like rocks
from 40 years ago
in a doctor's office um there were two
deaf people
and the mask had a clear space right
across the mouth so they could read like
oh yeah
but it was still a full mask
one of the thing prizes me is how much
maybe i'm just getting death or
something but hence i rely
i've tried to rely on on movement
to understand what people are saying
it's quite surprising
like if i'm a noisy environment and i
can't hear them then i'll try to
try to um read them out but it's
impossible to do that if they're wearing
a mask
you just can't do it yeah i was thinking
i thought at the grocery store like how
would someone who's hard of hearing
um deal with that like that's kind of
very true
yeah yeah
not to mention you can't really
see what kind of
muttering yeah
yeah true but you know when you unless a
tear starts
falling down then do you have some idea
but uh
whenever you're interacting with people
if you professional that's
that should be so anyway that's that's a
whole nother story though
isn't it did we get to mush man
i don't know we actually got to talk to
you we've got change of background that
bird that just keeps on making it but
i had nothing going on so you skipped
over me
i'm sorry i'm sure you had lots going on
please
thanks for watching i have a lot going
on very well
please tell us more tell us more no it's
it's we're trying to take a break from
there's a riptide out there that's
that's what keeps pulling me under
oh but oh boy did you not walk in town
today like your pedometer says you are
oh no i'm putting in steps like you
wouldn't believe
how is how are you doing are you just
walking around town every day
what's up i drive i drive to new york
city
and park the car and then i walk
everywhere
i don't i don't i try not to take the
subways i won't get on a bus i
definitely won't get in again yeah i
heard that
so i i walk i walk everywhere and then i
walk back to the car and
drive home required for your working too
i'm a field person i i've never had a
desk job
so okay i've never had an office job so
i'm
always i envy you sir yeah
i have to say that is a great it's easy
to do that in new york
because uh everything is so compact and
so yeah
yeah when the pandemic started
and everything locked down and i it took
me a week
and i realized i could never have an
office job
sitting here drives me nuts i can't yeah
yeah
yeah yeah well when i worked in
melbourne back in australia many
many many years ago i figured out
quickly i was able to walk from one side
of the central business district what
you would call downtown
from one side let me bring it into view
there it is from one side
to the other of the downtown area
i could do that in probably half an hour
and it's about the same from from south
to north as well
that's about the total total coverage
area of
the central business district now if i
had to go into the suburbs or something
that's a whole different story but
um but it would take probably half an
hour i think new york's a bit bigger
than that i know it's
i know it's pretty packed in but it's
still a bit bigger than that though
right
yeah and it's got residential areas so
you have the downtown financial
districts where the buildings are just
really compact and then once you get out
of that it's residential and small
business
and then you get into midtown new york
and then you got the tall buildings
again
so i try and schedule my days where if i
have
downtown clients i schedule them in the
same day so i park downtown and then
just do everything downtown and then
split okay and then i schedule the
midtown people
like a different day and i park in
midtown and then split
nice nice nice and still get 10 000 plus
steps
can't even walk to work like i'd love to
be able to walk or bike to work but
they went and they gave me the the
option of taking a company vehicle
and i'm like yeah i'm going to take i'm
going to take that
wow but now because i can't leave the
company vehicle at home i can't
bike to work i can't walk i can't so
it's like catch 22 it's a bonus but at
the same time it's like
peter we haven't had to catch we haven't
had a chance to catch up with you yet
tell us what's going on with you
uh on wednesday i went for the uh
grown out injection
and uh by about friday i
thought it didn't feel too good and see
this effect is effective
of having an injection and uh want to go
over if
i have a flu or a hangover
and massive and then once after
friday wednesday i sort of improved a
lot you know it just happened one day
but okay yeah but double right now um
we're going we've got we can't go out or
do anything with
like robbie i mean uh they're thinking
about uh
everywhere to uh uh bring the kids back
again
and uh and uh open up a bit more but uh
i'm just waiting them to do it probably
in april i reckon here
but most of the time i'll be doing
electronics uh with a friend of mine's
also
a minister and the same as uh the
chapter of the new chap
according to his name uh it
automatically means uh
i went to university where they made my
gives a few pcbs for him and designing
pcb
and every argument with amazon
particularly because they don't uh
deliver
or if they do if that you you
you quit something and then suddenly
they take it off the thing and say that
you can't
they don't tell you they've taken it off
to your page
which is a bit in the way because i've
had one or two guys though
and told them off exactly because i
thought they was playing quicker
particularly
um well
magazine which i reckon that they was
either on
smoking something very illegal or
something when they designed it because
they would tell you
easy peter easy now i know
i know even even my british filter is
having trouble
you know figuring that one out so i'm
going to have to
[Music]
my automated closed captions just says
dot dot dot
i'm not surprised
at one point i thought you were singing
music
dave i know you have to oh there he goes
yeah i was gonna
i was gonna say dave i know you have to
go so um you have to drop out
okay okay see you next time
all right so good to see you i'm not
trying to build and uh
the circuit was totally wrong i
generally got published in the magazine
because it was quite one
uh well-known magazine it was totally
totally wrong with the whole thing
okay does anyone have any
does anyone have any questions for uh
for robbie because uh you know
or marshmallow because we don't see even
marshmallow here very often
so maybe uh maybe uh if anyone has any
questions
yeah i was wondering if robbie had
noticed
a news that broke today i think uh about
the uh new colonel bug in the uh
uh release candidate
no i haven't seen it yet no it's um it's
um
mailing list uh warning about uh the
even trying the
release kind of the one for the um
kernel
5.12 um
there is an error within the uh swap
handling
for it only affects those who have
assault file and not a small
partition it makes it in certain
conditions the uh
swap file that will write to due to the
wrong part of the file system and it
will completely
screw up the root file system oh that's
not good
that is not good but typically we're
looking at it
typically candidate code doesn't get
into the stable
does it yeah you'd have to be really on
the bleeding edge
which i'm yeah yeah i'm running stable
i think i'm on development uh branch on
one thing
probably an old version of the pine
phone but
otherwise no i'm unstable as well
my wife computer decided to uh
uh dropped well dropped dads exactly uh
uh
last the other day when i was trying to
look up some information on some data
computer that drawing spray took upon
data
and uh i went to buy a drive and
you have you noticed the price of the
the drive streets and the robbie they've
gone up
like a factory or three they could have
manufactured
and stuff no everything's just robbing
for four gigs
with four gets one gigs uh one terabyte
three four terrorists one terrorist
uh ssds they've just gone up
absolutely fantastic amount of money wow
especially these days with the problems
with supply and demand
and yeah nothing that's what i think it
doesn't want to do it away
i i put a half a terabyte in there and i
hopefully
it's not a good one it's quite old and i
think it's that
this has got problems with it but it
would do for the moment to to
wait to september and uh see what the
price is to do
you know because i i'm not playing those
all funny prizes they will they were
they were
they were they were on their lake you
know anything else as well
some wouldn't yeah we'll have to we'll
have to see it happens with those design
i imagine eventually um somebody will
catch up with demand
hopefully the prices will come down too
because like
manufacturers are going to be bringing
out their new drives in the in the
spring
so it may bump off yeah if they have it
but
don't think they're shipping to england
or ireland
and to work you know that adds the price
as well that that day's old days fun
that he's getting self-help i
i know i know
he's great funny okay from uh amazon
yeah well we won't talk about that
okay all right i'm gonna keep speaking
with drivers i've got my uh m.2 nvme
adapter for the pine book pro
so i've ordered uh an a2000
drive so it's a single-sided low
power consumption and uh i'm going to
put that in there
so that's something that i really like i
may be talking to you about
nvme and good deals for those
we'll talk about that offline i think i
think on the way to
the particular surprise you do and then
i i would die to find one when that
happens but
uh i thought you'd do it with this
grammar and everything else that's what
i reckon it was so
boy you have to push the air don't you i
keep saying we're not in politics or or
coding
keep doing it all right we're gonna
we're done we're we're about to shut it
down so uh
thank you uh marshman thank you for uh
and especially you i appreciate you
tuning in and say hello
and uh i would have i would have said
here today while he was here too but he
had to drop out earl so
it was very good absolutely yes good to
see you robbie good to see marshman
thanks and you're the one anytime you
want to be
you know just shy come in and say hello
and give us a hard time because we
deserve it
good to see you everybody take care take
care everybody
have a good week see you next week take
care bye
[Music]