at category 5 tv we trust our files to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
whether for your server laptop or
desktop computer
you'll experience improved performance
and reliability
kingston is with you get ready it's time
for the tech
well welcome to the show everybody nice
to have you back with us again this week
great to see you great to see you jeff
you as well you've been well
i've been well it's december i i know
the month of the christmas it's crazy
like
where did this year go i know i feel
like it started
i stayed in my house and now it's
christmas yeah that's pretty much how it
went
you guys been busy we've been very busy
yeah yeah
i mean christmas time is always a busy
time but uh yeah it's a strange year too
and
you know going into the stores and
trying to do christmas shopping is very
different this year
a lot of it happens online i will admit
i've not stepped into a store to do
any buying really yeah wow okay well i i
have but one of the one of the things
that happens of course being a four-eyed
ninja
glasses get fogged completely up i gave
up on my glasses this year to be honest
yeah you're yeah you go that's i can't
see a thing i'm just
just a round bald head see at least for
me it's it's distance that's where i
need my glasses so within like
yeah i need distance and 50 feet in
between
yeah i need all that stuff so but what i
decided to do
i mean i've got a 3d printer no
i wish i could do contacts i've got a
misshapen
retina so i can't wear contacts so
that's just me i just don't think things
touch my eyes
that too yeah but um so i decided hey i
mean there's other people that are going
through the same thing so why don't i
use my 3d printer
to kind of help out with that situation
okay so i came across
thing number four six i'm looking down
at my at my sheet because i could never
remember this
thing number four six three five four
two
nine by le cutter juan
and i've got the link for you below and
uh and what
they have come up with is this mask clip
it looks like a dry bandage but it's
just it's 3d printed on
on the 3d printer here at the studio and
what it does
jeff is it it goes on my uh reusable
mask
yeah just like that and then when i wear
my mask it's
nice and tight around my nose oh my gosh
so it doesn't fog up my glasses and i'd
say
like huge huge difference so i'm like
okay well
this is working for me so i'm going to
see if i can print more and and give
them out so that's what i've been doing
and and so that's something that i've
been learning is with my 3d printer can
i
like do that kind of thing because this
is the kind of cool i'm sure there'll be
a dime a dozen
at the dollar store oh easily in a
couple months but right now
it's not something that's available so
that's interesting i got on thingiverse
i downloaded the thing
and i started printing them and they
come out like this oh wow
so you get you know i get a sheet of 40
of them and they're all tied together
but then as i'm you know i'm just
learning how to manufacture i'm
realizing okay well this is actually a
fair bit of work because now i've gotta
tear each one off the sheet and they
come off like this i gotta clean them
off i gotta get all the burrs off i
gotta cut them up i gotta
use a file uh to clean those up and so
each one takes me
like about five minutes to get it all
like ready for somebody to use
so so the cost is really really cheap i
mean i can print them myself and they're
six cents each
wow but then you look at okay well print
time for 40 of them is 18 hours
right plus get deeper cleaning up
deburring them is another five minutes
per
so it starts to be like wow you you can
never make a business out of this
no but it's something that i'm like
given away to family and friends who
have that same problem but for me
personally it's fantastic and then the
kids
who have glasses as well all i did was i
took it and i shrunk it down 70.
i was able to ask is it customizable
well yeah because it's just a file on my
computer so
i can just shrink it down and print it
for a smaller mask and there you go
very cool i mean once again 3d printing
is is showing itself to be something
that
is really really practical really useful
and in a situation where there's a
product that
you can't go out and buy in the store
yet but everybody wants one
so hey again link is below so if you
have a 3d printer and you got the same
problem that i do
walking into the stores and it's just
fog
well this is going to help you out a lot
so hey 3d print one if you don't have a
3d printer and you want me to send you
one i'm sure we could find a way
that's right just know that uh my my
cost is six cents but
you factor in the labor and they're
twenty dollars each
plus your picking plus that's a 40
part right there can you imagine
that's the thing right so i mean some
companies going to come
and start printing those or extruding
them or doing some kind of
new process that's really really quick
and easy and
they'll be able to do it so is there i
wonder could you
save on the
cleanup time by printing them as
singles that way you don't have this
engine
remember when i said it takes 18 hours
to print a sheet of 40 of them
well yeah so if i was sitting in front
of my 3d printer and wanted to print one
at a time sure
yeah i could probably save some time
well i just didn't know if like
i've never 3d printed before so i just
didn't know if you could like
print one here and then two inches over
print another one or does it all still
link it
you could but with these jeff they're so
they're so fine that there's not a lot
of surface to touch the
the platform of the 3d printer oh so
what ends up happening is you get
halfway through the print and it
loses its adhesion so it's no longer
stuck to the printer and so then as the
printhead is going over it
it moves it and then you've got a
botched print so that's where this
sheet comes in which is actually called
a i guess a skirt or something like that
but it basically gives you more surface
area
to adhere to the 3d printer makes sense
but yes
i mean if you really really dialed in
that 3d printer that's
you know maybe a goal to to be able to
do hey if you want to start a business
printing these things there you go
something to do in your non-spare time
yes yeah but
a way to to to give back we'll say very
cool that's
so that's what i've been up to what have
you been up to oh i've been busy
uh making websites and stuff oh cool
yeah i got it i got a new phone you got
a new please
i got the samsung a71 okay um
it's nice phone it's i we seem to go
through these trends where it's like
phones we get
bigger and then they get smaller and now
i think we're going back to bigger
phones because this thing doesn't even
fit in my pocket
really it's a big freaking phone yeah
it's nice and tall
my uh my pocophone f1 is it's probably
you know slightly larger phone than what
i'm used to wow that's previously that's
mo
yeah yours is yours is like the the
granddaddy yeah
my f1 and this wasn't even the biggest
one yeah
i was like my goodness they're like
phablets at this point pretty much yeah
but i will say
i like the size i've never had a phone
with a big hard drive like my first i
remember my first iphone size you like
the capacity of it
i love the capacity this is 128 gig okay
the biggest phone i've ever had is 32.
but you're using android so
unlike apple why don't you just throw
another sd card in there
well that's the thing when it comes to
android even like i have an sd card in
here that's uh i think it's a 256. yeah
um but the problem is the apps
themselves do not install on the sd card
okay they install on the phone right so
it'd be just like
um you know if you had an app on your
you know computer yeah you couldn't
install it on a usb
the data to it you could put on a usb
but the app itself is on your
your c drive um so same deal so i end up
like running out of space
they got to make that easier i find that
too with my phone
um like i do have a 256 gig kingston sd
card in here
gives me a ton of storage space for my
photos for videos i do a lot of video
shooting in this 4k
camera yep but um it automatically
stores to the built-in
storage then i can transfer it to the sd
card
which is great i do that in the field to
to free up some space for more shooting
yep but why can't you just select to
always save
to the sd card that's what i want and
some apps do it but
not all apps do and i'm thinking
specifically about you dji
well come on now that's the thing there
are some apps
that you can set in the settings that
the default save is to your sd card yeah
but i do remember at one point i don't
remember which phone it was that i had
there was a setting where when you put
an sd card in you can have
the phone recognize the sd card as part
of the internal hard drive
or like the actual storage so it just
expands it just expands the whole thing
oh yes
now how it works with partitioning i
don't know but it just looked like i had
a 64 gig
and so i would it would say oh you've
got room for your apps and all that and
so how it worked i don't know
it's magic right but the challenge i had
is when um
my wife and i went for a vacation to
hawaii yep first day there
taking a bunch of photos my sd card
fails
no so i was quite frustrated
because i didn't have my computer for a
backup it was not a kingston sd card
it was not a kingston sd card i see i
see how i just knew that
yeah i knew yeah but uh no the sd card
failed and so
i lost half my apps
so i lost half the apps i lost all my
photos
and i was like i don't have a computer
to back it up to is it possible that you
bought
a fake sd card no it was a legit sd card
it was legit
yeah it was uh it was a sandisk i think
but was it a sandisk oh no it was a
sandisk all right yeah
if it wasn't then well we've done
sasha and i took a look at some fake sd
i remember that
i was able to buy off of amazon and it's
a real eye-opener and maybe this is
important for you to note as we're going
into
you know it's the christmas season and
maybe you've got some gifts under the
tree and you've
got sd cards for various devices it's
important for you to note that so i've
got the link for that video for you as
well
yes uh up there and in the description
below depends on where you're watching
if you're watching this on cable tv
obviously nothing i say really works
so hey you know go to our website
category five dot tv
do a quick search for fake sd card it's
really really important for you to know
it was a great features exist yeah after
that on a bunch of my sd cards
you got to be careful what ones you get
and where you get them from
because they can still screen a card and
make it look like a sandisk absolutely
for sure
yep if it fails and you've got all your
photos on it
the nice thing about a situation like
that and and we do this with our
nintendo switch so
kingston has brought out an actual
nintendo switch optimized uh
cool and so you can store all your game
data and all your games
on the sd card and then what do you do
you shut down the switch you take the sd
card out you put it in your computer
and you make a backup yes right so if
it ever failed or if you ever ran out of
space and you wanted to add more space
you could transfer that data
absolutely and move it around to another
card so that's pretty brilliant so
that's good yeah got a lot of technology
speaking of kingston now i name drop a
little bit but kingston
is you know i i really do stand by uh
their products uh
so i've been using them it's quite
literally solid state products jeff
and i had this issue where here at the
studio we ran out of space on our server
yeah we're live right now but guess what
we're doing
we are recording multiple camera shots
in 4k
to a server well when you're out of
space on said server that can be a bit
of a brutal nightmare
for a production company such as
category 5 tv
so so i got a hold of some kingston dc
drives and started doing some tests
we're going to be looking at that
tonight
mark noland is going to be joining us to
talk with us about
how these are improving the the
performance of the server so there's
the capacity thing but then there's also
the actual performance of hey
like i'm producing 4k video well
the old spinner drives are really having
a hard time keeping oh yeah
so we're going to jump into that in a
couple of moments time before we do i
want to remind you hey we are on youtube
and if you're watching this on youtube
please
give this video a thumbs up give us a
like and a subscribe if you do
subscribe it's important to also click
that bell so you get notifications every
time we're live
that's a really great way to keep tabs
on what's going on here at category 5
technology tv so i'm going to jump over
to the bridge jeff
because uh we've got mark standing by
okay i'm gonna head over there
you take it from here while robbie's
going off to the bridge i want to
encourage you check out our website
category5.tv there's tons of stuff on
there
you can check out past episodes you can
also download
all of our episodes we've got everything
on a torrent file you want to get
that see what's been going on for the
last 14 seasons it's amazing stuff
and as well check out our shop and buy
all the cool stuff that we were telling
you about on the show
all right let's head over to the bridge
a bit of back story for you before we
jump into an interview with mark noland
at kingston technology
the server we use here at the studio has
been low on space for some time
i've actually had to delete things in
order to make room for the shows each
week
it's an old server but it still runs
great a bit on the loud side with those
dell cooling fans
but it runs well so there's no reason to
replace it yet
the storage however could use an upgrade
since transitioning our editing to 4k
last fall it's become obvious that not
only is the storage array too
small but the drives aren't fast enough
either
so after some research i picked up
kingston data center ssds they've got
ecc to protect against data corruption
and they're meant for business use in
the data center
now my data center as you can this is it
i've got a single old dell r510 server
but what we'll cover today is completely
scalable i don't want to give you the
wrong impression
whether you're a very small business
like myself even a home
server or a web host or large enterprise
with many servers the point is
that these competitively priced
enterprise ssds from kingston
can really improve your server's
performance now for my use here at
category 5 tv i went with the dc
500rs because they're optimized for read
intensive application
that should do really well for our video
editing of course i also use the server
for general data storage
to hold past seasons of videos plus i
run a few virtual machines on there to
run our internal infrastructure
so needless to say kingston's dc 500rs
are going to be ideal not just for my
general use but the bursts of sudden
read speed i need when loading big video
files
they've also got dc500ms as well and if
you need
higher write speed those will fit the
bill being a really great
big bang for the buck all round ssd for
servers
i wanted to know how much of a
difference the upgrade actually made
so i set up a comparison with the hopes
of making it as close
of a one to one as possible so i chose a
raid 5 with
four disks each and before i ran the
tests
i updated the raid controller firmware
while it is an old server i thought it
would be best to make sure
everything is as up-to-date as possible
from there
along with some helpful advice from
kingston's fio expert matt eaton
i wrote a benchmark script that i could
run against both my original spinning
drives and the new kingston ssds
giving me a pretty good view of how the
performance compares
the code's on my github page and the
link is in the video description below
huge thanks to matt for all of his help
and also dave leung for among other
things
helping connect me with the right people
at kingston i did a fair amount of
preconditioning on the drives
though time was of a factor here as well
and since the spinners were taking an
unreal amount of time to precondition i
did cut that process
short it should be noted too that the
drives are different capacities so this
is by no means apples to apples
but in a real world environment such as
ours here at the studio
i'm happy just to know that there's a
perceptible improvement
with reasonably accurate numbers to back
that up
i brought the server nearly to its knees
the fio tests
were brutal on these old spinner drives
but they completed way faster on the
ssds so i grabbed some 2.5 to 3.5 inch
adapters
that will match up nicely with the
server's backplane since the dell trays
only support
3.5 inch drives firing up the server
with the ssds and all appears to work
great
but all the drives are flashing in amber
light
i asked mark from kingston if this was a
concern well
with dell where did you get the drive
sled
wait a minute so you're telling me these
fancy expensive drive adapters or what's
causing this
it's the drive sled the drive set has a
chipset on it
all right let's try a different approach
then commander muffet posted thing
1830990 to thingiverse which looks
promising
i've got the link in the description
below let's give it a shot
[Music]
success the kingston dc 500 is connected
directly to the backplane using 3d
printed adapters
did the trick now i'd like to briefly
digress
because this is another testament to the
cost savings
of owning a 3d printer now i paid 16
dollars
each for these adapters the ones i
printed myself
these worked better and now while i used
expensive pla plus filament which cost
forty dollars per kilogram each tray
adapter
which is 14 grams price that prices it
at only 56
cents each so the material cost being 56
cents
i saved 15.44
per tray adapter that's a grand total of
123.52
saved to print eight adapters myself
if i did that just two more times i've
already offset the upfront expense of
buying my 3d printer in
savings alone anyway back to our subject
but first a quick word from our sponsors
when we return mark nolan joins us from
kingston
to make sense of the file results and
talk about how business users can
further improve the performance of the
data center
stick around
[Music]
i've run the fio tests on all the drives
and i've passed the numbers on to the
team at kingston so they can help make
sense of the test results
and here's what those numbers look like
so in the middle column there i've got
the four
dell constellation es drives those have
the sas interface
running at 7 200 rpm and i've configured
them in a raid 5. you can see the iops
input output per second
is very very poor by contrast to the
ssds in the far right column
those are the dc500rs from kingston and
those again are configured in the same
way a raid 5 with four drives however
these ones are one terabyte drives
versus the spinning drives that are two
terabytes each not apples to apples but
you can see clearly
that the speed is significantly improved
on the ssds
mark noland is a field application
engineer from kingston technology
mark thanks for taking the time to speak
with me howdy how are you today
great tell us a little bit about what it
is that you do at kingston
uh so i'm my title is field applications
engineer
uh but i interface a lot with uh clients
and users at data centers
um i also you know in my background i i
used to work
for autodesk uh in the film and video
industry
um and dealt with like sort of
everything from the desktop application
back to the data center you know uh so
if you break a bottleneck at the desktop
you know then your next bottleneck is
the network and once you break that then
your bottleneck is on the server
and so um just basically trying to
troubleshoot and
and break bottlenecks whether it's you
know uh
databases or you know
8k video editing systems uh things like
that
uh they all need uh big fast data going
through pipes
don't i know it don't i know it oh yeah
so you've seen that's quite a setup you
yeah well and you've seen our file
numbers from
our test today um and i i do realize
that those numbers are
slightly arbitrary um however
what i did is i ran the same tests
against the same scenario
on our old spinning drives as i did on
dc500rs
so just looking at those numbers can you
help us to make sense of
what's what's actually happening there
uh okay yeah so uh you know
first of all both you know both the ssds
and the hard drives are
connected to the sata bus right same
server
all the hardware is the same just the
drives have changed yeah
the sata bus is one of the older um
connection methods in in this in the
computer
uh and and it has uh you know
a few uh uh weaknesses and that uh
sort of you can only be reading or
writing to it at any one time
uh but you know with raid controllers
and that they've gotten really good at
being able to optimize that
uh the best way possible so then you
come down to the uh
raw you know uh interface
differences between a hard drive
spinning disk and ssds
and you know s's
ssds have been modified you know it's a
solid-state disk it's basically you've
got computer memory nand that is
being uh routed to speak uh disk
language right
and so uh in a way you're sort of uh
hobbling the uh the uh fast nan that's
in there by
making it go through the uh uh sata
interface
but uh it has to pretend that it is
uh it has to like at least translate to
speak disc language
so when you've got like uh the old
school heart spinning discard drives
um you know they're they're pretty good
at doing sequential stuff
uh random they start choking and when it
comes to iops
they really have a hard time keeping up
with uh
the memory you can see you know which
parts are
uh and the difference between your test
scores
you can see which parts are you know low
because
of the spinning disc itself and ones
that you know
uh uh are like the uh
nand on an ssd is actually able to you
know still
put pretty good uh bandwidth through so
like
in your in your uh read and write
performance
um you know the ssds are
anywhere between like on the read
maybe four times faster than uh the
fastest rate of hard drives that you
have going
right um this is also you're doing raid
5 so there's a little bit of overhead
with disk management so
if you did raid 0 on both the ssds and
i need redundancy yeah yeah you have no
redundancy but if you do raid zero you
know then you can see raw bandwidth sure
happening right yeah uh but and and that
that's when
ssds would even take a step above you
know sad
ssds would be even faster uh without
that
redundancy happening uh because there's
a certain amount of uh
overhead that's happening to to do that
but uh even with your raid 5 setup
you're still looking at about three
times faster
for ssds than hard drives uh
on uh on a re on a
right and four times faster on the reed
uh typically but the the one sort of
secret place that it ends up being much
much faster
is uh in the latency so that's like the
time
between when i click and submit a
request to the time
that uh it actually starts happening
right um
if if if it's like a random io uh
event it might be you know uh
when your drives are warmed up and
everything it might be uh
like 0.8 milliseconds to 1.2
milliseconds depending
uh whereas on the ssd it's going to be
microseconds so even if it's 20
microseconds
uh and you have a rate of four drives if
you say that your average latency per
drive was one millisecond on a hard
drive
and it's like 20 microseconds on the ssd
then uh you haven't even gotten to a
microsecond by the time you add up that
latency
across the four drives
the latency is a big difference and then
the quality of service
so one of the things that we really
tested the data center the dc
500 and 450 and dc 1000 drives
uh they're they're tested extensively
for you know
uh quality of service that's the main
the main thing you're looking for if
you're putting them into a data center
like tier 2 cloud something like that
you want a quality of service where
you know a consumer ssd might peak and
deliver super performance for a short
period of time
and if you're only transferring a couple
gigs at a time that's what you want it's
on your laptop
right you know you're trying to get
things on and off really quick that's
awesome
but if you're if you're running a drive
you know 24 7 with a database with for
online transactions
uh you're writing to it and reading from
it like constantly
and you you don't want to see big spikes
up or down in the performance you want
to see
like a a really flat line in that
performance and
and you'll see that with like a hard
drive you know uh it'll spike up really
fast initially because it's got a big
dram cat
anytime you're transferring a video file
or something it's like fast and then
and then it'll plummet down to
right 200 megabytes per second and then
it goes 30 megabytes yes
and you're like what happened yeah uh
and the problem is
at a certain point you're running out of
cash or something like that so
in that uh you know in in your fios
script
uh one of the important things to do if
you're wanting to test for
data center use is to do that uh warm up
on the drive to have it burned in
so that uh it's not just like fresh out
of the box i just
installed it and all the sectors are
blank and and you know like uh
because it's not having to have any
overhead of managing
uh data on the drive right you would see
what the
drives in use so is that is that kind of
the key difference between the consumer
ssds that i have in my laptop in my home
computers
versus these data center drives yeah
that and you might see over provisioning
differences
um like our uh dc
uh drives um number one they have a
decent amount of uh dram cash on them
uh where a lot of consumer drives might
have
a pseudo slc where they take tlc or qlc
memory and program it as
slc so rather than you know they might
take a sector
a section of the drive and and say this
is going to be programmed as
slc so i'm only going to store one bit
of data in this cell
instead of the three or four like if
it's uh tlc you're storing three bits of
data
and uh or bytes and and uh
and qlc you're storing four so you've
got much more
data that's being stored there uh you
know we had mlc
uh but then it was tlc and yeah qlc and
you know we're we're trying to clam more
more bits into
uh uh the more cells uh
and as you do that it gets you know it
takes a little longer to program
uh all those uh bytes and bits into
uh the different cells so if you use
this pseudo cache of slc
which we do on a few drives as well in
consumer uh but uh
you're it the reason you do it is it's
much less expensive than using
dram and so uh on our on our data center
drives there they all have like a nice
big
dram cache on them that's one of the big
differences oh okay
and so uh that that combined with
uh the over provisioning that is on
uh our data center drives allows for
uh as well as tweaks in the firmware
it allows for really uh high level of
quality of service so
you don't see big spikes way up and then
way down and and going you know
where you're at the max performance of
the bus down to zero back to the middle
and are you when you say when you say
over provisioning are you talking about
i o
now over provisioning is where if i have
like if you see uh an ssd that has
say it has 940 or 960 gigs yeah
uh of 960 gig capacities really common
right yeah
that that's a terabyte of nand that's on
there and it has
over provisioning of uh three to five
percent
for the data itself so the storage yeah
okay and so when
when you see a drive that says one
terabyte
uh lots of times that's still the same
amount of nand as if you bought a
a 960 but the thing you'll notice is
like on a consumer drive if you get up
to being
90 full on one that's not over
provisioned
you'll start you'll see the performance
also start to tank
whereas if you have one that if you have
the you know the 960 gig drive it can be
90 percent full
and you'll still be riding at the same
speed as when it was empty
uh you know you it well
i won't say when it was empty because
one of the things we do that uh
preconditioning right that's part of our
uh script that we
we we're working on there um that
preconditioning
basically make sure that the drives sort
of dirtied up and
and uh is doing real workload type stuff
so you guys
because you can test anything out of the
box and it might look spectacular but
then when you put it into real use
uh throw it into a data center and you
know week into being used
you're like this is not performing the
way it did you know
i threw these consumer drives in there
and they were great now they uh are
terrible
yeah um oh i see that like yeah i've
seen that on desktop drives and
and things like that yeah when they get
warmed up and dirty and make sense
they're under real world working
conditions and not just
running a benchmark and now my iops
on the and you mentioned iops maybe i
could get you to briefly
explain what that means to us um but it
is
through the roof higher uh on the ssds
what does that what does that tell us so
uh part of that is it's because of the
it's physics right so on the ssd
it's it's science we're talking about
physics because
the uh hard drive is actually relying
uh for the iops it actually has that
that
needle that moves back and forth with
the reader physical drives yeah
the the spinning drives and so it
actually has to in order to read a point
it has to physically move to somewhere
find that
read it uh verify it and then move to
the next point find it read it and
verify it so
uh just because of the way
physics and thermodynamics work the
drive can't spin
any faster they you know hard drives are
really really great for what they do
and they you can get really big hard
drives and
they're pretty durable uh but
physics can't take them any farther
because and
so when you go over to an ssd
uh you're just everything's uh
done through solid state you're not
moving anything
except electrons and so uh
you know you're you you have like your
seek times go down by a thousand
fold uh and that's why you'll see what
the iops difference the
random read which was your best on the
hard drives random read of
673 iops
whereas the random read on the raid of
dc 500r was 121 000 iops
so 180 times the speed
yeah it's it's just a little faster a
little bit
that's amazing so now we understand now
that
so i've jumped from uh going from the
spinning drives to the ssds now my
bottleneck is sata
the the connection so uh
that uh 121 000 iops
uh uh with that if you went to
now you go to pcie based drives
pcie gen 3 nvme type drives
so either m.2 or u.2
um u.2 is more friendly to
a data center because it is in that two
and a half inch form factor rather than
the gum stick form factor which is a
little difficult to manage there's a few
people that have
uh adapters and things like that to put
lots of m.2s into servers but
um you know i think the the u.2 and the
ruler are going to be much more common
uh going forward for putting in lots of
you know like 24
or more u.2 drives uh
like nvme ssds into a server
uh but now you're talking like the iops
go up another
factor right um so like an nvme drive
because it's not limited
to uh by the sata bus uh
it is limited by the pcie bus so
um you know you go to gen 4 and that's
twice as fast as gen 3 so
you know potentially twice as fast i
haven't seen any models where
like it is twice as fast but you know
significantly
gen 4 demos that i've seen are
significantly faster like uh
you know you're talking off of by 16
i think the fastest demo i've seen so
far is about
25 gigabytes per second off of one
device
on one gen 4 bytes
per second wow and and i don't know how
scalable that is
currently but that was when gen 4 was
still experimental which it's a little
experimental
i think the amd one is is looking really
good but uh
i'll call it kind of experimental until
intel and amd both have their gen 4 out
and
uh all of the enterprise servers
are shipping with gen 4 pcie because
at this point it's a really cool gamer
box or
a really high-end a really high-end
workstation
you know like it uh nvidia's got a lot
of cool demos with
four gpus on an amd proc with uh
you know lots of nvme uh uh
drives connected to it and they're doing
some really neat demos and as is amd
with their
their gpus um but
all that right now seems it it's like
if i have to go drop uh five to
twenty grand on a workstation um i i
gotta wait until it's uh
somebody else uh works out all the
wrinkles in that experiment
so thinking about my use case so i
obviously work here in a studio so i'm
doing a lot of video production
uh maybe some of our viewers are working
in an office environment where they've
got similar scenarios where
hey we've got to replace the drives in
an older server or maybe it's not even
that old but
they're they're not necessarily
replacing an entire server they just
want to put
ssds in instead of the spinning drives
because they're
kind of the way to go right now and
we're certainly seeing a big performance
boost here
um is there you know where
where is the performance gain so for me
it's it's in
editing real time 4k video it's it's
brilliant on the on the dc
500rs where where is the the average
business consumer
i t department going to find gains uh by
upgrading the servers to ssd
well i i think uh client satisfaction
and
my uh dad's a dentist and my mom's a
lawyer and
and uh i've used to do some computer
tech support for
people in those communities and and you
know like uh
uh doctors and lawyers are notoriously
cheap when it comes to you know like uh
spending money on on systems like that
but the systems also
drive all of the uh all of the uh
revenue in their business so it's really
important for them to keep them updated
and uh i think the thing that you get by
going from hard drive to ssds
on an upgrade of an older system you
know is you'll be able to ring
at least two or three more years out of
it if not more
um you know you'll you you'll you always
hit a bottleneck somewhere but
rather than your system being the
bottleneck it might be the os or the
version of the software
that you're using or something like that
but uh
you you'll make something much more
usable have you ever taken an old hard
drive ss
or a whole old hard drive laptop and put
an ssd in it and
you know it's like all sudden it's like
why was i gonna get rid of this thing
it's so fast
exactly it like breathes new life into
an old system and that's exactly what
this has done
for our server and i and as you're
talking about bottlenecks i'm thinking
okay well sata is six gig a second
so i think my bottleneck actually mark
is going to be my networking because i'm
only on gig
ethernet so that's my bottleneck but
being a very small business myself
having gig
ethernet and being able to edit video
over
one gig a second is is stellar it's
superb
um well the the trick you know for that
like because my job was breaking those
kind of bottlenecks uh
previously is i would put a 10 gig
uh on your server and have a switch that
distributes it out to
your gigabit clients and and until you
uh get a 10 gig uh or desktop or
something but
you could always go you know like uh do
it gradually just like adding
uh ssds to your uh uh legacy systems
yeah uh that's a good idea just to kind
of upgrade the the networking
as i go that's the next step what kind
of longevity am i going to be looking at
for ssds i know like when ssds first
came out so years ago
there were those of us who were hesitant
and afraid to switch to ssd
because the they weren't quite as
reliable but that has completely changed
over the past several years are we
seeing like what kind of lifespan do we
expect from
like your your data center drives uh
so our data center drives we warrant
them for five years uh
and then you know like the they have
different um
drive rights per day warranties as well
so
like the dc 500 that's a 0.3 drive right
per day so
if you have a four terabyte or a three
three point
uh was it three point eight six uh
if you have a four essentially there's
four terabytes in the end on there
but if you have like a four terabyte
drive or an eight terabyte drive
of the r which is a read centric model
you can get
up to you can do uh 0.3 drivewrites per
day
the m version of that is 1.5 drive
rights per day
and if you think about that for a four
terabyte drive
that's a lot of writing yeah if you're
riding uh
you know like six terabytes a day uh
you might be running facebook off of
your uh server i don't know
that's a lot of data to fill up and
delete
because that's it's not so much about um
you know like if you're just collecting
drives or collecting data on your drives
that's what the r
is all about right so the read centric
one
if i want to like have a database full
of video
and images and text files and
spreadsheets and
stuff that's going to live there forever
the
dc 500r is a really great drive because
i'm just adding stuff to it all the time
i'm not
adding you know like a terabyte at a
time and then calculating that data and
deleting the whole thing and and putting
in the answer that's another terabyte um
you know that that's something like uh
uh lamp where you've got
you know apache server and and or an
oltp server or you know some kind of
online transaction thing where
you know uh you're you're just grinding
through the data like you know
facebook where you're just adding new
cat videos all the time and then
deleting them as they get old
right um you know uh most people don't
do that like i i've got a
drobo uh server that i just add stuff to
constantly so
uh i actually had to unplug it because
it's so loud because of all the hard
drives
i'm gonna put uh four four terabyte ssds
in there perfect that'll make it quiet
yeah yeah
it's pretty quiet all of a sudden it's
interesting you say that like
because that's the other thing that we
don't necessarily think about with the
upgrade is this
the silence of them the energy
efficiency yeah
i i have to say that ssds
uh compared to hard drive
energy efficiency hard drives are
actually really good at when they're not
being used
shutting down like they've they've
really gotten good at being energy
efficient and
and i don't think that anybody's
replacing
hard drives with like
well they have that's exactly what we
are exactly replacing hard drives
but they have their places like if i
want to store
40 terabytes of data that's just cold
data that i'm not going to access all
the time but i really i need for legal
reasons or
you know like to make me feel secure or
it's my backup
that's a perfect use for hard drives if
you have data that you want to be able
to read and work off of
hard drives are terrible for that just
because of the latency and you know it's
like
if you're one user and you
are getting the data off the hard drives
it's bad enough to have to wait for it
but if you've got like 10 users
or even you know three or four users
that are all hitting that
uh hard drive array at the same time
you can start you know like hey you know
like why why is everything slowing down
so much and it's like
um you know you'll also see a lot better
multi-user uh efficacy happening when
uh when you go to uh ssds
just because of the latency lots of
great information i mean i'm
all kinds of thoughts going through my
head i'm thinking about how some servers
like you've got multiple users all
connecting for
samba shares and accessing files or even
accessing things like their bookkeeping
software
simultaneously on a single spinning hard
drive in a
system or something that's like the the
difference in the well if
you think about the the uh vm language
of
spin up uh uh virtual machine yeah
uh when you are coming off of uh uh
sata drive there's still a little spin
up time but it it's
like a fraction of uh what the spin up
time
because it really is a spin up time off
of hard drives
and then if you go to nvme it's it's
almost like it was in dram you know it's
like because the nvme drives
being the you know it's off the sata bus
and on to the pcie bus it's one step
closer to the processor
that's why like dram is the best because
it's on the processor right sure
even the you know i guess the cache and
the processor
is on the processor but it's also not
connected to your uh
display and and all that so
dram is sort of the king and which we
also make there
there's all these um kind of irrelevant
almost benchmarks of
people turning on their computer and how
long does it take to boot and it's
and it's it's kind of irrelevant in so
many ways and it makes me think about
those spinning
those drives spinning up we have such a
uh
we have a tendency to look at okay when
i click on something how quickly
does it happen how quickly does that
application come up
and for me in this scenario how quickly
am i able to open
large video files in my editor and right
that's like where yeah i'm not having to
wait for
for that that moment is just an instant
moment for me
i would do uh so i a lot of the i would
create demos for when we go to trade
shows like nib the broadcasters
uh north american broadcaster show or
ibc
in amsterdam uh i'd create some demos
with adobe
and uh you know one of the things that
we'd have to do there is like if we're
editing 8k or you know 4k or 8k video
you have to make sure that the clips are
long enough to blow out any
dram that you have uh you know because
if
you know like if i'm editing and it's
really small files they could all just
live in dram
or you know and i wouldn't know the
difference you know it's like it could
be
coming off a hard drive but the first
time i read it it's really slow but
after that it's nice and fast
uh because the f if the files are tiny
but if you are trying to pull
like 4k still frames rather than an avi
or
time you know that because avr quicktime
might be able to
be stored in if you have 64 or 128 gigs
of memory in your
system right you might be able to store
most of the video there
but you don't really see the performance
of the ssds until you
have something that sort of outmatches
the amount of dram that you have
available to you
mark if i may change directions just a
little bit
as we approach closing our interview off
one of the things as a business user
that are that's really important to me
is knowing that i can get support when i
need it
and throughout the course of this
process in upgrading my server
one of the things that really stands out
to me is the fact that your team was
there for me
every step of the way is that
is that pretty typical of kingston uh
before i worked here i
i didn't know that much about kingston
i've worked here for a couple of years
now
and one of the things that really blew
me away was the level of support so
uh if you have a whether you have a
problem with like a a
hyperx uh microphone like this or
a headset uh or a keyboard or dram
or an ssd if you call our support number
we have people here in southern
california in orange county that answer
the phone there's not a data center
somewhere around the world so during the
day
it's going to be people in orange county
if you call at three in the morning it's
going to be people in england
very good so we've got a
really great support where if you have a
real problem that they can't solve
with uh you know the all their known
database of issues
uh it ends up to me in the engineering
team for ssds
if it goes to us um like
within a half an hour it's in our
inbox and and you've got like a whole
engineering team from
uh southern california to uh europe
and and taiwan that are all dealing with
it uh personally so
fantastic i think that's one of the big
differences like i
i've had problems with uh drives from
other manufacturers that i've worked at
other manufacturers and
and i couldn't get anybody to support me
at the manufacturer that i worked at
previously wow
that's great and there's something to be
said for good support absolutely
now you mentioned the hyperx line of
consumer products of course i've
experienced it from the enterprise
kind of level um is this
you know level of support something that
can be expected from
consumers as well as business users
well yeah absolutely like i was saying
like uh we've
we've actually had people you know like
with broken keyboards or
you know it's it's uh you know it's it's
all one number every kingston and uh
you know has the hyperx brand for gaming
but we also do
you know high-end uh server products
dram
and ssds uh for the data center
as well as you know consumer dram and
consumer ssds and
usb sticks from consumer ones to
all the way to the encrypted ones with
keypads on them
one of the other things that also
surprised me coming from another
uh company to kingston was uh the level
of testing so
a hundred percent of our data center
uh ssds and and dram they're they're
there is every piece is tested uh
they've you know like they uh the server
stuff goes through a more rigorous
test uh but they simulate like three
months worth of uh
uh uh use on the d
on the dram side and and uh uh
like all the ssds are tested at uh
in an oven basically while they're when
they're being manufactured they're all
tested
at a high temperature to make sure that
they are uh
functioning in an optimal fashion
fantastic
well mark it has been a pleasure having
you here i appreciate your knowledge and
and sharing with us about
about your ssds and everything else that
kingston is up to
um how have things you know in closing
and closing today um how have things
changed in 2020 for you folks like
are you still um you know are you
working in the office and
and have things been being manufactured
and available to you
or how have you been impacted well
so uh there's there's been some impact
that the main thing like my job has
always been a customer facing and going
to
visit clients so i'll go with
salespeople
um and travel with sales people and go
visit clients in person which that's not
happening right now yeah
but but we're you know doing that
virtually uh
lots of uh phone calls zoom meetings
like everybody else
um you know uh our office actually is
considered an essential industry so
um because we do manufacturing ssds are
critical components
right we make a lot of stuff that's used
in you know servers
around the world and uh and
vital to the government so we we can't
just shut
our operation down and uh and we've
actually been continuing
uh the manufacturing side pretty much as
normal you know we
we have a lot of uh protocols in place
for safety
uh all the the less essential folks like
me that
like i don't have to go into the um
uh manufacturing department and and uh
put stuff together
so i can do things from home and on the
phone so
i go into the office maybe once or twice
a week
uh and and uh people on my team are
pretty much in that
realm and then um you know there are
other people there that
go in but you know like when we go in
we've got like a camera that
uh measures our temperature and uh
and all all kinds of safety protocols
everybody's
you know like there's i don't think
there's anybody within
80 feet of my desk when i go into work
we're all we're all pretty spread out
we're i think we're only at like uh
about 10 10 to 20 capacity of people
that are
in the office at any one time good well
keep up the great work and stay safe and
kudos to you and your team and
and uh i mean this is this is
an amazing upgrade for our studio these
dc500rs
and i'd encourage anyone who's
considering upgrading the
the drives at their uh in their server
room and their data center no matter
what scale i guess that's the thing
right mark it's
it doesn't matter if you're just a small
business with a few staff
or a big business running facebook as
you say
it's going to make a huge difference in
your in your data center
faster is faster it's like uh and and
less frustrating
that's true that's true nobody wants to
spend time after they click on something
you know it's like uh
i think amazon's whittled that you know
like how much how much a millisecond of
wait time is
you know in lost sales right yes between
the time i click
and the time i get a response there's a
the the
chance that i'll just cancel everything
and walk yeah it goes way up right so
uh everybody deserves that uh for their
own stuff
at their home or their office
like the way you think thank you mark
appreciate your time
oh you bet thank you all the best take
care appreciate it all right
cheers here's what's coming up in the
category 5 dot tv newsroom
there will not be ascent os linux 9.
debian officially supports the pine book
pro the eu is pushing for home workers
to have the right to disconnect
and scientists have created a plane that
flies without fuel
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5 tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
if you enjoy your weekly tech news with
a slight linux bias become part of our
fleet
choose your rank at patreon.com
category5
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
prepare to find your next distro centos
sysadmins
there will not be a centos s9 for years
centos has been a stable open source
release based on and functionally
compatible
with red hat enterprise linux that all
ended this week in what some users are
calling a betrayal to the foss community
when red hat announced it is severing
support for centos
and the centos team simultaneously said
they're moving to a rolling release with
their centos
stream distro a user commented on the
centos blog post saying this is dumb the
entire premise and the only reason
anyone uses centos is because it's a
rebuilt red hat enterprise linux
congratulations on undermining that
nitwits
the op received many plus ones for their
spot on insight
will this mean transitioning to a centos
stream
will the shift to a rolling release
result in more admins looking at trusted
alternatives such as ubuntu or debian
red hat said in their announcement
tuesday we believe that the real value
of open source lies in innovating and
solving problems
and have learned that a rebuild or clone
doesn't provide that opportunity
are you a centos user do you feel
betrayed by your trusted distro
or are you excited to see what's next
with a centos stream
comment below updates for the centos
linux 8 distribution will continue
until the end of 2021 centos linux 7
users will thank the stars they chose
the lts
since support will continue until june
30th 2024
centos stream nine will launch next
summer i am not a red hat user
um so it doesn't impact me
uh but i know good for you jeff but i
can i can see how this would have a
significant
impact to just suddenly walk away now
thankfully they're taking a year to
transition
but how do you just cut ties like that
yeah and now i am
i'm also not a red hat user centos user
i'm very much a debian baby as
our viewers know absolutely yeah i love
debian and debian derives
but in this case now who does this
impact i mean i've got customers who
who do use centos i know some sysadmins
who use centos and in fact my church
uses centos
as their email service um server okay
and so it leaves them in a weird
situation where okay
you know hey i've been trying to
transition them over to
you know some some other service for
some time but now it comes down to okay
now
the varied operating system the very
distribution that you are
using for your main server is no longer
supported
right and is being cut off and and all
ties are being cut off from red hat
so i mean it is really a burn um
you know we're going to see in the next
coming months because
you know a lot of stuff right now is
what is the reaction of the user base
and so some of the news comes from
that reaction so what's the response of
the sysadmin well the response is like
we feel betrayed
right but the one thing and i do
somewhat agree with the comment
from from red hat is that you know the
community is about
advancing and growing and developing as
opposed to just
building off something that's older so i
get why they want to make this movie i
don't even know if that's the point it's
more like
centos is basically an
alternative to yes red hat enterprise
linux
red hat enterprise linux of course
requires the purchase of
licensing yeah so
does that come into play where well we
don't really want to support
the clone that everyone is using
because we don't get paid for it again
you know don't
shoot the messenger i'm you know a lot
of stuff right now it's very very fresh
in the news
comes from the reactionary response of
the assisted men
and and right now it feels like red hat
has
pulled the plug on something great and
it's gonna hurt a lot of people
and and not only like hurt but like it's
really tough
to suddenly have support yanked out from
under you
on a distribution that you've been using
for 10 years and how
easy and i say that kind of
tongue-in-cheek
how easy is it to walk away from that
and switch to a new system like
i think like for anybody who's using it
i'm you know thinking your church
they have to build a whole new system
essentially
like that's what simple here's the
choice
the choice becomes do we now
transition to centos stream
which is a rolling release which is what
sent os
that was the appeal of centos is that it
was not
a rolling release yeah so now do we go
to
centos stream and become a rolling
release or
do we start looking at debian which is
going to fall under that category ubuntu
is very well supported by
canonical um so it opens up
now now we need to start looking at okay
well if
if we're no longer going to be on this
what we what we're going to call a
stable release and what i mean by that
is not
not that anything else is unstable in
the traditional sense but
we've got two different release models
yeah you've got that like
here's a distro that you can install and
it's just going to continue maintaining
itself
for years versus the rolling release
cycle where you need to keep it up to
date all the time you need to upgrade to
the next distro
or the next version of the distro and
could have some breakage in the in the
meantime and yeah
and so there's you know that that kind
of support issue as well
so do we start looking at other distros
it'll be interesting to see and only
tom's going to tell so
i wonder too how much this might drive
and not just the thought of moving to
debian or moving to
ubuntu but does this also drive us to
think
should we consider some of the cloud
options i mean if
the church says okay well our mail
server is no longer supported
so are we going to transition this old
mail server to something new or
are we just going to scrap it all
together and say you know what let's
just buy a nas
and use that for file sharing and go
with
one of the cloud options for email that
might be the better solution so
i'm eager to hear your comments below
i'd love to know how this affects you
how it impacts you what your thoughts
are do you fall on
the side of the sysadmin who is kind of
feeling betrayed right now by red
hat and even so much as to say feeling
betrayed by centos
or do you fall into the the camp where
it's like okay well i'm gonna have to
transition to something and it's
exciting and it's a chance to try
something new and fresh
where do you fall comment below love to
hear from you on the coattail of
ubuntu's announcement of official
support for the raspberry pi 4
it seems debian doesn't want to be left
out their next release contains a debian
installer enhanced for arm devices with
official support out of the box for
among others the 200 pine book pro pro
linux laptop from pine 64.
an alpha version of the debian installer
for buster successor bullseye
has added support for the linux 5.9
kernel series
and improvements to the rm64
architecture support
along with that come support for the new
arm devices including not only pine 64's
pine poke pro
but also the original 99 pine book
support has also been added for the
friendly arms nano pi
neo air and nano pi neo plus 2
as well as several other single board
computers from a variety of
manufacturers
could we be starting to see the
transition to an arm-based server room
post your thoughts in the comments below
we've still got a half a year left
before debbie and eleven go stable
but bullseye is available now as debbie
and testing so if you're particularly
adventurous or just really want to get a
debian powered pine book pro for
christmas
feel free to give it a try now becca
raises an interesting point
in that you know could this be the start
of a transition
in the server room we were talking about
centos and the transition there but
could this be the start of a transition
not only to new
distribution but also new architecture
i think it could i mean i i have i have
watched arm
grow and gain more um
user base in the last probably year it's
been
pretty significant it's happening
quickly very quickly and so i'm very
intrigued to see
where this takes things because i do
think
arm could really become the new standard
it's fast and it's cheap yeah and not
only that but to think
of all of the single board computers out
there that are arm based
i mean maybe there's still a hesitation
to put
um at least to rely and depend on
single board computing in the in the
data center
right and that there is some truth in
that and and part of that comes from the
reliability of storage so you think
about a raspberry pi with an sd card
well do you really want your entire
infrastructure housed on an sd card
probably not
no but arm is a lot more than just
single board computers and it's not
limited to sd cards you look at
things from you know boards from odroid
you look at boards from pine 64 and
other competitors to raspberry pi
and they all support emmc yeah and in
fact a lot of them
from both of those manufacturers and a
lot of other manufacturers are
supporting
um m.2 yes so you can stick an nvme
drive
on your single board computer yeah and
now you're running like something that
is screaming fast
super super fast super reliable and uh
that belongs in the data center if you
ask me i completely agree
and i mean right now you know in
my day job we're dealing with servers
and
you know all this kind of stuff and one
of the things we've been talking about
lately is getting
our own server and so what you know with
this story makes me think
are we at the point where we could run
uh you know take like a hosting server
or
you know you know a cloud server and run
it off
you know a rock pro 64 or something sure
why not where you've got it hooked up
to you know a whole bunch of terabyte
hard drives through usb or something for
the storage space
but that you're not even usb like i
think well and it has usb3
but think about um iscsi yeah
yeah sure right good example um but the
data center isn't
i mean sbcs flip the economics of the
whole situation on its head
because rather than having one intel
server with two
xeon processors and 32 cores and
and which are like gigs of ram power
hogs
and super expensive rather than having
one of those to do 10 different things
you just have 10 single board computers
doing those 10 different things and your
cost
not only up front goes way down but your
ongoing for the you know the actual
power that you're using
the heat that you're generating and and
the noise
from those big old servers i mean it's
really flipping it on its head
but keep in mind mac apple
are actually pushing their macbook pros
and the macbook air
and yes and um their mac lineup of
hardware into the arm architecture as
well that's right
one processors so we're really you know
it's not just
single board computer hobbyist stuff
anymore we're talking max
yeah which is huge and if we're talking
max which are
you know they have that kind of aura
about them of being
an innovative company and they push
trends and and
and they kind of shift the industry in
in so many ways
um when are we going to start seeing
real good
solid servers like 1u
2u 3u servers that we can stick in our
server rack in place of those intel
equivalents that absolutely happen well
we want to hear your thoughts let us
know
would you use an arm based
single board computer to run your server
where do you think this is going to take
things let us know comment below
send us in your thoughts now the eu
is pushing for home uh home workers to
have the right to disconnect i think
that's very important
oh absolutely scientists have created a
plane that flies without fuel
what what becca's got these stories
coming up stick around also robert's
here with the crypto corner don't go
[Music]
anywhere
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today i've got two things for you first
the first one is linked to the travel
rule
which says that when you've got coins on
one exchange and you transfer them over
to another exchange
the first exchange has to also transmit
the kyc
data so know your customers so your
street address passport picture
and so on to the other exchange
that looks like it's a law that will
come on an international basis
and that also means that if you want to
transfer those coins out of the exchange
onto your private wallet
this exchange has to do kyc on your
private wallet
so you have to prove that that private
wallet is really yours
how are they going to do that don't know
yet but it looks like that's going to
happen it's a law
that might happen in the u.s and if it's
happening here in the u.s it will happen
everywhere
so my recommendation at this stage is
take your coins and get them
off the exchange asap into your hardware
wallet or any other wallet that you have
because i don't know when this law might
or
come into into place the other thing
is coming um to trading so let's talk
about a little bit about trading
and i'm sure you have seen this here uh
like coin market cup or coin gecko and
you click on
on bitcoin here in this case and then
you've got the 30-day chart
and then you've got a lot of people
doing an analysis on those charts
yeah they they pull out the candles and
then they say this is a bull flag
or head and shoulders or in verse i
don't know what
and there are two camps the first camp
says
this can't be true i mean that might be
true on the large caps like apple
uh real stocks but in cryptocurrencies
they do anyway what they want
and it's an international thing so it's
not linked to a country like
like let's say apple shares this uh
cryptocurrency is linked to
many countries so why should uh
trent um be visible
in the chart the other one is saying
hold on
that might be right for ex for stocks
like here this is the apple stock where
you can do an analysis
and more or less fairly accurately no
not accurately but you can't predict
which trend the the share is um
and also a little bit in regards to
cryptos because
all those traders that are coming into
our area
um they're coming from the traditional
market they're accustomed to these chart
analysis
and therefore they will also apply them
here so if they apply them here
that means that uh they will be somehow
applicable to what we're doing too
but there's another thing that is really
interesting
in regards to um to
trading and that's uh unchained data so
in other words
data that is coming from the exchange
so not from um or from the blockchain
itself so not from the trading part
that is visible that you've seen on coin
gecko or market cap
is data that is linked to uh the
blockchain like
what are the miners currently doing
who's transferring data over to an
exchange
and so on and so there's a fantastic
website which is called
glass note they are they have got tons
of different charts
and if you go into glass note and then
you click on
market indicators then this is what you
will see
and just to show you that there is some
um legitimacy
in regards to those analysis so if we
take you for example
i don't know uh which one do we want to
take a look at the
pill pure multiple it doesn't matter
what that is
but as you can see here let's um
let's take that nut case away
so as you can see here in this chart
every time when there was an all-time
high or a peak
also this orange line went into
the red area so that means in other
words
if you read this chart correctly if an
indicator if this indicator goes into
the pink area here
that uh you have to start selling or
looking into selling your coins
it might be a risky area if you keep
them that's not the only one so there
are others that other indicators
like here we've got the net unrealized
profit and loss
again doesn't matter what that means and
i've got here free account so it ends up
it ends here in january 2020 but
an annual account only costs 20 a year
so it's not a big deal
but you can see here again when there
was an all-time high
uh the indicator this uh colored curve
went into blue
all-time high blue autumn high blue so
it's an interesting indicator i would
say
and here also all-time low red all time
low
red yeah so if this thing goes into red
means go and buy
if you think i mean it's not financial
advice of course
but if you you can more or less have
these indicators to really see
what the trend is and where the ship is
sailing to
i find it really highly interesting and
let's see where that will end up to
because this is just young industry and
a lot of things can happen
but i just want to make you aware of
these indicators that are on
that are representing unchained data
anyway that's it from me
i hope you liked it i hope you enjoyed
it i hope you learned something
as always i'd like to ask you for a
thumbs up
because it helps us in becoming known in
the market
and as always i'm looking forward to see
you next week again
and thank you very much for watching bye
bye
thanks robert now it may be confusing
when it seems like robert's giving
financial advice
and then we say we're not giving
financial advice well the fact is is
that we want to just
arm you with the information that you
need in order to understand how the
market works
so that you can make educated decisions
remember we're not
giving financial advice or encouraging
you to invest but only sharing what's
happening in the cryptocurrency market
at this time
always remember that cryptocurrency is
always changing
and always volatile now back to becca in
the newsroom
thank you robbie as the kovit 19
pandemic blurs the lines between home
life and job life for many
the eu is fighting for homeworkers to
have the right to disconnect
lawmakers have passed a non-binding
resolution arguing that homeworkers
have the right to be unreachable by work
the european parliament employment
committee voted 31-6 with 18 abstentions
in favor of allowing people to take time
off and urge the european commission to
create rules
that catch up with the new reality of
work
alex aguias soliba who spearheaded the
resolution
says the pressure to always be reachable
always available is mounting
resulting in unpaid overtime and burnout
many of us can relate how about you has
the need to work from home caused the
line between work and private life to
become hazy
comment below and let us know lawmakers
in favor of the new resolution say
workers should be allowed to be offline
without suffering employer retribution
as a result
the right to to disconnect in the eu
must now be approved by the full chamber
before it can be submitted to the
commission and state government for a
vote
no sorry i'm just taking a call from
work no you're not
you need to be able to turn off i need
to be able to disconnect
yes i'm busy doing my own thing
i i love this story and i like that
in in the eu they're kind of taking that
approach
to protect the workers because it's been
a problem now for quite some time
even before covid with the rise of you
know
e-commerce and internet connectivity
where people are not being able to turn
off
like i remember when i you know started
you know my former job in 2007
i think something like that and i had
the blackberry yep
and that was always with me yeah like
i'd be laying in bed
and 11 30 i'd get an email that comes in
it's like
oh yes you know and i never turned off
and it became such an addiction almost
not that i wanted to work but it was
like my mind was always going is there
an email waiting for me is there
something there yeah i love that they've
taken this approach
isn't it interesting though jeff that by
responding to those
pings you're actually training your
co-workers
and your employers that you're always
available
yes and and it's a hard thing it's like
where is that line and and
you know we're we're probably speaking
to a lot of it managers and
and folks that work in the i t
department and and realistically
i mean servers go down regardless of
whether it's past 5 p.m or not that's
right and guess what
we're the folks that have to run into
the to the office and take care of
things
i mean how many times have i spent a
saturday fixing up a server or doing
something
to do it work because something's down
and it's got to be attended to it's like
you can
it's not a nine-to-five job when that's
right and a lot of things these days are
not
nine to five jobs and you're lucky if
you have something that you can actually
shut down
and say call it quits at five o'clock in
the afternoon
yeah but realistically and especially in
today's
you know kind of covid 19 landscape
where
hey people are working from home and
when
the computer when the email comes in or
when the ping comes in on zoom
you've got to be there yep and you feel
like you've got to be there and and
maybe that's part of it too is
maybe employers have to say okay so
staff
here's our policy we understand that
you've got a life as well
we just expect you to put in a good
honest hard-working day
yep and uh and then deal with the stuff
that you need to deal with at home but
it's hard
i've been self-employed i've worked at
home yeah oh for sure and i mean like in
you know my former career as a labor
contract negotiator
it used to be the thing was you know
you've got your hours worked and then
there's on call
and then yeah like all the time on call
that's a burn yeah lexically
you're answering the phone no matter
what well yeah and so
those kind of things almost have been
lost because it's like oh you're not
really
on the clock but you're just always
available yeah
and so you know it becomes that fine
line between
going too far and you know dare i say
abusing the employees time
uh versus being able to have maximum
productivity and exposure to address
issues as they happen and so it i mean
with online work and whatnot it has
changed
the landscape of like you said a typical
nine to five
and most jobs that have gone online are
no longer nine to fives
yeah they're kind of you know your your
typical full-time work
but around the clock yep i env um
self-employed individuals who know to
call it quits at five
yeah after five it's like all right kids
let's
have fun yeah it's it's time to to hang
out with mom or dad
and uh you know that's that's a hard
thing to accomplish
when you are like only a phone call away
that's right and it's almost like you
know
your phone is in your pocket now and
you're you're stuck with it ringing if
uh
so it's like have a separate phone yeah
what's your answer i mean
we're all in this together what is your
solution to this
particular issue it may be a law that
has to come down from the government or
it may be something that you've
established within your own
within your own infrastructure of your
company we'd love to hear about it
comment below
here's becca a plane that flies without
propellers or jets and uses no fuel
sounds like something from star trek but
apparently it's a thing
the secret is to use ion thrusters which
also sound like something from sci-fi
next up molecular teleportation
the team responsible is from the
massachusetts institute of technology
they say the electro aerodynamic powered
plane uses a propulsion system to fly
which could lead to new aircraft that
are quieter and mechanically simpler
than what we have today what's more they
don't produce any fossil fuel emissions
alright to be fair we're not carrying
passengers anytime soon
the aircraft has a wingspan of just five
meters and weighs around two and a half
kilograms
but it works having taken two years to
create the plane works by removing
electrons from nitrogen molecules in the
air
which produces ions these are
accelerated toward the back of the plane
creating an ionic wind
which gives the plane thrust to move
through the air
wouldn't it be incredible to have an rc
version of this tech
think about a quadcopter and how quickly
its battery depletes
now put an fpv camera on one of those
ion-powered planes and rip through the
air at high speeds for hours
while that raises some frightening
militaristic possibilities
from a hobbyist perspective it sounds
incredible
what would you do with a small plane
that could fly without fuel
post your comment below while quite
inefficient at low speed indoor test
flights the group said that as the speed
increases
so does the efficiency in theory when
moving at 670 miles per hour
the plane could be 50 percent efficient
it's still only a prototype but
scientists believe that the future
possibilities are very promising
i think this is so neat that we now have
now granted
it's a small version but you have
itty-bitty you're what is this an
airplane for amps
exactly but you have this propulsion
system
that doesn't require fuel that has its
own ability to
convert within the air and keep going i
mean
in theory if you could hook this sucker
up to say
solar panels you could have non-stop
flight non-stop theoretically
unreal like that's wild becca makes some
really interesting points about
like quadcopter flight and yeah i love
flying my quadcopters but
she's right the battery is like in some
of them it's like 15 minutes flight time
and so you buy extra batteries so that
you can swap them in the field and you
get you know 45 minutes flight time but
you're still dealing with the fact that
the battery doesn't last very long
if you ever shoot any video in the air
it's the same kind of thing like you get
up there you take some video and then
you got to land and take it
change the battery yep well here's an
opportunity something that can actually
uh power itself essentially yeah but
will it ever see
passenger flight that's the thing like
so
it's more like it's gonna be tough yeah
it's gonna be more i think
um you know smaller payload payloads and
this is where
you know i think in terms of a camera or
you know being able to to shoot video
but they're they're flying like an
airplane so
yeah it's going to be moving pretty
quickly so what about
now we've had um henry bailey brown on
the show to talk about
how he uses his quadcopters to shoot um
3d um uh imagery
so that he can then convert that into
unreal engine
and even 3d print buildings and things
like that
but looking at topography and using a
technology like this to keep
constant tabs on changing landscapes
or on like the we think about like bing
maps or google earth and
the way that they're able to recreate
our planet
in basically what to us seems like real
time like sci-fi
but being able to have something in the
air that can just fly around the globe
all the time taking this imagery and
shooting it back to their servers and
making it like
virtually you know much more real-time
than the satellite imagery that they
have now that's four years old
yeah right yeah could those be things
but you know what
what kind of things spring to mind for
you and of course you know in the back
of my mind there is that
nagging i fear that the military would
get a hold of this kind of technology
guarantee they're already using it i
know and so this is probably from a
military contract
yeah this is probably going through your
head and and
so there that is very ominous and it's
because this is a really really cool
technology but like so many cool
technologies
it could be used for good and it could
be used for we'll we'll say evil
but you know what could we do with this
that is good
that's what i'd love to know and that's
where my head went
like the what actually caught my
attention the most in this story was the
fact that it was indoor flight
like initially i was like oh they're
flying it outside but when they're like
oh our tests indoors i'm going hold on
this is indoors okay
so could you theoretically take this
shrink it down i mean who knows what the
components are are you entering a fly
no no not that small but like how neat
would it be if they could take this
propulsion system to the point where
it's
um you know for lack of a better word
levitation
where you can have a stabilizer it has
to be moving though
well it has to right now but if you
because it's taking the ions from the
air and converting them for that
propulsion system
so i don't know what you know the
airflow is out behind or anything like
that but
could it you know i'm i'm thinking could
it be converted to things in your home
where it's like
you don't have to worry about ladders
anymore because you can have
you know scaffolding or something some
sort of painting unit that goes up for
you
but i'm just thinking the internal home
use i'm like this could
change the way we build homes so that
you don't have people falling off how
does he come up with this stuff
what are your ideas he wants to build
homes and get rid of ladders this thing
is like
five meters wide and it can only tech
and you could just convert it that
could be any living space jeff anybody
living space
see i'm not confined to the initial
thoughts yeah all right so when it can
carry
a human jeff wants it to lift him up
onto his roof so that he can put up the
christmas lights a little easier
i don't perform my life's been up for
three years
give us your ideas comment below big
thanks to soul boo roy w
nash and our community of viewers for
submitting stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category five from the category five dot
tv newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
well jeff it's been great having you
here again this week being here
every time um that's all the time that
we have of course uh
big thanks to our guest mark noland who
joined us from kingston today
uh to talk about those drives really
really exciting stuff hey um
make sure you subscribe to us on youtube
linuxtechshow.com is a great way to find
us there
also if you love what we do please
become a patron patreon.comcategory5.
but that's all the time we got
so we're out of here take care we'll see
you again next week bye
[Music]
you