covering the week's top tech stories
with the slight linux bias youtube dl
has been hit with a dmca takedown by the
recording industry association of
america
the ri double a has issued a dmca
takedown on the open source project
youtube dl on their github repository
this is done under the guise of
protecting content creators from having
their ad revenue stolen
youtube dl however is often used by
archivists and users who suffer from a
slow internet connection
in order to allow them to watch the
content there are of course those that
use it to circumvent
ads but we can't pretend ad blockers
don't exist
which accomplish the same goal with less
effort so are ad blockers next
on the list here at category 5 we're
content creators
we post our videos on youtube and we
depend on the revenue it generates
but like the electronic frontier
foundation points out
we believe youtube dl is a legitimate
tool with a world of lawful uses
see we know we have viewers who are
watching in areas where internet just
isn't very good
we've heard from troops who watch our
show in their tents while at war
we have fans who live in areas where
high-speed internet just doesn't exist
yet
so we make sure they have access to our
content for free
with the hope that they will support us
through patreon if they're able
we received an email from a viewer this
week asking us how they can watch our
show while circumventing youtube
is it surprising that we the very
content creators who rely on the
revenue youtube provides responded by
providing bittorrent files of all 13
past seasons
plus recommended the download button
found on the page of every episode we
publish
on our website as content creators we
understand the need for
revenue it costs a lot of money to do
what we do
but for the riaa to demand youtube dl be
shut down
seems shady the electronic frontier
foundation
fights these types of battles on behalf
of open source projects
you can help protect projects like
youtube dl by donating at eff.org
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you