welcome to
category five coffee break uh to
my oh i got it wrong again there it is
to my left is whatever it is is doug
give us a wave doug thank you sir follow
him we've got sobu give us a wave sober
thank you very much
and then i'm bp nine greetings everybody
um so yeah i've had some fun and games
as you saw from last week my
uh my audio and video completely messed
up
on my on my old samsung phone i should
have shouldn't have mentioned the
brand i suppose but it doesn't matter it
is an old phone i've had it for years
and years and years and
as i usually do i keep my stuff until
the wheels fall off
i keep running it till the wheels fall
off uh oh your green background is
bleeding through there so boom
yeah i'm trying to fix that not working
so well yeah
i need to mess with my background i want
that bird that marshman's got going on
but trying a vain you know without
without fail to try to get across the
screen over there i want
i want to see that but anyway so i'm on
a computer now so i'm i'm trying out the
computer to see what
see what happens there um
and it seems like the video and the
audio sounds okay
just verifying it sounds awesome you
guys yep
sounds great to me no no echo
but i'm hoping it's a local problem i'm
hoping it doesn't come through on the
recording
we'll see what happens um so i've got a
new phone coming as well
um it's supposed to be there by now so
i'll probably go up to the post office
this afternoon and see if i can go get
it
so otherwise that's been that's my news
so i'll be you're to hate this because
the the laptops running windows
i know i'm not i know you don't like
windows
i am not quite so rabid about about when
i'm not running windows
there is one problem with this laptop i
tried to transplant my
two and a half inch hard drive it's a
ssd but it's a it's a sata drive
tried to transplant it from from my
other laptop into this one
the bios does not recognize it i don't
know why
it's a it's a known good drive it works
just fine
but the but the bios doesn't recognize
it so i don't i don't know what's going
on with that
we'll have to um we'll have to figure
that out and see what's uh
see what's going on um
yeah so i've got all kinds of new tech
um
going through i'd like to get the the
hard drive work
you know the sata drive working on this
um
and if i if i can't get it to work i
guess i'll have to you know call the
manufacturer and tell them hey
how do i fix this so you have any
do you two have any suggestions about uh
making the bios recognize the um that's
right try updating your bios
i did not it's a fairly new machine um
i don't know i think the bios is up to
date but you're right i could certainly
try that
um once you get in the box you could
also
check that the uh on additional drive is
not
deactivated in in the borrowers because
it was maybe never meant to have another
hard drive there's a slot for it
there's a there's a setting for it it's
supposed to detect it automatically as
soon as it goes in
um but it just is not it's just not
detecting that
um that drive and i don't know why
i don't care if it won't boot from it
well i do care obviously i wanted to
boot but
i don't expect windows to recognize the
drive
at all um even if the
but i i need for the bios to see it so
that at least
it will have the opportunity to boot now
it does have a little m2 ssd inside it
right now you know the little card type
drive and it recognized that it knows
it's there obviously because that's how
that's how it came delivered um i'm
almost wondering
excuse me i'm almost wondering if i pull
it out if i pull that m2 drive out
whether that will um uh work any
any better if it'll force it to go look
at the um
i think i've had this uh problem uh
15 years ago on our system uh
back in the day when um five
or six gigabytes uh hard drive was still
uh
no big deal okay yeah
it was common back then we were fitting
a friend of mine i think it was fitting
uh
system was back at my place and we were
trying to install
a second hard drive the system wouldn't
see it so
um we deactivated it in bios and then
booted up just to see what would happen
uh it was
a linux was installed on that and on
that drive even even if the drive was
deactivated in bios linux
could still see it and could use it i
think that drive was
115 gigabytes
so the m2 has windows 10
um home on it which is what i'm using
now
sorry zombie and
i have to give you a hard time because
marshman did too so
what you can try is if you have a
linux mint uh a live cd or a
can see both drives well for that the
only way that would work would
be if i could plug the the um
uh the cd player into the usb
port then it would have to boot off the
usb port right
or you could have a
a usb flash drive and just boot from the
flash drive
well either way though it has to boot
off usb whether it boots off the
actual thing yeah and uh in most systems
there is um
you might have to activate something in
in the bios but uh
if there is a most biosystem you can
configure it used to be at the standard
that
when you build it up there was a a few
applause between
two and five seconds which told you you
press this to go to bios and press dash
to go and one of the keys i think if
12 on many systems um it will give you a
brute menu
over what device to boot from and usb is
one of those but
the usb flash drives they are
you have to select a hard drive because
they are
recognized yeah yeah yeah yeah i'll try
that
the only obstacle at that point could be
that if
there's a cubit is activated then it
might
not i've already disabled secure in the
bios so yeah
there's also a there's also in the bios
there's also some kind of
um some kind of a system monitoring or
system location
setting in the bios i shut that down
real quick as well
i remember when security had been around
for two years i think
um stallman had
he had a talk um and then in the queue
in the question session and afterwards
um someone asked him about his opinion
on
on the secure bridge and he thought it
was a dangerous idea
it could be uh used in eternity it
wasn't uh as dangerous um it wasn't used
for lockdown
uh or other uh overseas but um one of
the uh
other um questions behind him and he he
him again
they said that he quite fancy the idea
of
having a system where he could actively
actively deny
a microsoft system from booting up
works both ways though doesn't it right
so yeah
nice yeah yeah
as i say i am not raved a bit i'm not so
rabid about whether whether i can run
windows on the machine or not
don't like windows but if i have
programs that need windows to run
because there's no linux equivalent
i don't have a lot of choice um i did
the same thing with my um
with my aviation software there is a
package called forflight and that only
runs on
ipad so i don't have a lot of choice
my only option then is to uh is to
to run an ipad so that's that is what it
is so
so mr doug what sort of trouble have you
been getting i mean what else have you
been up to well
the uh saga of my rp uh raspberry pi
continues
okay um robbie suggested trying to
change the date on it force it to have a
new date
and i tried to log in i wasn't sure that
would work but how did how did it go
well i tried to log into ubuntu and it
didn't recognize my login
although i had been in it before
successfully
suddenly it doesn't recognize my login
so i think the
uh sd card got corrupted oh no
so now i got to get a new sd card i
tried uh reflashing it
windows didn't recognize it after i
reflashed it
so i think i the sd card
got corrupted or the flash um
did you try this did you try fisk on the
uh on the sd card to see if you could um
yeah whatever think about that that's
the partitions and stuff
i think about fdisk in terms of hard
drives not
not uh portable media uh well they're
still
as as silver's already mentioned they're
still drives yeah yeah
they're still looked at as drives i
don't think they look at i don't think
they
emulate a floppy disk i think they're
more likely to emulate a hard disk so
but i think in any case i think they
would have
they will always show up in lsblq
and command i already threw out the
list block i already threw out the sd
card so
oh i don't know in that case yeah i'll
just buy a new one
well i hope you destroyed it physically
destroyed it you didn't just throw it in
the garbage did you
well there's nothing on it other than an
unreadable os
i don't know you'd be surprised at what
hackers can
can can retrieve well i had but there's
nothing personal
i reformatted it a couple of times
before i tried reflashing the uh okay os
so i don't think there's anything
readable on there
okay all right good the other thing you
could have tried as well there's a
utility
that lets you physically check the size
of the drive by
writing to it until it gets to the end
of the drive i forget the name of it
and i think it's a linux utility now
that that will test the size of the
drive to see if it really truly is
check one of robbie's old um uh cat5 tv
episodes because he talks about those
um and amazon you know a um
an sd card that you got from amazon
that says it's 16 gig or something but
it turns out only to before giggle so
when you actually test it
um ebay is good for that too they're
right oh there's those
fake sd cards no this i bought this from
walmart it said it was a 32 gig drive
and um when i tried to format it
it recognized it as 29 point something
gigabytes so that's about right because
you always lose some space in formatting
right because it has a little bit of an
os of its own
there's some well but yeah it's just the
amount of space used by the formatting
procedure
right yeah remember
floppies were still uh uh widely used
um i was always intrigued by um the fact
that you mean
you mean yeah
i don't know what that is
it's a 3d printed save icon is what that
is yes
i remember that the
labels on those used to say there you go
now that's old technology right there it
sure is yeah
um on the old all the floppy
drive floppy disks 30 years ago um yeah
on the uh the ones that you have and
then the the capacity
was listed that's two megabytes oh wow
is that a zip disc
no this is a trevan eight gigabyte um
tape oh okay
i i haven't used these in ages the only
tape drive i ever had was a tape
recorder that i had connected up to my
uh atari 8-bit computer one time
for a while until i got a district yeah
right
so and then
[Laughter]
until most people they didn't know what
they were um
the labels on the 30 years ago at least
the label on them said
two megabytes and it also said that the
formatted capacity was 1.4
yeah 1.4 yeah wow
that is a lot of space used yeah one
mating process
and i remember five or ten years after
uh
that i noticed that then they stopped
listing the
actual capacity i mean just a formatted
capacity
i can remember when the uh floppy drive
that three and a half inch floppy drive
was 1.4 gigabyte
that's true wait gigabyte no megabyte
was it megabyte yeah yeah
but it was a while ago yeah well these
are these are 1.4 i think
or maybe window side has 1.4 anyways
yeah it says it's let me see if i can do
this without messing up the
there it is formatted for
one point yeah there you go one point
four four megabytes yep yep yep yep
i used to have some of those i still
have it actually yeah oh yeah yeah i got
nothing
right don't have a drive that will read
them exactly yeah exactly
i i noticed that i've forgotten
a part of the label uh i think in
today's young people will uh look at the
flop with house and
think that then what is this air
playstation uh too comfortable
something to put their coffee cup on you
know yeah
and most people young people today will
um
playstation 2 yeah that's a good point
yeah that's a good point those were the
days
so inside this laptop is a space
for a for a um a 2.5 inch
spinning drive or ssd complete with the
sata connector that goes with it
and then there's a little ribbon cabin
the cable that just runs straight to the
motherboard well
surprisingly looking inside this thing
it's not much different to the pine book
pro
i'm here to tell you it
it has a binky little main board there
you go pinky little main board
but mostly air in inside this thing um
there's a big little main board and some
sub boards and just ribbon cables that
connect them all together so it's
very surprising how how small the
technology has gotten these days
but it still won't recognize my um
my my setter drive so i gotta i gotta
figure something out with that
well another thing that you can try that
i just uh thought of you know that you
mentioned you have another
oh i'm open to all kinds whatever ideas
you've got i'm open
take the existing uh drive and uh plug
it into the
order just to see if that works
on that connection provided it is the
same same type of drive
so the existing drive is
a um is an m2 card
ah not a sata drive there's only room
for one starter driving here
um if i take that if i take the
ssd and plug it into an adapter
that's a sat adapter on one end and a
usb
plug on the other end i can plug it into
this it'll spin it right up no problem
at all
so windows and this pc will recognize
this laptop will recognize
the um the the the sata drive
it it works the sata drive works
it just won't work through that cable to
the main board
and i don't know if the cable's bad or
or what the deal is
is the cable part of the computer or can
you replace it
i can replace it i'd have to buy another
one from from the manufacturer yeah
i definitely try replacing that cable
yeah yeah yeah well it came with the
machine it was already there it was all
ready to plug in
so yeah so i agree with you that would
be the first step would be to try
replacing that
that cable and see what happens that's
what i would do and if that doesn't work
send it back and say all right fix it
what brand is the computer it's it's a
bill
okay well they're usually pretty good i
i suspected so as well i've had good
luck with dell that's the first time
i've had a problem with it
and all i can think of is that there's
some misconfiguration
um but one of the things i do want to
try is to
probably take out the coin battery to
reset the bios completely to fresh
to a fresh bios yeah um then
take out the m2 uh the little
card yeah and then put that and then put
the sata inside
yeah make that the only os right right
make it the only drive that it can boot
from see if it recognizes that yeah and
dell is usually easy to work on too
yeah they are that's why some of the
easiest computers i've worked on
yeah yeah yep yep as i say i've had good
luck with them so
um so it was rather disappointing to
to not be able to boot linux on it so
right
right we'll see what happens we'll see
what happens
sober what have you been up to oh
firstly doug did you ever resolve your
um
your raspberry pi issues because we
started talking about something else
no um i i threw out the
sd card i got to buy a new sd card okay
re-flash it and try again yeah wow you
are just having all kinds of issues with
that aren't you
yes i'm sorry i'm sorry when i get my
stimulus maybe i'll go
buy an odroid or something there you go
if that works better yeah
that'll work certainly couldn't work any
worse
we should have a minute of silence in a
memory over
his old drive yeah
no yeah
all right so what sort of trouble have
you been getting up to in the in
in nelix's kitchen over there uh
he had given me some delicious dinner
spaghetti and um yeah so
um today i have been yeah
my friend has this a big server um on
our shared server and he have uh
we have a few vms on one of them he has
on a next cloud
instance we upgraded the um yeah
reinstalled the front sketch and he um
he wanted to have a new kind of setup
now that he
know how it works and what he wants so
uh we have been not
updating to this to the uh newest uh
next cloud version so
this is next cloud running on your local
machine
running on a local machine on a server
on a computer in the data center
very the the the next cloud
runs in a virtual server on our server
okay
okay but it's it's it's your hardware
yeah okay well that's better than using
someone else's computer anyway
i guess that was the point i was trying
to make i wanted to make sure it was it
was
not someone else's computer that you
were actually dealing with
it used to be uh his computer but we
shared on the monthly bill and now we uh
five years ago we uh upgraded to uh
a faster server and and now uh
we only uh the half each and i believe
and i pay all the bills so
oh okay wow getting up in the world
yeah there you go there you go so it's
in a data center so you have
easy access to to the internet is that
why
or is it just it's managed better than
you could at that
at the house i guess yeah he's my
teachers
and my friend here in back in 2004 and
five
uh we used to have a shell accounts on
uh
on other server providers where we
we had we used to run
irc clients in order to be um and i i
run a couple of the egg drops and so on
okay
wait for that and then one of the one of
the
cool things about these kinds of survey
was that they had their
um one of them i think had
a hundred ip addresses that we could
select from wow
yeah and they had their host names and
ptr
yeah so his dream was to have um to
start
some type of server along those lines
and have ip addresses
where um without an obscene
names were they english curse words or
were they swedish first words or no
norwegian no combination oh
nice one of the most used domains
it was on norwegian but um it translates
lucy to um yeah
the sex school so and with all kinds of
serve domains
on there yeah so he didn't he didn't
want to use that
for too long so i've been looking a
little bit into
um uh into running my own mail server
um and it's it's it's
complicated a lot to it this is not
something you want to do lightly this is
something that you you should uh
think carefully through before you
actually do it
you have to look at it yes you do how
how
long did it take you to um uh to get
yours set
up oh about a year
wow from the time you decided to do it
to the time it started working properly
from there it took a year for me to
learn how how it worked
and when i knew how it worked then i
moved it uh in a
in-house and what term okay and why i
started with a mail server called uh
send
mail which was um but i knew that
it was uh only level but i only used it
to uh
send mail and out um i guess yeah
using like post fix right yeah okay
after three months i um
switched to postfix when i knew uh that
there was a no
there are a lot of there are a lot of
moving parts to it that's the thing that
that sort of surprises me
there's there's like three or four if
not more
separate services that actually run to
move pieces of mail from one place to
another
but even so that doesn't get you a pop
server
for you to retrieve your mail back to
your thunderbird or whatever it is that
you're using for your mail client yeah
for that
you have to have a uh the one i use is
something called
dovecot yeah i think i saw that in the
in the repositories in the in the linux
repositories that i was using and i
wondered if that was the appropriate one
to use
okay yeah a hard thing about uh hosting
and
hurting to get right when you're doing
this um at home or at
your own system is you get the
certificates right because you have to
have a public uh
valid uh certificate okay after
let's encrypt came um a year after they
came
we installed that on our server so we
had had that for uh
four years now uh but um um
and that's uh let's a group that takes
care of installing in
the web server software and i've uh
found out a way to uh configure that uh
uh any time that a certificate is
updated
then this is part of the let's encrypt
right then i i configured another a
shell script
to copy it uh to restart
uh three services okay yeah
sounds like i need to pick your brain
some more maybe we'll do that next week
and uh at the next coffee break um
we are running out of time oh i cannot
believe how quickly time flies when we
do the coffee break
seems to happen quickly it sure does it
sure does for some reason i always
picture and
peter in my head with the head in the
end
but i gave him plenty of warning i put
it up there i said
hour and a half away you know got
another yeah but if he is used to uh
only looking in there maybe uh yeah
maybe he'll come
maybe he'll come by in about half an
hour or so
my point was that every time that we are
in the end and you said yeah that we
have to hurry up um
i have had this uh voice in my head that
peter at one po
at one instance he said it's always one
minute
[Laughter]
so if you see this peter where we missed
you today
yeah sorry peter okay
doug any last comments before we close
this down no
i'll let you guys know about uh ubuntu
next week
please do i hope you have better luck
with the new sd card then
than your one than the one you threw out
so do i yeah
yeah good luck with that thank you all
right thank you everyone
much appreciated enjoyed it as always
and as you say it goes it goes quick
so have a good afternoon
take care everybody