covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias the latest
update from adobe's lightroom app for
ios
inadvertently wiped users photos and
presets that were not already synced to
the cloud
and adobe has confirmed that there is no
way to get them back
the issue first cropped up on the
photoshop feedback forums last week when
the lightroom app
on ios was updated to version 5.4
a user posted asking why all of his
photos presets and watermark data had
been removed after updating to the most
recent version through the ios
app store this was followed by replies
from other users saying that the same
thing happened to them
whether or not they were subscription
based or free
one user posted to reddit's r lightroom
subrevit
reddit saying that they had lost two
plus years of edits
after the update having spent more than
four hours speaking with adobe customer
service they report that adobe finally
said
the issue has no fix and that these lost
photos are unrecoverable
adobe provided nothing more than an
apology
confirming the user's claims adobe
officially confirmed the issue on
wednesday
explaining that customers who updated to
lightroom 5.4 on iphone and
ipad may be missing photos and presets
that those photos and presets are not
recoverable
and that they sincerely apologize to
users who have been affected by the
issue
version 5.4.1 has already been released
fixing the issue but it can do nothing
about the lost data
this serves as a strong reminder for
photographers to always have a backup of
your images in multiple places
so you're never subject to a single
point of failure mistakes like this
happen
even at some of the world's largest
companies
you