at category 5 tv we trust our files to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
whether for your server laptop or
desktop computer
you'll experience improved performance
and reliability
kingston is with you get ready it's time
for the tech
welcome to the show everybody nice to
see you great to have you here jeff
hey be back how are you i'm good good
it's been a while it feels like it's
been forever it really really does
it was christmas episode we did and yeah
here we are he's already used the cliche
behind the scenes tonight that oh i
haven't seen you since last year
it's true yeah yeah uh ontario canada
where we broadcast from is going into a
state of emergency
as of tonight at midnight so second
state of emergency yeah
so um that means the show is um
going to be a little bit odd over the
next few weeks if we're able to
broadcast at all so just know that
we're going to be here as best we can
within the within the
rules that are put forth by our
government and and we're doing
everything that we can to be safe
i was saying to our viewers before the
show that even though jeff and i are not
wearing masks right now we're being very
very careful we are socially distant as
best we can be
um and uh and we're wearing masks every
other time
behind the scenes uh and as of tonight i
guess it's
that's that's it it's like masks are
mandated and required
by law so um any shows between now and
i guess mid-february uh we're gonna be
massed up yep
so that's true and because of uh like
businesses have to be closed by eight
o'clock all the time
that's tough yeah that's gonna make it
even tough for the show because we start
broadcasting at seven o'clock eastern
yep
and usually we run an hour and a half
yep so even that or if it's a night like
this
a little bit later yeah yeah i want to
say hi to uh our discord our irc
i do see noman 5 myortix ameridroid is
joining us hey
the foo is here sad sac 963
uh who else have we got i saw marshman a
little bit earlier saying hi in the chat
albuquerque turkey's in there hey
albuquerque turkey uh we've got
we've got and we've got a couple of
folks that haven't yet set up a name
we've got some
guests in our irc that
automatically pump into our discord um
note that um if you want to participate
in
the show's broadcast so while we're
broadcasting recording live
all you have to do is go to our website
category5.tv click on interact and
follow the invite
to our discord server that's a great way
to participate or if you're old school
and you prefer irc you can join us
on freenode as well we're category five
on freenode could you imagine if we went
really old school and had an icq
chat yeah icq still exists
what are you serious yeah it's amazing
yeah man um becca and i uh so becca our
news
anchor uh we met on uh irc
really yes and then she married me
so well then it worked out that's
exciting so irc has a very special place
in my heart
wow look at that but you know speaking
of discord and our social
it's not just for live shows like
discord is happening
all the time like our channels just
happen we have got
my goodness there's got to be what 25
000. yeah 20 25 different channels
within the cat5 discord uh and it's not
just tech like we've got recipes and
food in there
it's like oh we sure do your entire life
every time i barbecue i'm posting
pictures
i know that's great there's so much good
stuff in there so
even if you're you can't catch the show
live it's a great spot to be throughout
the week
especially for tech questions and things
that are happening on the fly so
you want to get connected i like it all
right
thanks to our patrons for supporting us
uh over the the
past several months um just want to say
hey you know that's a really cool way to
support category 5 tv
head on over to patreon.com category5
we can really uh we could really use a
boost in our patronage um so if you have
the means to be able to support us at
this time
uh you know we're we're we're never the
kind of show who's like
hey no we're a free show and we want to
be able to do this for
free for all time that's right and in
order to do this for free we do require
the support of our viewers so
when you have the means and you're able
to do that we'd ask you to go over to
patreon.comcategory5.
there's a couple of things with the
pandemic and the lockdown here in
ontario
that have come to light that would be
really really helpful for us to be able
to purchase
that would make things easier for us to
broadcast in a socially distant and safe
way
and those things cost a lot of money um
when you're upgrading studio equipment
and things like that so
uh so you can help us to be able to do
those things and just to stay strong on
the air and be able to offer this show
free of charge yeah to everybody to the
world and and
i mean that you think well they're
asking they want money but
so that's not free anymore but really
like this is season 14
episode eight and you can go and you can
download
all 14 seasons on our bittorrent server
that's right
and uh and and watch all the old videos
some of the tech is obsolete but hey
it's a lot of fun to see how we've grown
and how we've
evolved the show over the past 14 years
and we couldn't do that without the
support of our viewers that's true
well jeff back on what was it
uh episode 33 of last season
so season 13 episode number 33
you and i had a discussion about
minecraft
yes do you remember that discussion yeah
on my raspberry pi
3 yeah my kids had been asking for my
minecraft server so we had some uh
subscription-based services online some
paid
and then i'm like well you know what
it's just it's just a couple of us i
really don't want to pay for this
monthly so then we found a free one
i was like i gotta log in gotta turn it
right off
like what if i could just make my own
server on a raspberry pi 3.
so i tried it wasn't great it didn't
perform well like it took forever to
load in very laggy
you know creeper comes along blows you
up and it takes like 30 seconds
for you to realize you've been killed um
oh my yeah it was not good
so then i tried the odroid xu4 yeah and
it was better
okay but not great yeah the xu4 is a
fantastic board but it still only has
two gigs of ram
right and i think that's the big problem
that is like the bare
absolute minimum for a minecraft server
and when you realize that
hey if you are just meeting the minimum
you're not going to see the performance
that you could have
and it probably would have been okay for
a single user
like if i was playing a single yeah sure
yeah uh but you want something for the
kids to play like i've got three kids at
home and they're like oh dad let's do
this and so i'm like okay
but of course for them they want to do
really cool stuff yeah that's
you know lots of red yeah so that takes
a lot of processing power and you need a
lot of
you know ram for that so it wasn't great
so you know we debated on the raspberry
pi
4 but i don't have one okay
i do yeah you do
and i think one of the things that
appeals to me
most about hosting my own minecraft
server versus
your original approach which was to use
online services
is that i hold the files yes
so when when you talk about a free
minecraft server
those those fly by night like they they
they work one day and then all of a
sudden your world is
gone that's right and that means
i mean us dads no that means crying kids
absolutely but on top of that the free
ones
are built off ads that's how they
that's how they do revenue so every time
my kids want to play like i've gotta
load up i gotta
win and it's just that inundation with
ads and i'm like
i'm i'm not like a deep state guy where
it's like oh it's watching us
but i like to avoid the ads as much as
possible sure yeah um so
okay yeah fair enough um and and
you know i talk about the the kids cry
and it's not about not having the
minecraft server it's about
they put a lot of work and a lot of
heart and excitement and and fun into
building up the world yes building their
builds and
uh and it's it's really heartbreaking if
they lose access to that
so using a raspberry pi 4 the question
becomes well is it powerful enough
right you talked about the pi 3 which is
definitely not
one gig of ram no way odroid xu4
you're approaching a reasonably usable
minecraft server but you're still
limited by that two gigs of ram
yeah throw a raspberry pi 4 in the mix
with
four gigs or eight gigs of ram which one
do you have four gigs you have the four
okay
yeah i'm looking at buying the eight gig
well let's take a look at my raspberry
pi 4
and what we're going to do is we're
going to actually see if a raspberry pi
4 is capable of doing this for us
running a minecraft server
and i don't mean just running one but is
it going to be good enough
yes all right so step one is that we're
going to
find out how to set this up step two
we're gonna actually play with it yeah
see how it works so let's head on over
to here
and uh i'm gonna see how we can get this
thing up and going
okay it's a common question we receive
and we've even discussed it internally
can a raspberry pi microcomputer power a
minecraft server
well today we're going to answer that
question and provide you with all the
tools that you need to get up and
running
the links are in the description below
but please follow along with us
throughout this video then you're going
to learn how to set it up
and see how it performs here's what
you're going to need
a raspberry pi 4 with either 4 or 8
gigabytes of ram
a very good power supply and active
cooling
since we're going to be overclocking
your raspberry pi to help get things
started quickly we'll use a micro sd
card but i want to be able to trust this
storage
so that's why i'm going to go with the
kingston endurance card which is built
specifically for write intensive
applications
this feature is brought to you by
ameridroid.com get your raspberry pi 4
or other single board computer to power
your minecraft server
at ameridroid.com american-based
electronic sales
shipping and support visit
ameridroid.com
now first up you're going to need to
install a debian-based headless distro
so that means no desktop environment and
no extra apps running
for the raspberry pi 4 the 64-bit of the
raspberry pi
os light isn't available yet so for now
we're going to have to stick with the
32-bit and this means that we're limited
to only 4 gigabytes of ram for java
so buying the 8 gigabyte pi 4 right away
is fine for future readiness and the
installer will accommodate this just
fine and allow you to later upgrade to
use more ram
once the 64-bit os is released but for
now
there's really no advantage of the 8
gigabyte model over the 4 gigabyte
because i needed a fancy name for the
project and because this installer is
built to work on any adequate sbc
such as the pine 64 rock pro 64
i'm calling the project pinecraft
it's simply not limited to the raspberry
pi so just make sure whatever system you
intend to run it on is going to be
dedicated and has at least
four gigabytes of ram let's get started
turning our raspberry pi 4 into a
dedicated minecraft server
i've connected to my raspberry pi os
with ssh
and the first thing that we need to do
is install git
so that's sudo apt install git
say yes that's going to download git
and install it for us and now get is
going to be a command
on our system so i can go get clone
https colon slash slash github.comcat5tv
slash and then the name of this project
which is pinecraft
like minecraft but it's going to work on
pine64 boards as well
so hit enter now we've got a folder
keep in mind i was in my home folder
when i ran that command so
where i am now is slash home slash pi
pinecraft now notice i'm using the pi
user because i'm using a default install
so please for goodness sake as the pi
user
type password it's like password but
spelt kind of weird
and then hit enter enter your current
password which is raspberry
and enter a new password please for
goodness sake do that because that is
just
common sense never use the default
password
that's one of the first things we're
going to do so
i digress look at the folder here that
we've
git cloned and you see a file called
install
i'm not going to show you everything and
explain everything here but if you have
any questions get onto our discord go to
category5.tv click on interact
but what i've done here is i've
basically
scripted the entire process of setting
up this minecraft server using spigot
so that you don't have to go through
each of these steps manually and so this
video is in three hours long
so this is basically the automated
process of how i was
able to get minecraft up and running on
a raspberry pi as well as possible so it
overclocks it automatically does a whole
bunch of stuff
detects how much ram you have what kind
of operating system you're running and
so on and so forth
i'd encourage you anytime you're going
to run any kind of installer script hey
look at the code
find out what it's actually doing and
and see this also gives you a chance to
trust what i'm doing here
but also it just is really good
information and shows you
exactly what i'm doing but this is
basically just the
installer the script that's going to do
it it is well commented so
i think you won't have any trouble
figuring out what it is that i'm doing
there
however if you have any questions let us
know all right so let's run it i'm going
to go
sudo because i need to be the root user
in order to run this
dot slash install because it's in the
current folder
and it is executable and then i need to
specify my linux user so
this is going to be who is going to be
running the minecraft server because we
don't want that to be
root right so if i type robbie for
example
you'll see that robbie does not exist i
haven't created that user the only
user on my raspberry pi is the pi user
which is default because it's just like
a vanilla
raspberry pi os so i'm going to instead
type sudo dot slash install
pi and hit enter and there we go it's
running so
first thing we need to do is accept mo
yang's eula the end user license
agreement so i've included the link
there for you
you have to accept that in order to
install
now this is warning me this is very
important now while
my raspberry pi server that we're going
to be looking at uh
with the gameplay in just a few moments
time is a raspberry pi with four gigs of
ram
i'm right now running this on one with
eight gigs of ram for the demonstration
so it's detected up here
that i'm running the 32-bit os so i'm
not actually going to be able to get all
eight gigs of ram i'm only going to be
able to use
four which is capping it off at 2.5
gigabytes of ram being used
by the game so that's fine it's still
going to run great but do keep in mind
if you've gone and bought the 8 gig
version of the raspberry pi 4
you have to use the 64-bit os but why am
i using the 32-bit os then
it's because they haven't released the
64-bit light os yet so
that is the desktop is currently in beta
and we will inevitably see the light
version of
of the 64 bit so keep that in mind keep
watch for it you can install this on
your pi right now then back it up and
then reinstall with the 64 bit once it's
released and you'll be able to take
advantage of all that ram
in the meantime it's going to overclock
to 1.9 gigahertz the default is 1.5 so
that's pretty good but conservative
because i don't want to void your
warranty and i don't want to cause any
trouble with stability or anything like
that so
it's just warning me that i'm going to
overwrite the config.txt file which
inevitably
uh when it does that it also backs it up
so keep that in mind you will find a new
copy
that has a date stamp in your slash boot
on that drive so if you get stuck
you're good to go it's going to install
the server now it's going to go through
anything that it needs to do
first of all it's downloading the
installer for spigot and it's going to
go through this process this is going to
take some time
so i'm just going to warp through time
[Music]
and there we have it all the steps have
been automated with the pinecraft
install script
and we're ready to start playing it's
really important for you to know and
remember that you can't shut down
or reboot a minecraft server in the
traditional linux way
if you do you're going to lose all the
blocks that are in memory
possibly a day or more of gameplay so
pinecraft includes a couple handy
scripts including one called
reboot and one called stop minecraft is
all set and ready to go at
load as soon as you reboot but
of course we need to reboot so we need
to do that safely using the command
sudo tilda slash minecraft slash
reboot it's going to store all the
blocks to disk
and reboot the pi that's the command
you're going to use
from now on similarly the stop command
will safely store your blocks and stop
the minecraft's
the minecraft server but leave it
running so that you can either then halt
the system
or run a backup or something like that
so both of these commands can take
several minutes
just keep that in mind because they're
going to be storing several days
possibly worth of blocks that are in
your ram
to disk so now that the new raspberry pi
minecraft server is rebooted
it's time it's like the moment of truth
let's try to connect
[Music]
absolutely flawless fantastic well
when we come back after the break we're
gonna give it a real world test
connecting
several players to a raspberry pi 4
minecraft server stick around
[Music]
all right it's time to check out the
gameplay performance notice that we've
got the cpu and ram stats at the bottom
of your screen
and that'll remain for the whole
demonstration all right so i'm here
at jeff's place and just going to kind
of quickly run around to show you the
you know that this is performing very
very well
so this is a raspberry pi 4 is the
server and
i've overclocked it to 1.95 gigahertz
it's got four gigs of ram and a kingston
uh endurance micro sd card all right so
i wanted to show
the performance with just me uh
everything looks pretty good and and
here at jeff's place jeff i guess things
should be performing
it poorly here if anywhere right because
you've got all these
animals and stuff and that's correct
yeah i tried to
to to build a base that was busy enough
with lots of elements and so there's
lots of animals making noise in the
background i want to try and tax the
surfer out
yeah okay so let's uh let's see what
happens as we start to add players
because i think that was one of the
questions that came up
when you and i were first discussing
this project was
you know what how many players are going
to be able to come on here
all right and uh i think i'm last to
join
there's mangled fox 70 yeah oh yeah jeff
maybe it'd be nice if you could join me
there he is that's a random one right
hey the one so
check this out
so we've got one two three four five six
seven eight people
online at once on a raspberry pi
4 server and a chicken and a whole bunch
of uh
animals in the background and there's
i'm not seeing a single glitch at all
no glitches it's hard to see right now
because it is late
late late at night and in order to
wow you're good uh in order to speed
through the night we all have to have a
bet
and jeff only has the one bed at his
place so yes
all right all right so we can follow the
one
oh okay you've got a shield i do not but
i will
i'm gonna be like your videographer
[Music]
done oh creepers let's avoid that yeah
these guys
these are the guys that if you get too
close they explode when you're
followed by a spider too and a bunch of
creepers
oh that was okay that was effective and
i see an enderman the shadow of an
enderman oh
somebody's oh
oh oh no oh no
chaos ensues
yummy oh no
okay nice i used the bed at your place
so
oh and there's zombies everywhere and i
have no weapons dude
okay we may have to just
wait out the night yeah you may have to
oh my gosh
there's an enderman yes i got an iron
sword
finally congratulations
do you guys see my stuff did you have uh
iron sword pants
and shoes yeah exactly but then i died
out in front of my house i think hinger
may have
collected your stuff um ball beard
i just killed a um
zombie and they had my no i did not pick
up
all that i have is
oh i got it here's my stuff oh that was
that was from the zombie that was from
the zombie i think
so bald nerd did you have this armor
here
that uh hingers wearing
[Laughter]
no that was the armor that i dropped
yeah the zombie picked it up
i did not know zombies could pick up you
um our viewers can see that the
performance is
like this is probably better than uh
more timer you would know because you've
played on a lot of online servers
how's the performance of our minecraft
server on a raspberry pi
uh compared to some of those online
servers
better actually this is better yeah i
would agree
i i have that's what i've been told
there's way less players though but i
mean
there i have a free server that uh
i've used with my kids and
we get lag issues when it's just the
four of us on
so the fact that this is a raspberry pi
and there's
what nine of us it's sorry my
my my internet just dropped out so i
lost you for a second there you were
talking jeff
well i was just saying that i have a um
a free server that i use with my kids
oh okay like online like a cloud server
online okay
yeah and it is um it can be quite laggy
sometimes
when it's just the four of us so this
performs
exceptionally better than that and i've
i've also paid for servers where it's
you know 60
a year and this is
better performance you don't have much
in the way of armor
but uh are you interested in following
me into the nether just for a quick tour
uh sure because that should be a
performance hit right that's loading
another world
yeah and then we're gonna have multiple
people in that world and multiple people
in this one
yeah let's do it all right
so instantaneous load
just be careful where you walk because
uh you don't want to fall into the lava
yeah i'll say all right
[Music]
oh man so look at the world jet now why
is it
that's not snow that's like from
stranger things yeah
it's the weird stuff that's just kind of
floating yeah okay
i'm just astounded
where did you die
were you were you here with us
i am so impressed with how well this
world jens
there's zero issues i was expecting
now i've i have no experience with
minecraft but i've seen
the lag that causes the world gen to
kind of
stutter on other servers
so i was expecting that because this is
just a single board computer
that's right but it's running great it's
running very very well
apparently this is the place to stand
i'm like safe from the rain right here
oh it's all around me
you fell yeah i put a cactus
on top and it collapsed
what
yeah i would avoid against touching
cactus
no i no it's not the cactus that killed
me i had cactus in my inventory and then
i dropped them on the ground
and like i placed it on the ground on
top of the sand that i was standing on
and then the sand collapsed and then i
fell into this
um yeah you know what i'm hearing here
jeff
what like i mean where the dads that are
you know the performance is really
really great on a single board computer
but the kids are having fun
well exactly i've got my three kids
sitting beside me and they're
they're having a blast so this is good
awesome i think it's a mission success
my friend
hooray so the next step for my raspberry
pi
in order to boost the performance even
further is
i want to get an nvme to usb
3 uasp adapter so
that's going to give me a solid state
drive
that i can run the minecraft world off
of right so that when it does that flush
the the storage in this case
the sd card doesn't get choked right
because an sd card especially on a
raspberry pi which
does not have a really great uh micro sd
card
uh reader writer it's pretty slow by by
contrast
to nvme for sure right um it should
get rid of that bottleneck absolutely so
that's going to be the an interesting
test
and i mean this was done on a raspberry
pi 4 with 4 giga ram yeah
i i can only imagine how much better it
would be on an ak ram
because possible yeah i mean we i don't
we didn't tax out the ram at any point
no and i was watching that buffer
i was watching h top there and and and
just kind of keeping an eye on things
cpu got pretty hot at some points and
because i only overclocked i was a
little conservative in in my case
overclocking to 1.95 gigahertz um
you could go higher than that but then
you risk stability issues and things
like that or
the the single board computer crashing
uh but the other
opportunity that we have is is with the
raspberry pi
uh 400 which does have a stock 1.8
gigahertz
processor which we could then bump up to
maybe 2 or 2.2
gigahertz that might make a difference
so that might be cool too
so i mean you can do this on on the same
method can be
translated to any single board computer
it's just making sure that you've got
enough power and enough ram but the fact
is it worked
it worked and it really wow really well
and i mean having com
i mean we didn't do the comparison on
the show but having done it on a pi
3 and android xu4 i was expecting it to
not go well
and you mentioned that it or more timer
mentioned that it it's even working
better than the online services
yes yeah and i i would agree with that
like
especially i mean at the top of the show
we were talking about uh or i was saying
how i'd use some free services
and the free services performed
worse than the pie and so you mean the
pie
performed better than the free services
yeah and even some
i like to put a positive even the paid
services uh
you know like five bucks a month stuff
like that like you know the bottom end
uh i would say that they were comparable
maybe like the pie kept up fantastic did
well and yeah
uh you know that was there was what nine
of us eight of us on there
something like that isn't that unreal
folks like and we did not tax it out
like there's
room for more so hey let's let's do it
let's land party
i'm game check out the links below head
on over to ameridroid.com to get your
single board computer
raspberry pi 4 with 4 gigs of ram is
what we tested on tonight
and anything as jeff is saying get the 8
gig
if you want and you're gonna probably
even see better performance than we saw
which is
pretty astonishing and there are other
single board computers and other
products there as well
and the links below also contain my
script
to set it up more information as well so
if you're not seeing that if you're
watching this on cable tv or anything
like that
head on over to our website category5.tv
and just do a quick search for minecraft
raspberry pi
and you'll find the video with those
links and the instructions and the
script to install it and everything else
oh yeah fantastic stuff all right we've
gotta head over to the newsroom
here's becca here's what's coming up in
the category five dot tv news room
the first ever super nintendo world
theme park
is set to open in february microsoft has
fixed a bizarre windows 10 error
mozilla's privacy vpn service is now
available on mac os
and linux and intel's newly announced
12th gen chip hybrid is set to compete
with both arm
and apple silicon stick around the full
details and this week's crypto corner
are coming up
this is the category 5 tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
if you enjoy your weekly tech news with
a slight linux bias become part of our
fleet
choose your rank at patreon.comcategory5
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
while a mario themed switch has been
announced we all hope for the release of
a new 4k nintendo switch pro this year
mario themed news keeps flowing out of
nintendo as they continue celebrating
the 35th anniversary of super mario bros
which took place in september we've seen
the revisited nintendo game and watch
and now nintendo has announced the new
game
super mario 3d world and bowser's fury
which they promise is a bigger and
better version of the game originally
released for the wii u
but our focus this week is on something
a little different
and a whole lot bigger we talked about
it way back on episode
604 in april 2019 but now
it's ready the first ever super nintendo
world theme park
is opening at universal studios japan on
february 4th of this year
a newly released sneak peek video tour
by shigeru mayamoto
creator of mario donkey kong and the
legend of zelda
walks you right into the atrium of
princess peach's castle through a
portal-like
shimmering green pipe from there
mayamoto shows you how to use decorated
smart wristbands to collect coins all
throughout a colorful
life-size version of the legendary world
just as in the classic super mario bros
game
punching up on each question mark block
encountered along the way
will release the coin straight into your
wristband replete with a satisfying coin
collecting ding
this wearable wristband technology is
linked to your smartphone
and unlocks the interactive gameplay
experience of the park
combined with the augmented reality
experience of themed rides this promises
to be a magical experience for visitors
of all ages
one such adventure bowser's castle is
sure to delight with its heavy stone
walls
looming staircases burning wall sconces
dungeon-like doors
and an enormous statue of bowser in its
depths
which as rumor has it just might be
animated
here you'll find the entrance doors to
an augmented reality mario kart ride
called koopas challenge
where participants will be able to toss
shells and steer about the mushroom
kingdom
thomas garatti senior director
innovation and global executive producer
for mario kart explains
guests will put on their headset which
takes them through the mario kart
universe
to experience never-ending excitement
and thrills
chock-full of the iconic landscapes
pipes castles and the beloved creatures
and characters of the super mario world
this 580 million dollar project is part
of an effort by the kyoto-based games
company
to increase falling revenue by expanding
its franchises
the park was initially scheduled to open
back before the 2020 summer olympics
in tokyo but both were delayed due to
the covet 19 pandemic while they are
doing
augmented reality what i found really
intriguing about this video is
that it appears like the park is all
physical
recreations of the gameplay which is
totally awesome
and i was expecting a nintendo theme
park to be like
filled with screens and you know
nintendo gameplay and everything else
but it's literally taken the uh like the
mario theme
and turned it into a real life park that
you can walk through to the point
where one of my favorite parts that were
shown in this
in this preview was that um
at one point you shrink
like mario shrinks do you do yeah
because the the
all the surroundings become huge that's
right yeah triple in size
and it's like oh my goodness the effect
is so
cool like you want to bring your
smartphone and start taking some
pictures
now i wonder if there'll be some sort of
like you know hey you can't film this
for i don't know i doubt it no something
like this
it's meant for kids well that's meant
for it's meant for
you these kids
it's meant for 80s kids boomers will say
yeah
[Laughter]
to take their zoomers with them
and uh and and show them what you know
it's pretty magical
i i mean i'm not a huge theme park
person
i mean like i remember going to disney
as a kid and yeah and i was like okay
it's just another place for attractions
and rides sure
but this is probably the first theme
based park that's legit
theme based yeah um that i would
probably go to
and simply because it is mario and and
the idea behind it
is mind-blowing like so the fact that
you can
take a video game and turn it into a
place and then they hit those elements
yeah
it's so cool and and i like that they've
got um
that interactive component yeah with
hitting the coins and
and all that kind of stuff because it's
not just about going and
and experiencing it it's about
experiencing it
which takes it to another level we went
to lego world years ago yeah
and and that was fun you can go onto our
website and do a search for
for lego and category 5 tv if you want
to see it but we took our kids there and
it was a lot of fun and it kind of
reminded me of that where you're you're
walking into a world that is
just lego that's right and you're
walking into a world
that is just you are basically
transported into
these video games that you and i grew up
with yeah and it's so magical now
what i can't wait to find out is who's
the first person that's going to slip on
a banana peel
and do they get away with saying oh part
of the experience don't sue us
the interesting thing about opening a
theme park
at the beginning of 2021 of course uh
you know like uh
japan you know last last i saw where
like friday they were at about 8
000 cases yeah and and so you know
how are they going to do this two years
ago when they first announced
this theme park there there was no
pandemic in sight
right but i mean at this point the
capital has been put in to build it
and maybe that's it like it's ready yeah
and when everything is behind us
then okay we can all go but will people
go
regardless probably not like not
travelers but locals
well i mean we just sure would we just
got stats as long as there's social
distancing and safety
sure is put into place which there will
be but look at the christmas holidays
here in canada
stats just came out that from was it
canada or ontario alone
4 000 people went to hawaii over the
christmas holidays
okay and that's in the midst of a global
pandemic so i can imagine
people people will people are gonna go
oh no
okay so stay safe i'm i'm absolutely
certain that uh nintendo will
um and universal studios in general will
have
um safety precautions in place and be
following the rules and everything else
but
uh something definitely to look forward
to taking the kids to
uh when things are a little bit safer
for sure absolutely all right becca
future plans include the opening of
super nintendo world parks at universal
studios
in orlando florida hollywood california
and singapore
microsoft has fixed windows 10s 60
60-second
self-destruct after upgrading to windows
20 h2 with the october 2020 update
some windows 10 users experienced a
bizarre windows 10 error
without warning a prompt would appear on
their screen to alert them that they had
only
60 seconds to save their work before
their system would automatically shut
down and restart
there was no option to cancel or dismiss
the restart and if a user happened to
have stepped away from their computer
at the time of the alert they risk
losing important unsaved data by not
being quick enough to do anything about
it
microsoft confirmed this back in
november explaining that some windows 10
updates caused
critical issues for certain
configurations with the local security
authority subsystem service
this was reportedly a filing conflict in
the system triggered by changing your
local username
especially the main admin account name
if your particular device was affected
this mysterious prompt might have
appeared and rebooted your system
these type of issues cropping up
following a windows update can be very
frustrating
have you ever had a windows update cause
you to lose data or functionality
tell us about it in the comments below
robbie have you ever encountered such a
thing
oh becca i tell you what uh jeff do you
remember our season 10
pilot episode uh where we shot
four years ago yes but you'll remember
because
it's the it's the episode where we shot
the entire thing
in 360 vr video oh yes absolutely you
remember that yeah
um shooting and
producing vr video is very taxing on
your computer
yeah oh yeah you had a ton of work to do
a ton of work
the rendering process of that episode
was more than 24 straight hours
just to render out a one-hour video i
remember that
and windows 10 rebooted
mid stream i forgot about that it did
and you know i'm not i don't work full
time at the studio and especially then
it's like you're there once a week and
you expect that okay everything's going
to be ready and no
it was sitting at the login prompt and i
had lost everything yeah because you
can't just
continue halfway through the round no oh
no no you had to start over
so needless to say yes becca i have been
through
similar situations um and i used to use
like things like notepad i'd have like
notes and everything up on my screen
about the show as i was editing and
things like that
um and then i'd head home for the night
and i had that lost a few times as well
and and finally i
realized okay this is not a this is not
for me so i saved
save my work always and yeah hopefully
never have a render
interrupted like that oh man wow
well at least this mysterious 60-second
self-destruct issue was finally resolved
on january 7
2021 the fix was pushed out
automatically
so you don't need to do anything as long
as your windows 10 device gets its
windows updates
however if you are working with custom
media or have updates paused
make sure you update your os 60 seconds
that's not enough time i mean
i would be furious thankfully thankfully
my system did not have this issue
yeah but for a while probably a year my
system wouldn't even do updates
oh really it would try and do it and
then it would crash every time oh wow
and then like a month and a half ago it
started working so i didn't have to go
through this
the worst thing is when that update
comes up on the screen
and you can't get out of it it's like
full screen and it blocks everything so
you're in the
you might be in the middle of something
and suddenly yeah you're locked out
now this is a case once again where
microsoft
has updated windows 10 and introduced
a problem that previously didn't exist
yeah and that i mean i don't have to say
that bugs me i think that
that bugs all of us that that kind of
thing still happens
yeah but we we've uh you know we've been
through this
it seems like it's a recurring theme
that microsoft keeps doing this where
they're breaking
systems and unless they're consistent
you know what you're getting
bugs you know what you're getting this
is where that
slight linux bias comes in and we say
hey check out linux mint
check out ubuntu check out ubuntu mate
yeah what else can we say debian
definitely debian just about anything
just not centos yeah it's
i don't know why this stuff doesn't get
caught first by windows
like i i gotta hand it to them i mean as
software developing
as software developers it's it's
virtually impossible to think of every
sure every case of every scenario um
sometimes it has to do with the
particular graphics drivers you have
like they just can't test everything
but you know in it
one of the one of the practices that we
have is
okay we're going to make a big change to
the network we have 1200 computers
we're going to push this out to five
isolated systems first
we're gonna see how it goes and then we
wait it out we see
how everything goes right great okay a
couple of days of have passed
let's push that out to 30 systems and
let's see if any complaints or problems
come in
and as we work through those things then
we feel confident and we can push it out
to the 1200 systems
right but you've got windows is on
probably billions of computers
right so why do they not have a test
well why don't they run their update on
all of their systems one percent
of those ten systems yeah let's
release this update to one percent let's
see what happens
but could you i'd hate to be the one
percent
yeah but at least then they could fix it
before
pushing it out to billions of people
yeah and i mean i'm sure
that this kind of i can exaggerate you
know like
it was isolated cases i mean i say that
sure loosely it wasn't
every system yeah but imagine if like a
government defense computer was running
windows and they were middle of
something important that's like you've
got 60 seconds it's like
yeah what uh-huh like
enter the disarm codes now
you have 120 seconds to disarm you have
60 seconds before i reboot
oh boy yeah it's unfortunate but at
least they got it fixed quickly
i will give you know microsoft that as
they fixed it
quick so hopefully some other other
issues hopefully you didn't lose
anything
yeah mozilla's privacy vpn service is
now available on both mac os
and linux and intel's newly announced
12th gen chip hybrid is set to compete
with both arm
and apple silicon becca has these
stories coming up also robert is here
with the crypto corner so don't go
anywhere
[Music]
go
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today i'd like to focus on something
that a lot of people are asking us
i'd like to get involved in cryptos but
i have no clue how to do that
so um let me focus on that today let me
show you some ideas on how to get
involved
and so there are a few components that
you have to think of the first one is an
exchange in other words
you've got your cash and you would like
to convert it into
cryptos and uh for that you need an
exchange
and the one that we recommend is
uh kraken so this is the kraken
exchange kraken.com k-a-k-r-a-k-e-n
dot com they're by far the best um they
also accept u.s residents
and they'll have got all the cheapest
rates
um or fees and also
they have got the best service so this
is the
exchange that i recommend the others
like uh
bittrex um coinbase and so on
but kraken is from my point of view the
best one so
you can wire transfer money over from
your bank account
into kraken and then you just have to
select
the cryptocurrency you want to buy there
are a few categories of cryptocurrencies
basically three
the first one is bitcoin which is the
old the grand ad
that's the most stable one um that's the
one that just
went well above all-time high
and you cannot make big mistakes there
so the
fluctuations of course will exist there
and as you can
see currently we've got a dip of 25
which is absolutely normal in this
market
but you will not have those 10x or 100x
that you might have heard of
the next level is ethereum and um
then the rest falls in into the third
category so i
as a beginner never get involved in the
third category because you have to learn
first how this market
works it's a little bit like horse
racing yeah so if you go
to a horse race and you start betting on
a horse
then of course you will lose your money
if you have got no clue
which host horse performs which way you
can bet on any horse
and the hope that that horse will win
but the likelihood is very
small and for that you have to do some
research
and the research is also very simple
much simpler than
with traditional uh in the traditional
market with stocks and and so on
and so if you go into coinmark gecko.com
which is our favorite
um directory where you find all the the
big um
cryptocurrencies and then you select one
that you like
let's say you've heard of um
let's take your celsius network and that
they've got a good potential and so on
and so you've got two options here you
first you can listen to all those
experts that are not real experts yeah
i mean you've got a few people that have
got insider knowledge
um but you'll hear also opposite of
opinion from other people and there's
nobody in this market
that can predict how the the values are
going to behave in the near future
so you need to rely on your own research
and that's really really simple
so first part what you have to do is you
go on to gecko.com you click on the
favorite
currency that you're interested in and
in here you've got all the information
that you need yeah so if you scroll a
little bit down you see of course
the trading view and then you've got
here the all-time high so all-time high
on celsius was 6.82 on the
third of january uh 2000 was eight days
ago and the all-time low
is beginning of to the end of 2018
so about two years ago that was the
all-time low
which is interesting to know that so you
know if there is a big potential
uh in regards to the price then here
a little bit further up you've got the
markets
and the markets just tell you where you
can buy those and this is also important
so for example you've got uniswap here
you can go
of course directly to unit swap and buy
it there you run
risk that you fall into a hoax because
not
everybody uh i mean you can launch a
celsius network
token on uh on unit swap
so the best way is to get to coingecko
you click on this
field here that will redirect you to
uniswap and there you can then exchange
your ethereum for example against
celsius tokens so that's one way the
markets
is where you find the liquidity
next one in regards to your research is
you go onto their website and just check
on how this looks i mean is this
something you would like to get involved
in
is this something that appeals to you
personally
do some research what are the people
that are involved are the developers
all those things next is you go into
twitter or telegram
both not so much facebook not so much
write it but twitter is definitely
important and telegram is important
telegram
is people like you and i that
telegram is a group where they we meet
and
we discuss things you know so if you've
got a question around the celsius
network
regardless of what question that might
be you go into telegram you ask that
question you'll get
for sure a very swift answer
so that's telegram twitter is more of
i mean you know twitter so i don't have
to tell you anything about that
so that's basically the research so the
research
revolves around um the product yeah does
the product appeal to you
then the users how many users are there
is this a coin
that only few users are interested in
then i would be careful because you know
that
if there are not many people involved
then it's unlikely that this thing will
go
10x 100x or whatever and then the
utility of the coin yeah so you can what
can you do with it is there already an
example the sample
so this is different to the traditional
market because the traditional market is
always around
the valuation of the company management
and also key figures of the company
yeah and you buy a share in the company
that's
completely different in this market here
this market is built on hype
uh we're currently in a bubble uh yes it
is a bubble and it will burst at one day
like they always do in the crypto market
and so
you only work towards this bubble yeah
and
once this bubble burst the equation is a
different one
you have to change your mind shift uh at
that
stage when will that be nobody knows but
until then
this is what we recommend to you so get
an account on kraken
buy with your fiat uh the currency that
you like
do a research beforehand if you're
complete newbie
uh focus only on bitcoin and ethereum
don't touch the others
um because you might make big mistakes
like with horse races yeah so you can
make big mistakes there too if you bet
on a horse that nobody ever heard of
so that's um that's basically
it uh from my point of view just showing
you a little bit on how to get involved
in this
i didn't touch anything in regards to
wallets or other things
that will come at another stage so focus
on
the exchange get your tokens currencies
purchased on that exchange but do your
research beforehand
so that's it for me it's an exciting
market as you can see we've been saying
that all along the time
so i hope i hope you get involved
not financial advice of course anyway so
thank you very much for watching please
leave us a like
and subscribe and come back soon next
week
thank you bye thanks robert just a
reminder that we're not providing
financial advice as he mentioned
uh but we're just sharing what's
happening in the horse racing i mean
crypto current cryptocurrency markets uh
always remember that the cryptocurrency
market is always changing it's always
volatile
so only invest where you can afford to
lose yes
here's becca thank you ravi mozilla's
privacy vpn service is now available on
mac os
and linux mozilla vpm launched in july
but only for windows 10 or android or
ios
devices the new availability on linux
not only opens mozilla vpm
up for linux desktop users but is our
hope that this will also mean the
service will be available in the budding
linux based smartphone market
with devices such as librium 5 and pine
phone gaining in popularity
for now though the system requirements
seem to hint to linux compatibility
exclusive on ubuntu
we'd love to know what the appeal of a
vpn is for you
is privacy of ultimate interest or are
you hoping to gain access to services
that aren't available in your area
or maybe a little of both comment below
and let us know
mozilla vpm users uses wireguard to
encrypt your network activity and hide
your ip address with no bandwidth
restrictions
they also boast that unlike some vpn
services they do not log your internet
usage
mozilla vpm cost just five dollars per
month and allows you to use it across
up to five devices the service is
available in the us
the uk canada new zealand singapore and
malaysia
with more regions coming soon it's
amazing what you can get for a fiver
these days
that's true no that wasn't quite a plug
but yeah it kind of is
um yeah five bucks that's pretty
competitive so and mozilla is obviously
an a household name that yeah that we
can all know and trust
so that's pretty great but i think the
key thing here jeff
and becca touched on it but the real
sense that i get from mozilla vpn is
that
they are aiming to be truly private
yes if you will in that they are not
collecting the data of
what you're using the vpn for correct
and so
you know that that has all kinds of
you know that can be good and that could
be bad however from a privacy
perspective because vpns are meant to be
private
it's important to realize that a lot of
the affordable
or free that's even better air quotes
free
uh vpn services that are out there a lot
of them track you
and monitor what you're doing and log it
and sell the data
and and so when you're using a service
that's meant to give you
anonymity and they're logging it
that kind of defeats the purpose if yes
yeah so and that's something that
mozilla has really
uh stepped up to to say hey for five
bucks a month we're going to give this
to you
and we're not going to monitor you we're
not going to lose what it is that you're
doing
vpns can be very very helpful we talked
about proxies on the show before
and it's sort of a similar idea but a
vpn allows you to basically place your
ip
elsewhere in the world so that means
even though i'm here in barrie ontario
canada
i can go on the internet and any website
or service that i use
will think that i'm in sunny california
yes and
so that can be good from an like a
privacy perspective because they can't
tell that i'm from berry ontario canada
but also it can allow me to access
services that i can't normally access
yeah up here in canada for example um
we have different services than
in america yes so and sometimes it
is crippled services and so that that
can kind of stink and
and you know maybe there's a gray area
there and i don't want to get too far
into that because
it is a little bit of a legal gray area
but we understand what it means and
um but where it can be helpful as well
is if by um
an incident that is not malicious
you get blocked on a service yes then
you can change your location
to that service using a vpn or a proxy
but uh
using a vpn in order to be able to
continue using that service and a good
example of that would be
um even so much as where i myself
from home have been working on category
5 tv
and accidentally put in the wrong
password yeah
my firewall says oh somebody's trying to
hack in block that ips address
so then i'll use the vpn service in
order to
to actually do my work so that's a good
example of where i don't want them to be
tracking
how i'm accessing my back end yeah i
want to be able to log in even though
i'm locked out because i'm going to have
to go into the studio and unlock my
my ip from the firewall because i just
lost access
or i can use the vpn to get in unlock my
access
see and that's there's a lot of good use
cases i i've i mean
with my work i view a lot of training
videos and whatnot and
and there's a couple times i've tried to
view different training videos on
different services
yeah and sometimes it goes sorry this is
blocked you can't view it in your
country
sure and i'm like why it's a training
video it's not like it's a
so i've had to use vpn for that um but
as well interestingly enough at our
church
uh we bought uh our internet services
and lte
um but the modem that we got
is uh or sorry not the modem the um
router uh no the sim card that's in our
modem
uh because we can take the model
wherever we want is a us-based sim card
oh so even though it's it's operating in
canada it registers as an american
device oh wow
and so we need to use a vpn to access
some of our services and
canada wow even though that makes it
even slower jeff
it really does that's another thing
about mozilla's vpn is they do boast
that
it's fast yes i mean i have there was a
vpn
service you know you're talking about
free services i purchased one
a couple of years ago that it was a i
you know
paid some money for it but it was a
multi-device vpn so i could use it on my
phone i could use it on my
android box all that kind of stuff and
uh
great why would you want don't answer
this why would you want to put it on
your android box anyway carry on
um yeah not for that yeah um
but uh we're strictly above board well
for me it's about i just don't like to
be followed
you raised a really interesting comment
about business and i'm thinking
immediately international business yeah
and
how some services that may be in use by
a uk partner i can't access from here in
canada correct
so there's another legitimate i'm not
being blocked from it because i'm a bad
person or a bad guy
no i'm being blocked from it because
it's it's like region specific that's
right
and so with an international business
that can cause problems
absolutely yeah interesting yeah
let's check it out it's really
interesting to see uh i wouldn't have
thought of mozilla for this kind of
thing though yeah well they're kind of
expanding
the line you know stay competitive stay
competitive that's right
check out the link below if you want to
check it out here's becca intel's newly
announced 12th gen chip hybrid is set to
compete with both arm
and apple silicon intel announced at ces
just this week that its 12th generation
chipset hybrid
alder lake will integrate big little
technology
placing it in its closest yet
competition with arm
and apple's m1 with big little
technology processors are multi-core
with
some cores being high performance while
others are high efficiency
this enables the device or desktop to
efficiently utilize performance cores
versus power saving cores
depending on each specific function
while intel's forerunning lake field
ships also use technology similar to big
little
they were only for mobile devices what's
so significant here
is that the alder lake chipset will take
the next major leap by becoming the
foundation for intel powered
desktops and laptops as well this is
definitely an exciting step for intel
but it has a bit of a feeling of being a
follower rather than an innovator
how is your faith in intel these days
are you considering amd or arm or will
you hang tight for the coming alder lake
performance numbers
post your thoughts in the comments below
just like intel's 11th gen tiger lake
chips
the 12th gen alder lake chips will
feature an enhanced version of the 10
nanometer superfin designs which will
include new high power cores called
golden lake
and gracefont while some of the some
people see this move strictly as a
competitive one by intel
others speculate that the move is to
appease stockholders who might be losing
faith in a company
that seems to lag more and more behind
with each passing year
though delays and long waits are
anticipated alder lake chipsets may
possibly be available as soon as the
second half of this year
now before we comment on this story i
have to give kudos to becca for making
it through
because our cottage is on eagle lake
okay and eagle in german is
adler oh okay so with a little bit of
dyslexia you're gonna take that l and
move it before the d and now it's
alder right alder lake oh my goodness
she hit it every time
didn't once say adler lake
so well done big.little in an intel
processor i mean that means
so we're talking multi-core processors
becca really broke it down and
you know i'm i'm impressed that
big.little is is really revolutionary in
that
when i'm doing really intensive tasks i
want my system to be performing
at its best i don't care in that moment
about energy con
consumption or um uh reduction in
energy uh however when my computer's
idle or i'm just surfing the web or
whatever i don't need all that power i
don't need the heat that it generates i
don't
so big dot little means rather than
throttling your
processor which is the old traditional
intel way which is you know take a
three gigahertz processor and when
you're using it at its max it's going to
be 3.2 gigahertz but then
when you idle it's going to go down to
one gigahertz
and and so you know that's the old way
throttling
this is multiple cores and some of the
cores the little ones
are simply more energy efficient so it
will choose based on the task
which cores are being utilized for that
task
it's quite interesting and that's
something that that you know
arm has been doing for a long time we
see it on single board computers we're
talking about the rock pro 64.
the rock pro 64 has six cores
it's a single board computer with two
big cores
and four little cores yeah and so it's
able to
really perform well when it needs to but
then when it needs to be energy
efficient or
just being used as a you know an idle
server it's going to utilize it's going
to
use a very small little trickle of power
right but that you know that alludes to
what beck asks
uh you know in the news there but are
they just kind of following suit
or they're being innovative yeah and i
have
felt it that way for a while with intel
like for
mac as well well yeah exactly but
for the longest time intel was like
the one to watch it was like if
something new was coming out it was
intel
and i feel like that's shifted lately
and they are playing ketchup
but isn't it interesting who it's
shifted to right
do you know arm yeah so
the new m1 chips from apple arm-based
arm-based yeah intel's new chips
are utilizing a similar technology to
what arm is already doing
and we covered this like a month or so
ago
like is because we see this coming
arm is already huge but they are taking
over
they are and i can't wait to have
armed servers and this really we have
the discussion about armed servers in
the server room yeah i
it never even crossed my mind about
big.little no
and so now i'm thinking oh my goodness
for my debian web server running on
these
extremely efficient cores and then
suddenly there's a burst of traffic and
mysql goes crazy and so it needs to use
the big cores
that's a fantastic scenario absolutely
i'm loving
where that's going but is you know where
where is
intel going to fall into all this it's
an interesting thing and then amd is
doing their own thing and they're doing
really really well at it yes
so it's a very competitive market we're
going to see a lot of change in the
coming years
what do you think hey becca mentioned it
but do comment below we'd love to hear
from you
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
we're on twitter at category 5 tv
and once again just a reminder to check
out our patreon page patreon.com
category5 great way to support what we
do here and help us to keep category 5
free for all time
yeah and for all people it costs a lot
of money to do this and we couldn't do
it without you so
thank you to our patrons we appreciate
you very very much
it's all the time that we have jeff and
rachel we don't
really know what the coming weeks are
going to hold no
follow us on social media get onto our
discord you're going to be able to
communicate with
us and chat with us and find out
hey what's going on with category 5.
we're here
not necessarily physically but the show
will go on it's just that
ontario canada is about to enter
an emergency state of lockdown and so
we're not sure what that means for us
just yet
but we look forward to seeing you next
time
whenever that is that's right so take
care everybody stay safe stay healthy
we'll see you soon
[Music]
you