today we're going to talk about
a really new exciting segment on
photogrametry
what is photogrammetry latch asked
basically we can take our drones now and
we can produce
3d images so we can make 3d models of
real world objects
so whether that's a building a field
your house
your business whatever you can take your
drone
take photos of your property and make
that into a 3d
image or in this case 3d model with that
being said we're going to take it one
step further
and we're going to take that 3d model
and 3d print it
so then you have your house in the palm
of your hand
what use is this i'm glad you asked an
example of what this can be used for
is if you're a real estate agent and
you're trying to sell a house but
somebody has a hard time seeing they
could be blind
etc what you can do is that you can 3d
scan the property
3d print that property and then they can
actually feel the house with their very
own hands
how cool is that now stay tuned for this
exciting segment as we go over how to
3d print as well as 3d capture using
photogrammetry
let's take a look
[Applause]
[Music]
so now that our drone's safely back on
the ground what we can do is head back
to the studio
upload these images to the cloud to the
software
that will then stitch it all together
into our 3d model
so that's pretty cool let's go take a
look at that
let's go all right now we're back in the
studio here
um i know this is a different building
than we used before but this one's a
really nice example so we're going to
use this uh
provided example here so let's pretend
we we've finished flying we did our
little grid pattern or whatever we flew
now we upload our photos to
your provider in this case it's drone
deploy but it could be pix4d
or dji um and then after
it processes you get something cool
looking like this
so again we have our ortho mosaic
so it's like a giant 2d map so kind of
imagine this as a more high definition
google maps or
satellite image right so this image here
now you can see on this overlaid map
this is made of hundreds of images
stitched together
to make make it look like it's a
satellite image
which is really really cool it's a it's
a really cool program
but of course with this since there's
gps data within
the files so again we have our
geolocation data
we can do cool things such as measure
distances
we can do different spot heights we can
do different locations you can pin
things
but this isn't just everything i'm going
to show you right now
no what we really want is this
and that is the 3d model of the
environment
all right this is what we're looking for
this is the cool
looking 3d map the 3d
model that we have been able to create
using our images that we've uploaded to
our program
so pretty much again we take our photos
the program stitches everything together
and it's able to create this
cool 3d file this 3d model
photogrammetry really is the future and
again it's not perfect like again going
closer into things we do have like a few
little weird nubs and a few little uh
errors
but again you can correct those in
blender or if you
pretty much the more advanced drone you
have also known as the better camera
if you have fleur or lidar or anything
that makes
a much better high resolution image a
more accurate image
but again today we're just using uh
standard off the uh
off the shelf drone so hey that that
that's still a pretty nice those are
some really sharp looking lines
so now what we can do is that we can
actually download this map
depending what program you're using and
we can
export this as an obj file or another
readable
3d file format and we can actually
import this into a 3d printer
so let's take a look at some images that
robbie gave us
of him converting one of my files i did
into a 3d model
all right so before we turn into a 3d
model i just wanted to show
what model i gave robbie so this is a
house we shot a few years ago you can
take a look at this on sketchfab.com
under air support aerial photography
that's my company
um but as you can see it's a really nice
looking home you know uh the resolution
is actually not that bad this was shot
with a phantom 3 professional
um again there are a few errors like
this section right here
so this is there was a tree right here
so we weren't able to get proper
photos that's why the program kind of
freaked out in this corner here
but everything else is pretty uh it did
a really nice job
and again the algorithms have become a
lot more accurate
uh these past few years so chances are
if we did this again it would be a lot
more accurate
even if we still use the phantom 3
camera and of course you can add other
details in like right here
just in blender or other programs so
let's see how
robbie's program takes this dot obj file
and turns it into a 3d printer readable
file
let's take a look thanks henry we're
going to dig into the software that's
used to convert henry's aerial
photogrammetry into a 3d printable
object
and we're going to send it to our 3d
printer right after this
[Music]
the software that henry is referring to
is called ultimaker cura
it's a free program it's available for
windows mac and linux
and you can follow the links at cat5.tv
3d printing in order to grab that what
i'm going to do is i'm going to open the
file that henry was showing us there now
keep in mind henry was looking at a
textured file so it had like the
the brick overlay and everything all the
coloring and all that stuff
what we're about to see is just the obj
so the object
just the actual 3d printing file
and bring that into cura and let's see
what we find now we got this little itty
bitty
like what is this a house for ants
all right so it's put it up on its end
you can see how that is so what i want
to do is i want to rotate that
so i'm just going to click on it click
on the rotate tool and bring it down 90
degrees
there we are that's going to put it flat
on the surface but it's still this
itty-bitty house for ants so let's
increase the size of that as well and
boop there we are so that's awfully big
like 200 millimeters let's bring it down
just a little bit
okay so the first thing that i notice
here is that we've got a lot of ground
see the earth around the around the
building we've got some boulders here
some shrubs
and this guy here looks kind of messy
what i'm going to do is i'm just going
to lower
the position of the house a little bit
so that we can push that ground into the
build plate
on my printer i don't want to go too far
because we don't want to like submerge
the house we just want to
pull back some of that that landscaping
there so that we're not actually 3d
printing
the dirt and there's that area where i
think that's
is that where the no yeah that's where
the tree where henry was showing us the
tree is
and it looks like a cave so that's going
to be rather interesting
a couple of quick mentions is you know
typically
when you're 3d printing you're going to
need supports if anything overhangs
because
otherwise it's just going to droop and
and you're going to get this stringing
coming down
so i'm looking for anything here that's
going to overhang and i don't really see
much there is this overhang here
and kira is showing me some red to to
tell me that
this might be a problem but i think
because it's such a small
overhang i think we're probably going to
be okay to do it without supports
we don't need supports you might think
well we need to support the roof because
you know the roof
is like this and if it's a hollow thing
then it's
uh it's going to you know completely
cave in
but the way kira looks at this when it's
slicing it is
it treats this as a solid object so
rather than supports for the interior of
the object that's actually called infill
so there's a couple of things that we're
going to set here so if we did need
supports we're going to click on
generate supports
i don't think we're going to if i
preview that
yeah see the whole outside has now been
basically
covered in supports so that would be a
lot of stuff to trim away
and i think that's because of the fact
that
being that it's a 3d scan using just a
standard camera
the edges are not quite perfect as
you've as you've seen there
so that's something that henry might
might want to clean up
before trying to 3d print let's turn off
the supports and i've got an infill
density of 20 percent
and we're looking at about 14 hours to
print with supports my fear is just that
that's a lot of supports to remove um
it might be very difficult now it's not
but it might be worth it
it's a hard thing to call this is what
it looks like without supports but what
i'm looking for is the infill density
to make sure that this the roof is going
to be supported so i'm going to pull
down my preview here
so that i can see inside what's being
printed
so you can see that with a twenty
percent infill density
that is placing these kind of
their supports to hold up that roof
as it prints but without using you know
100 infill
and wasting a whole lot of filament
that's going to take about 10 hours and
67 grams of filament
so if you're wondering well how much is
that going to cost to print at that
scale
just go into your calculator and i know
that i paid 40
for the one kilogram of filament so it's
cents per gram and we know that this is
going to be 67
grams so that's 2 dollars and 68 cents
to print at this scale and that's pretty
big considering my under 3
bed is 220 by 220 millimeters so what
you're
looking at there is uh you know it is
let's see
143 millimeters by 112 millimeters
so it's pretty big i'm gonna try scaling
it down a bit
so that the overhangs are not as big
as they would be if it was 143
millimeters wide
so i'm going to make this about 50
millimeters
width and see
how that slices up with no supports
so it's going to be a lot smaller but
it's going to
probably do a lot better without
supports because
we don't have such a pronounced overhang
and let's give that a go i'm going to
send that over to my printer
and we'll see how she comes out
[Music]
there it is this is my tiny house oh
it's so
cute i have always wanted to live in a
tiny house everyone who knows me
knows i'm a tiny house kind of guy and
this just proves it right here
in all seriousness though henry the
reason that i printed it so small
as i mentioned was i wanted to see if it
would print without supports and it did
and it printed quite nicely and it looks
pretty good
but it's very very tiny it is so i did
decide to take it to the next level for
you
and throw something on the printer and i
sent another file
and here you go what
what do you think okay that's so cool
check that out folks yeah
and i'll hand it to you i just want to
kind of show the camera here just so
that you can
kind of see i know that is pretty robust
i printed it in
white filament for you because i thought
hey maybe you'd want to prime it and
paint it
um but then i realized as i was running
it that
the cameras kind of don't like white
filament because they white balance
themselves and overexpose themselves
yeah it's like what are you doing to me
here
yeah that's tough that's tough our poor
camera guy is just like ah i don't
get it seriously like that amount of
detail that you managed to get out of
that 3d model that's pretty amazing eh
well you took your drone up and just
kind of it software
took it around and flew overhead yeah so
like
literally from the future what you're
able to see is that literally we just
did our kind of grid patterns we were
able to take those photos
mash them all together in a blender and
out comes this now how hard was it now
when you sent me this it was an obj file
yeah it was already a 3d
ready yeah like pretty much ready to
print as you saw yeah
pretty much how hard was that to put
together oh no no not at all
from photos yeah literally because the
program that you're able to see through
the feature
even if you use another one i use drone
deploy i've also used pix4d there's so
many
awesome programs out there but literally
just
download as and save it as obj i believe
there's a few
other file types you can do but obj is
the more
widely written it's pretty universal
yeah you can even open it up in blender
things like that right so it's it's
great so
um so hold up yeah if you can open it in
blender that means you could take this
house that you scanned yeah
and put it in a a 3d movie that you
create
you can you can even have a real engine
you could put yourself in it you could
so you could put it
you could put it in a game yeah so i've
actually had this exact same model
in unreal for running so like i could
have like little fires around it
not that i'm planning on anything or you
could have like a sky box
so there's so many applications for this
cool i mean like again besides the 3d
environment so like video photo
film things like that yeah um i think i
mentioned this before to you that
if i'm a real estate agent and i'm
trying to sell a house to someone
right and maybe they're blind how do you
sell a house to someone blind and
describe the exterior
yeah you mentioned that that it's like
okay well you can actually feel it
exactly
now you can literally 3d print your
house or the house or whatever
and you can feel what it looks like feel
and is that legit
like do people like it maybe if some of
our
our folks that have vision problems
would that be a benefit to you would
that be a selling feature
for even just education things like that
right like being able to do like
historic monuments or
things like that i think so you see from
my perspective henry
yeah this does a couple of things um in
that it captures
buildings or whatever it might be maybe
landscapes or whatever
in such a way that it will last forever
as you say you can throw it in an unreal
engine with the textures
exactly it will even if the building
disintegrates
it's forever captured well that's the
thing is that there's a
there's a lot of famous stories about
people going in the middle east and as
you know there's a lot of conflicts over
there
but before a lot of these buildings and
stuff were destroyed
um people actually went in with uh
photogrammetry kits
and they were actually able to capture
all these older monuments all these
older
uh beautiful places so they were
destroyed so yeah
they're they're they're gonna live on
forever now in 3d format or future
generations can go and say
yeah this is like at the very least they
can see it in like virtual reality
yeah exactly and it's literally i'm
really excited this is just the start of
this technology
it's it's fantastic wonderful well thank
you so much for sharing
that with us henry that's really really
cool stuff thank you for printing it
it's it looks a lot more realistic in
real life
than it does on a computer and when you
brought it up when you brought it up in
the
with the textures and everything it was
it was very very real-looking that was
really fun and that was with an
older version of that program that that
the model that we used for this was
around three or four years old
okay so the methods that the programs
use now their algorithms are actually so
much more accurate and i'm using an
older drone right so
phantom 3 pro my friend uses a maverick
they have a matrix as well so like a 10
drone wow imagine how that looks having
like a full
dslr camera unreal is this the same tech
like when i see on google earth yeah it
is it actually is
so um a lot of people think that um you
can even use
lidar or like floor things you which you
can and it makes more accurate
with using lidar and fleur but yeah so
google maps
bing maps those guys um they literally
just use photogrametry so they have
multiple pictures
from satellites yeah up in the grape
view blue yonder
and they have similar programs are able
to stitch that together they're using
satellite
imagery to do what you're doing with a
drone it's pretty much this but on
steroids yeah so
using a drone they're using satellites
and using uh
amazing data putting things together
and yeah so whenever you see your house
on google earth and of course there are
some ai um like some
ais are fixing a few errors here and
there but
when it comes down to it yeah that's the
basics of how uh
a lot of these companies are doing
things now cool stuff so yeah
i'm really keen to see how this brings
real world objects into
same here things like video games like i
really think
with virtual reality to be able to well
we actually already see this um a famous
one that just came out is the new
microsoft light sim right there
the entire 3d world is just big maps
but it's just in a 3d environment and
for years we've always had flights in
google earth where you just use your
arrow keys but that's not a flight sim
but
it's it's amazing to see where we're
going with this technology
very cool so yeah very cool uh where can
now i understand this model is
proprietary so this is something that
you shot professionally and this is
owned by the people who own the house
yeah so just just for privacy and
copyright reasons i'm not going to be
releasing this
variant of the model yeah however i do
have um another one i'll get to that in
a second
you can look on free websites uh one of
them that i'm featuring personally is
sketchfab.com
all right um it's a 3d file sharing site
you can get free files you can
buy files on there you can do a lot of
different licensing
opportunities as well but there's
there's a lot of very unique projects on
there
i might make one of mine free to
download soon as well
i did a local school um public property
you know during the summer
but uh it's it's a great ability to have
just download play around with it even
if it's not my file but somebody else's
file like just
play around with it if you have a 3d
printer if you have a 3d program just
take things apart stitch things copy
paste have fun with it that's what this
technology is for i want to say thank
you so much to our patreon supporters
you can follow us
and become part of our fleet at
patreon.comcategory5
we greatly appreciate your support it's
how we're able to do
the show that we do and we couldn't do
it without you
and thank you everybody for subscribing
on youtube and for being a part of our
community
we've got our discord server where you
can chat with other people in the
community we've got a ton of ways
to interact and make sure you go over to
our website
and you'll be able to follow along
figure out all the different ways to
interact with us a category category5
dot tv oh and i should mention there's
years worth of video what i can binge
watch all 14 years
you probably could
enjoy that especially season one it was
dreadful
uh hey you take care have a wonderful
week henry great seeing you man high
[Music]
five
so