hello
this is category five uh coffee break
good afternoon or morning or wherever it
is in your part of the world
um welcome we have peter up on the left
hand
my my top left hand wherever i am so
peter give us away were you there we go
hi
peter give us a wave sobu all right then
don't oh there we go thank you sobu
and i'm beat p9 good morning afternoon
whatever it is
so let's see what fun have i had
i fell into the
um i fell into the youtube
uh uh rabbit hole
um this weekend hello
lance man how are you sir good
nice sunshine yeah
it's uh actually creating a lot of glare
on the
and it's fine it's okay there you go
much better now we can't see you
it's all good don't worry about it it's
all good
it's it we can see your face fine that's
important
don't worry about it it's all right
it's okay oh geez
it's okay there we go
that works that works how are you
all right how are you i'm i'm wonderful
thank you very much
i was just i was just saying we
literally just started the meeting so
i was just saying that i fell into the
youtube rabbit hole
and uh sobu you might um you might
know this group i don't know but i found
a um
i found a guy in a group called
wintergarden i don't know if you're
familiar with them
no they're from sweden not norway so
probably
probably not um you probably wouldn't
know them
but um i don't know whether you've ever
heard of anna music
is this something you've seen oh yeah
you have
i've heard of it so doug you okay so
without a music it's all okay so without
a music it's all well
you see the t-shirt right it's all um
a computer generated an um animation
right and the whole idea is that
before the note strikes the animation
kicks off the movement of the machine so
that the note strikes just as the
as the um as the striker hits the um
the key or whatever the case may be
right
um so this this
this group called wintergarten or at
least the fella who um
i don't recall his name at the moment
but at least a fellow who
uh who who heads up that group
built a marble machine
that does pretty much what
you know these these guys are trying to
do in in
animation it's crazy it's taken him
years to build the thing
it really is a rube goldberg machine
it's crazy
um but it seems to be working so i'll
put links to
to both of those down in the um in the
show notes
so that you can uh so that you can see
um what i'm talking about i'll put links
to both anna music
and to enter winter garden it's quite
it's quite amazing it's uh
it's fun to watch it's painful to watch
sometimes because
it goes through so much um
a design and engineering to try and make
the machine work
and it's it's it's crazy it it just
doesn't
it's it's crazy anyway so
the other thing i got to play with is a
new arrival
no this is not a model 100 i know you've
seen the model 100 before
this is a uh let me see if i can focus
on
it there it is let me see it that's the
wrong way there we go
it's a dtandy it's a tandy wp2
word processor too okay
it it's focused primarily on writing
is what it's it's what it's there for
and that's all i ever wanted the model
100 for right was to take notes
the biggest problem with the model 100
was that it was
um it only allowed 40 characters by
four lines so you really couldn't see
very much
on the on the screen at all you couldn't
see much of the
of the document that you were or the
file that you were that you were typing
into
this does 80 characters across
by eight lines down so it's much more
usable screen
the characters obviously are a lot
smaller
but still easy to read so so far i'm
really pleased with i've only had it a
few days so
i'm still still getting used to it still
figuring it out
figuring it out but uh yeah it
looks like it it looks like it'll work
what i'm trying to find is
is something that i can carry around
it's still fairly large to carry around
but i think it's probably the
the smallest form factor that you can
have for the kind of
um for the kind of use case that i'm
thinking of and that is that
something to carry around to take notes
on
that i don't write down and then have to
transcribe right so i mean
i'll do it either way but it works with
that
see if you can that looked like a
core radio uh car radio no
it is nice it is a disk drive yep
now that is that is a a um
that is a cardboard keeper to uh
keep the heads protected while you're
around while you're traveling
they look like a comic commodore one
type one it's a metal design
it's probably from that it's probably
from that
uh vintage this is a 19
i don't know if it says when it was
built
no no it'll be the 80s or 90s it won't
be it certainly won't be the 70s
because the model 100 didn't uh didn't
come into being
until uh until 80s
mid to late 80s or something
in the 70s i don't think they'd started
using uh drives yet they were still
using magnetic tape
they might have been using uh they may
have been using eight inch drives
yeah possibly yeah
oh nice now i like to treat my media a
little more with a little more respect
than that peter
oh yeah but we'll do work doing that you
know obviously we had the boards here
nice these these are 3.5
inch floppy disk drives um
you want to guess how much you could
store on one of these things
okay maybe 100 no 1.4 black
1.4 megabyte and what did you say sober
300 something k a actually
actually you're the closest out of all
of them never know i know
i know doug you said uh what one point
no it was peter said 1.4 meg right
yeah well this thing was built well
before
that standard was in place this holds
this holds 200 kilobytes
oh wow and this
is the this is the tptpd
whatever it is too this is the second
revision
the first revision looks exactly the
same
but only holds 100 megabytes
there was some an article in one of the
local papers
in my county um about the uh uh
radar installations and uh they said in
part of the article that
um it was an article about the old
storage media and about uh
floppy drives and and they said that uh
uh
all of the software that was running the
military in radar installations in
norway all the software fitted um
on one of yours uh 200 something k
sure and the same thing was true
for um for the apollo space flights as
well
these things that i'm showing off have
more power than those computers
that were in the apollo spacecraft but
peter i'm going to give you another
giggle because i'm going to show this
again
[Laughter]
peter stop it peter don't say anything
this is a this replaces
my jewish roots he left my jewish roots
with that
[Laughter]
this um uh uh this replaces
the uh the disk drive that i just showed
you
and it lets you store the files on a
pinky little
sd card that you can just transfer back
i showed you this last week so i don't
have to
belabor it but there you go that's
that's my collection we'll see how we'll
see how that works
uh let's see a few weeks ago i talked
about
um a client server that i was working on
a client server application that i was
working on
and i was trying to do i was trying to
use a crypto library
to encrypt traffic and to um
and to sign the traffic well in my tests
i couldn't make it work every time
and that's still true i still can't make
it work every single time so it's
even running the tests exactly the same
way
as their test harness works so i don't
know how their test harness
uh survives it unless they how it passes
every time
unless they just don't run it over and
over and over again
so you know it might work
i don't know 60 of the time something
like that so i've i've finally given up
on um
on gcrypt and now i'm gonna try and use
uh and and i apologize in advance if i
don't
pronounce this correctly because
apparently if you call it gnu
then you're a newbie
shelby want to weigh in on that
is that is that true i know
the name of the new system that the
stallman launched in the 1980s
um he on purpose uh picked the name
because it was the funniest in his
opinion it was the funniest word in the
in
english dictionary um because
the g is supposed to be silent okay
okay so i didn't even know that canoe
was a real word
it is a little real word and they had in
the 60s they had yeah yeah
[Music]
the wildebeest wilma beast yeah
what were you going to say peter i would
just say the same thing yeah
all right okay oh i did not no i did not
know that i'm going to have to write
that down
in in the 60s um there were a few songs
written about uh because of the english
dictionary it says that uh
guinea is
supposed to be an uh pronounced new
and stallman used that word uh because
to say that something is not
a unix and a glue is uh um
new is not unix i thought that was what
the uh acronym was
uh and it's old and it's also uh it and
it's also a word at the same time so
yeah
i i did not know it was a word i i
simply assumed it was an acronym yeah
in in the first ten years when they were
meeting up all the developers they would
sometimes ask what's new
he had a talk in norway uh in 2005
and he and he told this story and he
said that um
he and he and he said that uh it's um
the joke is not working so much anymore
because it's not so new
yeah oh you could play on that word over
and over and over again
couldn't you that's crazy and yeah and
he has said and he also
talked you know um often in his um
talks about in the 60s
it was a it was a song by two
by two people uh who were um who who
were
the reason he uh chose that word
and it's um it's called
the the new song and it's by uh flanders
and swan
who were um
what was the [ __ ] yeah he was in the
wheelchair yet yeah
so i think i'll have to get you i'll
have to get you to send that to me in
chat so i'll be so i can put it in the
in the show notes i i didn't catch the
correct name the name of the group
so it'd be easy just to type it out
it'd be easier just to put it in the in
in discord if you wouldn't mind
so i can spell it correctly when i put
it in the show notes
that's one as long as it's one london
wonders like in
flanders like in holland yeah okay
okay okay okay
so um so gnu tls and again i'm sorry if
i did not
pronounce that correctly you'll just
have to put up with my newbie
um my newbie pronunciation but what i'm
trying to do
is to make it so that
when a client contacts the server
it's encrypted over ss over
tls which that's that's the main
aim is to encrypt that communication but
i also understand that it's possible to
identify
who it is that's making the request by
um sending either an id or a key
or a private key um
and i'm looking at uh tasks task warrior
at the moment because i'm
using that you know every day and it
uses exactly this process
but as far as i can i'm digging in the
source code and as far as i can tell
although you generate a private key i
can't see how the server uses that
private
or rather the public key because the
client would have to have the private
key
and the server would have to have the
public key and theoretically
the two should allow for the
identification of the user
i'm still working through that code to
figure out how it works
there's also an id an actual user id or
a username
passed as well and it might be that that
or some sort of id is what's um is what
identifies the user
if that's true then i'm not i'm not as
happy that as i thought i was with
um being able to identify the user i'm
still looking at that
still figuring out how that fits
together so
i was going to ask you soul boo about um
about running your own mail server not
the details of it but
the advantages of it because way back
when
in a few companies ago that i worked for
i
actually stood up a mail server for the
company and
um uh and i was surprised
shocked even at how much was exposed in
the logging
um of the of the mail server and i yeah
i can just imagine how much
just browsing the mail the mail server
logs
how much a a an internet provider can
glean
from your from yours from your
yourself just by browsing the mail
server logs it's scary
is that why you're running your own mail
server
no the reason that i'm running my own
mail server is
that i control the
the mail storage um and also that
i can have as many email addresses
as i want and i can share
um can give other people access
but it's that i am controlling the
server who holds the mail that is the
main uh
the main reason is it difficult to mine
is it difficult to maintain
no and also one of
the biggest advantages of running your
own mail survey
is that um no one
can kick you out because you said
something uh
yes um yeah so
i think about someone who um after
being using gmail for 15 years he was
banned for something um and he
appealed and the band state and he lost
all
uh access to all his mail for
that he has been had for 15 years and he
also used their
photo storage service and he also lost
access to all of his stuff
to a lot of his photo albums
so wow and if you're running your own
mail server
gmail can't kick you out yes
wait what say that again if you are
running your own mail sir right gml
cannot kick you out
oh oh i thought you said gmail can kick
you out a little what wait no
no it's yours so
are you running the mail server
you're running it locally at your
location
yeah and are you treating it like
webmail do you log into it with a
browser
no i use a pop email but i can set up
i have a server uh together with my
friend eric who was uh
widows for two years coffee breaks uh
half a year ago
and we have a server in a data center uh
and there we
are providing a webmail for uh
clients and all the clients are people
that
one or both of us and personally no
personally no so we have full control
over who gets access
yeah i don't i don't think many people
use pop anymore
most folks can continue to use most
folks are using web based pay on now
either um either gmail or
you know whatever whatever is available
or
through their own internet provider
would you agree with that or
i guess the old folks like us would use
pop i use pop all the time
because i'd rather have all my mail
local
yeah there is three ways to use
email most people today they are logging
in via
a browser or um
like my friend eric he uses imap where
the
mail is stored at the mail server but he
yeah
and then he have the same email like
same email
of course all of his uh he said uh
the devices the downside so but that's a
good
that's the point of that though is that
you have to have access to your own mail
server
if you want to use imap from your phone
or your tablet and you're away from your
location right
you're away from the house or wherever
the machine is you'd have to be able to
connect into
um into your device from outside
otherwise i haven't deliberately chosen
to only have access inside the house
so so my um the mail comes in
but in order for me to check the email
after i have to be at home
yes that is not deliberate uh this isn't
by my and that's fine
yeah yeah yeah i get that and you you
have to decide for yourself
if that's something you want to put up
with by running your own mail server
yeah and i also use an old
non-smartphone so yeah when i leave the
house
i also leave the internet behind on that
these are deliberate decision i don't
want the internet i have a i have a trio
around here somewhere
that has
it's not a tr i've got i've got various
palm devices all over the place but
um i have a trio floating around
somewhere that
finally bit the dust and uh and it
checks mail too
i mean but i i don't remember if it does
i map or not but it certainly does pop
so
yeah anyway let's let's let the other
folks have a go because
uh because we're running out of time
already can you believe that
peter what are you what sort of trouble
have you been getting into
well donald's on um uh we had a bomb
scare
a bombshell in the bedroom oh boy
i bet they pop pop but uh they put it on
the wrong car
oh wow that's no joke that is what
happened
we had a place everything from the squad
the army does though
are you okay is uh is everyone at your
place okay yeah
well yeah yeah i couldn't go nurse and
i needed to be cleaned down that's the
problem
and uh she let's say she belongs to
she's not present she's from the other
side she's quite nice
and uh he told herself john's how to go
around the back way
this plane has to go around the back
i'm glad you're all okay good
okay and uh i wrote my verse to be
at that hell today the other day is that
new zealand yeah yeah yes but
you like this one well the sunspots are
starting to get more active so
uh yeah so you should be something you
know or something
if you go to qrday.com yeah and you you
put in that l3
sv he's got right brother down
go on type it down
zl3 sv yeah yeah
i'm using i'm using my fountain pen to
write it down
because you know i'm old school
he's got a multiple halfway which is 640
meters long which is about half a mile
oh my god wow the gain
the gain is unbelievable
[Laughter]
i can do the same see
i can i can add as many pins as you want
because look at this
oh there's only one in there
and it sounds down 640 meters it's
uh it's uh 32 weight down to 120 meters
wow was 160 up to up to two meters
and the game was absolutely crazy very
big
i have not been i've not been on hf for
a long time peter so
i don't know how long it'll be before i
get back on so and
the other thing i i found a new mode you
might be
everybody might be treasurer programming
basically
um what it does is it uses a
uh like a uh 360 degree
clock and every uh 45 degrees
uh it it changes the digit and the
number
so the number starts at zero
the next 145 degrees phase shift will be
zero zero one
sector two three four and what you do is
that
when you write a text file you just
change the phase of the
we've got to start closing it out peter
sorry sorry
yeah all right doug you haven't had a
chance to talk yet what uh
what else are you up what are you up to
i have a raspberry pi that i set up as a
sort of an entertainment server good did
you get you a new 400
raspberry pi 400 no it's a raspberry pi
3.
oh nice okay and as an entertainment
well you're running clicks on it or
something
what's that you're running clicks on it
or so
um no it's raspbian um okay
i do have flex but i don't have anything
to play on flex okay okay
i don't have any i don't have a uh a
drive with movies on it or anything like
that
maybe you want to get rid of them one
once you go pledge you'll never go back
i enjoy it i like it a lot
although i have not signed i have not
signed up for the um
for the plex account because uh so far i
don't see the advantage so
um
what's that they get free still good
well
it's it's free for local use
but if you pay for a if you pay for a
plex account
um which apparently this past this past
good friday
i just passed um black friday deal you
can get it at a bit of a discount
but what it means is it lets you access
your plex server from
outside of your own network i don't see
any advantage to doing that
because i'm about to shut us down uh i
went to the roll
and uh i couldn't get anybody to take me
and that cost me 80 pounds to go or 80
dollars or whatever it was
and uh i i made a complaint to the
hospital that i can't keep your
forwarding to
do this yeah on a regular bloody basis
yeah and so i i i almost didn't go
i was not very well before it and
we found out the reason was because then
my valve out
i tell
they have to give me a new one they have
to give me a never could have failed
that he failed
yeah adorable it's been 30 it's been 30
minutes folks so
it's time to close this uh blows this
party down so
thank you all thoroughly enjoyed it as
always
and uh enjoyed the insight for a lot of
the programs
um and the chat have a good day
everybody take care
[Music]
bye-bye
you