[Music]
our live recordings are trusted only to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
revive your computer with improved
performance and reliability over
traditional hard drives with kingston
ssds category 5 tv streams live with
telestream wirecast and nimble streamer
tune in every week on roku cody and
other hls video players
for local showtimes visit category5.tv
welcome to the show everybody it's so
great to have you here here at our
studio
in barrie we've gone through all kinds
of technical difficulties oh my goodness
so far this week and so that sort of
shapes the way that our show is going to
be today
but uh hey i i'm glad to have you here
and uh glad to see you as well jeff i'm
glad to be here have you been well
i i've been i've been good yeah
surviving the whole
covet thing yeah yeah i'm glad
to clarify i have not had whoa if you
suddenly were like i have coven yeah
dude where's my mask no
but i mean like all of the the the
restrictions and social justice thing
that it's playing i mean it's it's a
very different life and this week with
school starting
um depending where you are i know that
in the states
some kids have already been in school
for a couple of weeks but for us here
school started up yesterday uh so i set
my
my oldest off to high school i do not
feel like i should be old enough to have
a high school kid
yeah i feel like i just left high school
that's enlightening isn't it
yeah yeah i think i think the first time
i was on cat five i was only a couple of
years outside of high school
and you guys gotta keep it in high
school wow by the way robbie you're
super old
you've been doing this tv show for so
long it's
nuts but yeah so i mean we had we sent
them off to high school and that was
very weird like
just the the restrictions it's a whole
different type of semester for them like
you know the high school that i had you
have four classes uh
for half the year and then you switch to
another four classes
because of cohorts and and trying to
group kids as much as possible
he goes under this system uh it's called
a quadmaster
which is four semesters of only two
classes each and he only has one class
per week
so he has the same class all day every
day this week
and then next week he's got a different
class all day every day
and then he switches back and forth wow
so it's it's it's different
yeah but he's excited so you know what
whatever and how do you feel about
sending your kids to school through like
because
right now you know i'm not
we're not really sure where we're at
right like
are we in the midst of a pandemic i
think so like we're
you know we seem to think that we're on
the way to
things getting a little better and then
things go back up again
yeah so we've heard all the at least i
have heard all along that
there's always a second wave and i mean
you look at
the states and they've gone into a
second wave
you look at some places in europe
there's a bit of a second wave i know
that a
couple of weeks ago i started hearing
about a second wave in bc it looks like
the numbers are starting to go back up
again in ontario
so you know maybe we're on the
you know the downward side of the first
wave and going into second maybe it's
just a blip in the map who knows
every day is a is a changing target but
as far as sending the kids to school
um in our area you have the option of
your kids
doing online learning or being in school
and about
45 of the parents have chosen to keep
their kids
home and do online yeah that's us yeah
and so you guys have made that decision
and we debate it back and forth but
because
our son was going into high school for
the first time i'm like i don't want to
rob him
of the high school experience and he was
really excited to go so we're like okay
you can go to high school
if it's a problem we're pulling you out
our daughter is in french immersion
and i about the only french word i know
is toilette
which you know works with my humor style
so
wait that's an english word jeff
oh there's like an absentee guru i know
toilette
and resume that's right there we go
three words um so i mean i'm useless to
her at home
for for schooling something sure that
makes it tough we're gonna send her and
then with her third we're like well if
two are going
you're going as well so that's really
kind of how it played out and we're
completely on the other side of the
spectrum in that we've decided to keep
the kids home
yeah because that's an option yes just
because we just don't know like what
what's tomorrow going to bring right now
so you know let
let's play it safe i don't have kids in
french immersion or anything like that
so yeah you know maybe we're fortunate
in that way but
all that to say like here we are up in
ontario canada
and we know that you are going through
this as well if you're a parent then
you're probably going through the same
kinds of things that we're going through
like do we send our kids to school
do we keep them home do you know what
happens if we have to pull them out and
you know it's a really tough time for
all of us so you know it's just
just know that we're all in this
together we're thinking of you and and
uh
and really hope that uh that everything
you know we're hoping for the best
yeah and i mean and then on top of
global pandemic
uh it's it's uh you know you look at
some of the areas in the states i mean
last week was a hurricane and this week
california with the wildfires
it's like how much more can 2020 hand
out
yeah this is ridiculous and it just
seems to be non-stop for a lot of folks
like i've got friends
in california who work in uh tv
productions yes you know
that's right and with with their studios
having to
have shut down in march and then they're
coming up
you know august time and and it's
looking like maybe we can reopen and
start doing some filming with social
distancing in place
and uh and then the fires start and so
we've got to shut down because of the
fires
and it's it's unbelievable so
you know i just you know we're thinking
of use we have it so
very good up here in canada in that you
know i don't want to ever be complacent
and i don't want to ever um take for
granted the fact that i don't
i've never had to live through a big
fire like that right like a wildfire
we we just don't get that kind of thing
here in ontario where we are
i know like we've heard of some out west
and things but
um certainly not here and uh you know
it's it's
hard for us to watch the news and think
we have viewers in all these places that
are you know being ravaged by a
hurricane or
going through these wildfires and
thinking you know we we really care
about
you and and really want the best for you
and
and so just know that you know even
though we are up here in canada
uh we are thinking of you and and we
wish you all the best
and every bit of safety um to you and
your loved ones
um so one of the things that we wanted
to look at this week
is the pine book pro and i know like
we've got some buzz going on twitter and
you know
folks are really excited about what
we're about to do because we're going to
be showing you
how we can hack up our own distribution
our own installation of debian linux
on our pine book pro however
unfortunately
the tech now our scenario up here our
the impact of covet 19 is completely
different for us
because it's really impacted our studio
in that like the technology just
you know it's we're doing our best uh
amidst um staff shortages and and all
those kinds of things and not being able
to be here
with staff um for the amount of hours
that we should be
yeah in order to prepare for a show so
unfortunately the technology is not
there for us this week
but we will be looking at that next week
so the pine book pro
is a sleek slimline beautiful
linux laptop i'm so jealous every time
you pull that out oh yeah
look at that jeff do you want to feel
that how how heavy is that like uh
that is you know what he's just like i'm
just going to slide that in my pocket
yeah and i'll let you know how heavy
that is when i get home
it's got like a 1080p full hd screen
like i'm looking at debian right there
and it's like it just feels like this
like
lightweight toy in a way and yeah and
that's saucy
yeah as well and yet solid and so you
think about like the
the apple air or whatever they call it
what is it the
is that what they call macbook air yeah
macbook air can't afford that which
which has a
you know as far as i can tell is is you
know it's a slim
notebook computer as well but you know
it costs what ten thousand dollars
yeah this is 200 bucks right that's a
beautiful price right there
yeah there you go i can buy six of these
and be happy um but we're going to talk
about next week
why this may not be for everybody even
though it's a great price a great
product uh we're gonna we're gonna get
into all of that
uh i really wanted to get into it this
week jeff i know but i'm surprised
unfortunately we're unable to but
becca is here with the news yes and uh
we've got robert koenig here with the
crypto corner as well
so they're going to share with us um so
can we just we'll just throw it right
over to becca
yeah here we go here she is here's
what's coming up in the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
a frightening takeover vulnerability in
the popular file manager plugin for
wordpress
is being exploited in the wild giving
attackers the ability to drop and
execute code on around
700 000 wordpress sites
a u.s startup unveils a battery made
from nuclear waste
that could last up to 28 000 years
on thursday 60 more spacex satellites
were launched to join the rest of the
starlink fleet
the latest windows 10 cumulative update
breaks
sleep mode we'll share the fix and
minecraft is making a jump to
playstation vr
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5.tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight
linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
attackers are exploiting a critical
vulnerability in a popular wordpress
plugin
that enables an adversary to run
arbitrary commands and
upload files to a target wordpress site
the flaw is in the file manager plugin
which has more than 700
000 active users and is designed to help
administrators manage files on their
wordpress sites
the plugin includes a third-party
library called elfinder
and the vulnerability results from the
way that file manager renamed an
extension
in elfinder the vulnerability was
introduced in version 6.4 of file
manager which was released in may
but it wasn't until late august that
researchers first saw exploit attempts
against the bug
an exploit for the vulnerability was
posted on github in the
in the last week of august and on
september 1st
the maintainers of the file manager
released an updated version that fixed
the bug
although the fixed version has been
available for nearly two weeks
researchers say not many of the
wordpress sites running the plugin have
updated
which means they are still vulnerable
ram
gal of wordfence said on friday sites
not using this plugin are still being
probed by bots looking to identify and
exploit vulnerable versions of the file
manager plugin
and we have recorded attacks against 1.7
million
sites since the vulnerability was first
exploited
although word fence protects well over 3
million wordpress sites
this is still only a portion of the
wordpress ecosystem
as such the true scale of these attacks
is larger than what we were able to
record
the severity of the vulnerability makes
it urgent to update especially when
automated scans for the bug ongoing
especially with automated scans for the
bug ongoing
identifying vulnerable sites is a
trivial task and with an exploit
publicly available
time is of the essence particularly
given the fact that an attacker would be
able to upload arbitrary files to the
site after a successful exploit
sick of your smartphone dying at 3 pm a
u.s startup may have the answer as
they've unveiled a battery made from
nuclear waste
that could last up to 28 000 years
the power for the nanodiamond battery
comes from radioactive isotopes used in
nuclear reactors
its radioactive core is protected by
multiple layers of synthetic diamonds
one of the hardest materials to damage
or break
the energy is absorbed in the diamond
and used to generate electricity
the battery can be used to power devices
and machines of any size from
aircraft and rockets to electric
vehicles and smartphones
nema gol sharifi ceo and co-founder
of ndb said as members of society we are
extremely concerned about the welfare of
the planet and are focused on lowering
climate change to protect our planet
for future generations he goes on to say
with the ndb battery we have achieved a
massive
groundbreaking proprietary technological
breakthrough of a battery
that is emission-free lasts thousands of
years and only requires access to
natural air
in order to power devices the company
says the development of the first
commercial prototype battery is
currently underway
and will be available later this year
on thursday another 60 spacex satellites
were launched from the kennedy space
center in florida to join the rest of
the starlink fleet
in just the last month there have been
three successful launches and
deployments
making spacex the largest fleet of
satellites in the world
with more than 700 currently in orbit
spacex founder and ceo elon musk wants
to create a constellation made up of
thousands of starlink satellites that
can offer high-speed internet anywhere
on the planet in march musk said that at
the
he said at the satellite 2020 conference
the world seems to have an insatiable
appetite for bandwidth
we're certainly happy to launch other
satellites
if our appetite for bandwidth was
insatiable
insatiable before a global pandemic were
even hungrier now
the plan is to ultimately create an
interconnected network of about 12 000
small satellites in low orbit around
earth
using a small dish customers will be
able to connect and get fast internet
speeds
with rural and tough to reach areas
being the primary market
spacex recently said it's building about
120 satellites a month
astronomers are concerned the extra
points of light will make it harder to
observe the night sky
analyst carmi levy says they're trying
to look at things far away in the cosmos
and you have
all these pesky little satellites
orbiting in front of them
causing streaks across their imaging
spacex has responded to the concerns by
modifying its satellites to make them
less reflective
the company hopes to use starlink
internet as a way to fund the company's
version of our vision
of going to the moon and to mars spacex
says the service will first be available
in the u.s
and parts of canada public trials are
expected to take place later this year
they said friday that starlink has
already seen extraordinary demand from
potential customers
with nearly 700 000 individuals across
the united states alone
indicating they are interested in the
coming service the latest windows 10
cumulative update has
broken sleep mode and we'll share with
you the fix
also minecraft is making the jump to
playstation vr
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert's here with the crypto corner so
don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
i hope you're well and i hope you
survived the recent correction in the
market without any harm
this week i'd like to focus on something
that i touched on before
which is d5 decentralized finance and
the reason is
that some of our viewers started asking
questions hey isn't d5 a scam
why should i be part of this year so let
me answer you those questions
first no it's not a scam it's on the
country it's going to be the future of
our financial system as we know it and
yes you should definitely be part of
this year
now um where is this coming from
and if we look at this website here you
can see that if you would provide ample
eth as liquidity
you would get over a thousand percent
apr and that sounds like magic right
it doesn't sound very real especially if
you would put money in your
uh normal account in your traditional
bank
you would probably get 0.5 apr
so why is this number so big and what
i'm going to do now is i'm going to go
into the detail of where this number is
coming from
and i'm not going to be going too much
into too much detail
so i'm simplifying a lot but you will
get the idea
the first part is if we look at the
rates
of where the market is in the in the
crypto market
it's not that much different from the
traditional bank so usdc
if i would provide usdc's to to
uh for example aver i would get 2.1
percent
interest if i would borrow at other
usdc then i would got 4.4
so far so good right so that's no
different so that's part one part two
is if i would provide liquidity and for
that we go to something called uniswap
and uniswap is where you can exchange
tokens so if you've got eth and you want
to buy
let's say band then as you can see down
here
you would have to provide a liquidity
provider you would receive you would
have to pay a liquidity provider fee
and this this year and if you would
provide money into this pool so if you
in other words you provide eth and band
so that other people can participate in
this year
then you would get part of this fee
most part even yeah so it's very simple
you click on pool
you click on add liquidity you say what
is it going to be
and then you approve this here and
that's it that's all you have to do
so that's how you provide liquidity
that's something that is unknown in the
current market yeah
that's reserved to banks market makers
federal reserve you're not allowed to
provide
you're not allowed to be a market maker
in the traditional market
crypto market's different you can be uh
participating in that
the fourth one is something that we know
also in the traditional market
and there are high incentives and let me
show you some examples first one
is um here with credit cards
if i sign up with this blue cash
preferred card
they would give me 250 dollars straight
away
or if i would go with chase sapphire
there's a bonus value of 1200 attached
to this card
so as you can see there's also marketing
costs that they are investing in
that you will participate off so that's
that's one way
of um how the so-called traditional
market
is incentivizing you to be part of their
network other example is flights yeah i
can
book a flight now at the moment from
dallas to las vegas for only 36 dollars
return
no airline will survive on those rates
but they do that to attract people
to fly uh on this day with that
uh airline on that on that journey um
if you booked that a day before that
would be probably 300 400
same with air miles why don't why do
they give you air miles
so that you can book them after a few
flights
a free flight same thing it's just they
want to attract you
to be part of their network
and the third one that i forgot to
mention before is staking rewards
so if i i would take for example tesla's
to secure the network um
by proof of stake then tesla's would
give me in this case through coinbase
five percent staking fee yeah that's
just by providing
by keeping my money my tesla's in a
wallet and not using it
i would receive five percent so there
are a few incentives that are compared
to the traditional market equivalent and
not that much different
to the default market now the beauty of
the default market is it's software
it's not just some people sitting there
and deciding what the interest rate is
or what the
incentives are going to be it's a
software uh
platform that you just participate in
and it's neutral you can nobody will ask
you for some
uh weird uh passport pictures or so you
just be part of that
and that's the strength of this year so
these software packages
or software platforms don't have high
costs in building
people and so on just a bunch of people
that coded something
they put it online and that's why they
cane
can offer you so high interest rates
now before you really dive into this i
would like to show you two websites that
are important
the first one is uh defy safety.com
because here you can see which platform
is really safe and which one isn't safe
so if i take arva for example
uh which is one of the big ones then
they have got a score of 84 percent
and why it's because execute code
validation 96
documentation because it's all public
available they documented everything 90
testing almost done audit like in a
traditional market with finance where
you've got an auditor to
review books so they do that here with
the code so
it's a third party that reviews your
code how good it is
so this is pretty good but on the other
end you've got something like based
that print in principle did not do
anything really
i mean they just put the code online and
didn't even test it
beforehand it's nothing is documented
and an audit was done only to 20
so this is something that i would really
be careful of
yeah unless you you are you know what
you're doing i would not be
part of those that are in here in red
because it's uh it's a little bit
dangerous
that's the first website the second
website is one where you can learn a lot
uh it's defyrate.com this includes
everything in relation to the
decentralized finance market
yeah so if you want to learn what uh
how insurance can be done uh and
what the lingo is everything in relation
to d5 yield farming and so on
you'll find on this website it's very
well explained and i can only highly
recommend you to be
a part of that anyway i hope
i was able to explain to you why it is
important that you participate in this
here
uh just play around a little bit don't
plan to make thousand two hundred
percent just make hundred percent
um but at least be part of this year and
learn more about
uh d5 because as you saw it is going to
be the future um
anyway that's it from me uh today i hope
you enjoyed it i hope you learned
something i thank you very much for
watching and i'm looking forward to see
you next week again
thank you bye-bye thanks so much robert
now if you're watching
we are not giving financial advice this
is uh educational purposes on how the
cryptocurrency market works
and things that you need to know and
different uh tips and tricks
uh you know as we've always said in the
past you know and as robert has said
you know only invest what you're willing
to lose because the market is very
volatile
it's always on and things can change in
a heartbeat so again we're not giving
financial advice
it's just uh more so education for you
all right we're going to throw back to
becca here she is
thank you robbie having trouble sleeping
the latest windows 10 cumulative update
breaks sleep mode
causing laptops around the world to
become insomniacs
we have the fix to yet another microsoft
update blender
microsoft september 2020 optional update
seems to be causing some trouble for
those who are running windows 10 version
while the update comes with fixes for
critical issues and improvements
like many of microsoft's previous
cumulative updates this one is far from
perfect
some users are reporting that the
optional update broke windows 10 sleep
mode
with the update installed some users are
reportedly facing an issue where their
pc keeps waking up from sleep mode
one user states on feedback hub when i
close the lid press the power button or
select sleep
in the power menu or the win x menu
instead of sleeping the screen simply
turns off and my laptop does not go to
sleep even after leaving it alone all
night
similar complaints can also be found on
microsoft's forum website
what's worse is that at the time of
broadcast there isn't a fix available
from microsoft
there's a temporary solution available
if you're affected though it's a bit
hacky and reminiscent of the old up up
down down
left right game hacks of the 90s
first you need to stop the windows
update service
then start it again then restart it
then do a check for updates and install
the pending updates
once they're in reboot your computer and
you should be good to go
with a working sleep mode minecraft
is making the jump to playstation vr
minecraft is already available in vr
forum for windows 10
with the oculus rift and windows mixed
reality plus there's a samsung
gear vr version minecraft playstation vr
is based on minecraft vr tech from these
other vr
platforms mojang studios executive
producer roger carpenter said
everyone who has minecraft on
playstation 4 will get that patch
automatically
download that patch and you'll get
access to the new microsoft vr
functionality of course you'll need a
psvr setup in order to use it
the ongoing covet 19 pandemic forced
them to adjust how they develop
minecraft
carpenter added but the process was
relatively drama-free
skybox labs also working on halo
infinite
helped mojang work on this release the
minecraft playstation vr experience will
retain
everything from the base ps4 version and
we'll add a bunch of new settings
this includes two ways to play the game
immersive
and living room mojang didn't expand on
what that means but if we were to guess
the letter the latter may feel like
sitting in a virtual room and playing
on a giant screen mojang didn't reveal
whether minecraft playstation vr will
work with the upcoming ps5
sony has said their playstation move
motion controllers playstation vr
aim controller and playstation camera
will all work with supported ps
vr games on the ps5 but it's not yet
entirely clear what that means
get your playstation vr ready the free
update drops later this month
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom don't forget to like and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category 5. from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
well thank you so much for being here
with us again this week we are
endeavoring to do our best through this
time because you know our studio is not
quite up to
the shape that it needs to be in to be
able to broadcast a
full uh broadcast for you but we are
doing our best so
i appreciate that you're here and thank
you for
for joining us this week jeff what are
we doing next week
well next week we're going to be uh
looking at your pine book
doing the debbie pro yes
uh so that's exciting and uh
then we'll probably have some witty
banter a lot of that
two really good-looking guys um
and just some all-around good fun yeah
well i hope you'll be here so
join us at category5.tv and of course
follow us on twitter
we are at category 5 tv i'm personally
on twitter at robbie ferguson
you'll also find us on on facebook and
everywhere else i mean youtube obviously
get us on your roku devices you'll find
us all over the place just do a search
for category 5
technology tv and you'll find us and
we'll see you there and also get into
the community
we've got a very robust live active
community on discord so you can find
that link right on our website
and uh all throughout the week you know
just because we're not broadcasting
doesn't mean cat5 isn't live and well
uh through our viewer community and you
pop into discord get help with all your
tech issues and talk about recipes as
well
it's a phenomenal group we have a weight
loss room as well
because i've been losing weight clearly
and i'm not in that room
i'm i'm in there and i'm i'm doing my
best i'm learning
everybody stops you at i feel like we
haven't talked i don't know i'm not
wearing my step counter today jeff
uh mine oh look at that i switched the
face that doesn't have my step counter
on it oh
oh that's a good strategy yep anyway
it's it's depressing to see how few
steps i actually take
it's true i'm a geek
so you take care we'll see you again
next week take care everybody bye
[Music]
you