i've been
teaching myself how to
use a 3d printer and also it's arrived
well no well this is the thing is is
my my experiment
is i want to know if i were to get a 3d
printer
is it going to be so onerous
for me to learn how to use it that
it becomes another one of those
technologies that i purchase
and then never use right because we fall
into that that's right
cool tech comes out and you want it and
you buy it and then it's too hard to
learn and you don't have time and it
just sits on a shelf somewhere
and then it becomes obsolete yes so i've
taken a different approach and said okay
i'm going to learn how to 3d print first
okay and then i'm going to
make that decision so yes working with
design very cool so i use a tool
at tinkercad.com which is made by the
autodesk folks
and it allows me to use my
web browser to do 3d designs
cool so what ideas have you come up with
so my original ideas
are very very basic jeff as you can
imagine i mean i'm just learning
the ropes but so so
and i mentioned this two weeks ago when
you were here that i was going to do
this and i've done it
is that in my laundry room
i wanted a place to hang face masks
because
we have we've got three kids at home yes
and we all have
five or more of these i think i've got
like 10 of them myself because i'm
working in the field and the kids each
have five yeah face masks
but we bought the washable ones
and you don't want to put them through
the dryer so
right i want to make a rack for them so
i've designed i haven't printed because
i don't have a 3d printer
but this was the experiment can i design
the the idea that comes to mind which is
a
half inch piece of pvc pipe hanging in
the unfinished laundry room so i've got
access to the rafters i can just screw
right into them
and so i designed the um the mech
well the mechanism the plates to put the
half inch pvc up on the ceiling okay
hanging
and the hooks that are going to hook on
to that to allow us to hang as many
masks as we want
very cool so it is kind of cool so it
feels like something that
i hey i'm i'm actually designing i'm
actually creating
based on a need based on something that
i probably couldn't just walk into a
hardware store and buy
and probably doing it a lot cheaper
there's the cost of a 3d printer
but as bp9 mentioned in on on the
discord earlier today
the the fact is is that even though
there's an investment in the 3d printer
which is pretty cheap these days
you can go to our website category 5 tv
click on shop you'll see an ender 3 v2
there
and they're not very expensive so the
the
initial hurdle of like the investment
is there but fairly quickly as you
design and print things you're going to
make that back of course
that's the idea yeah and that makes
sense i'm really seeing that as i l
as i look at things in online shopping
and think could i this is the challenge
that i've given myself
could i create that myself with a 3d
printer
and then i start looking at okay well
that thing
would cost me 20 and i could print it
for 20 cents
right so how quickly could i make that
back
it's an interesting experiment but but
i've proven to myself that
one i can design things i can take my
ideas
very very basic right now folks you can
see the designs that i've done
at thingiverse.com
ball nerd you can see my designs but
you'll see the hooks that i made and the
the mounting apparatus for it and then
i've also
taken it one step further and i've taken
other people's designs because you can
get onto thingiverse.com
you can find things that are close to
what you want
then load them into your software in my
case
tinkercad for now and uh and yeah tweak
it
modify it change it make it so that it
suits your purpose
very cool it is kind of cool so i'm at
that point i think where it's like
yeah i can i can do this so now when i
do make that investment when i get the
3d printer and i and i
set that up and and i'm ready to print
i'm ready to print i have designs
i've proven that i can design and uh and
i'm good to go
i like that interesting right so tinker
tinkercad.com is the software that i'm
using
for now it's probably rudimentary in
so many ways but it's really really easy
for me to get my feet wet when it comes
to
3d printing you got to start somewhere
and then i talked with beau lechnowski
from ameridroid and he's telling me
about
how he programs 3d designs
he uses software that is so much more
sophisticated than what i'm
i'm doing through my web browser right
and is able to actually tweak things by
adjusting numbers
in the in the program and it that is but
that's why he's able to now
he's able to do things that i can only i
can imagine
but i i'm not capable of yet right right
yeah oh yeah thingiverse.combaldnerd
check out my designs
[Music]
you