covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias the uk
government has said hands-free driving
could be legal by
spring of next year the department for
transport has issued a call for evidence
into automated lane keeping systems
such technology controls a car's
movements and can keep it in lane for
extended periods
although drivers need to be ready to
take back control
the society of motor manufacturers and
traders claims it could reduce the
number of accidents
the technology for a car to steer itself
and stay in lane even around curves
already exists in some modern cars but
the law says that drivers must
remain alert and ready to take over
instantly
tesla's so-called autopilot is one
well-known example
it is considered level two on the five
defined levels of self-driving cars
the next step level three would not need
the driver's attention at all times and
in theory the driver could do other
things
such as check email or even watch a
movie
until the car prompts them to take over
again introducing those systems would
require
changes to current legal framework
something the dft says it is now
considering
while the technology has been approved
by the united nations economic
commission for europe
it is limited to traffic jams at speeds
of up to 37 miles per hour
the change could give the go-ahead for
speeds of up to 70 miles per hour in the
uk
potentially making long stretches of
tedious motorway driving a thing of the
past
the uk government wants to hear from
people within the motoring industry to
decide
how to safely implement the technology
the consultation closes on october 27th
[Music]
you