covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias google photos
will soon count against your overall
google account storage space
which will mean fees if you exceed 15
gigabytes
google's popular photo service is used
by over a billion people
with 28 billion new photos and videos
uploaded uploaded to the surface every
week
and until now it is offered free storage
for your photos
but google says it will stop offering
the free storage model within google
photos on june 1st
2021 instead google says
any new photos and videos you upload
will count toward the free 15 gigabytes
of storage that comes with
every google account or for those of us
who require
more space additional storage may be
purchased
presumably this means google photos will
become part of the standard google
account storage billing model which
gives each user
15 gigabytes free for drive gmail and
other services
so going forward your photos will also
take up storage within the limits of
that account
there is some good news though the
change is not retroactive
this means photos already in the free
google photos storage will remain free
so no fears of your google bill suddenly
including the terabyte of photos you
posted of your cat while in quarantine
but moving forward all photos you add
will count against your overall google
account's limits
and therefore could affect your monthly
fees
and now for a little google favoritism
users of google's pixel lineup of
smartphones are completely
exempt from the change and will continue
to receive the service free of charge
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you