it seems like chia is all anybody's
talking about and we're not talking
about those little planters that you put
the goo
on we're talking about the
cryptocurrency oh
it's an exciting new cryptocurrency and
the reason it's exciting is because it's
changing the face of cryptocurrency
farming
by going with a completely different
method through
uh proof of or proof of space is that
what you call it proof of space
end time yes
now we've had a couple of episodes where
we're talking about uh some of the
questions that have come in about chia
and even more are rolling in as people
are starting to catch on
they're getting involved and so the
questions are getting a little bit
deeper
jeff i'm getting involved yes you are
actually we
both are getting it's exciting times
so i'm going to hop right into it and
i'm going to see if i can stump robbie
oh you got some questions
i do if they're getting deeper they're
getting harder let's hope i did enough
research
i hope so what do you got for me all
right first question yeah
for my chia farm drive should i format
an ntfs
uh okay so this is the farm drive this
is nothing to do with the plotter
correct i am planning to put my chia
farm
on a raspberry pi 4.
um so it's going to be an external drive
on my raspberry pi connected
because it's such a light like
so low powered so low cost and so
ntfs is not the right solution but the
problem that we run into is that we want
our farming drive so where we put our
plots to be
accessible from any machine so that be
like i i'm assuming jeff that your um
your plotting system is a windows system
as an example
so because i'm going to be moving it
onto a raspberry pi which is
linux i want a format that's going to be
compatible with that
of course yes i can use ntfs but then
you've got to install
ntfs 3g you've got to get everything up
and running with read write x
forget about all that and just go exfat
exfat is compatible right out of the box
with windows
and linux as long as you install the
exfat dash
utils and fuse tools uh using your
favorite package manager
so just type in apt install um
exfat dash utils and you'll be able to
access that drive so
it's as easy as that so i would go with
xfat
i like fat i need to lose some weight
all right
so all right the next question
all right will i have to replot once
pools are available
because right now there are no pools
okay so i'm sorry uh
the question is once pools are available
for
chia coin will i have to replot
my farm because i've already plotted it
for solo mining or
solo farming correct yes and no um so
yes in that if you want to use that same
space
for pools yes you will have to refarm it
uh re re-plot it but the fact is is that
plotting takes a long time jeff and so
what i would actually do is i would
take a different approach and instead of
re-plotting
just simply continue plotting but as we
continue plotting
we're going to continue plotting um
for the pools right does that make sense
so
totally makes sense so right now we're
plotting for solo farming but
we can't use those same uh those same
plots for
pools um when pools are available to us
we want to be able to create new plots
and those plots will be accessible by
our
by our pools makes sense now so like add
to it yeah now speaking of pools they're
not yet available
no do we know not technically i mean
people are they're they're our friends
like
jeff if you and i wanted to go together
and say
hey let's create like a clustered
environment where
you and i are creating a bit of a pool
but as far as official pools go um
the question is when i don't have an
answer to exactly when i don't think
anyone
really does however it should be noted
that just
um a few days ago as we're recording
this video but um
i think may 18th we started to see some
action
on the official chia network
github and on that on that github page
we started to see some open source code
coming out for pool
um connectivity for the chia plotter so
this is going to be really exciting do
we know when it's going to
actually take place no but it's very
very soon
i mean may 18th we started to see the
code going up and
we're going to start seeing that take
effect that's exciting
very cool all right should i say what
pools are
sure so as we're solo farming that means
that
it's your hardware trying to get chia
coin as we pool
it would be jeff and me working together
with the power of all of our computers
in order to get well all of our storage
i guess
in in this proof of work uh proof of
space
and time not proof of work and
so we can kind of pool everything
together it's exactly as a sound
and with that pool we'll be much more
likely to get
chia so as a public pool becomes
available that means that there may be
hundreds or even thousands
of chia farmers who are going to be
using
the same pool and so me the little guy
who just has
four terabytes of chia plots
i have much more chance of actually
seeing some chia in my lifetime
right it's true okay now speaking of
plotting yeah uh if you've
stopped plotting say mid plot
uh mid plot yeah mid plot no don't do
this could be that you accidentally
stopped it maybe potentially stopped it
or maybe there's a power
tripped over the power cord exactly so
can you just pick up from where it's
going will things be frozen uh yeah the
plot will be lost
so anything that you're plotting will be
lost
but your previously finished plots will
be okay
but the stuff that is lost
there's a little trick right now and
this may be
improved in time i mean we're still very
very young
with chia so the the software itself i
mean
so what you need to do if you're on
windows
you're going to go to c colon slash
users
slash your name slash
dot chia and in that folder you're going
to see a wallet
folder just simply rename that something
else or delete it and then
reopen the chia blockchain software
and i should say before you rename it or
delete it make sure you have the
software
closed or like actually kill the task
on linux it's going to be in your home
folder slash dot
chia so that's the wallet folder you're
not going to actually lose anything
other than the currently progressing
plots
so your old plots will still be okay
things will sync and then you'll get
back and
up and running um but you know that's
that's
that's just one of those kind of a
little bit of glitchy kind of
um it hasn't it hasn't been perfect as
far as if a plot is partially created
and then fails but you can
resume and start over uh i should say
if if that happens okay all right
now for people who are
looking to do a little bit more one of
the comments we've got is that i'm
hearing of people having
chia factories factories factories
factory farms and i like the sound of
that now assuming i can afford the
components to say
100 terabyte farm 100 terabytes
that's going to be expensive by the way
for the components so keep that in mind
but how can i get it fully up and
running as quick as possible
oh my gosh are you kidding me so
imagine if you've got a hundred terabyte
farm
okay you have to actually plot those
plots first
so how would you do that you would have
to have
multiple nvmes set up in a raid array
set up in some kind of or not even a
raid array i mean
let's be honest you could have just
separate plotters you could have
separate nvme drives
and you could be plotting on each of
those at the same time and then
piping that data out to the farm but a
hundred terabytes jeff
that's a lot that is a lot i mean i'm
getting
so on my i990 9900k
with an mdot no i've got a
i'm using an ssd right now just an sata
ssd and i'm getting about two plus a day
so like you've got to imagine you would
have to have an
astronomical amount of speed
as far as your nvmes go as far as your
data goes your i o
right um it would just be ridiculous but
you see folks doing this and
you say it's like a factory um and i
call it a factory farm
but that's exactly what it is you have
to have
the amount of capacity and in order the
the power to to actually create those
plots
you know jeff like you've been plotting
for the past couple of days yeah
it's it has been a lot slower than i
anticipated but part of that is because
i'm running an nvme
but it's over usb 3.0 or 3.1
3.0 3.0 yes you're not even on uh usbc
that's correct the old usb-a yeah i only
had one nvme slot on my uh
my computer and that's where
everything's located
so i'm doing everything over the the usb
so yeah it is slower
now getting into the post plotting
post farming you've earned some chia
we have great yeah we have fantastic
cash out let's go buy some
wendy's and we have two questions about
that
and uh the first one chia isn't readily
available on high profile exchanges like
binance or kraken yet
you can get it on some exchanges but
they're very
down the wrong in what i would call
trustability but that's my opinion
um so so this person's asking what do i
do with my chia
hold yeah okay so is the price
and how is the price fluctuating if i
can't do anything with it
and and what do i do if i want to trade
it
we can't yet that's coming presumably
um but this is all you know we're we're
early adopters we are
the early bird right now okay so
understand that so
so a big part of the process of farming
chia right now
is to be that early bird you want to be
the ones who get this chia coin
while it's really easily available
for by farming rather than purchasing
because you've seen the price
go from six thousand dollars down to a
thousand and jeff was telling me what
about eight hundred today
uh yeah as we're recording this because
we're seeing
um we're seeing the cryptocurrency
market right now we're seeing a
consolidation so
things are kind of figuring themselves
out and and we're going to see those
prices
equalize and and we're going to see
where those land now as far as chia goes
because it's not currently on an
exchange that is readily available like
binance
we're not going to be able to trade that
right
so it's all about holding it's all about
accumulating and holding
at the moment and sure there are
exchanges that will allow you to trade
but i would as jeff says stay away from
those for the moment
that's just my personal opinion because
um i'm
i'm gonna hold my chia absolutely
okay so then is chia a hold coin or
is it setting up to be a trade coin coin
jeff isn't a
bottle coin well fair enough yeah but
there are some coins where it's like
this is the one i'm gonna trade with
it's focused on trading
okay or is this one of those ones
because it's a new model in the fact
that it's
i don't know that we really know yet i
mean
there are coins that are very volatile
and that their
their value fluctuates incredibly and
right now i know it's a very confusing
time
to get involved in cryptocurrency in
general because
it's so volatile the entire market but
we're going to see that pan out
as things start to equalize and figure
themselves out
but as far as chia goes we don't really
know where it's going to fall
and when it does fall we just want to be
in there we just want to be
a part of that cryptocurrency as far as
the
the market goes so if it's worth
400 when it finally drops on the
cryptocurrency exchanges great i want to
have a thousand of them
so do i yeah but if if it ends up being
worth
two or three thousand dollars like we
just don't know folks i mean
realistically
there's no way to really know at this
point what it's going to be valued at
when it hits the exchange
right when it does though you you know
you hope to have some
and and the fact is now jeff you were
asking a little bit about pooling
um and whether or not we're gonna have
to re-um
plot our pool uh our farm in order to
pool
um the fact is we can do both we can
both
farm pooled chia and we can farm
uh solo chia right so
knowing that well we we may as well kind
of get in on it
as soon as possible and then when it all
drops when everything comes together
we're ready for it we've got our gear
we're ready to go you've
accumulated whatever you've got in the
storage closet and put something
together
yep sounds good so let us know are you
farming chia that's that's what i want
to know i
i do i do know of some people who are
farming chia it's exciting to be
in at the beginning so are you let us
know
comment below and if you have any more
questions about chia
just ask and when it hits the moon
patreon.com category5
[Laughter]
all right back to plotting
[Music]
you