welcome to this week's coffee break
everybody nice to see you
i see peter at the top left i see bp9 at
the top right
sulbu at the bottom left small crew this
week
but hey we've been off for a few weeks
and i'll tell you what that was
well needed well earned some would say
well i hope you got a nice relaxing
vacation you know we got rained out bp9
so i'm sorry for me
so for me personally robbie it was time
off work
it gave me chances to like think about
some projects and kind of do some
planning
i even came in and i spent two days at
the studio at the tail end of my
vacation time
just to get some things done around here
so for me it was a break away
it was like time away from work my like
my day job
yeah for my wife and kids though it was
going from one quarantine to another
quarantine
yeah i guess they were stuck inside and
couldn't do anything usually
which is basically you know that's their
life since march yeah
so um so to you know take them to the
cottage it was just
another place where you couldn't go
anywhere or do anything because we got
rained out
so that meant no no campfires no
um outdoor activities um taking them to
the park
i did get them to the park but you know
what i mean like
rainfall a couple of days
[Music]
so we make do but i enjoyed having time
off anyways and i'm getting some things
done around here but i am back to work
and uh after my vacation time
feel a little more refreshed you know as
you as you do after a bit of a break
away
so just you know feeling feeling good
and and ready to rock this and
looking forward to all that's to come
this this i don't know if you guys
realize but something that's in the back
of my mind is that category 5 tv
is coming up on season 14.
it's fast approaching so it's like so
i'm preparing for that at the same time
and get
you know as so season 13 becomes
accidentally like we never saw this
coming last october but
it has become like the transient
season like this is the season where
everything is changing and every
you know we're at a new studio we got
new space every
every show i'm saying you know i got
this done i got that done
but i still have this this and this to
do and uh
you just excuse me you just did episode
and i've already made fun of you know
what's coming with
episode 666 six weeks away
yeah so sorry how does that
happen how does that coincide with the
end of this season and beginning of
season 14 when
i mean is it gonna drive is it gonna
jive exactly
wouldn't that be crazy yeah
this would be the right time to switch
to the uh
season 14 episode one
i don't know how many episodes are left
so it's gonna be close
yeah we're getting there uh so on here
what do we got oh that doesn't really
help me i can actually jump over to
calendar
and let's see how things coincide so we
are at 6 61.
yeah well that'll be the next show
because you just got 660.
yeah so it's six weeks away right 663
664 665 666 will be september 23rd
oh so okay good that's good
because that means that episode will be
in season 13 and just be piled on with
all the rest of them
maybe we should move it maybe we should
move it to friday
friday season 13 episode 66
um if i recall correctly though
that would be the final episode of
season 13. let me just quickly look at
the year view
and jump back to 2019 and september
is it uh october that you generally
switch beginning of october
well no
technically it's uh september 25th
i believe let me just quickly check i'll
i'll jump on
my i'm looking for another way to do
this i'm gonna jump on to season one
episode one
september 25th yeah correct so so
september 25th is our
first show of episode 14 so whichever
date
coincides with that september you said
yeah so september closing
yeah so 666 will be the last episode of
season 13.
that's okay that's okay yeah we should
just
oh boy i think that's appropriate it
really no not burning down the place but
you know
it really thumbs up oh it wraps up
twenty
[Laughter]
so bp9 what have you been up to well
let's see first my uh
uh my pine time yes
still bricked gilbert have you figured
that out yet
i haven't had a chance to to be honest i
haven't had a chance to look at it
because i am working with my man yeah i
was working on that uh i think a couple
of weeks ago i talked about the
client server version of a program that
i was writing
yeah i was built you know sending
requests back and forth between the
client the server
yeah well the client's all done it's all
storing locally
but it's uh it's not syncing with a
server yet and i'm just now starting on
the server
so i'm grinding away with that
and then this hey
you tell me look look at the time look
at the time on that thing
is it does that look functional to you
it looks like it's holding at three
o'clock
well yeah is it really three o'clock
there no
it started it started doing this a few
uh uh a few days ago i put a
pay-as-you-go sim inside it
um and it's been working fine from when
i first
put it in there um and
i've been able to make and take calls i
i can make him take calls
when it when it holds on to the um
uh when it holds on to the network
here's what the front screen looks like
oh it's it's it looks you know you'd
love
this because it's it's mate isn't it
that looks like unity or maybe like
a derivative there like that is ubuntu
about that um and the two bottom icons
you know uh i don't know if i can do
this but i don't actually know like
it could be a but with the icons it
makes me think it's like
unity or i mean gnome 3 style right
what happens when you hit that ubuntu
button oh that gets you
to a bunch of uh applications can we see
it
come back i wish i could there you go
yeah there you go
oh okay so yeah see that really looks
like unity but that
works on a phone yeah for me yeah like i
don't like that on a desktop but i like
it
on a phone i i i'm still
you know the jury is still out as to
yeah
they have been able to make text
messages work
in and out i was able to make phone
calls work
in and out and i don't know if you can
see the icons
on there but it yeah i don't know what i
just did
oh yeah the camera doesn't work either
by the way just in case you're wondering
so people are thinking like why are why
are you interested
yeah and that doesn't help when you drop
it either sure
people are wondering why are you
interested in a pine phone when you know
all these things don't work and it's
like
part of that is the tinkering aspect oh
it's the open source aspect
yes the fact that they're breaking
ground on
a legit um secure
safe private um
like privacy-focused linux based
smartphone but i've got to tell you i'm
all over this phone i love the phone
but it's not ready to be a daily driver
yet
no no on the on the check to on the chat
group
sasha was saying you know i'm going to
get me a new phone i'm going to get me
one of those i said
right hold on a minute yeah yeah think
about it no
no no no no no no no don't we got to
think of
[Music]
20 years for a libra m5 or you can get a
pine phone right now
and experience linux on a phone right
like so like wait until it's completely
ready or
get in at the bleeding edge when you
know it's open source so like we're
gonna see a lot of
improvements at the moment yet i don't
have a lot of time to get in there and
try and figure out how
how it all hangs together um so
for right now i'm just leaving it alone
letting the experts play with it
and downloading the latest version i had
to i had to switch to the
um peter would you mind muting your
microphone for me please
um i had to uh i had to switch to
the development branch in order to make
in order to get phone calls and text
messages working
oh yeah the stable branch
doesn't work at all um the stable branch
well
it's not surprising because it's still
under such heavy development
so um phone calls work
text messages work that's about all i
can report at the moment
um i've had it probably a week a week
and a half or something like that
it keeps dropping off the telephone
network and it keeps dropping off my
wi-fi and i don't know why not sure
what's going on there
and if i you know sometimes it will say
i don't have a telephone network
but then it will it will still make a
call or
still take a text message so yeah i
don't know
i have not i remember when i first
talked about this with bo
from ameridroid yeah i asked him about
um how do i make it sync up with um
my kaldap
yeah i know um because i want to i want
to take the contact list that i have on
my own machine and i want this to sync
to that contact list
i can do it my laptop i can do it with
my pc they're all running ubuntu
i can do it with my phone it's running
android so you know i think i should be
able to do it with this
you would expect you could go to the
command line and say apt-get install
or app install of evolution right
app doesn't work on this on this distro
so i don't know yet so i don't know
what's going on with that
all you can do is go to the online store
and get a a and pick from a bunch of
applications you want there an evolution
is not in there
there is no calendar or rather no
no cal dab or card dev
there is an an option to let you connect
caldav
to a kaldab server but when i select it
it just spins
it doesn't actually do anything it just
so eventually can you can you um
compile from the cli
can i compile on the phone yeah like
could you grab
uh a copy of evolution source code and
compile it
probably yeah yeah probably and that's
certainly
worth a try it's going to compile up on
a arm or armhv
architecture which is going to be
interesting
um i have not tried it yet what i was
what i would like to know is and this is
one of the things i want to do when i
tinker
um what i would like to know is when i
connect it when i plug it up to charge
it up
on the usbc port on the bottom
um when i go to charge it up does that
also give me usb
tty access does that give me an
option to because that would be handy
otherwise the only way in would be via
ssh over wi-fi and that would mean
making
the phone a wi-fi server
which freaks me out that's not something
i want could you
could you install open fsh server oh
yeah yeah of course
and it's only going to be and then just
install
uh a firewall you should be able to
install like ufcw or something
well as i say normally what i would do
is is do apt install and
you know do whatever i need to do yeah
it's not available on this phone
right okay can you bring up the terminal
on the phone screen
oh yeah yeah sure so if you can do that
get a uh
like a usb usb c
to uh hdmi adapter and plug it into your
tv
and then use a bluetooth keyboard and
it'd be just like a computer
there you go so just use a bluetooth
keyboard to do all your typing
well yeah but whether i type on the
keyboard or whether i type on the
built-in
i mean there it is there's the built-in
keyboard right on the phone
on the terminal so i mean i can do
[ __ ]
in the cli is fun with the on-screen
keyboard oh you just do mate right you
just do mate and away you go i mean yeah
obviously
but you still have to do i don't even
know if it's on here let me check
no it's not found so normally i would do
apt install git
but i can't do that because that's not
available yeah so you're gonna have to
double you get
the zip file or car file from github
i haven't figured out yet what i'm gonna
do with that i may try a different
distro
it doesn't have to be ub ports it just
came with the phone
but that was a point that that um
that bo made was that he has half a
dozen different
sd card uh you know little sd cards yeah
yeah all of which have different distros
on them
and i'm reading on the forums that other
distros are more
um uh more successful so
we'll see what happens do not recommend
it for a daily driver
it's just not that ready for it yet um
it took me switching to development
branch to actually make it
make it at least take and receive phone
calls take and receive text messages
um and that's about all i can report at
the moment
um i don't have anything i don't have
anything more to report i wish i could
say more i wish i could say yeah it's
great you should get it but
i really can't i can't do that i can't
do that
in good conscience i just can't do that
yet just a strange observation guys as
i'm sitting here i see this box in front
of me
it was just making me think of bp9
oh i got it oh okay
okay okay i don't know what it means
maybe
maybe i should have used like a7 instead
of big bang
i got like a three k three i don't know
what they mean
well maybe it's the size of the box
what are you up to man so i've been
there uh upgrading my systems a little
bit
oh yeah you got a surprise oh nice
podcaster
yeah this is just one of the items um
it will be uh interesting uh watching
the uh
when you post this afterwards uh to hear
the the
sound quality as compared to built in um
but yeah i am spent
sorry sorry to interrupt seoul but bp9
do you think that it would be fun for me
in post to like drop his voice two
octaves and
please do yes make him squeak like he's
been breathing helium
okay all right we'll take care of that
all right go ahead
so i'm i've been upgrading my systems um
i used about 950 dollars and bought that
two
computers um almost brand new
and the guy who sold it was he was
getting out of the computer industry so
you have no use for them so i've been
planning to to
switch to and replace two of my systems
anyway
and the biggest system i had had a hard
drive that was
starting to have problems so um the
first thing i did was um
i set the uh i installed the operating
system and
and then i uh um or synced um
my entire uh home folder nice
it took six hours um yeah
yeah it's also close to uh
1.8 uh terabytes or something
like that it's funny how stuff just
collects in your home folder isn't it
just sort of
levitates the air just sort of i noticed
that it was uh
in a few folders that it had trouble
reading the files but it managed to read
everything so it was about time to do it
anyway
yes your hard drive's starting to flake
out for the show and
in the other system that yeah the the um
slower system uh it had the hard drive
with almost a year old uh something so
it's um relatively new i just moved it
to the
new system so yeah and i also have a
curved um two screens and they came
along with their
um so one of those things it's a curved
one and it's and
still uh adapting to uh
times i had a hard time switching from
two smaller screens
to one huge screen i had a hard time
with that because
when you have two smaller screens you
can
what i did specifically i had a fairly
large screen as my main screen
and then a smaller screen off to the
side and in fact i had the laptop screen
open this is at work
the laptop screen open as well so i
could work on the main screen
and then drag off the windows to
subsidiary screens whenever i
didn't want to work on that right away
even expand on there
and now it wouldn't blow up on the hole
like the problem you'll have solder is
with your curved screen
it'll all when you expand the window
it'll it'll go
all over your main screen and you don't
have any room for any of it
yeah but i kind of like
having everything um and maximized so
yes
only one window is visible at the same
time it's how i
usually am it's how i do things but
the first thing that was strange was uh
setting up the first system
and then comparing um and then comparing
um
alongside the the other screen that was
still here
and then i noticed uh how bad the old
screen really was
when i had a really good so it's
probably really
dim and you don't even notice it because
it happens so
gradually that you don't even notice it
happening right yeah
um on on so on bp9's point
i i'm sure this is probably both of you
but
uh have i frozen oh there i am no you're
not you're good this is probably pretty
obvious but
on both windows 10 and any modern linux
desktop that i've seen
if you drag your window all the way to
the left or
all the way to the right or even all the
way to the top or all the way to the
bottom it will actually
split it it will maximize it and split
it so you can drag one to the very very
far left and let go and it will only
take up half of the screen
then take another one and drag it all
the way to the right and it will only
take up the right hand side
so i think they've accommodated that
like major but i know exactly what
you're talking about and that's why i
got screens all around me
because i like to at work i have three
screens in front of me so i have windows
10 on one screen
because internally we use that for
communication unfortunately and i got
mint on my screen in front of me and
then i've got another windows machine
which runs my time
tracker for tracking hours and things
so but uh yeah i i hear you there
so that's so upgraded so here's one of
the
one of the handy dandy things you can do
with this is if you drag the window that
way
now the screens
that's the only way that's the only way
that i know that you can select programs
that are
all running in parallel or dismiss the
program
altogether just by swiping up well it
really here we go
and swipes up and then now i don't know
if that's something that that
um ubuntu this particular version of
ubuntu
has been doing all all the time but but
i don't know
yeah everything that i was thinking
about when
you've described
not working and i'm not
sure if you did that already but one
thing that you could check is that
the the sources files in the etc
that it's actually have their sources
configured so
that it has a server to at least attempt
to fix uh updates from
the the actual the actual apt program
does not exist
it says command not found
say that one more time robbie we've lost
audio on bp9 i think
was that just me no no it was you you
you dropped out for just a second
[Laughter]
thanks for your patience man what's new
what's new with you peter
peter how's everything going okay yeah
okay
yeah yeah yeah yeah all right
hey
i've been overworked tired like i i put
in like a
20-hour day on thursday and just like go
go go and constantly going so yeah i i
feel you man
yeah peter needs it too man he can't get
i can't leave the uh premises because
i'm
on uh at risky has a problem with me
uh i can't leave the premises yeah yeah
i'm stuck though yeah but uh i'll
bother i am i will be being on land
the other day that don't tell him and
i've got five and nominated melbourne
uh the guy was on the radio in melbourne
and uh he was moaning to me about being
locked in
and i explained to him i've been
and he said the next the next days
they've talked to me
we're not allowed to move from melbourne
because there's
doing this since march you know and i'm
quite happy with it all year but uh
and then i uh i i uh sort of worked
south africa
and uh another australian with the name
of diarrhea
so peter are you able to are you able to
use your ham radio to communicate all
the way to australia
yeah do you say yeah unreal
you're in england if i recall nominal
island
ireland okay ireland
and people are not playing games and
people that they do work for me and
they don't turn up oh no
and that's tough too like my mom had
that happen where like she was in the
middle of a move
and then like people who were supposed
to be helping her didn't show up because
they're like because of the pandemic
right like it's
because i'm a foreigner
yeah uh that person
basically votes sometimes you know and
uh i accept it and uh but uh
three weeks so i got some meal to do it
in the end
relationship because i just couldn't
bloody wait uh uh
um i just couldn't keep up i couldn't be
naughty to him because uh you know
but you got family who are coming to
help or yeah a good family can
get to multiple work
i would say we get the thing
your rest man you need your rest off
tall towers and
um i i like to like if i'm having
trouble sleeping i know
our situations are very very different
but for me it's usually like things
running through my mind and i just can't
get
i can't get my
and i can still not sleep i'm sleeping
on top of the bed i'm
trying to find a room which is cold i
last night i just stayed up all night
because i just couldn't go with it
anymore and i did well the funny thing
is that
here in the states we take air
conditioning for granted and i don't
know if that's also true
uh in canada robbie is it um
but i i think so yeah i mean yeah
certainly
to my knowledge that's certainly not
true in england am i right peter island
i'm just waiting for it to rain i want
it to rain
but you understand that i said that at
the beginning of my vacation and then i
regretted it
i wanted just one day of rainfall so
that we could so they could lift the
fire ban and we could have a campfire
and then i got torrential downpours
together two boys drowned together
anyway been playing the um
and worked all over the world but he
worked into asia as well
wrote all the continents i think uh
including asia
i looked into indonesia twice
as well having trouble making you out
peter i'll be honest
a little better yeah i haven't having
trouble there
but i i hope i hope things cool off for
you dude
and uh and i wish you all the best and
and it's been nice chatting with you
guys
um keep track of the vlog if you if you
receive that
um i i will be showing some of the
behind the scenes on category 5
technology tv as well
yeah go ahead peter
i think that is the closest that he is
that's all you're going to get peter
yeah okay at least on the air i think
playing secret squirrel game without no
name and
no place either anyway okay
you guys take care it's nice seeing you
um good to be back
uh it's going to take a couple weeks for
me to kind of get the momentum going and
everything with everything because
there's a lot of stuff going on here
uh bp nine sobu you guys know all about
that through the vlog
and uh like it's here i am today like
vacuuming up sawdust and and and
finishing the wiring and getting
everything done
um and then i gotta shoot some video for
the show on wednesday
um
you're going to control the rotator with
the raspberry pi yeah
right yeah and your d converted it all
out
what's that a to d h d converter is an
analog to digital converter oh yeah yeah
yeah
it's very cool
i think that's what's neat about like
single board computers you can use them
for anything
you know a question i said how many uh
a today converters are on the pi
how many hd converters are on the
raspberry pi oh i don't know you'd have
to
the spec diagram that would i agree
there are
there are gpio pins there are digital
and analog pins but i don't know if
they're
going to do what you need to do peter
there's 40 pins there's i squared c
um but looking at a pin out diagram and
that's beyond that's that's beyond what
i can help you with to today on
at the end of the coffee break have a
wonderful week everybody and i will see
you
again um well i'll see you wednesday and
again for coffee break again next sunday
so take care everybody see ya
thanks robbie enjoyed it man cheers
yeah me too csv see peter cbp9
it went too fast
it always does so i've been upgrading my
systems um
[Music]