hello
this is category five tv uh category
five tv coffee break
i'm uh bp9 giving you a wave over there
and we've got solberg give us a way of
solving
oh okay close enough and then we've got
doug
give us away and hello there you go and
hello peter give us away peter
there we go hello peter all right then
welcome to the
to the coffee break and uh my news
basically this week
is uh uh is to do with yesterday oh
yesterday last week i think i talked
about um
uh primarily
uh unit tests in c programs
and that was a big deal for me because i
used to do that in java all that time
where i would try to get 70 or 80
coverage on my on my java code
for you know for commercial reasons that
was required you know you needed to be
sure
that your code matched that your code
actually did what you expected it to do
so what i've done uh one of the other
things that we'd like to do is to make
sure you get good code coverage
and with code coverage that's something
that's that's
not well that i did not think was quite
so easy to get with um
with c but it turns out it's trivial
the gcc compiler
will quite happily generate coverage
data for you
when you use the minus minus coverage
command one argument so you give that
command line argument to the
to the compiler and to the linker
and then when you run the program with
your test harness
what will happen is it will run all of
the tests and it will just
it'll just uh uh you just run all the
tests that you that you have in your
test suite
in the end you get a whole bunch of
coverage data that you then convert to
an html page
and you get a you get a very nice
uh screen um a website basically
that tells you how much what sort of
coverage you get at the whole program
level
and then at each file level and even
down to each
um function and line level if you wanted
to do that
so that's been fun for me i've been
getting into that
um i have been working on that client
server program that i mentioned probably
a week or two ago
where i've been trying to get the um
uh where i've been trying to get the um
um uh the the
the client to encrypt and then sign the
payload
and then have the server um uh
decrypt and then verify the signature on
the payload
but i haven't been able to make that
work reliably at first i couldn't get it
to work at all until i figured out just
just by looking at other people's code
how to
how i had to create a hash of the
payload and then encrypt
and then sign the hash that
works but it doesn't work reliably i can
out of ten runs i can make it work maybe
seven times
out of those tens but i haven't changed
anything all i do is i run that test
harness over and over and over again
sometimes it works and sometimes it
doesn't and i don't know why
so if anyone has any insight into that
i'd love to hear it because right now i
can't
uh uh right now i can't do anything
about that
so what's your connection between the
client and the server
uh it is a uh it is a tcp socket
but since both are running on the
well correction on when i'm running it
on the test harness
um the connection there is no connect
they're running in the same process
um so i'm i'm taking a payload i'm
let me put it in frame i'm taking a
payload i'm signing it
and then i'm taking that signed payload
and then verifying the signature with a
different crypto function
all in the same process all on the same
machine
are correct yes sir okay now maybe
maybe it doesn't like me signing and
verifying the very same signature on the
very same payload
maybe maybe i have to do it in separate
processes or something i don't know
how about trying it on separate machines
uh i could do that but then i would need
to actually write the code that makes
the connection between the two machines
i have not written that code yet i'm i'm
basically proving
that i can encrypt and sign first and
then i'm going to write the code and
and verify that it will talk over the
internet over tcp
socket i'm confident i can do that i've
written that code
enough times that i can you know i'm
confident that i can
make that part work what i wasn't sure
about
considering the unreliability i'm just
wondering if something's not getting
dropped in transmission
well for for this it's not there's no
connection involved here
for this it's um it's quite literally
just a
um for this it's a straight up
connection
to um uh i keep saying connection and
i'm wrong
the the signing and the verifying
is all happening in exactly the same
process in the same
address space there's no uh
uh there's no intermediate connection
going on between the two no we're
forbidden
if you were trying to say something no i
don't think so
what were you trying to say peter i
apologize you are making some noise and
i have to
temporarily i said that
it could be modifying the things that
are sticking to it's wrong again
every time you run the attacks it's
changing the
code in some way very literally and that
might be changing why one worked the
second time or the third time round
of that one well the program code the
program code is identical for each run
and the payload is identical for each
run the only thing that's different
is the is is the signed value because
the seed is slightly different
each time it each time it runs but i
can't imagine that that would have
anything to do with
uh i can't imagine that would have
anything to
that's the only thing i could think is
something there's something changing
because it says like something's
changing in the loop somewhere
and that's why it's not working oh i
would agree
yeah i would agree that uh that
something's different but the thing is i
don't know what's different
and here's the here's the unfortunate
part about using
libraries from your from your code uh
just like you do in pascal peter when
you use units right or when you use
libraries you rely on those libraries to
do the right thing
but in order for the libraries to do the
right thing you have to actually
understand how the libraries work
and i'm not quite sure that i've that
i've understood all the rules that are
involved around
around calling the various especially
crypto functions because
they are so sensitive all right horrible
things yeah
and you have to pull the right right
things into it as well because that can
make you go
bang as well oh sure yeah oh
absolutely but anyway because i'm
running exactly the same code
go ahead i'm sorry is there any way to
monitor the throughput
is there any way to monitor the threat
literally
i'm thinking i'm thinking i could
literally step through the code
with the the gnu debugger um
if i wanted to do that um i
typically don't like stepping through
the code because it changes all the
timings
around how the code works right so i'm
not sure that
so i'm not sure that stepping through
the code is going to be very productive
yeah i would rather rely on log messages
except the problem is
that log messages even so tend to
uh alter the timing of the code if
you're writing a lot of messages to the
console
that slows the whole program down and
that could be enough
to uh to hide the bug um
you know right is there any way to reach
is there any way to record the
throughput and then step through it
afterwards
i'm not sure about that i'm not sure how
i would do that
um i mean i i write log messages uh
as far as the results of the tests go
and so from that
i can tell um whether the
whether the encrypt or the the signing
was successful or not
because i get a return code back to
return code zero then the signing was
successful and it's all good right
but if the return code comes back with
some nonsensical value
and that nonsensical value by the way if
you convert it to hex and then
you know take away the the very highest
bit it resolves in it resolves to
what i think is a return code that means
a conflict
of some sort but there's no
documentation about what that conflict
return code means it just says uh yeah
there was a conflict
well thanks i knew that
[Laughter]
if i'm reading the return code correctly
that's what it means but
but how on earth do i do i
um you know how do i
proceed with that i don't know so i'm
going to keep plugging away at it
sometimes when i see some
error message from some process and
sometimes i
think to myself yeah i knew that tell me
something i don't know
exactly right that's exactly how i feel
right now and
i get i get it if i'm reading the return
code correctly because it did involve
converting it to hex dropping off that
high value that high bit value at the
very
high level and then reading the
remainder because it was what the bit
level was one
zero zero zero zero zero zero zero zero
and then
whatever was the hex value of the return
code was one idea that i'm
thinking of yeah you said you are uh
signing
um a payload and then you are verifying
that it's
signed correctly correct yeah and
have you tried just to verify that
that it's um have you tried uh
decrypting
the payload afterwards save the each of
the payloads
um save one that is correct and one that
is not correct
and then decrypt each one and see and
then see
what is different yeah so i'm doing so
i'm doing
the um the encrypt and decrypt
separately from the signing and
verifying to prove that i can do each
individually and then if i can prove i
can do each individually
then i will take the payload sign it
encrypt it
decrypt it verify the signature and then
retrieve the payload i'm not to that
point yet i've proven i can encrypt and
decrypt no problem at all
i can do that that's that works just for
i can do that reliably
every single time no worries at all but
it's the
it's the whole signing and then
verifying the signature of the payload
that is that is biting me right now
yeah that is exactly my point have you
uh
tried just to verify that
you know if not to eliminate
that those two payloads
are actually the same even though you
haven't um
come to the point where uh you have any
um
good use for it yet but just to verify
that okay
yes i've done that with a very good
yeah so i've done that with i've done
that with encrypting and decrypting
all right peter go ahead sir
i'm gonna be rude but they could do a
checksum before and check them off to
see if their numbers change
because i have that okay yeah that's no
idea
okay so so the thing is
the payload is plain text okay it's just
it's literally a json document okay
so it's trivial to verify that the
payload is the same
now the operation of signing a payload
does not change the payload signing the
payload creates a
separate a hex string
that you store separately okay and then
you take
both of those and you encrypt them
then later on after you've sent it over
the interwebs or whatever you've done
you decrypt it
and then you take that signature and you
verify the
the payload after you know
from the signature you do not
the payload does not change when you
sign
or verify the signature so the
trick is in order to test to make sure
the signing and verifying work
is that you sign it you get the
signature
and then you pass that signature to the
verify along with the payload
and you say okay does this does this
verify
does this verify correctly the only
thing that i can
think of that um there are two places
that i can think of that
there might be a problem one is uh that
uh the actual
signing uh uh fails somehow
or that the verification
fails somehow and it doesn't tell you
why or where it there or
yeah okay so
the point of failure is the signing
because i can see the signature
as well as get a zero return code
whenever the
signing operation is correct it works
so i can see the signature okay because
i i print that in my log message
so if the signing does not work
um my test code is dumb i just go ahead
and try to verify it anyway but of
course there's nothing to verify because
the signature failed
so the point out the point of failure is
the signature is the signing of the of
the payload
that's where the failure is happening i
i can tell you that
unequivocally it i've never had a an
issue where if it signed successfully
that verification failed if it signed
successfully
verification worked every single time
but the signing
is where it's filing could it be that um
it could be a timing issue uh could it
be um
i'm just thinking out of my head as
usual could it be that um
but it's starting to sign before the
payload is
uh properly delivered so that it's
signing something and
um i think it's running too soon so to
say
oh so the test code so the test code
doesn't run
to it doesn't attempt to verify the
signature
until after the signing process is
complete
because i don't move on to the next
operation until i see a good
zero return code from the from the
signing process
yeah but so i don't think it can move i
don't
think it can move on to verifying until
after i know the signature's good
yeah and this is where uh either our
debugger or the debug messages would uh
come in handy
because then you can see if
if there's a time manager
yeah and by the way a big shout out to
the glib
uh test harness folks
they did a great job they did a very
good job making it
making the test harness look and work as
much like
uh the java equivalents
as um as as as i can
they did a better job that i could do
for instance because my clunky test
harness just runs all the tests
and i don't care how long it takes but
you can categorize tests to say whether
they're really really long running
and therefore whether you choose to run
them on a on a regular test harness yeah
all that sort of stuff
but now whether there's something going
on with the test harness now you know
there may be something
going on with the test code that i don't
know about you know but
this also proves that uh they're doing
uh something that requires an
encryption and doing it properly is
really hard
so those uh they are and
projects who do a good encryption um
um some of their
somewhere along the lines of such
problems they had to have
a couple of times in order to uh so um
yeah just explain it
it's hard agreed i agree but i will say
again though
encryption is working great i can
encrypt and decrypt to my heart's
content and i get the same payload back
every time
not a problem that part works great it's
the signing that that's biting me in the
backside so that's the only thing that
i'm i'm trying to
uh i'm trying to get my head around i
don't understand i wouldn't be using
rsa i believe
i need to go check i haven't looked i
could go look
i mean i could but i don't want to mess
up the recording so
i'll tell you later
uh yeah so that's what i've been up to
if anyone has any other other any other
ideas i'd be really happy to hear it
so let's go around the table real quick
because i've hogged up way too much time
here
so what you got going on uh this weekend
i've been uh yesterday and today
and i've been helping my brother
to move yes he got a new job
so he has
he has to close or end his uh
rent agreement uh in the
in his old flat and before he can move
into a new one he had to yeah
so he is a moving uh he has a temporary
place to stay
um half of his uh furniture are in my
garage right now so
and he has a few uh so for the americans
on the line
for the americans on the line a flat is
is the same as an apartment yeah right
that's what i've been doing i know you
knew that after this
coffee break i'm going to head in and
put my uh trailer on my car and i drive
to meet him somewhere and then he is
taking over the trailer and
uh moving the last uh pieces of the
of the air how far away is he
and far away yeah two and a half hours
to drive from
here to him oh
so it's not exactly a good commute the
option to stay at his current
home to to to drive to the new work is
not really an option then
from his old place onto the uh to the
new york it's one and a half hour can
you work
yeah yeah oh okay maybe two hours
trains public transport maybe
yeah is that an option no because he has
to um
if someone uh need to go to hospital and
then
um he is okay one of those who take
those calls
so it okay
yeah yeah so here's he's a cab driver oh
well
so oh nice okay so he got a new um
signed a contract with that cab company
in
one of the municipalities
an hour from me um and
he and he has a big increase in uh from
in the old job he had a 10
uh work um and uh all the others were
extras and um um if someone was sick
they called him
and so on but now he has a 70
work agreement so
he can plan his spare time a little
better
so the bridge looks great the voyager
bridge looks excellent i see you're
doing the night shift again
um you may want to check the very bottom
of your
uh of your screen because um your green
screen's not
quite reaching all the way
[Laughter]
i hate to call attention to it but i
thought you might want to know there you
go
there oh much better oh yeah much better
much better
doug what you got going on sir how are
you feeling
firstly i am feeling much better i will
return to work tuesday
nice hooray hooray
i've been out three weeks i'm getting it
i'm i'm getting a phone call coming in
so i may lose the internet
again if so please just hang on don't
don't hang up okay
so i'm getting political calls left
right and center it's crazy
uh so you're feeling better doug
you thought you were going to go back to
work last week right
well then i talked to my doctor and he
said you got to have time for your
digestive system to recover
so that's what i've been doing i've been
working on that and
okay i'm doing well so i'll return to
work tuesday
are you back on you're back on solid
foods then everything's good
yes all right
well done yep so it was that funny name
did i spell it right in the
in the notes last week y-l-o
b-a-c-t-e-r wait wait let me write that
down
wait spell it again c
camp c-a-m-p actually
yeah y l-o
b-a-c-t-e-r campylobacter
okay there's no b in there
see did i not say b sorry
i thought you said b maybe maybe a m
p yeah can't belong yeah c a m p
b y okay
l-o-b-a-c-t-e-r yeah i read that b
isn't e so i thought that can't be right
there's got to be a b
in there somewhere
i'll smell it right this time i promise
maybe maybe robbie this is my family all
this user
when they are spelling absolutely yeah
absolutely yeah or you
yeah well there is that too yeah i
probably could have done it and it
probably could have got it right
yeah sorry about that my bad because
they particularly google works
very well with attempted spellings how
nice
yeah that's true it does correct type in
a misspelling it will figure out what
you're trying to do
yeah or in my case duckduckgo i don't i
don't know
that yeah duckduckgo doesn't track you
doesn't track you either right right
right start page
yeah start picking another search engine
oh yep oh
oh i gotta write that one down too
you guys are really helpful thanks start
page
dot com yep sweet
thank you appreciate that i'm using my
handy dandy
stinky dinky tiny little uh
yes yeah man works great
love it no more no more ball point pins
for me except when i write checks
because
you can't you can't push down hard
enough to get through the carbon copy
with this if you try and push down too
hard it'll just spread
the paper well it'll just play the tines
on the on the fountain pen right
now it'll i don't know if you can see it
because it won't focus on my face
it won't focus on that um
on the ad it's still not going to focus
but
the thing is that um it'll it'll um
spread the the teeth the tines on the on
the
on the fountain pen instead of putting
more pressure on the
on the paper so you can't get a copy
peter four five minutes left what you
got going on sir
um my shoulder is still um
and pain uh go go move it and
uh we're knocked down again oh
again yet uh i've got to do anything
particularly
though i've been locked in again and uh
that the numbers are going up there as
well
no no they're all getting evacuated
and i had the flu joke as well the other
day
as well okay and my mother as well
but uh i couldn't have eggs and i
couldn't have
er i like this one um
with a mixed up uh rubber gloves from
latex yep
yep yep i don't know why they take it
i told them it was
oh dear i knew you'd go there i knew you
would go there why am i not surprised
how is your how's your wife feeling
about her bones
knitting up is she resting no
you know she needs to behave herself man
i know i can tell but they won't be they
won't be told
none of them won't be told yeah all the
bloody things
don't just get up
[Music]
okay but the doctor the doctor must have
some idea of what will happen if um
if she doesn't you know knit up properly
what's the
worst case the worst cases are
it should be deformed there and uh it
just won't be right every time he breaks
an arm and then try to because of
anything
the bones will heal back yeah the bones
will heal back up again they'll just
heal up wrong
right that's what i'm saying yeah
they're all done they're all up totally
wrong yeah
they've been in the wrong place though
they could give her a problem problems
but they've reached up and knocked
around there and they don't be told that
i'm not being told by any authority
i'm afraid so you know you know we've
gotten got that bit out because
you know but uh
sorry to hear that i mean yeah all i can
say is you know
tell her to to you know rest up and
heal up and hopefully all will be well
and i i
i can't say any more than that our
thoughts are with you hope uh i hope
everything works out for both you and uh
and your wife so yes oh yeah yeah yeah i
see you
like go ahead go on go ahead um
that's all no i was just
so any closing any closing comments then
before i uh
before i close up the meeting because
it's hard to believe not only that we've
done 30 minutes that's crazy
but um we're only what three months
yeah go ahead yeah
last week the uh recording ended with a
real
a bit sudden when i think you lost your
internet connection
um the end oh that's right awesome
i love that
yep and i i told robbie that now i'll
tell him again he did an excellent job
with that
uh with that ending i loved it so that
was the best picture
of the entire coffee break was the end
was that ending
absolutely oh thank you very much
i appreciate that so the ending was more
entertaining than our
ramblings thank you i appreciate it
all right then on that note i'm going to
go ahead and close
close the meeting so thank you much
appreciate it and hopefully we'll see
you next week maybe rob you'll show up
one time you know just for once and
let us know how his uh studio stuff is
going on
he was gone last week presumably because
he was playing with the
theme song so um we'll see how that
we'll see how that turns out
if he hasn't already has he already
dropped the episode i haven't i don't
know
has he dropped last week's no no not the
entire
but i wasn't able to get it to play
oh really what happened okay
the facing page on patreon had the
little round
play symbol in it you know the triangle
on it
and i hit that and then it went to what
appeared to be a photo
and when i clicked on the photo that's
all it was was a photo there was no link
to a video
now can you can you um download
the video from patreon does it point to
somewhere that you can download it
one thing that i think that this might
be is that the video
is uh still uploading and
being processed so that
the photo is a preview of what is coming
when they are
finished that is yeah yeah yeah i think
yeah so you might just
want to try again maybe try again yeah
yeah all right then well good good news
all right well thank you again
thoroughly enjoyed it as always and and
uh much appreciate your participation
we'll see you we'll see you next week
and
and uh okay try and stay out of trouble
everybody and stay
safe all right take care bye-bye okay
bye