here's what's coming up in the category
tv newsroom toshiba shuts the lid on
laptops after 35 years
the discovery of salt bound to water
molecules on serra's the largest
asteroid in the solar system
suggests that there may be an ocean
lurking beneath the akitore crater
a convincing phishing scam is targeting
targeting cpanel users with a fake
security advisory
a teenager has spent nearly twenty
thousand dollars in twitch donations
with their mother's debit card and
google is creating a worldwide
android phone-powered earthquake alert
system
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5 dot tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight
linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
it's official japanese giant toshiba has
sold its final stake in the personal
computer maker dynabook
which means the firm no longer has a
connection with making pcs or laptops
sharp bought 80 of toshiba's personal
computing arm in 2018 for 36 million
27 million pounds and has now bought the
remaining shares
toshiba said in a statement toshiba's
first laptop the t1000
1100 the t1100 launched in 1985.
it weighed four kilograms and worked
with three and a half
inch floppy disks according to the
toshiba science museum website it was
launched only in europe at first
and had an annual sales target of just
10 000
units in the year 2011 toshiba sold more
than
17 million pcs but my how times have
changed
by 2017 this had fallen to just 1.9
million
in 2016 it had ceased making consumer
laptops for the european market
focusing only on hardware for businesses
recent years have been difficult for the
conglomerate in 2015 the firm
posted a full-year loss of 318 million
dollars
that same year its president and vice
president resigned
after an independent panel found the
company had overstated its profits for
the previous six
years last year they wound up their
nuclear business new gen in the uk
after failing to find a buyer for it
consumer demand for laptops has soared
in the last few months because of the
coronavirus pandemic
and global lockdowns but overall the
market for personal computers has been
tough for quite a while
analyst marina kocheva from the firm ccs
insight says only those who have managed
to sustain
scale and price like lenovo or have a
premium brand like
apple have succeeded in the unforgiving
pc market where volumes have been
falling for years
the results of a major exploration
mission showed monday that the dwarf
planet serra's
long believed to be a barren space rock
is an ocean world with reservoirs of sea
water beneath its surface
maria castine christina de santeef from
the national institute for astrophysics
in italy says of the discovery i'm
extremely excited to find some evidence
of liquid water
together with the fact that this body
has a lot of minerals very interesting
for the formation
of life it's a good combination of
chemical compounds that help in forming
biological molecules
de sancti and her colleagues analyzed
high-resolution images and seras
of seras taken by the dawn spacecraft
which orbited the dwarf
planet between 2015 and 2018 before it
ran out of fuel
in his final phase the spacecraft
orbited just 35 kilometers above the
surface
of sures focusing on the aquitar crater
she and her team were able to identify
salt by comparing data
including images and spectral analysis
from the dawn spacecraft with equivalent
analysis of chemicals here on earth
earlier observations of bright deposits
on the crater had hinted at the presence
of salty water underneath
but the discovery of hydrated sodium
chloride provides much stronger evidence
of an underground ocean
impact fractures on the surface of the
aquitar crater analyzed in a separate
study
suggests the ocean is some 40 kilometers
below the surface
although the exact size is unknown it's
pretty large says the snake t
adding that the present such a large
body will certainly have
influenced the geology of sores with
water coming up from below the surface
and bringing minerals with it
ralph jauman of the free university of
berlin in germany says
the mineralogy is unique and so far not
observed
on other solar system bodies jawmen says
these findings demonstrate that even
small bodies like sores
could have water in their interior
a clever phishing scam is targeting
cpanel users with a fake security
advisory alerting them of critical
vulnerabilities
in their web hosting management panel
cpanel is administrative software
commonly installed on shared web hosting
services
that allow website owners to easily
administer their site through a
graphical user interface
starting last week cpanel and web host
manager whm
users began reporting a targeted
phishing email campaign
with an email subject of cpanel urgent
update request
that was pretending to be a security
advisory from the company
this fake advisory stated that updates
had been released to fix security
concerns
in cpanel and whm software and
recommends all users install the updates
in addition to a well-worded email with
little or no grammar and spelling issues
the threat actors use language commonly
found in security advisories
the attackers registered the domain
cpanel 7831.com
to make the scam appear as a as an
authentic advisory from cpanel
and are using amazon's simple email
service ses to send out the emails
if a recipient of this phishing email
falls for the scam and clicks on the
update your cpanel and whm
installations they were brought to a
website that prompted a user to log in
with their cpanel credentials
as this is a well done and convincing
scam it would not be surprising if some
users fell for the scam
if you received a similar email recently
and entered your login credentials at
this site
it is strongly suggested that you
immediately log into your web hosting
provider
and change the password on your account
you should then perform a complete audit
of your site while paying extra
attention to the addition of strange php
files that can be used as backdoors also
be sure to examine the website's
dot h t access file for changes that
automatically inject malicious code
into every web page or redirect visitors
that's an interesting story because for
a lot of people who don't have a lot of
background knowledge in web development
to be able to go to a
diy web hosting service where you can
build your own website with your own
cpanel
it seems like such an easy thing but
most people wouldn't have that tech
knowledge
to recognize a phishing scam when it
came to the cpanel sure
and i mean some of the stuff that they
get access to if you give them login
credentials can
really cause problems yeah like if they
have linux access
yeah but yeah certainly i mean
any like cheap hosting solution is going
to have some kind of a
portal whether it's cpanel or otherwise
but you think about cpanel and
and as you say a novice user
signing up for the five dollar hosting
account not really
up on the latest security trends
yeah it could be dangerous same thing we
see with wordpress exactly you get a
wordpress site because
you think it's easy to set up and
administer yourself but you don't
realize necessarily
i am generalizing but maybe you don't
realize that
that leads to major security and
implications if you are not on the up
and up
it's true super careful so for somebody
who's sitting there going
uh i do my own website i just happen to
update myself oh your cpanel
i just gave my login to these hackers
like what
i i know that you know becca covered in
the story you know
checking some certain things but what
are some i think
well she hit on the the first thing i
would do is check for any
recently modified files and on a linux
or whatever it's really easy because you
can do a find
dash m time and and sort by the time
uh that the file was last modified okay
and so
you can see any file that was modified
in the last
10 days and if you don't you know if you
uploaded your
site six months ago you know that hey
those files are suspect so you can look
at them yeah because it's not like a
virus it's not like you're doing a virus
scan and
and find the malware no it's like
perfectly legit tools that they're using
to allow them to con
command and control your website yeah or
even going so far
using the wordpress example of creating
users
cpanel same thing maybe they create
users maybe they add
uh an smtp account so they can use your
mail server for
sending spam that's right that's a big
one yeah so if somebody doesn't have the
tech knowledge to go in take a look at
their account
what's another way that they could deal
with that
go through the hosting provider and say
hey can you check my account
jeff if you if you really have that low
of a knowledge when it comes to that
kind of thing
you shouldn't you shouldn't be doing
yourself hosting right
realistically if you're for sure if
you're not familiar with terms like
ftp sftp and what the difference between
those two things is
ssh ssl smtp
pop3 imap if you don't know what any one
of those terms are
mysql mariadb if you don't know what any
of those words mean
then self-hosting is not for you that's
right
um again i'm being general
but that's those are red flags for me
and and you don't want to find yourself
in a situation where yes
i'm saving money on hosting but i
part of that is that you are
relinquishing
the desire to pay someone to
maintain that's right and putting that
all on you
so it works great if you're
knowledgeable and you're getting the
five dollar a month hosting account or
whatever
right as an example because you're able
to do that maintenance yourself but this
is where
church websites become illicit websites
yes and other business websites become
defaced
and data theft occurs and
some companies are you know irreparably
uh
have their reputation damaged yes
because of these things um
well and also if you have a website
where you're doing any monetary payments
you know if you're if you're receiving
customer payments like that's even
that's a whole other can of worms you're
getting into there jeff well yeah but
you've got to be careful for that kind
of stuff so
please please please number one change
your password
just like becca said number two start
going through the files on your server
to make sure something hasn't changed
if you haven't logged into your cpanel
for an uh security update
chances are you're probably not hit by
this but if you did
you need to start doing some checking so
good advice good advice
we've got more coming up a teenager has
spent nearly 20
000 in twitch donations
on their mother's debit card and google
is creating a worldwide android
phone-powered earthquake alert system
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert is here with the crypto corner so
don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome to the world of cryptos and
welcome to the crypto corner
now it has been an interesting week
hasn't it let's take a look at it
if we look at coin gecko which is my
current favorite
directory then we see that the market
cap has increased since we spoke last
time
to 364 billion with a small decrease at
the moment of 2.7 percent
which is normally nothing unusual there
if we look at the top coins also nothing
unusual here well we've got chain link
with minus 8
but it had an increase of 40 already 40
in the last seven days and as always we
sold by those seven days and then the
picture changes significantly
normally we have got around 15 to 20
coins that achieve more than 15
this time we've got over 50 coins
achieved more than 15 percent
and i guess that one or the other of you
is uh contemplating in investing in
cryptos now
and there i'd like to just uh give you
some recommendations
the first is if somebody recommends
something to you
just be very careful because um
not everybody has got your best interest
uh
in mind and and you can do the same
research they are doing so let's take a
look at here band protocol that's an
oracle like chain link
and if i click on this one here i'm just
showing you how this this system works
then we have got here the current price
uh here is the website so if you click
on this you you it will be read our
you will be redirected to the website
medium.com that's publications
uh etherscan this is an erc20 coin so
based on ethereum
then you've got the writ reddit twitter
telegram so that's whether you see
the community talking about this coin
and
if we scroll a little bit further down
then we've got the numbers of this coin
so um in the last 30 days band increased
by 600 percent
um currently we've got a retracement of
uh also i would say this is normal here
and if you're interested
in buying something then there's some
interesting numbers like for example
example
what was the all-time high it was 17
so that's uh one day ago
as you can see here one day ago with
chief all-time high here
and the all-time low which was november
25th on
2019 so nine months ago it increased
seven
639 percent from that day so that's
interesting statistics so probably i
would not invest in something that
just had its all-time high because
i assume that short term there will be
no significant growth in it
if you're interested in any way buying
then you click here on
markets in markets you have got
all those exchanges listed that are
that are trading where you can trade uh
band so
on binance you have got two or three
possibilities one band with usdt
with tether with bitcoin and with the
binance coin
here you see the price so of course
there will be all
more or less the same and then you've
got the debt the debt
means how far can you go before
there is a significant impact on the
price
yeah so if i go for example in to hot
bit no idea what type of
uh exchange it is and i want to buy four
thousand dollars
then i will get significantly a higher
price than those
dollars thirteen you will buy if i've
got thousand dollars to invest in
binance with finance
then it will have no effect of this the
price i will get
so this is how you read the my plus two
percent and the minus two percent it's a
it's an interesting number if you want
to invest in coins because some of those
coins
that people are recommending as the next
big thing
have got absolutely no liquidity and
then it's difficult to buy something and
it's very difficult to sell also
something
yeah and um and once you have bought
i my recommendation is always not your
keys not your coins
so um my the recommendation is as always
to put it either on uh on a ledger
which is this year or on a trezor which
is this year
um because that's uh currently the state
of art in regards to
the security of of cryptos um
if you're planning to buy one of those
then go only to the original website
um and buy there don't buy it on amazon
because you can i heard sometimes uh
some of those
uh hardware wallets have been
compromised so always go to the original
it takes you probably
four weeks or three weeks longer to
receive that
device but i think that investment is a
very important and very good investment
otherwise be very careful in where
you're investing
do your research uh don't trust i mean
listen to what experts have to say
whether they recommend band or
channeling or whatever they recommend
but then do your own research
i showed you how to do that so you go
into every website
and see where you want to put your money
there
and last but not least also be very
careful with exchanges because they're
exchanges that
are dangerous so i mean binance
coinbase and so they are here from the
western world you can
more or less trust them although i would
never keep i said never keep any coins
on those exchanges
but but you never know if you have to do
kyc in other words you have to
give your passport picture or driving
license address telephone number to
these exchanges
you don't know what they're doing with
that like in the case of coinbase
they said that they're going to sell
your data so i don't know if that's in
your interest
anyway that's it for me today so i hope
uh you enjoyed you learned something i
wish you a fantastic week and i really
hope
we'll be uh seeing each other next week
again thanks
bye bye thank you robert and just a
reminder that we're not providing
financial advice but only sharing what's
happening in the
cryptocurrency market always remember
that cryptocurrency markets are
ever-changing
and always volatile so you should only
spend what you can afford to lose
i don't i don't like it when robert says
things that make me scared
it was like yeah i i gave my driver's
license to coinbase
should i be worried now robert comments
oh i don't know while we're thinking
about that
we're gonna throw back to becca in the
newsroom thank you robbie
a teenage twitch viewer sent 19 870
usd to several streamers using his
mother's debit card over the course of
two weeks
the teen's mother found the charges
toward the card between june
14th to june 30th claiming years of
savings were taken from her account over
the two-week period
she says these donations went to popular
streamers on the platform
the mother who has decided to remain
anonymous to protect her family
says that nearly all the money she lost
has been credited back to her account
after struggling to contact anyone at
twitch to discuss the issue the woman
successfully received a refund
from the streaming sites paying service
zola
using the company's online chat feature
she got adjusted credits on nearly all
transactions but in exchange was told
the account is permanently blocked to
prevent future unauthorized charges
before contacting sola however
she attempted to communicate with amazon
and even resorted to sending a
registered letter to twitch ceo
emmett shearer when all else failed she
tried contacting her bank
but they could only provide further
assistance if she was willing to press
charges against her son
she found out about sola by discovery by
discovering
other parents online who also had found
success in similar situations
although she was able to receive most of
her money
she said hitting a brick wall with
twitch was the most frustrating thing of
all
the fact that no one would respond and
there was no way to speak with anyone
was horrible she said
that was probably the worst the son is
remorseful according to the mother
and is going to counseling he's also
been limited to one hour of monitored
daily playtime
with a stipulation that he must do
positive activities throughout the day
get exercise and interact with the
family in a positive manner
you know as a father of young kids
that are very
engrossed in youtubers and
yeah yeah yeah all that kind of stuff
this story makes me
go whoo am i glad i'm
not giving my kids my debit card when i
first got an amazon fire tv stick
uh i made the mistake of not setting a
pin
oh no and of course you're logged into
your
um your amazon account yeah so
um i was at work and suddenly my phone
started blowing up
i'm like what is going on so finally i
pulled out my phone because i'm getting
all these notifications
one after another after another and i
look at my phone
and i'm seeing amazon charges one after
another
after another to the tune of 450
dollars nothing like 20 000
but this was a case where my son was
playing a video game
yeah and he determined that if he put
zero zero zero
zero as the pin because that was the
default
yep that he could buy anything in the
game
not realizing not realizing was actually
my credit card
so did you get it refunded i did amazon
is fantastic that's good for that kind
of thing so they reversed it and no
problem whatsoever but i can just
i can feel that stress that this woman
must have been going through to realize
20 000 gone from my debit card
and and that makes me think
like is this a failure in our
electronic system right now i mean i
think this about tap
and how three four years ago at the
toronto santa claus parade
somebody had a tap receiver
attached to their phone you know how you
can get these devices and they went
through the parade and they stole
20 at a time just by yes approaching
people's pockets
yes and so walked away with thousands
and thousands of dollars and but
i don't even know i never heard if they
ever got caught oh i'm sure they would
have everything's tracing
yeah so it but it just makes me think
about debit cards how they have the visa
logo now yes and so like that has
happened to my wife
um she had a visa debit yeah and
remember when debit was the safeguard
right i remember that i want to say it
was maybe two years ago
yeah um she went to use her debit card
and she couldn't use it and she was like
what's going on oh no went online and
found out that her account was locked
for suspicious activities so she looked
okay so at least they're doing that
right yeah so she so she looked into it
and over the course of
three days there was hundreds of dollars
in
food purchases from all over california
using uh the visa debit function so
somehow
somebody had gotten her visa debit
information
and was making food purchases and so cuz
it operates just like a visa
exactly yeah and so it was no big deal
to do like 20 bucks to this pizza joint
you know 30 bucks to this restaurant and
so whoever was was doing it now
thankfully she got all of her money back
it all got
you know returned but i mean in the case
of this story so i mean there's a couple
things here one is
how did the kid get the debit card or
was it just registered to the
just from mom's wallet right and it's
but second you'd think the bank accounts
most debits have a daily limit of a
thousand dollars
true and so if he dropped 20 grand over
a two-week period
either she had a higher daily limit or
there was no limit on it
i'm thinking mama has 20 000 in the bank
she probably has a higher limit than i
do
well that's probably true i don't think
i've ever had twenty thousand dollars
not all at once maybe just before my
mortgage payment
came out just after the put the money in
that's right yeah
yeah but but the other thing is the fact
that
you know there are kids that are out
there they're going i want to donate to
my favorite
person and i mean right my kids are
always talking about their favorite
youtubers
and uh you know our son with his
chromebook like i you know i have an
email for him because he's at the age
you can have an email
now and so i have the you know master
login for his email
and every once in a while i'll just
check up on what he's doing and i'm
finding oh
he's commenting on different youtubers
and i'm going
okay i need to have a conversation with
him about internet awareness and whatnot
and so i'm now very aware of what is
linked up to that account
could he purchase this kind of stuff and
so you have to think very security
conscious as a parent
if you're gonna start handing online
accounts to your kids that's a tough
tough situation now my my producer is is
giving us the look that we need to move
on sorry
but i'm a blogger as a final thought on
this particular story as a content
creator on platforms like youtube
uh a twitch creator who you know
that's that's the biggest like fear
and burn and even i'll be honest with
you and some of you
may or may not know this but even having
had such a successful kickstarter
campaign right up until the
moment that the money's in the bank
you're you're on the edge of your seat
as a content creator thinking what if
they back down
right what if you know i've i've
basically budgeted these funds that have
been donated
what if they retroacted that
that would be a real bad situation for
me as a content creator
so to these content creators who
received that twenty thousand dollars
from this child from this teenager
and then had it reversed where did that
leave them like that's such
a hard situation so we need to be there
need to be things put in place to
protect
those content creators the kids the
parents um there need to be you know i
hate to say regulations
that's not what i'm talking about but
but maybe twitch is
irresponsible maybe they're partly to
blame for this
maybe there's something that needs to be
said about that
i own the route whole conversation and
that's
is just opening that box and just
letting you dive in to comment below
what are your thoughts we're going to
throw right back to becca
google is creating a worldwide android
phone-powered
earthquake alert system the first part
of that system rolled out tuesday
if you opt in the accelero accelerometer
in your android phone will become one
data point for an algorithm designed to
detect
earthquakes eventually that system will
automatically send warnings to
people who could be impacted
it's a feature made possible through
google's strengths
the staggering numbers of android phones
around the world and clear
clever use of algorithms on big data
as with its collaboration with apple on
exposure tracing and other android
features like car crash detection
and emergency location services it shows
that there are untapped ways that
smartphones could be used for something
important to the community at large
google is rolling out the system in
small stages
first google is partnering with the
united states geogra
geological survey and the california
office of emergency services
to send the agency's earthquake alerts
to android users in that state
those alerts are generated by already
existing shake alert system
which uses data generated by traditional
seismometers
marx dogade gadis principal android
software engineer at google says
it'd be great if there were just uh
seismometer-based systems everywhere
that could detect earthquakes
that's not really practical and it's
unlikely to have global coverage because
seismometers are extremely expensive
they have to be constantly maintained
you need a lot of them in an area to
really have a good earthquake
early warning system so the second and
third stages of google's plan will be
powered instead
by the android phones the company is
proceeding
fairly cautiously though in the second
stage google will show
localized results in google searches for
earthquakes based on the data it's
detecting from android phones
the idea there is that when you feel an
earthquake you'll go to google to see if
that's what you felt or not
an android phone can become a mini
seismometer because it's an excel
an accelerometer that the thing that
detects
if you've rotated it or not android
system uses the data from that sensor to
see if the phone is shaking
it is only on when an android phone is
plugged in and not in use
to preserve battery life once it has
more confidence in the accuracy of the
system
google will begin actively sending out
earthquake warnings to people who live
in areas where there are not seismometer
based warning systems over the long term
google hopes to create an api
based on its earthquake detection system
it doesn't plan on using the system on
iphones
but if the api comes out then apple
would be free to use it
more interesting though is what other
systems would benefit from an earthquake
detection api
for example somebody could build
something that automatically stops an
elevator at the next floor and opens the
door so that people can get out before
the wave comes
and you can turn off gas valves
automatically you can have something
that stops medical procedures or open
the door to fire stations ahead of time
that's a common problem in earthquakes
where fires are a big deal and
firefighters often just can't get out
so you can build something that does
that airplanes can stop landing as
they're doing this
aboard their landing trains can be
slowed down
there's an entire ecosystem that can be
enabled by using this android-based
detection
and having it published server-side so
that others can plug into it
google's plan is to minimize false
positives and tune the system right away
and users near earthquake fault zones
will soon see
info in google searches and the
inevitable rollout of local
notifications
it wasn't long ago jeff that simon
weckert berlin-based artist
took 99 android smartphones put them in
a red wagon
and walked down the main street that was
completely devoid
of vehicles and yet google's
map service showed that
there were traffic jams everywhere he
went right because there's 99
android phones so you know i hate to put
the thought
in people's heads but this is the thing
with an
android-based system such as this while
it sounds amazing well it sounds like
hey this is a very
brilliant idea
how hard is it to take a raspberry pi
zero
and a motor and connect it
to one centralized server
and share the diagrams of that online
and say okay everybody i want you to to
build this take a raspberry pi plug it
into this motor
put your phone in this motor when you go
to bed and
because it's internet connected they can
make it they can set off all the phones
vibrating like this
in any area of the world where they have
these devices
it'd be so easy it'd just be it's such
an easy hack so it's like
how can they trust that data well i
think it's brilliant
an accelerometer to detect earthquake
well and that's the thing like this is
an amazing thing that they're doing but
with amazing ideas also comes the
amazing ability
to mess with it thanks to human beings
yeah
i mean not only terrible like what if
you have you know
if somebody decides to use it as a uh a
type of
social attack so to speak where
there's a group of 15 20 people they all
of the phones
they congregate in a particular area and
they just sit there and start shaking
their phone
and if they also synchronize it with
with
like raspberry pi is through the
internet like you could actually
like pick a spot and make an earthquake
on google maps because
you know it's just so it it'll be
interesting to see if that's
exercising oh really you got steps just
there
nice brilliant just quickly before becca
wraps things up
uh robert k uh robert koenig from the
crypto corner says hey with coinbase
robby you should be okay
they are selling your data to the
government though and it says
i don't understand that's because
they're centralized i yeah yeah and i
just
like can i assume that the government
knows everything about me anyways
but probably but the government issued
my would that be like irs tax purpose
yeah i suppose so but i mean
selling my info to the government so i
don't hold my crypto
in uh in a centralized um exchange at
all
however i do use the exchange to
transfer funds between
us dollars and bitcoin for example so um
uh sad sack 963 makes a really good
comment about the debit card issue and
how and a child being able to use mum's
credit card
and says what if the debit card what if
these debit cards had 2fa
wouldn't that be superb so what if there
was 2fa
on your debit card that somehow you you
know whether you pull out a
an authenticator token or or the
authenticator app on your phone whatever
it is that you need to
to use to be able to yeah i think that's
very very smart so thanks for submitting
that
uh becca big thanks to roy w
nash and our community of viewers for
submitting stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom don't forget to like and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category 5. from the category 5 tv
newsroom
i'm becca ferguson
you