[Music]
as we continue our series on content
creation i'm
watching for your questions and i want
to answer them to the best of my ability
so let's jump back to my video where i
featured kingston's workflow station
device
and check out this question from brian
jarvis who asks
why do you buy sd cards would you not be
better future proofed by buying only
micro sd cards and using an adapter when
required
i thought adapters have no effect on i o
speeds and i'll tell you what brian you
could be right
for me i think it's probably just a
matter of preference where
i feel like the sd card is a little more
rugged than this wafer thin
micro sd but is there a difference i
don't have the answer to that
and i think you'll find with category 5
technology tv
one thing here is i'm not ashamed to say
when i don't know the answer to
something but i find someone who does
and that's where david leong comes in
from kingston technology i gave david a
call
and david thank you for joining us would
you be able to touch on
brian's question he'd like to know
whether there is a performance
difference between
an sd card and a microsd hi robbie
and thank you brian for the question you
know the difference between an
sd and a micro sd card there really
isn't that much of a difference at all
it's really just about the size
so capacities generally are the same and
then
if you're talking about performance now
the one thing you want to be concerned
about
is that some of the lower capacity sd
and micro sd cards
are going to be just a little bit slower
than the higher capacity
the reason why is it's more on the
engineering backend side
you know the higher capacity sd and
micro sd cards
sometimes they have more chips inside of
it so that means there's more chips for
the controller to address
if we think of this as like the freeway
in
traffic well the more lanes on the
freeway the faster
the cars can move so that's really what
we're talking about when it comes to
performance
wow okay so the larger the capacity of
the card presumably
the faster it's going to be that's
interesting okay cool thanks dave
now question for you then when i think
about the ruggedness of these two
devices
like you know this one looks like it's
such a little tiny thin little thing and
this one's got a little more heft to it
do i have to worry about this one with
like heat for example like if i have
this running in my car
or in a hot environment while i'm
shooting video
sd cards can operate and micro sd cards
can operate from negative 25 celsius
to 85 degrees celsius so that's usually
not a concern for most everybody
if there is that industrial case use
you're working in a super super harsh
environment
there are industrial cards that you can
look into
as well okay so my final question about
this dave if i may
uh i've got these adapters that will
convert my micro sd card
into a full sized sd and it feels like a
full-sized sd at that point
is this affecting the performance of my
card
it's a pat the adapter is passive so
when you put that micro sd card into the
sd adapter
that's really more of a flexibility
thing there so let's say your device
uses a micro sd card but the laptop that
you have only has an sd slot
well that's why some companies will ship
an sd card adapter with it
to make it easier for you to kind of
offload that data from the device
into your computer so that's really what
we're talking about when it comes to sd
and micro sd cards the bottom line is is
really this
why buy the fastest card if you don't
need the fastest card
look at your device specs and buy your
make your purchase
based on that because it's your
hard-earned money after all
so brian i hope that answers your
question and robbie
thank you for the opportunity that's
great information dave thank you so much
now of course
me shooting at 4k video all the time
i do feel like i do need speed and i
need capacity
so it still makes sense for me but it
sounds like brian you're right
to future proof myself i should be
investing
in microsds and using those sd card
adapters
can't really see a benefit to either or
so i think you're right
these little guys are probably the the
way to go so
hey thank you for the question get your
questions and post them below
anything you'd like to know about our
broadcast facility here at category 5
technology tv
how i create the videos that we do put
out as content creators here on youtube
i'd love to hear from you i welcome your
questions and i look forward to
being here with you for the rest of our
series as we learn
the content creation process of category
5 technology tv
thanks for watching take care everybody
[Music]
bye
you