covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias last week
canonical released the latest
intermediate version of ubuntu 20.10
groovy gorilla which for the first time
adds first-class
platform support for the raspberry pi 4.
groovy gorilla itself is a pretty
typical interim release offering an
updated
gnome version with lots of bug fixes and
small feature additions
support has also been added for windows
active directory in the
ubiquiti os installer itself
and while it has been possible for some
time to install ubuntu on raspberry pi
hardware
up until now that has been strictly a
community effort the pie itself ships
with raspberry pi
os at debian based distribution whose
origins began with the pi community
but which has since been officially
adopted and supported by the raspberry
pi foundation itself
while canonical added the pi as a
supported platform
in 20.04 earlier this year
that support was only for the ubuntu
server distribution
not desktop with 20.10 groovy gorilla
canonical has
added full desktop support for the pi 4.
martin wim press canonical's director of
engineering for the ubuntu desktop
says this means the pi is now a
first-class citizen
canonical guarantees the same level of
integration q
a and support from kernel to user space
that it does for a standard pc
the entire ubuntu software repository is
available and supported on the pi
of course that's other than architecture
specific packages that start with names
like i-386
and are therefore not compatible with
the raspberry pi's arm processor
if you'd like to install ubuntu 20.10
desktop on the pi
you'll need a 4 gigabyte or eight
gigabyte raspberry pi
as long as you meet the hardware
requirements the install is a breeze
ubuntu 20.10 desktop is an option in the
standard raspberry pi imager now
the imager itself is available for linux
windows or mac
platforms to get up and running insert a
four gigabyte plus micro sd card
open the imager choose ubuntu 20.10 and
click
right a few minutes later you'll be able
to boot the official ubuntu 20.10 for
raspberry pi 4. big thanks to roy w nash
and
our community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you