well jeff
this is the orville interactive fan
experience with the halloween update
which you can download for free
through steam now to start the halloween
event
all you need to do is go to the quantum
control console on the bridge
and go to the top rows google location
now this is meant to be a single player
event but for us right now we're just
basically running around we're not
getting into the scenario
when you play it make sure you press i
in order to see which consoles need
repair
and then you'll be able to participate
in the actual scenario but as i say
we're just going to run around and show
you what it looks like let's go red
alert
that's not me doing that what hold on
what
it's like for spinning i mean
what on earth what happened there
where are we it seems like hey
welcome weary traveler
to my domain
find your shiny starship of no use to
you now
who is that i have a challenge for you
a challenge you'll no doubt fail
disastrously
i'll let you leave and continue on with
your adventures
around the galaxy if you can repair
all nine of the damaged consoles on your
starship
that's simple
however things
who's taking control of the ship some
kind of
supreme being
i can't help it if you're afraid
where are you going no idea jeff
[Music]
trying to get let's try to get out of
here
[Music]
is it weird that i like the sound
of screaming
i do not like that
i think something's coming
do you think it's weird it's sometimes i
like the sound of screaming
[Music]
oh man oh those spiders gave me the
heebie-jeebies
you can install the oroville fan
experience for free
it's in steam right now don't forget we
are on twitter
at category5tv and i really appreciate
it if you would consider becoming part
of our patreon
fleet head on over to patreon.com
category5
it's a great way to support the content
that we create here at category 5 tv
but at the same time you're going to
gain access to some behind the scenes
and a lot of great content that is only
available
to our patrons thanks for watching
everyone have a wonderful week
[Music]
do
so