setting up a minecraft server can be a
big
pain in the many of the easiest
solutions out there will end up charging
you a monthly fee
and you never even have control over
your world files so if the company goes
belly up or otherwise disappears
you lose all of your builds so i set out
to create an
easier way pinecraft installer lets you
host your very own
multiplayer minecraft server on a cheap
little single board computer such as the
raspberry pi
4. the new version 2.6 just came out and
it's killer
today i'm going to show you how to
install it and i'll highlight some of
the great new features
many of which are a direct result of
user requests on our last video
stick around till the end because i'm
going to show you how to add your own
user
as an admin this feature is brought to
you by ameridroid.com
get your raspberry pi 4 or other single
board computer home automation devices
and electronics accessories at
ameridroid.com
american-based sales and support visit
i've got some exciting ideas for
pinecraft that i'd love to implement in
a future version
but it'll take the support of users like
you to help me do it
so if you love pinecraft please consider
supporting the project
at patreon.com pinecraft
now i released the very first version of
minecraft installer back in january
and here we are it's less than three
months later and version 2.6 is already
out
implementing several user requests in
its infancy
pinecraft only installed spigot and only
in survival mode to boot
but users wanted more options and i
received a ton
of great feedback from users who have
already done their homework so
now paper is the default server flavor
but you can choose from an assortment of
available servers and don't worry i'll
explain the basic differences between
the available server versions in just a
moment
in this video we'll turn a raspberry pi
4 with 8 gigabytes of ram
into a high performance multiplayer
minecraft server using pinecraft
[Music]
installer
the very first thing that i need to do
is grab my linux based distro and i'm
choosing ubuntu
server 20.04 since it has a 64-bit
version which will let me take advantage
of the 8 gigabytes of ram
on my raspberry pi 4. you can grab that
at ubuntu.com and i've got the direct
link for you in the video description as
well
you want to use fast media otherwise
your server performance is going to
suffer
so i've flashed the ubuntu image to a
hyperx gaming microsd card
which boasts 100 megabytes per second
read
and 80 megabytes per second right i've
got
my pi 4 booted and grabbed the ip
address of the pi from my router's dhcp
pool so let's connect ubuntu server
gives me a proper 64-bit distro
i've got 8 gigabytes of ram on the pi 4
and i can see
7 gigabytes are free while it's running
to install pinecraft we're going to need
git so first thing i'm going to do is
update our app repositories
sudo apt update will get you there and
after a few seconds it'll be done
so now i can run sudo apt install
git and i can actually see that ubuntu
server comes with git
already pre-installed and it's already
the latest version so i'm good to start
i'm going to make sure that i'm in my
user's home folder and then run
git clone https colon slash slash
github.com slash cat5 tv slash
pinecraft that downloads the latest
version of pinecraft to our clean distro
let's cd into the pinecraft folder and
it's super
simple to get up and running we're going
to type sudo dot slash
install and hit enter pinecraft will
quickly install
any dependencies it needs to run and
then will be greeted with the splash
screen
simply hit enter to proceed you'll see
again that pinecraft will install
any components that will be required to
run your minecraft server
give that a moment to complete and we'll
be prompted with our first question
which server flavor do you want each of
the available options are just
different teams of developers working on
various improvements on minecraft's
server
and it'd be tough to give you an
exhaustive comparison but essentially
we've got paper
which supports plug-ins and it installs
very quickly
it's been optimized to perform very well
and it does so even on a single board
computer
it's lightweight and it runs great so
that's why i've made it the new default
next in the list is fabric which is yet
another lightweight
well-optimized server which supports
plug-ins and has a fast
build time then there's spigot which
runs great but it's a bit heavier than
the first two
and it certainly takes a lot longer to
install since it compiles from source
then there's the experimental
implementation of kuberite
this one's interesting though quite
niche since it's a full
rewrite of the minecraft server in c
plus plus
since it's not a java based server it's
significantly more optimized
and could even allow running a minecraft
server on a super cheap board
such as the raspberry pi zero
but it does have caveats in particular
it only works with
older minecraft java clients but it's
definitely fun to give it a try and
see if you can get a minecraft server
running on an ultra cheap system
finally there's one called vanilla and
this
is the legit minecraft server as
provided by
moyang it's included in pinecraft for
the purists
but as many will tell you you can't
expect it to perform
nearly as well as the optimized servers
nor does it support
plug-ins or mods so all that said we're
going to go for the default today
and install the paper server if you
don't know which one you want this is a
great starting point
next we'll select whether we want a
survival or
creative gameplay server if you want to
follow our series and learn how to play
minecraft make sure you choose
survival if however you want to try your
hand at master builds without having to
mine the resources
give creative a try creative is likely a
great starting point if you've got very
young children
but if you want exciting gameplay you're
probably going to want to lean toward
survival enter your linux username
in my case i haven't changed it from the
default on my raspberry pi
and that's ubuntu you'll need to accept
the moyang end user license agreement
which you can do here next is our world
seed you can choose one that's provided
in the pinecraft installer
enter a custom one or just have your
seed generated randomly
you can have your minecraft server load
automatically at boot
so just choose yes if that sounds good
and finally we get an information window
that simply tells us a bit more about
our selections
you'll see on my raspberry pi 4
pinecraft installer
is also going to overclock my cpu to 1.9
gigahertz to maximize gameplay
performance
plus my minecraft server will have
almost five and a half gigabytes of ram
allocated to it hit enter to continue
this screen is just warning me that my
pi
is going to be overclocked and since i'm
fine with that i'll hit enter and the
installation will begin
[Music]
and it's done my minecraft server is
already installed
and running hit enter to exit you can
see if your server is running by typing
slash etc
init dot d slash minecraft space
status one means that it's up zero means
it's down i'll likely improve that in a
future release
as of pinecraft 2.6 the minecraft server
runs under a linux
screen session so if you want to access
the minecraft server console directly
simply type screen dash r on the server
as you can see my server is still
generating the world
it can take several minutes so be
patient to exit the console while still
leaving the game server running
press control a followed by d
that's the screen command to detach the
session
if i list the running screens you can
see one called pinecraft
and that's literally all it takes to get
your minecraft server up and running
so let's connect and check it out in
your minecraft java client on any
computer on your local network
go to multiplayer and add a server give
it a friendly name
i'm going to call mine new server
minecraft
2.6 and enter the ip address of the
raspberry pi
on which i ran the pinecraft installer
remember that this
only works on your local network if you
want to give your friends access
to the server which you can you're going
to need to open
port 25565 in your router
and grab the public ip address of your
network at
currentip.xyz
and share that with your friends now
every router is
slightly different so i can't really
show you how to set that up
but consult your manual and look for a
feature called
port forwarding or something similar to
that if in doubt
hey get your nerdiest friend to come on
by and give you a hand
and here we are in my brand new
minecraft world
[Music]
interesting a floating tree
well as i run around you can see that
the performance is really
excellent oh and if you want to know how
i make minecraft look so sexy
click on the video here so there you
have it a pinecraft 2.6 installation of
a paper minecraft server
on a raspberry pi 4 with 8 gigabytes of
ram
running the 64-bit ubuntu server os
took no effort at all and here we are
so thanks for staying with me till the
end just for that i'm going to show you
a quick way to add yourself as an admin
to your shiny new minecraft server we
already learned how to connect to the
minecraft console screen
so let's do that from there you can
enter console commands directly so it's
super easy to just go
op bald nerd that's me to make myself a
server operator
now that i'm up i can run my server
commands from within the game
including opting other players if i'd
like changing game modes on the fly
setting the time of day giving players
resources
and so much more i really want a plaque
one day to put on this wall so please
subscribe to my channel like this video
and click that bell to be notified next
time i release a tutorial
if you want to see all the awkward
moments behind the scenes
and even chat with me directly join our
fleet patreon.com
category 5. i'm robbie ferguson at
category 5 tv
don't forget if you're not having fun
you're doing it wrong
thanks for watching
[Music]
you