covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias microsoft is
easing the requirement for windows
subsystem for linux 2.
instead of only working on windows 10
2004 or higher
wsl is also now available for windows 10
and 1909 users windows 10 users who
wanted to work with the new windows
subsystem for linux version 2
needed to have the latest feature update
for windows the windows 10 may 2020
update
aka windows 10 20 000 2004
but on august 20th microsoft made a
surprise announcement
wsl-2 has been back-ported to windows 10
1903 and 1909 as well as it turns out
microsoft has been working on bringing
sl2
sorry wsl-2 to 1903 and 1909 for the
last few months
they said in a blog post that the goal
is for the back port to make wsl-2
available
to more windows users the back port will
be for
x64 systems only those using arm 64
still need to use windows 10
2004 to get wsl 2. wsl-2
is a much reworked version of the
original wsl
it changes how linux distributions
interact with windows
as officials noted in today's post each
linux
linux distribution running on windows 10
can run as
wsl1 or wsl2 and can be switched at any
time
according to microsoft wsl2 provides a
full linux kernel built into wsl2
improved system call support for all
linux apps including docker fuse
rsync and more and improved file system
performance to get wsl2 for 1903
and 1909 users simply need to check for
updates via
windows update
you