[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today we're going to take a journey back
in history and why because
things are looking pretty good at the
moment in regards to pricing
and cryptocurrencies if we look into
what the market is currently doing by
the time i'm recording this year bitcoin
is at 17
520 went up by 14 in seven days
but as you can see most coins are
behaving quite
quite positively let's say that way
and so that you don't take any wrong
decision because there are a lot of
people
having an opinion out there and also if
you look into the pressure this is coin
telegraph
um bitcoin up 375 percent since peter
ship accidentally called the exact
button readership is somebody
that is a gold buck he hates bitcoin but
he loves his code
so he's an old guy um
uh the reasons why bitcoin hit uh 17 000
uh somebody predicts here novogratz mike
novogratz predicted 65 000
the price of bitcoin then we had some
bankers uh citigroup
predicting the price will be at uh 316
000.
we've got here a bitcoin analyst has
four reasons why btc price will hit
22 000 next so you'll be hearing that
from many
other sources too and
that's why i would like to take you back
in history but i said
this is not going to be financial advice
yeah just to be clear on this year
so this is just to show you what
happened in the past and why because
i've been living through this year
already four times
so let's go back this is coin gekko and
i look i clicked on the bitcoin price
and went
back to 2018 december 2018
and as you can see this is the bull
market we lived through the last time
yeah so it went
up from around eight hundred six hundred
dollars to twenty thousand dollars
in the all-time high was at that time
around the nineteen thousand six hundred
sixty five dollars
and if we look into the numbers so this
is the number so this is going market
cap
um they did a historical snapshot 10th
of december 2017.
bitcoin went up in seven days 34
most of the other coins as you can see
are in red so they went down
so there was no correlation at that time
that significant between
when the bull market start really starts
between bitcoin and the other clients
so bitcoin was at 15 000 and ethereum at
440.
iota somebody at that coin is probably
not even under the 20 top 20 any longer
is it was it four dollars one week later
only one week later seven days later
bitcoin was close to its all-time high
19 000.
ethereum almost doubled in that week um
iota went a little bit dance 8 but you
see
others like cardano went up 360 litecoin
in one week yeah so this thing when
things go really really crazy
a week later bitcoin went already down
so it was
19 000 the all-time high and now we're
16 400 so this is on the 7th of january
but other coins like here ethereum
continued going up
yeah so not even close to its all-time
high
i think in all time i was around 1 400
for ethereum
cardano one dollar so um yeah other
coins were still growing significantly
while
bitcoin was going down because people
were thinking bitcoin is going down so
let's invas
invest in those old coins and make a lot
of money that way so you have to be
really really careful on where you're
investing what you do
to do your research be very calm in what
you're doing
and uh what i find encouraging at the
moment is that this bull market
that we're currently living through i
mean as you saw
after the bull market will come a true
retracement and in cryptocurrencies that
will be around 20 to 30 percent
you can't expect that but what i find
encouraging is
if you look at google trends so people
that are searching for the word
bitcoin for example on a global basis
in 2018 that was 100 equivalent to 100
percent
at the moment we're only at 11 10 11
so not a lot of people outside of our
little industry are talking about
cryptocurrencies
just imagine this thing goes out in the
press and everybody starts talking to
you about bitcoin yeah so if your aunt
emma comes to you and asks you about
this weird stuff called bitcoin or your
cab driver
tells you that the best thing to invest
in is bitcoin
then you know that we're getting nearer
top but
this is just a guess i'm not an expert
this is what happened in 2017 looking at
the at the data on how that was
last time so that's um
that's the journey that i wanted to show
you so that you uh take the right
decision
um so stay calm when these things happen
don't uh don't
over stretch yourself and just listen to
the market very carefully i mean
this is the third time as i mentioned
that i'm running through this year the
first two times were
identical you know you had these these
crocodile teeth where it went up by
50 and down by 20 in in in a week
and then we had um and i i also both
times i was not able to read the top
market so i
miscalculated that one too as i guess
most of the people
anyway that's it from me please leave us
a like it helps us
to spread the word and as always i thank
you very much for watching
it's i'm really looking forward to see
you next week again
so thank you and until then bye bye
thank you robert just a reminder that
we're not providing financial advice but
only sharing what's happening in the
cryptocurrency markets
always remember that the cryptocurrency
markets are ever changing and
always volatile so only invest what you
can afford to lose
[Music]
[Applause]
so