[Music]
so
robbie i've been thinking about trying
out a distro oh yeah uh
linux distro a linux distro but the
problem
is i hate having to install
and uninstall and test and install again
but you could use a virtual machine
and just like download all the isos and
spend
like a week so much work so much work
why do you want to do this
well because i've exhausted the one
distro that i've got on my computer and
i want to do another but
it's all the backing up of files and
everything how do i save time well
here's the thing is that distros are
aplenty
there are tons of versions of linux
available and
we've all encountered this before and
especially if you're new to linux
the question comes up okay what distro
do i want is it ubuntu is it debian is
it
like am i going to go with the mate
desktop am i going to go with
like what am i going to go with and this
is why they call them flavors because
really it is about what's your favorite
flavor
linux mint mintes
yup delightful although don't lick your
computer screen
please don't there's no flavor
especially if it's touch screen it's
going to completely whack out your
windows
the fact is that as you kind of allude
to it's
it's a bit onerous to download every
single iso so you go
so you got to find them first so you go
to ubuntu.com you download ubuntu oh but
there's also ubuntu mate
so do i want to try that one yeah oh and
there's there's a fork called linux mint
which i've already mentioned
um so i could download that oh but
there's also oh they've got linux mint
cinnamon and mate
which one do i want it's a nightmare
it is right especially if you're just
looking for
a new version of linux for your desktop
computer
i'm in that situation right now at work
where i've been running ubuntu
mate for uh or pardon me no i'm running
linux
mint on my system and i have been for
some time but i'm at that point where i
want to upgrade
and i don't think the upgrade path on
linux mint
is the one for me so i'm starting to
look at other distros
so i'm in that same situation where i
want to try other distros
but to install them all it's just so
time consuming
yes linux installation process is
brilliant
it's easy in that regard but there's so
many you got to download a 3 gig
file and then install it and then test
it and
what if we could tap into the cloud
and test any one or 10
or 50 or 500 linux flavors
with just a couple of mouse clicks see
that such a time saver
wouldn't it be wouldn't it be if only
there was an option
let's do it this is distrotest.net
and on distrotest.net you're going to
see a long list
of all kinds of linux flavors
wow give me a linux flavor we talked
about ubuntu so let's look under
u for ubuntu so we've got ubuntu ubuntu
budgie
ubuntu ce see how much of a nightmare it
would be if you were just looking
and you're sure well which one do you
download and try are you going to
download the iso for cinnamon mate
server studio unity unity remix
into web hokey doodle so let's say we
want to start with
uh ubuntu so this is like tried and true
so oh there it is and you can click on
the link and it'll take you out to the
ubuntu download site
you can learn a little bit more about
the product from the manufacturer
that's taking me to ubuntu.com but what
if i could actually test it without
having to download it anyways
see that'd be awesome yeah so the cloud
gives us that option and distrotest.net
lets us start
a system with a single mouse click ready
click so i am in queue it says i have
less than one minute
for my deployment and so it's actually
deploying a virtual machine
right now in the cloud for me so that i
can test ubuntu and see how it works
as soon as it's finished booting uh now
it says
open vnc viewer so let's click it but i
don't have a
vnc viewer installed okay so is this
going to be a problem for me
let's click it and see
and there we go so i'm actually looking
at the ubuntu
live cd so i'm just going to hit enter
and it's exactly what you would see
if you downloaded it created a virtual
machine
installed it went through all these
steps yet it's just running
directly in my web browser here we go
let's click try ubuntu now you can see a
little bit of latency on my mouse and
this of course is the fact that i'm
vnc'ed into a virtual appliance that's
just booted up just to show me
what ubuntu looks like this is not a
gaming system you're not going to be
booting this up
firing up games and doing all that kind
of stuff but it gives you a great
opportunity to test the de
the desktop environment gives you a
great opportunity to see what suite of
software is included with the operating
system
and gives you a chance to give it a go
so here i am already booted
directly into ubuntu now these virtual
appliances do not have access to the
internet
you can't install a whole bunch of stuff
through apt or anything like that
but it has access to the the suite
that's included
right uh let's see here i'm gonna click
on the applications
button at the bottom here and i can see
everything that's included
in ubuntu out of the box wow look at
that
again a little bit of a latency there
that's typical of what i am doing
imagine what i've actually achieved here
i i booted this up in my browser that's
sweet so once you're happy with that and
you've said okay well
uh all right uh let's try a different
distro i've given that a try distro
hopping can be a nightmare because
you're going
from one iso to the next yes this makes
distro hopping
instantaneous so i'm just gonna close
that window so you don't even need to
shut it down
why would you because it's going to
scrap itself as soon as you shut it off
so i'm going to power it off now
with the system stop button so i just
push that now it's gone
the system stopped that's amazing
completely gone you can upload files to
it if you want to try running your
favorite scripts or anything like that
now let's see okay this is a big long
list let's actually jump into system
list
okay and let's go to e
and i'm kind of curious because i've
been hearing
good things about this endeavor os so i
can click on details or just hey you
know what i want to see what endeavor os
looks like
so i'm just going to boot it up so i
didn't have to download it i don't have
to do any configuration on my computer
it's now booting up spinning up a live
session
of endeavor os when you were looking at
that list
you saw the images yeah are they the
current versions
like because you're going down the list
and you're seeing all the desktops like
ubuntu and
yeah so are they are they the current or
are they a stable version are they
they've obviously been updating it like
this endeavor os which is
already booted by the way and i can open
it up um is showing as version
20210203 and we're shooting this
in april so just so two months old yeah
so it's obviously current enough
um how often they update it and
everything i'm not too sure but um
let's boot but still the fact that it's
only two months old it shows that
this is not something that they built
and deployed and then it's just sat
yeah with old iso images that's cool so
they're definitely keeping it up to date
so i'm booting up endeavor os for the
first time i didn't have to install a
[Music]
thing
endeavor os looks like we're in
sweet we don't have a hard drive in this
machine so i can't install it or
anything so i'll just close out of the
installation thing here
uh and click on the endeavor os menu
button
this does look kind of sleek yeah it
does i like it
uh what do we got multimedia office no
office suite included so i can see
what's included but know that it's linux
so i can install anything that i want
right but this looks pretty sleek so i
kind of dig that
now i had mentioned that you can upload
files
okay how do we do that so if i bring up
i'm assuming it's going to be in folders
here
yes you see this 105 megabyte volume
if i click there this gives me access to
an empty volume so over in my browser
here
i can actually choose a file and then
upload that file it's got to be under 10
megs but it gives me a chance to test
my favorite bash installation scripts or
something like that
test various things on various distros
and see how they run
and you can do those right within your
browser but if i'm done with endeavor os
i can close it out and i can hit system
stop and i've just
terminated that virtual machine that's
really just really good
so i've showed you so far we knew about
ubuntu we've heard of endeavour os just
never seen it now i have and it looks
pretty
sleek um but what if you've never heard
of these flavors of linux and you just
want
to have that experience like because if
you've never heard of ubuntu how would
you know to go to ubuntu.com
right you just wouldn't so you'd start
googling around and trying to find your
way to different distros and maybe
looking in forums and things like that
but this site gives us an opportunity to
go through the list
kind of look at the picture and see kind
of you know judge a book by its cover a
little bit but it gives you an
opportunity to see
what things look like and say hey you
know what what one
appeals to me and then take it from
there so let's jump into a
which is i guess where we are here and
scroll down
and start looking at the images there
are a lot of just desktop wallpapers
oh but this looks kind of interesting
first of all it's called av
linux never heard of that but av
is audio video click on the thumbnail oh
that does look sleek and i see
like a custom icon set down here um
i'm imagining that this is probably a
multimedia distro
so let's click on details for more info
and it has a link to the website so i
can click on it and i can find out more
so yeah av linux mx edition
is a downloadable installable shared
snaps so see i've
discovered a new flavor of linux that
i've never heard of
but is it any good i don't know let's
boot up a system
[Music]
oh look at this so we are now running
av linux what's all the uh
oh is that system stack this is like
conkey over here so it comes with conkey
already pre-configured
uh which is yes as you say it's like a
desktop widget system stats
so this gives us some insight into the
virtual appliance that we're running as
well so we see that it's a 64-bit
uh linux 5.9 kernel uh we're running
with a high load
two is our average load
uh 2.5 gigahertz
so we can see a little bit of
information about the virtual appliance
that we're running so what do we have
so we've got like this dock bar down
here i kind of dig that
show my desktop oh cue jack control so
this is the jack controller so you've
got
full control over your audio inputs
outputs that's beautiful so this
really does tell me this is most likely
a uh a very optimized for audio
production
uh and that kind of thing
uh i'm going to click on here because i
assume bottom left is always the menu
that looks sleek
i like that graphics it comes with gnu
image manipulation program which matters
to me
i'm going to click on it just to see
what version it comes with out of the
box
and remember we're running this from a
live distro on
uh distrotest.net so let's run a 210 and
it's 2.10
and uh we haven't done like an uh dist
upgrade or anything like that
there it goes so wheat
perfect wow we're running in a little
window we probably
it will look a little nicer on a big
screen full screen
speaking of if you'd like to i imagine
if we pull out this
guy over here we can switch that over to
full screen mode
and it looks like that just stretches it
it doesn't actually
adjust the window resolution so
right probably not worth it um but let's
see what else we got here okay
multimedia we definitely feel like this
is a multimedia distro
yes we've got our door uh which is like
a multi-track audio
recorder and mixer everything else uh
we've got a ton of multimedia stuff here
i'm not even familiar with a lot of this
stuff guitarix simple
mono amplifier simulation no way
guitar simulator handbrake is for
ripping dvds
nice uh k3b is for writing your
own uh audio cds and dvds and things
like that with a burner
um then what have we look at all this
stuff obs studio if you want to
broadcast your live streams it's built
in
it comes with it already pre-configured
and ready to go
reaper uh for uh music production
uh it's like a d-a-w
wow with uh sequencing as well
that is cool i dig the look of this one
i kind of like the sweet because i'm a
multimedia guy
yeah but uh that's pretty cool so that
one
that i just found is called av linux and
this is not an app for av linux this is
a
we're talking about distrotest.net yeah
i just discovered a new distro
on distrotest.net i never would have
known to look for that
no neither was it cool so go through the
list check them out
and this is a chance for you to distro
hop without actually having a distro hop
distro distrotest.net check it out today
[Music]
you