jeff what good is a neural network
if you can't use it
to turn yourself into a zombie
you know what answer me every morning
asking myself that question
jeff give me a really good toothy smile
no just give me a smile come on yeah
there we go
okay so we got the picture now what i'm
going to do is i'm going to bring up my
web browser because this
tool is available through your web
browser that means there's no app to
install
it doesn't collect anything other than
just google analytics it's perfectly
safe
and you don't have to put it in and it's
platform agnostic doesn't matter if
you're on your computer your phone your
tablet
whatever you go to makemeazombie.com and
we're going to browse to that picture
that i just took of jeff
there he is and we're going to click on
that and
click make me a zombie
okay what's happening is that again
a general adversarial network a neural
network
is now taking your photo and turning you
into a zombie
oh my gosh
[Laughter]
wow uh that's wow
you like that note self don't become the
undead
oh jeff that is fantastic
i feel like i'm the guinea pig of the
show make me
make me a zombie dot com and you can do
that on any device
don't forget we are on twitter at
category5tv
and i'd really appreciate it if you
would consider becoming part of our
patreon
fleet head on over to patreon.com
category5
it's a great way to support the content
that we create here at category 5 tv
but at the same time you're going to
gain access to some behind the scenes
and a lot of great content that is only
available
to our patrons thanks for watching
everyone have a wonderful week
[Music]
[Applause]
you