remember
any time you shop on ameridroid.com use
the coupon code
cat5 tv supporter at checkout no matter
what you're buying
you'll get a buck off your final total
and 10 of the sales profit
will be donated back to category 5 tv to
help us produce videos like these
we moved into our new studio space in
the height of the pandemic
contractors weren't allowed to work at
the time and even hardware stores were
closed
so i couldn't get a conduit installed to
run cables into our studio space
from the production room nor could i
even buy a hacksaw to cut up the single
piece of abs pipe that i had on hand
so i simply made do by drilling a hole
between the two rooms
and i laid the abs into the hole and
that was just there to protect the
cables
and it's makeshift and it's messy but it
got us through the past few months but
now i'm ready i want to make find a
basically a solution that is going to be
more permanent and it's going to look
better
so i started looking into ready-made
solutions out there
and stuff that i could do myself without
having to hire someone else
with you know all the mad skills to do
contractor work and everything i wanted
to be able to do it
save some money as well so as it turns
out ameridroids
easy portal product is exactly what i
was looking for it's designed
for running cables between rooms you
know for networking or things like that
but
ideal for basically any type of cables
if you need to go through walls or
through the floor
through a desktop or ceiling tiles it's
really really easy
and it's much more tidy looking and it
protects your cables as they're passing
through as well
easy portal doesn't require any special
tools or skills to install which is
perfect for me
no skills when it comes to carpentry and
things like that but
as long as you've got a hole saw which i
do or some other kind of
tool that will be able to cut the whole
to the right
size for your easy portal depending on
which one you buy
easy portal provides a clean pass
through for your cables and it's
complete
with the finished flange which i'm going
to show you up close and personal here
on both sides of the hole it's
customizable to meet your needs
with port diameters all the way from
itty bitty ones like this
half inch to two inches
and this guy here is the two inch
model or maybe a little bit bigger than
that uh this one is a custom one that we
had built
but i have a three inch hole saw
in order to drill uh the hole that i
need for this particular easy portal so
keep in mind of course the diameter
is the inner diameter so when you're
ordering it that's the size of the hole
not the actual size that's going to be
required for the hole
through your wall so just keep that in
mind in addition to that
the thickness of your wall can be
anywhere from 0.4
inches so very very small
to 16.15 inches so the smaller one is
really ideal
for say something like the ceiling tile
so this is going to be great when we're
doing
lighting if you need to hang a projector
in your projector room or something like
that with a drop ceiling
this will go perfectly on the tile so
you just drill the hole screw it
together and you've got this
nice little pass-through for the cables
to go through
and of course you can choose the
diameter if you need something wider for
the hdmi cable or something like that
you can go with something that's going
to be you know smaller this way
but a little bit larger as far as the
hole diameter goes
if you contact ameridroid at the time of
your order you can even custom print
your easy portal
in any of the 13 colors that they have
available so in my case
i actually wanted to have a different
color on each side of the
of the wall with the green being in the
main studio since that matches our logo
color
and white in the production side because
the walls in there are like a light gray
so while there's a modest fee for the
second color
ameridroid was even able to accommodate
that request so it's
very very custom plus as i mentioned
this is an oversized version a little
bit bigger than what's
generically available on their site so i
just requested that we get a larger
conduit for the amount of hdmi cables
and things that i have to pass through
for the studio and they were more than
happy
to oblige me on that so very very cool
easy portal are custom and they are 3d
printed at ameridroid so i want to be
clear about that
due to the very process of 3d printing
you're going to get some
kind of imperfections visibly
but you can see that that is not
affecting the performance of the
the product at all so that just screws
together
and clamps onto the wall very very
simple but
very very nice so the imperfections are
you know it's not gonna affect your
usability whatsoever uh but if you if
that's a problem for you
um just keep in mind these are 3d
printed products
so you can see here there is a little
bit of imperfection on the visible area
it's very very minor and you could
actually just like any 3d printed
product you could if you wanted to use a
fine grit
wet sandpaper and sand that down if you
wanted to
you could paint them if you wanted to
but again
the imperfections are just because of
the 3d print and i think that is
very very good and in fact this you know
i'm i'm
quite impressed with this it's it's
really really good quality
and exactly what i needed so let's see
how easy it really is
and get the easy portal installed so
that's the hole
in the on the bridge our production room
leading out
into the main studio so um so you can
see all the wires here
going in through the uh the pipe
so we'll just pull that through and
no effort whatsoever to do uh to do the
installation you'll see but
uh for me it's just getting all this
stuff out of the way man
i forgot how big and bulky that pipe was
oh jeff all right all right
speaking of big and bulky check out our
old lights that's right now we're all
led so anybody want to buy some
some old lights now here i'm actually
kind of measuring all scientific like
uh the size of the flange to make sure
that the whole
because i did pre-drill a hole for the
pipe so i needed to actually
make this hole a little bit higher which
is a little bit difficult because i
already had a hole there but
i i was able to just kind of quickly
figure out how much room i needed for
the flange
and you can see on the other side and
now there's actually a little bit of a
broken space
on the lower part of the other side of
the wall you'll see that in a moment
here
even better jeff it's nice and flush
yeah so but here on the other side so i
came through from that side so that it
would line up really well
yeah but i think that previously there
was
some there was another hole there that
wasn't patched properly so that's why it
kind of cracked at the bottom there
right however my i'm lucky because the
flange is big enough to cover that
so even though you can see how bad it
looks right there
on the other side of the wall it covers
it up yeah the flange is big enough that
it
uh that it really does cover up any of
those kind of like
the damaged look see that wow that fits
so smoothly it's perfect so
that looks and i like that it covers up
my
horrible hack job but so super simple so
i'm just
do it by hand and we wondered if it
would spin and i needed someone on the
other side and nope
it worked perfectly incredible so i'm
pushing that through
so much easier now to run cable um
through the wall and it's only going
through that wall i don't have to feed
it through a big long pipe
which was part of the problem i couldn't
i couldn't feed
xlr cables through because there's no
way to push them through a 10-foot pipe
that's right yeah so now i've only got
six inches to go through it's perfect so
so here what i'm doing is i'm i'm
binding the cables together
using a like a winding that i
picked up off amazon um so that
that winding just kind of makes it a lot
nicer it makes it like a snake
and binds all the cables together so
then i can kind of hide them
uh in the easy portal so you don't see
anything other than that snake sticking
out
you don't have this mess of wires like i
did before
which is kind of what we're up against
here at the studio because you have
so many cables going to all the cameras
and everything so
yeah wow that is so slick well done
amerijoid
i like how easy it was jeff yeah i guess
oh
smart name easy portal look at that
so there's my so my snake coming out so
there it is on the back of the computer
going through the easy portal
and out to the outside
in the studio that keeps it so
clean so there you have it that's easy
portal
from ameridroid.com don't forget as
you're checking out use our coupon code
cat5 tv supporter
a buck will come off of your final order
but they will in turn know that you saw
this video
and they will throw some money in the
category 5 tv tip jar to help support
what we do here at the show so i
appreciate that very much whether you're
just trying to pass some cables through
your drop ceiling or wall or desk at
home
or whether you're a contractor i mean
these are very practical very easy to
install
and anyone can do it if i can do it and
they're
very affordable too so because of
because of the customizability
i think there's just no end to what you
could uh what you could do with these
so you know in our case here we
installed one between the two studio
spaces for all the hdmi cables
but you can obviously do more these are
going to be used for the lighting
that we're going to be hanging off of
our drop ceiling so we're going to get
to that as well
but you can get them on ameridroid.com
just make sure that you reach out to
them when you place your order to
request your specific colors and things
like that
thanks for watching
[Music]
you