covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias two years ago
microsoft sank a data center off the
coast of orkney in a wild experiment
that data center has now been retrieved
from the ocean floor
and microsoft researchers are assessing
how it has performed and what they can
learn from it about
energy efficiency their first conclusion
is that the cylinder packed with servers
had a lower failure rate than a
conventional data center
when the container was hauled off the
seabed around half a mile offshore
after being placed there in may 2018
just eight out of the 855 servers on
board had failed
that compares very well with a
conventional data center
ben cutler who has led microsoft's
project natick says
our failure rate in the water is
one-eighth of what we see on land
the team is speculating that the greater
reliability may be connected to the fact
that there were no humans on board
and that nitrogen rather than oxygen was
pumped into the capsule
mr cutler says the nitrogen atmosphere
reduces corrosion
and is cool plus the absence of humans
aboard
with the absence of humans aboard it
means there's no movement or things
being
banged around orkney was chosen for the
trial by microsoft partly because
it was a center for renewable energy
research in a place where the climate
was temperate
perhaps even chile the idea was that the
cost of cooling computers would be lower
if they were underwater the white
cylinder emerged from the cold waters
with a coating of algae
and barnacles after a day-long operation
but inside the data center was still
functioning well
and is now being closely examined so
that the research team can learn more
project natick was was partly about
working out whether clusters of small
underwater data centers for short-term
use might be a commercial proposition
but also an attempt to learn broader
lessons about energy efficiency in cloud
computing
the overarching goal of project natick
is to evaluate the feasibility of
underwater data centers
phase one was just to be able to figure
out can we get computers into a
container and can we deploy them in the
water without it leaking and
do the computers survive and how well do
they last phase two
was to show that we can make it in a
manufacturable
production scale component so
the container behind me it fits on a it
fits on a trailer it fits on a cargo
ship and it
allows us to actually build up this data
center to any size that we want
orkney is a great place for this
partnership because they've got
renewable energy
for 100 percent and more of their grid
power
computers are not designed to work in
the environment that we humans operate
so things like oxygen moisture in the
air
that is really bad for computers it
causes corrosion on the components
you also get temperature fluctuations so
the heat from night to day and summer to
winter can cause those components to
fail and so we have this theory that if
we're in a really stable environment
we're in this cylinder we've taken all
the oxygen out we've controlled the
humidity
no one's walking around there's no
nobody bumping things or causing any
additional failures that we'd see better
reliability
this project gives us the ability to
feel like we're working not just on
computers not just on data centers but
on sort of moving forward environmental
responsibility as a company and as
individuals
i mean everybody uses the cloud
everybody needs data centers this
this need isn't going to go away we're
going to continue to build larger data
centers and use more electricity because
the demand is there and the
demand keeps growing how can we do it
that's better for the environment
and that's just better for us as a
people the experiment on orkney is over
but the hope is that the result will be
more environmentally friendly data
storage
both on land and underwater microsoft is
cautious about saying when an underwater
data center might be a commercial
product
but is confident that it has proved the
idea has value
you