at category 5 tv we trust our files to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
whether for your server laptop or
desktop computer
you'll experience improved performance
and reliability with kingston
ssds get ready it's time for the tech
welcome to the show everybody hey just a
quick reminder for you
don't forget to click like and subscribe
to this channel
and that's going to make sure that that
you receive our notifications every time
we
post a new video or when we're live
jeff we talk about 3d printing every now
and again
in fact we've had some great
conversations which i've posted at
cap5.tv
3d printing and on that page
we are starting our series on 3d
printing as you can see
we've gone and gotten one yeah it's a
very nice one
i've settled on the ender 3v2 for a
couple of reasons first of all i'm brand
new
to 3d printing jeff it's interesting
that this is the one you've purchased
i have it sitting in my amazon wishlist
for christmas
oh yes yes and i just said to jen today
i'm like
i really want to get a 3d printer for me
and the boys
and this happens to be the one that's on
my list well there you go you get to see
it
kind of firsthand yeah and some of the
reasons why i chose this printer jeff is
the fact that it's kind of the it's it's
out of the box
ready to print yes as far as like
it's it's easy to use it does a good
print job and it's really really
affordable
yeah so there was a few i saw that's
like oh it needs four hours assembly
time i'm like that's ridiculous hey
assembly time i didn't take four hours
but yeah it does come partially
assembled but there's
a fair bit of setup that has to go into
it yeah we're gonna look at that today
i'm going to show you
how it went for me to assemble it
again though being completely new to 3d
printing here it is it's
like q4 2020 and robbie the tech guy
has never done 3d printing before but
you're more of like a programming tech
guy sure yeah but
to be fair jeff like i've had my eye on
3d printing for a long time yes
um it's kind of covered it on the show
for you sure yeah we have
uh we've we've been talking about it
since the poyo 3d
like this is going way way back when
consumer printers were like
two or three thousand dollars and they
were just coming to market
and then we've like we've had people on
the show to talk about 3d printing and
how it's going to change the world
yeah there was that book here we are
you know 2020 finally getting into it to
my
credit though i now here
in our our hometown of barrie ontario
hometown
our city our libraries have maker spaces
yes they do so early this year
i was actually email corresponding with
their makerspace
people okay and talking about okay well
i want to get into 3d
printing how do i get started and we
were setting up for me to come in
to their makerspace to start 3d printing
for the very first vid well and that's
what happened so
they had to shut down their maker space
as i was already kind of learning so
they
they taught me that okay well you need
to have these stl models and
so that's how i learned about things
like thingiverse and
sites like sites like that where people
share their designs
but because they closed down i couldn't
actually print anything
yeah but i didn't stop there i kept
trying to learn how to do 3d printing to
see because i wanted to see
is is it something that's going to be
practical so i started doing designs
on my computer before i even had
a printer even selected a printer so
i think that was a really good way for
me to do it because it gave me a chance
to learn
some of the ins and outs of how to do it
these hooks
yes that was the reason you wanted to
get into this right yeah we're going to
talk about that
well not the reason i wanted to get into
3d printing but
right and we'll talk about it after i
show you how how i've assembled this
um but the hooks that i'm going to show
you are a big part of
you know one of the ideas that i had so
simple too
there's a dialect there there's a
dialect yeah of all the things to
print of course it's like you've got to
you know i've only printed three things
and the dalek is one of them
and priorities and a little kitten yes
i'm learning um and you're going to be
able to learn along with me so i'm
taking the approach i'm not trying to be
that you know there are a lot of gurus
3d printing gurus who have been doing
this for years and they know what
they're doing and they're on youtube and
there are some great channels
filament friday has been a wonderful
channel for me to learn on
i'm actually running a filament friday
firmware on the under three
v2 right now um there's a lot of
there are a lot of gurus out there and
i'm not one of them right
so my approach is a little bit different
with the show in the and with this
series
in that you're going to get the chance
to learn along with me
why am i doing the things that i'm doing
what have i learned
how have i messed up and what am i
learning as i go so it's a good
opportunity for you to
kind of see how 3d printing works and
learn the things that i learn as i learn
them
i think it's going to be a lot of fun i
know it's going to be a lot of fun we're
already
absolutely having a blast at home with
the 3d printer i'm looking forward to it
so let's say we get a look at oh and i
said you know some of the reasons that i
chose this printer over some of the
other options the under three
from creality of course is a very famous
um consumer printer because it's cheap
as far as affordability goes
it works with tons of different types of
filament for our series we're going to
be using pla
it's a very good entry level filament
it's known to be
easy to print and it does a reasonably
good print job
but it's it's pretty universally like i
can just swap that out
with a different spool and start
printing and it's really really easy
but creality introduced the v2 this year
and of the ender three and it kind of
comes with
a lot of the upgrades that people were
having to
create for themselves okay so you get
a lot of the stuff out of the box that
otherwise um wouldn't have been an
option with an
older gen of of the ender three so
there's there's a lot of reasons to
choose this printer
i'm not saying this is the best printer
by any stretch right but
as far as the economics of it go it's
really affordable and it does a great
print job and as
far as out of the box experience goes
you can see i've already been printing
stuff
and i'm just getting started yeah so
very clean prints
like that's one of the things with some
of the printers is you know you you read
reviews you look at the
the close-up photos and it's like wow
it's not really a smooth looking print
it's kind of clunky
these are really clean thanks jeff i'm a
noob
well done yeah all right so let's take a
look at how
i went about assembling the ender three
let's do that together
the ender 3v2 comes partially assembled
the base
is assembled but we are going to need
the instruction manual
because we need to make sure that
everything goes together correctly there
is
some assembly required you should be
able to do this
reasonably easily especially if you
follow along
what's in the manual what you're going
to see here today
let's start looking at the components
we've got the extruder kit here um this
is what the filament is going to
it's the hot end of the printer so this
what the filament is going to come out
of it's going to melt it
and move around on all the axes
then we've got the the screen here which
is an upgraded screen from
the previous iterations of the ender 3.
it is color
but it's not touch just like previous
versions
it uses the dial wheel here we have the
xe
axis kit which has the xe motors
x being left and right e of course being
the extruder
which is basically pushing the filament
into the
hot end we'll set that aside and here's
the material rack and the spool holder
and this is where you're actually going
to put your spools of filament
and we've got some aluminum extrusions
for parts of the frame that we're going
to put together
so this portion of the ender 3v2 is
already assembled this has got the
heated printing platform quite often you
hear this called the bed
and it's all part of the machine base
it's all put together already for us
and it looks like one of my leveling
knobs has come off in shipping
we'll fix that in a moment but the
machine base and power supply are
already
assembled that has the y-axis tensioner
and the motor
for the y-axis power cables there uh
what else have we got here we've got
more extrusions uh for the frame
these look like the z-axis which is your
up and down
uh part of the frame and just watch that
z-axis rod that's packaged inside you
don't want that to fall out
so you can see that's a threaded rod
it's got some grease on it so
watch that's why it's got that sleeve
but we're going to set everything aside
here
and get started so here's the z-axis
motor it has the rod coupling for that
rod
so we'll assemble that in a moment
on to the final stuff we've got some
sample filament the belts
extrusion nozzles things like that
and the belt tensioner for the z-axis
a couple screws
[Music]
then we've got the z-axis passive block
that's the wheels that are going to go
up and down on the right-hand side
and it came with a scraper which is
great for removing prints from the bed
or slashing the eyes of your enemies and
we've got a couple of tools here and
screws and such for the assembly itself
and there's also some side cutters
included in there as well a little bonus
so first things first i'm going to
replace that bed leveling knob that
came off during shipping
[Music]
ah there it is so should just go right
on there
[Music]
our first 3d printer repair right there
just tighten these up so they don't come
off and just note as
i'm moving things around here that glass
bed
is held onto the heating platform
by a couple of clips just make sure
those clips are snug before you start
moving it around like i am here because
you don't want that to fall off it
shouldn't but
just keep in mind there's the extruder
with the
hot end of our 3d printer
[Music]
and back to the book jeff will be so
proud of me
to see me reading the manual
i'm just going to kind of lay everything
out here we've got the z-axis switch
came with an sd card and card reader
like a usb reader
just lay everything out so it's easy
access as i'm going through the manual
and figuring out how to set everything
up
and there's the side cutters that
they've included for you that's great
for
trimming pieces of your
3d prints especially if you have any
platforming
you're going to need those now it is a
bit of a process to work your way
through the instruction manual and
assemble your ender 3v2
as i'm about to do so just follow along
in your manual
and i'm going to speed things up through
the magic of television
[Music]
there we have it the ender 3v2 is fully
assembled and ready to print
when we come back after this quick break
we're going to talk about my first
impressions
as we print our very first 3d prints
on the creality ender 3v2 stick around
[Music]
so
welcome back you'll notice at the end of
the
fast motion video there this particular
cabling here was on the outside of the
top
uh extrusion so i had to just simply
remove two screws and put it inside
but you'll save a bit of time uh maybe
if you make a note of the position of
this it wasn't quite clear in the manual
and there were a couple of things like
that that
just weren't quite clear but easy enough
to figure out as long as you're patient
and
and uh take your time but uh i think now
that i've assembled it jeff
i could probably throw one of these
together in half the time
oh that's easily how long did it take
you to assemble this well
i mean i was shooting video and
everything so it's not really a fair
um equation right because you know i had
eight cameras around me and i'm setting
everything up and
and setting up my shots and things but
good for camera oh i got it uh
about an hour and a half it took me all
together so
i think you could probably put this
together in about a half hour
realistically pretty decent yeah yeah so
the the first things that i've noted as
a brand new 3d printer guy
maker never 3d printed anything in my
life
the the first thing i did was i leveled
the bed and that's really really
important to use these dial wheels use a
piece of paper and i'm going to be
demonstrating how to do that there are
videos on youtube but we will make that
part of the series as well
leveling the bed is the first thing that
you need to do once it's level and
things look good
then you can start your 3d print so it
came with
an sd card as you noted there and
the sd card has some g-code models on it
so
okay my son liam wanted to print the cat
it was just
on on the screen we just saw there's a
cat so let's try that
man you guys have cats we do now yes
so um so he printed this and
as you mentioned jeff like it it came
out really
really great so this was our very very
first print yeah so this was just the
g-code that was included on the sd card
and it came out absolutely beautiful and
he's thrilled with that so that was our
very very first print on day one okay so
then day two came and nothing was
working
the bed wasn't so because i'm starting
to
i'm starting to play around with my own
designs you mentioned these hooks we're
going to look at those
but so the hooks were going to be my
second print
okay i designed my own mask hooks
yes and these are these are meant to go
on
a half inch pipe so the cold water
pipe in our laundry room because we have
an unfinished laundry room
yeah this clips on to the half inch pipe
and it gives
us a place to dry our reusable washable
masks
are face masks so it's just a neat
little
thing that i came up with but my wife
was was thinking like hey this is really
really high
i can't quite reach it so the next
iteration was a little bit longer and a
little bit longer
and i went through a couple of
iterations so this was the the first one
was just this little tiny guy
yep right and then the next one was a
little bit longer and then
finally the final print
came out like this so i simply i simply
extended the uh
the length of it and i designed this in
a program called tinkercad which is a
free it's a free website tinkercad.com
all the links of the tools that i'm
using throughout the course of the
series are at cat5 dot tv slash 3d
printing
uh but that's what i use to design this
cool so i basically just
i laid it out in tinkercad and and
that's what i came up with
cool so and it printed great once i
figured it out but
day two came and nothing was working and
i say that
because i was struggling to get the bed
to level because nothing was sticking to
the bed
and it's really really important what i
found is it's very important that the
first couple of layers are stuck to the
bed
because if they're not as the printer is
moving up
it's gonna it's gonna lose adhesion and
it's gonna move
the the print is gonna move and then
it's not gonna be printing the right
thing in the right spot and it's not
gonna work out was the bed heating up
the bed was heating up to 60 degrees
celsius everything was working there
so i did everything from i gave it a
quick wipe down with some
isopropyl alcohol i upgraded the
firmware to one from filament friday
because it came with an
like the original firmware had some bugs
in it that he'd mentioned
and so i installed his firmware and it
still wasn't working for me yeah
and then i started thinking because you
know i'm i'm
the troubleshooter yes so i've tried
everything every time i leveled the bed
it still wasn't adhering to the bed so
then i started saying okay well what's
different between yesterday and today
and the one thing that i came up with is
our first day
print was from the g code provided by
creality yeah creality my second print
second day print was a g code that i
created
now understand so i've learned a couple
of things so i mentioned that i made
this in tinkercad i designed it in
tinkercad
but that gives you an stl file yes or an
obj or whatever so these are the file
extensions
so that stl file can't go to the printer
you need what's called a g-code which is
a file that tells it how to build the
layers okay
so that's i'm using a program called
cura which is also free
links again at cat5 dot tv slash 3d
printing
and with that software it creates the
slice
layers yes and it spews out a file
called a g-code file
and so the g-code for this was on the sd
card came with it the g-code for this
is something that i made in cura okay so
then i started thinking okay well what's
different so
i got researching i got looking into it
and then
finally after several hours of tinkering
jeff i
found out that g-code is actually a text
file
a script oh so i opened it
in my text editor yep and looked at it
and i started seeing that this is just a
script it's like code
so then i looked at the code for this
one
and i looked at the code for mine and i
compared the difference
at the start of the file and found that
my g-code from cura
was telling the extruder to raise
two millimeters at the start of the
print and there was a comment that said
oh so that it doesn't scratch the print
bed
and it was raising a full two
millimeters so i started looking
so i started another print and i looked
down at the extruder and sure enough
at the beginning at the beginning of the
print i saw the extruder go up two
millimeters so it wasn't
quite down on the bed so it wasn't able
to adhere to the bed so i went in
i copied the header from this g-code and
pasted it over top the header
of my g-code and i printed out a good 10
15 of these hooks and it worked
perfectly
why the different header because you
didn't program that
different start code no it was just the
default profile
so it had this raise up two millimeters
or whatever so
so having replaced it with this header
the start code from this one everything
printed just fine
so i was like oh so that was a
revelation for me to realize that
the g code is an editable script that
you can go in and you can modify and
then i'm thinking about all the
wonderful things that you can do with
that knowledge
yeah and it's wonderful so then i took
that g code the
the start part of the g code and i
pasted it into my profile
in cura to always use that as my start
code that's
replacing the one that came with it i
made a couple of little mini
modifications based on the knowledge
that i had accumulated from
the research that i had done yeah and uh
now i've got a start code that is
working like that just beautiful so
every print comes out people would have
run into that issue and would have said
the machine's just not working nobody
was saying check the start code on your
g-code
everybody was saying okay make sure your
bed is level yeah i did that
10 times make sure that the bed is clean
yeah i did that
make sure you know that there's no
interesting yeah so all this stuff make
sure the bed temperature is good
uh the g code from cura was defaulting
to 50 degrees celsius
i noticed that this one was 60 degrees
celsius so i increased it
yeah and that was done through the
material
in cura again i'm going to show you how
to do all these things so don't worry
okay but that's what i learned so then
we started printing other things and
my other son zach said i really want a
dalek
yes and so we got onto thingiverse and
downloaded the stl file for a dalek
now that is not monochromatic that's
got two colors you're right so what we
actually did is we
first printed these parts okay
okay so these little guys the extensions
and these actually clip
into the daleks so we printed it in two
parts
very cool yeah um you'll see that these
are all white
yes they are all printed jeff with that
sample spool
of filament i was able to sample i was
able to get this out of the sam
sample that they said wow so i didn't
even have to tap into
my purchased filament so that is uh what
we came up with for
for zach as well so i was really really
impressed with that and he's very very
happy with that model
uh when i was removing the um the
supports for the uh the black parts
because they're so
tiny yes i kind of clipped a little bit
too far in places but we can reprint
those little parts
i was able to say you can reprint and we
start talking about how because they're
attachments we could create other
attachments and yes play around with all
that kind of stuff
so speaking of wanting to um
basically adapt our designs to
our own needs so creating attachments
and things like that
the next thing that we wanted to do is
well he wanted to print in black
of course so i got a little spool 250
grams of black filament
and it's fine but it was affordable
because it's only 250 grams i didn't
need a big
one kilogram thing but it doesn't fit on
the spool holder because the hole is too
small
oh no so i was like well what do i do
what do i do
jeff any suggestions you weren't a new
school holder
so i actually i went on and and i
started designing
based on some designs that i found on
thingiverse but i created this little
guy
so this is printed with the uh
transparent
uh filament yep um this is a new spool
holder specifically designed
to hold these little spools well so i
built i
made this spool holder specifically to
replace
that and it just screws on yep and
allows me to
to print using the 250 gram spools so
then i'm like
i can actually adapt my 3d printer
create
accessories and attachments yeah that i
i don't have to get on amazon and buy
new parts or
try to track down a smaller school you
print it yourself so how cool is that
that's awesome so overall my experience
so far has been great i'm learning as i
go and that's part of the fun
my kids have been so patient as i've
been learning and that's that's been a
good experience for them i think as well
uh but the ender 3v2 has been i mean so
far so good it's a fantastic little
printer
it's quiet it's got the quiet circuit
the the board itself is like
i don't know it's upgraded on the uh v2
um and apparently is quieter than the
older versions we're going to be looking
at the actual
sound that it generates but you hear the
fans
there is the cooling system to keep
things cool yep um
but uh it's reasonably quiet like we
could have it running right here and
it wouldn't uh it wouldn't probably even
be picked up on our microphones
yeah so that's kind of you know that's a
bit of a primer as to you know here i am
i'm brand new to 3d printing and i'm 3d
printing
i'm doing my own designs i'm using free
software
uh in my browser in i'm using cura which
is an actual installed application that
you can download and install
i did find tinkercad has one limitation
being a free
online service is that the um
stl files have to be below 25 megabytes
okay so i'm limited on size yes now
that's not a problem when they're only
like 200
kilobytes and things like that but as
soon as i got into some more
sophisticated designs
i was like oh wow this is this is 26
megabytes and i can't edit it
in tinkercad so that will eventually
lead me to start looking at other things
but i think tinkercad is a really good
starting point
okay so cat5.tv 3d printing is where you
want to go to
follow along with this series learn from
my mistakes
and from my victories and uh i'm also
sharing absolutely everything that i do
through github you'll see links there so
i've got the designs here on my
uh what is it called my mini is it my
mini maker or something like that
i started using thingiverse but it's
really buggy yeah so
um you'll see the links there anyways
cat5 dot tv slash
3d printing i'm still learning all the
terms i'm still learning how everything
works
that's exciting i'm brand new to it but
i am sharing everything that i've
learned and even that start code for
for cura is available on my github
repository as well so excellent that'll
get you
started as well so all the tips this
uh you know as i mentioned earlier this
is
the one that's actually sitting on my
amazon yes list yeah so
uh if you could do me a favor
and just let my wife know how amazing
this is yeah i'll just kind of let her
know
i'm just going to start sending her all
the videos yes hey check this out i hear
jeff might be interested in 3d printing
yeah it's totally amazing yeah and if
you follow along with the series jeff
you're going to have a real good head
start on me because
a lot of things that i've had to learn
the hard way um you're going to be able
to do and even
so much as these designs are available
for you through my github
now maybe this doesn't fit into your
full review but i've got to ask
why clear filament as opposed to the
typical red white blue
you got to buy filament anyway so i
needed i needed filament to print the
small spool
yes because i didn't have a small spool
to print with the cheap filament right
the 250 gram filament
the reason that i got translucent
filament is because i'm going to be
making signage for category 5.
oh yeah so okay the first
handful of layers so about a half an
inch are going to be translated
and then the top layer is going to be
black so i thought hey i've got to buy
filament anyways i'm going to buy
a roll of the translucent filament
because i'm going to be using it anyways
and it looks really cool
yeah it does really really nice yeah
that's great
well there you have it let's head over
to the newsroom here's becca
here's what's coming up in the category
5 tv newsroom
the public beta of spacex starlink
internet service has begun
youtube dl has been hit with a dmca
takedown by the riaa
ubuntu groovy gorilla as raspberry pi as
a first
class citizen zoom has added
end-to-end encryption for all for free
though there are caveats and will tell
you what they are
and a nasa spacecraft spacecraft
successfully touched down on an asteroid
to collect a sample
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5 dot tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
the public beta space of spacex starlink
internet service has begun
spacex has begun sending email
invitations to starling's public beta
and will charge beta users 99 per month
plus a one-time fee of 499 dollars for
the user terminal
mounting tripod and router the emails
are being sent to people who previously
registered interest
in the service on the starlink website
spacex is calling it the
better than nothing beta perhaps partly
because the starlink satellite service
will be most useful
to people who can't get cable or fiber
broadband
but the email also says as you can tell
from the title we are trying to
lower your initial expectations
the email reads expect to see data
speeds vary from
50 to 150 megabits per second and
latency from 20 to 40 milliseconds over
the next several months as we enhance
the starlink system
there will also be brief periods of no
connectivity at all
as we launch more satellites install
more ground stations and improve our
networking software
data speed latency and uptime will
improve dramatically
for latency we expect to achieve 16 to
19 milliseconds by summer
2021. there is apparently no data cap
a starlink mobile app to help beta users
set up and manage the surface also
just went live on apple's app store and
google play
elon musk recently said that the public
beta will be for the northern u.s
and hopefully southern canada spacex
plans to provide starlink to a school
district in texas in early
2021 but that doesn't mean the public
beta is available to anyone in the south
the wait may not be too long though as
spacex has said it will reach near
global coverage of the populated world
by 2021.
you know that starling story is an
interesting one because for so long
we have been hearing about this project
and hearing about how
it's going to change the face of the
globe with providing internet high-speed
internet to
you know unreachable areas so it's
interesting that
they're offering this beta version to
lower expectations
that's totally contrary to what
companies do they want to
heighten expectations so why would they
take that approach
when quite frankly if you don't have
access to internet
even to hear that you can get you know
50 make download speeds is phenomenal
sure like that that to me is great i
mean
but it's satellite you expect that
there's going to be downtime you expect
that there's going to be
interference from weather so i don't
understand why they
would call this about lowering
expectations like what were people
thinking they were going to well i mean
we know that it's meant to be really
really fast and they're saying
it's not yet there no so let's try it
out but no
it's not yet there yeah so i think you
know they have to set
expectations perhaps to avoid you know
complaints and things like that
but i think about like my you it's
it's hard for us to fathom if we live in
a city that there are places still that
don't have high speed internet
i i'm literally thinking about my church
yeah
we are yeah you're just on the outskirts
we're less than a kilometer from the
edge of barry
we cannot get anything
internet wise other than sure your basic
dsl
our old studio studio d brutal same deal
yeah my father-in-law is using lte
internet at home because they do not
have high-speed internet where they live
that's what we have at the church
that's unreal 200 bucks a month just to
have basic internet just for basic lte
internet
man so i mean like this starlink for the
price it's going to be
could be a great solution yes for you
for you then in that case or for my
father-in-law
it's a great option and it's probably
going to be better than what they
currently have so maybe setting the
expectations
low in that you know those of us who
have gig internet
aren't going out and and signing up for
the new
you know this is the latest and greatest
from spacex right so
it's going to be the best well they're
setting the expectations low
purposefully so that it's the right
market yeah i i guess
if you're in a city where you've got
that high speed but if you have nothing
yes i mean what they're offering for
speeds is phenomenal it is
so i mean i'm i'm excited at first i
wasn't sure how i felt about this
project when i first heard about it
because i'm like oh
he just wants to space debris yeah
but now that i'm starting to see it roll
out
i'm getting excited about but what's
interesting is that it's upper u.s
possibly lower canada for their base
start
why not beta test in like a low like
pick somewhere along the equator of
africa maybe
you know like some remote well it makes
sense though that they would want to
test it in a place where well think of
it this way
if if it went down i have something else
to fall back on
yeah i have the 4g infrastructure to
fall back on if i needed to
so maybe that has something to do with
it i mean we're speculating here but
there there are so many thoughts yeah
but hey how
how does something like starlink affect
you is it something that would be better
than what you have or is it
a severe downgrade that's really what it
comes down to but i think in a lot of
cases this is going to bring
high-speed internet to areas that
currently don't have it and not only
that
jeff but we've hit on it in the past
when we've talked about starlink
and that's that in an event of natural
disaster
or infrastructure um issues
it's an opportunity to still receive
good solid internet
high-speed internet that is not reliant
on things like
towers yes right now one of the things
that will be interesting is because
i mean this is not new like satellite
internet
is already well good satellite internet
what's new that's
that's the challenge here is uh i mean i
used to
another iteration of my working life i
was a
uh a ser recognized installer for
satellite internet
um so i have an inner working of or an
inner understanding of how it works and
it was quite
uh cumbersome and unreliable
yep i mean the dish moves just a slight
bit from wind right
and you're out so i'm really interested
to see
how starlink's internet
works in that regard and if a little bit
of wind is going to knock it out or if
it's a more stable platform
time will tell maybe the beta test will
show some results so we'll see over the
next couple months
we've got to head back to becca youtube
dl
has been hit with a dmca takedown by the
recording industry association of
america
the ri double-a has issued a dmca
takedown on the open source project
youtube dl on their github repository
this is done under the guise of
protecting content creators from having
their ad revenue stolen
youtube dl however is often used by
archivists and users who suffer from a
slow internet connection
in order to allow them to watch the
content there are of course those that
use it to circumvent ads but we can't
pretend ad blockers don't exist
which accomplish the same goal with less
effort so
are ad blockers next on the list here at
category 5 we're content
creators we post our videos on youtube
and we depend on the revenue it
generates
but like the electronic frontier
foundation points out
we believe youtube dl is a legitimate
tool with a world of lawful uses
see we know we have viewers who are
watching in areas where internet just
isn't very good
we've heard from troops who watch our
show in their tents while at war
we have fans who live in areas where
high-speed internet just doesn't exist
yet
so we make sure they have access to our
content for free
with the hope that they will support us
through patreon if they're able
we received an email from a viewer this
week asking us how they can watch our
show while circumventing youtube
is it surprising that we the very
content creators who rely on the
revenue youtube provides responded by
providing bittorrent files of all 13
past seasons
plus recommended the download button
found on the page of every episode we
publish
on our website as content creators we
understand the need for
revenue it costs a lot of money to do
what we do
but for the riaa to demand youtube dl be
shut down
seems shady the electronic frontier
foundation fights these types of battles
on behalf of open source projects
you can help protect projects like
youtube dl by donating at eff.org
last week canonical released the latest
intermediate version of ubuntu 20.10
groovy gorilla which for the first time
adds first-class
platform support for the raspberry pi 4.
groovy gorilla itself is a pretty
typical interim release offering an
updated gnome version with lots of bug
fixes
and small feature editions support has
also been added for windows active
directory in the
ubiquiti os installer itself
and while it has been possible for some
time to install ubuntu on raspberry pi
hardware
up until now that has been strictly a
community effort
the pie itself ships with raspberry pi
os at debian based distribution whose
origins began with the pi
community but which has since been
officially adopted and supported by the
raspberry pi foundation itself
while canonical added the pie as a
supported platform in 20.04
earlier this year that support was only
for the ubuntu server distribution
not desktop with 20.10 groovy gorilla
canonical has added
full desktop support for the pi 4.
martin wim press
canonical's director of engineering for
the ubuntu desktop
says this means the pi is now a
first-class citizen
canonical guarantees the same level of
integration qa
and support from kernel to user space
that it does for a standard pc
the entire ubuntu software repository is
available and supported on the pi
of course that's other than
architecture-specific packages that
start with names like i-386
and are therefore not compatible with
the raspberry pi's arm processor
if you'd like to install ubuntu 20.10
desktop on the pi you'll need a four
gigabyte or
eight gigabyte raspberry pi as long as
you meet the hardware requirements the
install is a breeze
ubuntu 20.10 desktop is an option in the
standard raspberry pi imager now
the imager itself is available for linux
windows or
mac platforms to get up and running
insert a four gigabyte plus microsd
card open the image or choose ubuntu
20.10 and click
right a few minutes later you'll be able
to boot the official ubuntu 20.10 for
raspberry pi
4. zoom has added end-to-end encryption
for
all for free though there are caveats
and we'll tell you what they are and a
nasa spacecraft
successfully touched down on an asteroid
to collect a sample
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert is here with the crypto corner
don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
this week i've got some really good news
for you um
if we look at the market by the time i'm
recording this year the price of bitcoin
is at 13
128 which is equivalent to 2.3
increase in the last 24 hours and 14 in
the last seven days
i think that's fantastic news and one
reason why i believe that
is if we compare it to the stock
exchange the u.s stock exchange
or the gold price then there is a
decoupling happening
it is not confirmed yet that will take
some time but at least there is a
decoupling at the moment
this is the charge chart since beginning
of october
and the red line is the red curve
is the u.s stock exchange
the blue is the gold price and so you
see there's a significant gap
uh especially since yesterday where we
had a huge drop
in the stock exchange new stock exchange
uh
to bitcoin so i think that's that's
great news it's to be
expected because it's a complete
different asset commodity
and so let's see what will happen the
other
good news is paypal
paypal decided to get involved in
cryptocurrencies and so you can buy now
uh some cryptocurrencies on their
platform
and the great news is because they have
got over 340 million
users and you can uh by using paypal pay
for services and goods and you can now
use for example bitcoin
to pay for services and goods but at
least that the offering this year to
this huge
community is i think fantastic news
also one that i have to take with a
smile
is our friends from jp morgan one of the
largest financial institutions in the
world
and in 2017 jamie dimon their ceo
said that bitcoin is a fraud and will
blow up
joseph said that he if he finds somebody
in his organization uh
trading uh cryptocurrencies that person
will be fired on the spot
now like in politics things can change
significantly and dramatically and so
this has
happened this was published uh two days
ago
uh by jp morgan where they are now
saying bitcoin has considerable upside
is it's better competes with gold as an
alternative currency
i find that fantastic news because the
organization
embedded in the old system like jp
morgan suddenly changes their opinion
180 degrees
is for me extremely bullish not
financial advice
but for me that's a bullish sign so
um yeah one thing i'd like to focus on
is it's a question that a lot of people
are asking
us in regards to private keys and
public keys so i'd like to spend a few
minutes on that subject
and for that i pulled up a website
called ian callman.io because this is
uh uses um
the web the the content fantastically
well
and so there there's somebody in bitcoin
or team
that came up with this process of how to
convert
uh a private key into a public key and
they expanded that and now a lot of
different cryptocurrencies are using the
same process and that's why it's called
bip 39 or bip 44 because it's bitcoin
improvement protocol
but other currencies are using that so i
just gen clicked on generated on 24
words
and so out of a repository uh the system
generated 24 words
and that those are the words that you
need to remember
uh when you generate a wallet for
example you
create a new wallet uh well it will uh
generate those 24 words and those are
the ones that you have to remember
because everything
derives from those 24 words so
with a little bit this little bit
technical here but from those 24 words
we deduct the private key from that
private key we deduct the public key and
that public key and then generates the
address
yeah so and the reason that is done is
that there is no way in the world that
you can get back to the private key
that's why
cryptocurrency is so secure yeah and so
what you do is you take the private key
you hash it that's a special
crypto cryptographic process and with
that you generate the public key
and the public key is hashed twice and
that generates the address
the reason that this is done is that
there might be future some computers
that are able to deduct from the public
key the private key
they don't exist yet but we're thinking
well ahead in the future and that's why
we are using the address as the key that
you
uh send to other people in case you want
to resee some bitcoin or so
so this is all the magic behind
it it's based on those 24 words those 24
words generate the private key the
private key generates the public key and
the public key generates the address and
address is what we use
and that set is used in many other
ikea cryptocurrencies they use the same
um same process
anyway that's it from me
i hope you enjoyed it i hope you learned
something um
thank you very much for watching please
leave a like it helps us
we need to grow and um yeah come back
next week
thank you very much for watching bye
thank you robert
just a reminder that we're not providing
financial advice but only sharing what's
happening in the cryptocurrency markets
always remember that the cryptocurrency
markets are ever-changing
and always volatile so only invest what
you can afford to lose
now here's becca thank you robbie
zoom has added end-to-end encryption to
its video conferencing service at no
additional cost for all users
whether they are paying subscribers or
not the feature has been long awaited
given the service's massive adoption as
a result
of pandemic lockdowns something that
swung a spotlight on its patchy security
the company announced on tuesday that
the new feature is available now as a
technical preview for the next 30 days
and is looking for user feedback before
rolling it out on mass
zoom see so jason lee gives kudos to
keybase who joined the company in may to
develop the security feature
taking just six months to do so zoom
says its end-to-end encryption will use
256-bit aes gcm
and a secure key exchange is performed
beforehand to ensure only the
participants on the call can decrypt
each other's part of the conversations
and no eavesdroppers not even zoom
itself can listen
in zoom had already encrypted some of
its
communications though it wasn't truly
end to end until now
in order to use the end-to-end
encryption an account admin has to
enable the feature
zoom's end-to-end encryption is limited
to 200 participants so for larger
meetings where encryption may not be a
needed feature
such as a public forum or a digital
comic con
it can be disabled to allow more people
to join
other restrictions of the service are a
lack of cloud recording and live
transcription breakout rooms polling and
one-to-one private chats are also
unavailable when end-to-end encryption
are on
as are live emojis perhaps the biggest
caveat of all though is that each user
must have the official zoom client
installed in order to participate
so browser-based participation will not
be available for encrypted meetings
third-party zoom clients will also not
work when end-to-end
encryption is enabled the feature is
available on new releases of the zoom
software for mac os windows android
linux and ios
after orbiting the near-earth asteroid
bennu for nearly two years nasa's
osiris-rex
spacecraft successfully touched down and
reached out its robotic arm to collect a
sample from the asteroid's surface
last week the sample will be returned to
earth in 2023
to achieve this historic first for nasa
a van sized spacecraft had to briefly
touch down its arm in a landing site
called nightingale
the site is the width of a few parking
spaces
the arm reached out to collect a sample
which could be between
two ounces and two kilograms then the
spacecraft backed away to safety
we have never done this before we're
actually going to collect a sample
and bring it back down to earth for
further examination by scientists
in order to achieve that objective the
osiris-rex spacecraft has been
navigating around bennu for about the
last two years studying it in great
detail
and also overcoming a number of
challenges that venue has presented
we were looking for locations on venue
that were 50 meters in diameter
relatively flat and covered with
fine-grained material and by
fine-grained
material i mean stuff that's the size of
a dime or smaller
we realized that there were no sites on
bennu that even came close to meeting
this criteria
everywhere we looked was too small and
covered with boulders
so we actually had to fly a number of
additional close passes over the
asteroid
and rethink our entire plan for grabbing
the sample
the tag event is our touch and go event
which is where we'll actually be
retrieving the sample from asteroid
bennu we start with a series of
maneuvers one of them being the
checkpoint burn which is where we'll
actually check our position velocity in
relation
to the sample sites and then the match
point burn about 10 minutes later
we'll zero out our horizontal velocity
relative to the surface
and then about 10 minutes after that we
make contact with the tag sam
fire the gas bottle and then back away
and we hope to get
at least 60 grams of sample and then
we'll be able to store
that and bring it back down to earth
everything went perfectly based on the
data returned by the spacecraft
according to dante loretta
the mission's principal investigator and
a professor at the university of arizona
lunar and planetary laboratory he said
he feels transcendent and the team is
exuberant
based on the current data loretta said
in a statement
after over a decade of planning the team
is overjoyed at the success of today's
sampling attempt
i look forward to analyzing the data and
to determine the mass of sample
collected
we have to verify that we have a proper
sample
first we're going to image the tag sam
head by sticking in front of one of the
cameras then we're going to do a
maneuver called the sample mass
measurement in which we stick out the
arm and we spin the spacecraft
in order for us to decide if we've
collected enough mass to be able to stow
the sample
and return home or if we have to try
again preliminary data show the sampling
head touch bennu's surface for
approximately six seconds
after which the spacecraft performed a
back away burn
thomas zerbuckin associate administrator
for nasa's science mission directorate
said
in a statement a piece of primordial
rock that has witnessed our solar
system's entire history
may now be ready to come home for
generations of scientific discovery
and we can't wait to see what comes next
the mission which stands for origin
spectral interpretation
resource identification security
regolith explorer
launched in september 2016. since
arriving at bennu the spacecraft and its
cameras have been collecting
and sending back data and images to help
the team learn more about the asteroids
composition
and map out the best potential landing
sites to collect samples
the main event of the mission is the
touch and go sample collection event or
tag
that occurred last week the event took
about four and a half hours total to
unfold and the spacecraft
executed three maneuvers to collect the
sample from bennu
which could help scientists understand
not only more about asteroids that could
impact earth but also about how planets
formed and life began
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category five from the category five dot
tv newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
halloween this year is a little bit of
an oddball
really what is that well we may not be
able to necessarily
do trick-or-treating or have big parties
like we normally would
but we can still have fun no we can't
yeah we absolutely can so tonight
and kind of celebration happy halloween
uh we're going to
do three things first of all i'm going
to turn you into a zombie
second of all we're going to learn a
story from canadian
folklore and thirdly we're going to take
a tour
of the orville and i hear
something something has gone wrong
unless you fall in something has gone
very
very wrong jeff what good is a neural
network
if you can't use it
to turn yourself into a zombie well
you know what i answered every morning
asking myself that question
jeff give me a really good toothy smile
no just give me a smile come on yeah
there we go
okay so we got the picture now what i'm
going to do is i'm going to bring up my
web browser because this tool
is available through your web browser
that means there's no app to install
it doesn't collect anything other than
just google analytics it's perfectly
safe
and you don't have to put it in and it's
platform agnostic doesn't matter if
you're on your computer your phone your
tablet
whatever you go to makemeazombie.com and
we're going to browse to that picture
that i just took of jeff
there he is and we're going to click on
that and click
make me a zombie okay
what's happening is is that again a
general adversarial network a neural
network
is now taking your photo and turning you
into a zombie
oh my gosh
wow uh that's wow
you like that note self don't become the
undead
oh jeff that is fantastic
i feel like i'm the guinea pig of the
show make me
makemiazombie.com and you can do that on
any device
that's fun becca ferguson from the
category 5
tv newsroom is an author and she's been
putting together a series of ghost
stories and folklore
and we've been putting it together as a
video series so
let's jump over to that here's a little
sample for you
of catching nuance catching nuance
canadian folklore and ghost stories as
retold by author
becca ferguson narrated by robbie
ferguson
[Music]
this is la corrivo of new france quebec
in 1761 st valliere new france
15 months after the mysterious death of
her first husband
marie joseph corriveau married a second
farmer
two years later he was found dead in the
barn
with his head smashed in at first
his death was deemed accidental multiple
kicks from a horse's hooves but
rumors of murder quickly spread around
the town
the local british military authorities
soon charged marie joseft's father
joseph corriveau his daughter was
thought to be an accessory only
and given 60 lashes the letter m branded
onto her hand with a hot iron
joseph however admitted that his
daughter was the murderer
claiming she'd killed her abusive
husband with two blows from the back of
a hatchet
while he slept thus thereby found guilty
by the tribunal
she was put to death in quebec city by
hanging
her corpse was fastened into an iron
cage gibbet
and dangled from a tree branch at the
crossroads of saint joseph street
and de lontante boulevard in levy
there it rotted on public display
for an entire month feasted upon by
flies
and maggots torn asunder by crows
it wasn't long before the hauntings
began
travelers soon learned not to take the
river road leading past the cage at
night
lest her vacant eyes should glow blood
red
and her shackled leathery arms should
stretch out toward them
even after the gibbet was taken down her
body buried within
the cage the hauntings continued
her spirit rising from the grave each
night
to torment travelers one such night
a well-known citizen named dubai was
walking alongside the saint lawrence
river
when the air turned chill
he stopped short just as a pair of bony
fingers
closed in around his throat from behind
tendrils of greasy black hair
tickled his cheeks and a ragged voice
whispered
take me across the river
dubai swung around glimpsing over his
shoulder a set of red eyes and yellow
teeth within a face of putrefied
flesh he fell to his knees
tearing at the slimy hands that refused
to let go
leave me he screamed then passed out
from fright the next morning
his wife found him and shook him awake
on the vacant road
his story spread and a curate was called
in to exercise the spirit
a century later the cage was dug up
during an expansion project and put in a
church cellar
it was stolen and sold to an american
who put it in his museum
in a glass display case with a placard
that read simply
from quebec in time it was returned to
canada
and placed permanently in the museum of
civilization
in quebec city you can catch more
folklore and ghost stories
from catching nuance on our website
category 5
dot tv well jeff this is the orville
interactive fan experience with the
halloween update which you can download
for free
through steam now to start the halloween
event
all you need to do is go to the quantum
control console on the bridge
and go to the top rows google location
now this is meant to be a single player
event but for us right now we're just
basically running around we're not
getting into the scenario
when you play it make sure you press i
in order to see which consoles need
repair
and then you'll be able to participate
in the actual scenario but as i say
we're just going to run around and show
you what it looks like let's go red
alert
that's not me doing that what are hold
on what
it's like we're spinning are we whoa
whoa
what on earth hey what happened there
where are
[Music]
of no use to you now
who is that i have a challenge for you
a challenge you'll no doubt fail
disastrously
will let you leave and continue on with
your adventures
around the galaxy if you can repair
all nine of the damaged consoles on your
starship
that's simple
who's taking control of the ship some
kind of
supreme being
i can't help it if you're afraid
[Music]
where are you going no idea jeff
trying to get let's try to get out of
here
[Music]
is it weird that i like the sound of
screaming
i do not like that
i think something's coming
do you think it's weird that sometimes i
like the sound of screaming
[Music]
oh man oh those spiders gave me the
heebie-jeebies
oh the clown i did not like you can
install
the oroville fan experience for free
it's in steam right now give it a go
we'll be right back after this
[Music]
well i hope you've had fun with us this
week it's sure been a blast for us
happy halloween have a safe one and uh
have a wonderful
wonderful week we're looking forward to
seeing you in two weeks time because
next week is production week here at
category 5 tv what about that
yeah and if you haven't uh been
following our schedule make sure you go
on to our website category5.tv and
you'll see
our calendar on the bottom of the
homepage
don't forget we are on twitter at
category5tv
and i'd really appreciate it if you
would consider becoming part of our
patreon
fleet head on over to patreon.com
category5
it's a great way to support the content
that we create here at category 5 tv
but at the same time you're going to
gain access to some behind the scenes
and a lot of great content that is only
available
to our patrons thanks for watching
everyone have a wonderful week
[Music]
you