covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias apple unveiled
four new phones tuesday which are
equipped for faster technology with
5g wireless networks the pandemic
temporarily paralyzed apple's overseas
factories and key suppliers
leading to a delay of the latest iphones
from their usual late september rollout
the company also closed many of its u.s
stores for months because of the
pandemic
depriving apple of a prime showcase for
its products
now the new lineup has been unveiled the
iphone 12
12 mini 12 pro and 12 pro max
range in price from about 979 dollars
canadian
to upwards of 1550.
the tech giant said the new phones will
also be more durable
in a move that may annoy some consumers
apple will no longer
include charging adapters with new
phones the company says that will mean
smaller lighter boxes that are more
environmentally friendly to ship
apple however separately sells two
models of power adapter
which are likely a required purchase
since the included cable is not
compatible with the traditional usba
style
wall wart apple has one of the most
loyal and affluent
customer bases in the world which has
many
analysts betting that the next wave of
phones will sell well
the iphone remains the foundation of
apple's business
apple boasted about the 5g capabilities
and brought in verizon ceo
hans vestberg to champion the carrier's
network
5g is supposed to mean much faster
speeds making it quicker to download
movies or games for instance
but finding those speeds can be a
challenge while telecom operators have
been rolling out 5g networks
significant boosts in speed are still
uncommon in much of the world
including the us the iphone models
unveiled tuesday will launch at
different times
the iphone 12 and 12 pro will be
available starting october 23rd
the mini and the pro max will follow on
november 13th
okay i gotta i gotta ask why would they
not include a charger
they're saying it's more environmentally
friendly jeff but the fact is is that
you gotta buy the charger anyways
yeah it's gonna come in separate
packaging yeah this is why uh
there's a bit of an uproar about this i
think it's a total
price grab and i mean apple
i know right shocking but i mean
apple phones are already any apple
products already crazy expensive as it
is now
yeah um now they're going to make you
pay for a charger sure they are like
this is ridiculous that is supposed to
be commonplace
just like a pair of wired headphones you
say that but there are times jeff when i
think like when i buy
a monitor for my computer yep why do
they throw in a dsub cable
it makes no sense fair enough and that
to me is wasteful sure right
right but you don't charge your monitor
through a dsub cable
right but there will come a time when
they're right
when everyone does have a usbc charger
that's a fast charger
yeah you know but because we all use
usba a lot i
i generalize but a lot of us use wall
warts that have
like a usba which is the you know the
fat thin one that you have to try three
times before you plug it in
that's right yeah um but but there will
come a time when we all have usbc
chargers yes and i know that that's the
that's the goal like they're trying to
transition everybody onto the same
connection yeah
um but still it seems kind of ridiculous
that you'd buy a phone without a charger
like i don't know that's the story
and the other thing is is four different
models of phone
they got you got the pro you got the pro
max you got the mini
the mini is smaller like it's the
same i poke fun it's like the same nuts
and bolts just different size
like essentially like oh well no i make
i mean good for them for for bringing
out
a new product during a pandemic i mean
that's great
yeah it's hard for for companies to
manufacture right now
sure absolutely it is and i mean the
fact that they've they've had
shortage of supply because of factory
shutdown and all that and the fact that
they can roll this out that's great
uh i just he's not a fan boy you can
tell
no i i am very anti-apple all right like
yeah i just i mean if
ugh if i'm like oh where's he going with
this
if i bought an android phone without a
charger i would probably lose it in the
store but if you had an android phone
it's usb a
to probably usbc yeah so you're you're
fine because you have that
yes charger already you're probably but
that's the issue
so we'll just we'll just leave it at
that and head back to becca
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category 5. from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
you