welcome to the category 5 community
coffee break for july
26 2020.
hi everybody hello hello
hi everybody the community coffee break
is our opportunity to just come together
as a community we're a small
crew that come together but if you'd
like to join us it's
uh it's available to the public on our
website category5.tv
just scroll down the home page now a
little uh
mentioned that i am taking vacation time
i haven't got it yet
but uh i intend to um be
absent and that means no coffee break
for the next
two weeks following this one so the next
one will be august
16th so just make a quick note that
uh this will be the final um coffee
break until
august 16th and uh category 5 technology
tv will be off the air for the next two
weeks as well
so summer break isn't it lovely
no so we can't really travel people
can't really travel and i've got
you know people and i can't have people
coming here and i can't be going
elsewhere but my wife does have
her family has a like a family cottage a
little north that we're going to head up
to that just kind of seclude ourselves
in the wilderness
and enjoy some disconnected time
no devices absolutely yeah
so i'm not even taking the phone book
pro
um no i don't think so to be honest
i i think i will take we have a couple
of laptops we call our family laptops
and they're just
old laptops from the e-waste pile that
i've refurbished myself
and and we use those for like
the kids use them for games and stuff so
i think i'll bring one of those for
um uh for watching shows if there's a
rainy day
keep the kids entertained when dad's
making supper that kind of thing so
but otherwise we're pretty much going to
be disconnected like entirely
i don't have a data plan on my cell
phone so
it's like i you know i i have just the
uh
just the calling plan so very nice
it should be very good yeah this year
has been one of those hasn't it bp9
where
you're right about that oh boy
you are so right about that i've never
taken
time off for a vacation really like i
always do like a cottage
uh show or like i've done cottage
specials so you guys may have seen
the family cottage or you know we go
somewhere in the local area which we
can't even do now
like we can't go to a local like uh
silver beach or somewhere like that
and sit down and do a show in front of
an audience so
this year i just decided let's keep it
not complicated
let's actually recover from from the
hellish
first two quarters of 2020
and come back full force because now i
can get the contractor in here
and he's been in here a couple times
already and get some things done
so when i get back all refreshed just
get this place
up and rocking so yeah
yeah yeah your enthusiasm isn't is
[Laughter]
encouraging
oh well we just got news from work that
it doesn't look like we'll be back in
the work building until december
so yeah and even then it's all it's all
speculative like it's it's going to keep
getting bumped back until it's safe and
that's
that's what it comes down to we just got
to stay safe so
and i'm i'm of the mindset like i'm i'm
the kind of person
you may get this from me but i i rather
play it safe and not just when it comes
to
what's going on in our world right now
but it's like i love roller coasters but
i wouldn't go
skydiving it's like right right yeah i
agree
because of that i mean i'm rick i'm a
comedian so i don't have any problems
staying
at home by myself but even even now
i'm i'm starting to get stir crazy now i
just need to
get out like curmudgeon borderline
on the edge of hermet like are we at
that point oh yeah oh yeah
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah oh absolutely
peter you can
you can relate right sounds like me
and you know what i'm i'm i i would
really love to be like that
have that ability to work from home and
and stay home
with my family but i've been the guy
like i've
had no choice but to go into work as an
essential service provider so
um so it hasn't been bad i've got a good
setup i've got
an office with a closed door and you
know so it's been okay that way but
i i still kind of envy those of you who
are able to stay home and work from home
but your services we're essential
services as well
yeah but they um they've allowed you to
work from home right
we have not had that privilege so yeah
i wish i could work from home yeah the
only time i go out is
to go grocery shopping or whatever so oh
sure yeah
um you know and for that you know mask
up and all that good fun stuff
you just do what you got to do right
again just play it safe yeah i've got
this very
fortunate scenario in that if i'm not at
work and i'm not at home i have the
studio
it's a blessing guys like to be able to
come in here and get some work done
and i have actually come in here and
done work from here for my
job which has been you know that's
that's been really really nice i like
that
because peter peter peter
microphone man one of these days one of
these days
[Laughter]
very very warm here you know it's warm
here too but i gotta
i have to wear the shirt otherwise i
just wouldn't have anything to clip my
mic to
at least that wouldn't be painful no no
i would collapse if i
are you you're working in your garage
today so it's warm in the garage is it
very warm yeah do you have a fan do you
have like a just a rotary fan or
something that
no i'm not playing
that really helps just to move the air
around i added one you guys saw i
brought one into the studio here and it
really helped when the ac
wasn't working do you have a placement
peter do you have a basement no garage
okay
okay no no no because i've got a i've
got a basement and if it gets too warm
upstairs i can go downstairs it's 10
degrees
cooler down
because i went and bought a um
a thermometer from amazon that has three
remotes
so it has one for the main display
station
and then three more remote stations that
all
bring a little trick back to the
basement cool
i put one outside because i've always
been curious about what the outside
temperature is compared to the inside
temperature
and i put one downstairs because i've
always noticed it's noticeably colder
down there yeah in the basement than it
is upstairs
and i put one right next to the
thermometer or the thermostat
of the um air conditioner to see what it
really thought that
the temperature was um it's 10 degrees
difference
fahrenheit um downstairs
compared to upstairs cooler downstairs
amazing
it's amazing the difference you have
central air right yes sir i do
yeah so have you looked um i i
i'm a fairly new home owner bp9 like i'm
only
i'm still learning things and and
discovering things
about being a homeowner but on the
ductwork in the basement
sometimes there's like a thing like
there's flaps inside
of their ductwork so you looked at that
to see because i found the same thing so
what i did is i changed the flap
inside there's like a a screw that you
can turn to make it
sure yeah and then that drew more then
push
more air upstairs yeah that shuts the
vents off downstairs
yeah absolutely i can absolutely do that
another thing that i could do would be
to put a door between the
on the stairs that lead downstairs yeah
there
i could see where a door used to hang oh
yeah but uh the door's been
gone since i bought the house many years
ago
um i also have the boiler in the room as
well so that makes it warm as well well
that's certainly
wow yeah for sure yeah over there
you know that direction roughly about
about 10 feet
that was very warm yeah yeah yeah so um
yeah so that's what that's and of course
the temperature and the humidity goes up
and down like crazy outside it's it's
nuts um and it differs quite a bit from
what the uh
the weather guesses so the temperature
in the humanity should be as well
which is always interesting now of
course it depends on what the accuracy
of the
sending devices you know the sensor
device but you know
if it's off by a degree or two it's
still going to be
it's going to give you a good idea oh
it's more than a degree i've i've seen
it register 100 degrees fahrenheit
outside
when the uh the weather um uh the local
weather station
uh which is at the local airport um is
reporting like
85 90 degrees fahrenheit could it be
like in direct sunlight or anything like
that no i
explicitly placed it so it would be in
shape no matter where the sun was
oh yeah so i was careful about doing
that so
yeah i don't know you know it's just a
bit of fun so
but it was i i did notice it was it was
specifically cooler
outside and i mean specifically cooler
downstairs
yes and uh and i did wonder uh why that
why that was or if it truly was and sure
enough it is so
yeah i showed a little usb dongle on
category 5
a while ago like back in old studios
studio d
um called the temper and it's just a
little 20
usb dongle it looks like a flash drive
and you plug it in and it gives you a
temperature
and humidity sensor for your computer
really handy i love those things so i've
got one
i've got a couple in my house on
different floors and
i've got one here at the studio so i can
keep track of the temperature and
humidity here
and and i use that to like to just
monitor the
the temperature make sure that my server
room at home isn't too hot for example
maybe i should get a maybe i should get
a link for that because one of the
things i was curious about doing was
because it's wi-fi it's wireless yeah it
runs on like
433 degrees
yeah something like that i think mine's
on 0.92 but it doesn't matter
in any case who's watching it is
specifically this frequency
if you want to tie it into pp9's
thermometer but the reason why is
because then i
actually tuned my ham radio to the
to that frequency and i could hear the
data bursts yeah and i was thinking
yeah oh yeah absolutely so i was
thinking maybe i could decode those
but if there's already devices that can
do that then
a good one and my one is on the uh was
on the input of the local
uhf repeater it doesn't call them in
defense because it's too far away but
it's on the input to the
local ufs with beta
yeah i'm trying to i'm pretty sure uh
for 433 megahertz is actually inside the
ham radio band isn't it
yeah it did yeah yeah it did interesting
okay i did not realize
i suspected it was and i meant to look
it up and it's been a while since i've
been on the air
so i needed to by the way
oh very nice very good unfortunately my
antenna is down on the ground because um
i've had a whole bunch of trees taken
down
in the in the backyard because while i'm
home why not right so yeah
i had a tree come down and and uh
in the backyard and i had to get that
cleaned up and i took the opportunity to
tear down uh
to have a couple of more trees taken
down as well
you go and i get what dinner what
antenna you go
oh it's just a dipole peter okay okay
just a dipole just a dipole it's nothing
special it's not it's not a big old
directional antenna or a yagi or
anything like that
it's just a plain old dipole and i i was
talking to california from
from my location and uh they said how
many
uh you know what sort of power you're
running just 100 watts just running
barefoot
i said oh my god well done good job yeah
well done
because you know they're used to people
firing up what they call linear
amplifiers
to get them up to a kilowatt or or
1300 watts or something wow no i'm happy
to run at 100 watts
what's the maximum you can do in ireland
in england yeah that's it what
wow okay thank you you'd still need an
amplifier for that though because uh
you know your your radio won't go oh god
my radio goes up 160 bucks okay turn the
drive down and uh and then i could draw
an amplifier but
uh the problem is all the other people
scandinavians the germans the french
and and white power and it gets a bit
dicey up from nature sometimes
you know yeah it is what it is do you
deal with that kind of interference from
other transmitters is that what you
you have to deal with
it's called qrm uh man-made interference
as opposed to qr in november which is
natural interference
okay uh okay so introductions we've got
peter at the top left
we've got doug in the top right hi guys
pp9 at the bottom left
i do see marshman trying to enter and
marshman
can't hear you if you've got a mic going
but i saw you light up
i saw you light up when peter was making
less noise
so yes peter hasn't figured out
and we've got rd blair is the black box
at the bottom right trying to join us as
well so
if those guys are able to join that's
cool um doug have you been doing
anything
um over the past couple of weeks that's
uh like technologically
you know fun that you're enjoying um
not really i work 40 hours a week i
don't have much time for tech
i use tech at work every day yeah but i
print pictures
and i make signs for the store using
[ __ ]
yeah okay cool that's the technology
i've been involved in
yeah so you're doing graphic design to
some degree
like are you talking like eight and a
half by eleven prints are you doing
larger scale stuff oh i've i've made
banners that were
five feet yeah they wanted a picture
um made for the top of
a bunker if you know what a bunker is in
uh
retail it's those uh freezers or
refrigerators that are in the middle of
the floor
oh yes yeah it's you know that you put
stuff into their open top
yeah those are we call those bunkers all
right and uh
they wanted a sign made for one end of a
bunker and it was
50 some inches wide or 60 inches wide
so i had to print that on a six foot
banner and then cut it down
wow so when you when you laid that out
did you just plan it out
to fit on a certain number of pieces of
paper
or is it well or do you have like a
large scale plotter type printer
we have a wide format printer an epson
i can print up to an eight foot banner
wow
cool we print two by six and two by
eight foot banners
i'm not sure that i mean um uh robbie
you specifically asked about a plotter
and when
when i think of a plotter i think of a
literally a pin
being held by a by a device that runs on
maybe it's
yeah i don't think you can even get
plotters anymore i don't know they're
even used anymore
i haven't heard anything about a plotter
in decades
now you know the last time i printed big
stuff
yeah we've got a wide format printer
with nine colors in it
and it's got printheads so are they
inkjet now
yeah yes this is an inkjet printer
and i'll bet you can probably print to
it wirelessly
um ours is cabled yeah
our whole lab our entire lab is cabled
yeah yeah it should be yeah when i think
about printing large-scale stuff i'm i'm
thinking about how we used to print like
blueprints and stuff like that
that's what you'd use a plotter for yeah
yeah so that's
that's the last time i ever used a big
that's all square line drawings we're
using
a an epson 7890 wide format printer
takes paper that's two feet wide and can
print banners uh
two foot by six foot or two foot by
eight foot we can also print
by 24x36 posters the largest poster we
print
that's cool we had we had one of those
uh
three jobs ago um and it's all inkjet
none of it was uh none of it was was
paper
none of it was pen based plotter it was
all inkjet right very nice though
that reminds me thinking about inkjet do
you guys remember
years and years and years ago
hillary rumble was on the show and her
and i
demonstrated the uh
epson eco tank printer yes
we've been using that at the studio ever
since that day
so that became our main printer
i just ran out of ink last week did it
really wow
just last week and very first time for
the very first time since then
so that was just her birthday wasn't it
uh yeah yeah it was
so i dug through the boxes because i
knew
i knew when they sent us that printer to
review they also
included a refill kit but i never opened
it
because it was like it just kept going
and going and going and
you can see with the eco tank you can
see the levels of the ink on the side
and it's like still
half full and so inevitably we did run
everything
last week unreal that it lasted that
long i've been
i've been thinking about whether i
should get one of those but i have a
laser printer and i
love that oh yeah it's an ipad
it's an old hp laser printer laserjet 5.
i've got a duplexer on it color or
grayscale it's great it's it's black and
white
not even gray scale it's black and white
oh wow okay
i would love a laser printer because i
tend to dry out
cartridges and heads so on on that epson
eco tank because i
never printed it
so i want to i need to flush the heads
out i can beat you there i have an old
hp
disc jet 500 yeah
which is a really really old-timey black
and white
uh inkjet printer i haven't used it in
literally years
and so the printheads have just dried up
yeah
see i'd love to have a laser for that
reason but i don't want to bring a laser
into the studio because
if we ever tripped a breaker
if that fuser ever heated up and and we
tripped a breaker then i'd be in big
trouble
so so that's why i want to stick with
the eco tank so
looks like we've got marshman at the
bottom middle and
rd blair at the bottom right have
finally been able to join us hey guys
let's see if we can hear
the hey hey marshman rd blair
is your mic working this week can i call
you wilson
he needs a little piece of fence to hold
up in front of it that's right
that's right yep because all we can see
is just the top of his eyebrows yeah
so why not make sure he's much working
yeah it doesn't seem to be but
we can see the top of your head anyways
so good to see you
um remember how a couple weeks ago i had
this issue
because we shoot with multiple cameras
so when jeff was here we had
three cameras plus the audio recorder so
that's four
sd cards and so i had to
take an sd card out of camera a plug it
into the computer
copy a 33 gig file to the hard drive
then unplug that plug in the next one
from the b camera copy a 60 gig file
like these are 4k video files for an
hour and a half right so
huge file so i'm waiting and waiting
waiting it took like four hours to copy
all the files in so that i could start
editing
and i said i wish i could find a uh
like a usb card reader or something that
you could plug multiple sd cards into
found one and um turns out it does exist
that has
four readers in it it's you usbc so good
and fast
uh usb 3.1 um but it was about 120 bucks
yeah so i thought hmm let's just see so
anyways needless to say i said 120 bucks
is too much and instead
what i did is i got um a usb
4 port hub usb 3.1
with usb c which will plug directly into
the motherboard
and then four um sd card readers
just usb sticks so you see that i don't
know if you guys can
really see that so it's just a usb hub
oh we see it's full lights just sort of
sticking out the top
so it's it's just four usb um
usb 3.0 card readers plugged into a usb
3.1 usb c hub okay so
so i should be able to get full speed
out of these at usb 3 speeds
each one same time all at the same time
wow
um with like some bandwidth sharing of
course because
3.1 but 3.1 is what like 10 gigabits a
second or something like that
if i recall correctly so it's it's
ridiculous so what i should be able to
do is take each camera card plug it in
so all three cameras plus this sound
board
which is like wave files from the from
our microphones the iso recorder
and be able to edit directly through
this
so i'll be able to import the files
directly into davinci resolve
without having to copy them to the hard
drive and that's why you need the
clapboard
now i get it because you have to sync up
all four of those separate
files individually exactly yeah wow so
the clapboard gives me
what it does is you look at the
wavetable no
sorry peter
waveform you look at the waveform i'm
i'm an old old-school dj so i still say
wave table
because that was a synthesis that we
used to use
and probably still do um
yeah so you look at the waveform you
look at the waveform and
as soon as that clapboard hits you see a
big spike it's like a high heat
just go like that so then you just line
up those spikes and boom you're done it
just saves you so much work so
that's gonna save probably on
an average show night so on a wednesday
night that's gonna save about
two hours worth of waiting right there
and i can just get straight from record
into editing
right in one fell swoop just plug them
in and be ready to go
so i mean two hours is a perfect perfect
time for you to go get something to eat
while you're waiting on uh
while you're waiting for the files to
come no i don't i don't even have to
copy them anymore
i'll be able to edit them directly on
those drives they're fast enough
so so needless to say so the difference
in price to the four
unit um this was like 14 bucks for the
hub
and eight bucks per sd card reader
so you know you do the math i didn't do
the math it's a lot less than 120 bucks
so so i have a question
i have a rotating hard drive still in my
main machine
yeah and it i feel like the machine is
running slower
because the hard drive might be old and
and getting decrepit or whatever i may
have asked this before
replacing it with an ssd is certainly
doable i have no problem doing that
question is do you think the reliability
the reliability of the ssd
is going to be as good as uh spinning
drive
these days now we have as we general
read write all that mess right yeah yeah
um
so first thing that i would look at bp9
is how much ram how much ram is in that
system
uh i want to say a gig okay so just keep
in mind
anytime you start swapping that's going
to be using the drive so that will
definitely slow things down
i don't i don't believe it's i don't
believe that any of the work that i've
done is
has has caused it to swap out okay so
ssd yeah when ssds first came out we had
a concern about the read writes
um like killing the life
lifetime of these things and failing
right right
these days i don't think that's an issue
i mean really realistically the the
technology has grown so much
and becomes so stable that
you're not you're not going to have any
more trouble with an ssd
a decent ssd than you would with a
standard spinner
i have eight gig in the machine yeah uh
it looks like
about uh two and a half gig is committed
right now
and zero swap at the moment perfect
that's not swapping at all yeah so yeah
i deliberately put
enough memory in it to make sure it
didn't swap unless
there is swap space in case it needs it
but i honestly it just hasn't uh hasn't
had to use it
so um what i would stay away from is
like like sd card storage
is agreed i find that even with the
raspberry pi
sure yeah um emmc is an
uh is a step in the right direction
ssd is now taking it to the next level
and is very very very reliable
especially if you get into data center
storage so like the
dc 400s dc 500s from kingston um those
are
really like they are meant to be always
on always reading always writing
and they can handle any kind of abuse
you throw at them
and then things like m.2s
um nvme drives are very very reliable
now
i have had one nvme drive fail on me
but they fail in an interesting way i
mean they can
sometimes they can just fail like their
ssd right you want to have a backup
it's not like a spinner where you can
replace the heads and be
able to copy your files off when mine
failed i was able to
get the data off of it but you can't
but i couldn't use it to boot from like
it was just it was corrupted in some
strange way
that's the biggest concern i have about
ssds is that they failed
catastrophically
that's always it's so funny you're done
right whereas uh at least with a with
as you say with a spinning drive there's
some chance you could get the data off
it
correct yeah so backups
absolutely and so for people people like
us who are wise to the fact that you
have to have
good reliable backups at all times um
never have your data in one place at a
time
it's always going to be two three places
at any given time
so i have a question so you're fine go
ahead yeah go ahead doug
um i have well the laptop that i'm doing
this on right now
i've had for almost 10 years and it's
spent most of its life being on 24
7. that damage an ssd under those
conditions
it's the reads and writes the constant
reads
um right i think you're probably gonna
theoretically and technically an ssd
should should live longer in that
scenario because it's not
it doesn't have any moving mechanisms so
when it's idle
it's doing nothing yep it's doing
literally nothing
so the only time that the ssd is
actually being is doing anything is when
it's reading or writing
versus your spinner which is spinning
presumably all the time unless you have
it
for what it's worth doug i've had an ssd
in my laptop
for probably two two years or so
granted it is it is not running 24 7.
my main machine is but my laptop is not
um and i've pretty much switched to the
pine book pro
for development now although i have
found that uh the
microsoft visual code does not run so
good
on the um on the pine book pro it is not
a graphics issue
it is a it is an implementation issue
it just there are there are plugins and
and
extensions and stuff that are just not
uh
doesn't want to go and not and not
developed for the arm
architecture and i found that i found
that with powershell as well
like they're it's really really
difficult to get it
reliable unarmed and that's microsoft's
fault
that's not anything to do with the pine
book yeah so i've been i've been using
vi
as my sure primary is my primary uh you
know
development environment as silly as it
is do you want to know my solution
not good no i have i have a
a windows machine that i have google
remote desktop setup
and so i don't do remote desktop well
google remote desktop is different than
remote desktop it's not rdp protocol
and it uses two-factor authentication in
order to gain access to the device so
it's it's safe so i actually have
multi-factor authentication
i have to log into my google account
then i have to
go to remote desktop and um i have to
enter
the two well no i have to factor
authenticate my google
account then i go to remote desktop
google remote desktop which is remote
desktop.google.com
and click on the computer and then it
asks me for the pin for the computer so
there's three factors
in order to gain access to the computer
itself then
once i connect to the computer i have to
also log in as the user
on the local machine so for four factors
to get in so unlike rdp which is
extremely insecure
okay so i understand that never use rdp
um well i i know that you'd like to use
the pinewood pro
effectively as a terminal to remove this
back into other machines
me i use it primarily as a development
machine sure i do my development
work on the machine and comply i do as
well
well i don't technically i ssh to my
server
and i do the development there because
myself you're just remote desktoping
yeah well yeah you're going to work on
the server not on the actual
laptop itself and the reason for that is
the server has all the files all the
data i'm i'm very much of the mindset
that my laptop should never have any of
my stuff
period okay so that's me because
that's what it's for
yeah i do that i've got my github
account and i
clone my my git repositories and i work
directly on the lap
on the pine book pro the roku channel
work that i've been doing is directly on
the pine book pro it's sitting on my
desktop
but i do have it syncing up to github as
well so
yeah oh why are we out of time guys
wow it's so much fun just to sit down
and
this is this has been fun because it
kind of feels like we're just happy
dad please
oh boy marshman real quick what have you
been up to dude
working working working working working
yeah
yeah workers back in full swing i've
been in new york city every day this
week
ah yes you've been competing in every
day
i've been driving in yeah oh boy oh wow
so wow and long days long long days
i'm
yeah yeah two hours each way and i've
been thanks
my teammate out on long island's been
out so i've been going out
out to queens and long island too
so i'm just i'm just knackered yeah you
gotta hurt
yeah well hey i hope you get some good
rest man
that's i got my pill yeah there you go
yeah i'm about to get some good rest
as you guys know i'll be disconnected so
so are things are things well with work
like are you right back to the grind or
are things you're finding they're really
different
it's funny because i mean even though
i'm i'm doing a lot of work
many many people are still not in their
offices i noticed your pine book pro
uh impact on your finger there just for
a second
this is why i warn you guys be careful
it's sharp edges
i was thinking you tried to take the
bottom
yeah okay and i slid my fingers across
and i said oh
that didn't know do you remember when i
said
be careful guys be careful it's sharp
sorry i didn't mean interrupt i just
noticed that when you held your
finger yeah but i've had that cover off
so many times
yeah but this time you i just felt it i
said to razor
it's like paper cuts man i mean same
thing you don't know until
until it's done it doesn't hurt until
it's done yeah and then you just look at
it
okay and then
super glue gotta wear gloves when you're
working on a pine book pro huh
oh yeah or just no you just gotta know
yeah
yeah so so with work it's how are things
changed
for you in new york uh not not much
not really all that much uh you know
right now they're
it's more of um trying to get the their
equip the customer's equipment set up
so when the people do come back to work
they're ready
you know everything's been sitting
around like i posted a picture yesterday
or or friday um where i i installed the
new printer
and uh it's still decorated for
saint patty's day
wow i mean that's sad but like wow
yeah yeah yeah cause their last day in
the office was march 12th so
yeah yeah so suddenly too
yeah plotters still exist they they do
exist out thanks bill
many of them are ink jets but they still
call them plotters
yeah in fact i was i i had to move on
out of the way the other day it's like
it's like eight feet long it was a
massive massive
man if you could shuffle that thing onto
a truck and
and send it down my direction you know
i'd appreciate that you know
i could do that i could just get rid of
it
hey man there you go email me man is
your is your plane
is your plane in the air bp9 can you go
pick it up
it is yeah i could i could fly up to new
york absolutely i could
get it yeah no problem i don't know
just put it on the passenger seat yeah
yeah eight feet long let me show you oh
that could be interesting yeah
i think it's massive it's one of the
best wow i'm not surprised
so they still call them plotters it's
like when i say we're recording this
we're taping this we're taking this for
you guys yes yeah
even though it's not a pen and paper
plotter it still acts like one
well the the save button on windows is
still a floppy disk
yeah true true yeah i got in big trouble
on the last show
um in on youtube i don't know if you
guys caught for calling
um uh acrylic plexiglas
i
[Music]
it's not the same thing it's a brand and
i'm like
let me get you a kleenex to wipe your
brow yeah
exactly well the best one was i saw
it was the final final round of uh
was that wheel of fortune and they said
it was a thing
and the answer was xerox
you're just not a thing no it's a person
yeah and even if
if it would be a thing right but i would
say xerox could be
a verb because people do say i'm going
to xerox something
right or well just as good as a xerox
we know just like photographically it's
not technically correct yes
xerox they they use it as a verb but
that is incorrect it is a brand name
right right just like clean x you said
yeah kleenex yeah uh what was jacuzzi
is another one that i cited yeah oh yeah
there's your band-aids yeah and so is
kleenex
is a big one i mean how many people use
that synonymously with facial tissue
facial tissue that's ubiquitous for
facial tissues
exactly right yeah right right
how many how many copyright
infringements have we just done
just in the last five minutes
[Laughter]
that's all right robbie you're going on
vacation you can worry about it when you
get back
yeah you know i'll let my lawyers handle
it
yeah i i have the cop out that it's not
my industry
look man i said i don't i don't i don't
deal
in plexiglas or acrylic so
like for me to say it it's it's just
using the vernacular
now for somebody who is in sales like
you couldn't sell someone
an epson printer and say it's a xerox
right
you just that's that but that's because
you're in the industry
i'm not in that industry so if i say i'm
going to xerox something it means i'm
photocopying it
right yeah so by the way
i agree with i agree with oh
[Music]
oh
so it turns out you have something you
can clip your your mic too
thank you
i love you guys have a wonderful couple
of weeks and i will see you when i'm
back from vacation so
august 16th august 16th is going to be
my first time back
those of you who are patrons kickstarter
supporters i will be
checking in i will be here at the studio
doing construction and doing some
various things to get things set up for
our relaunch on august uh 12th
uh is the first show back so um so
check in on on those platforms as well
so
nice to see you guys take it easy