a new feature in google assistant on
your android phone
is blowing my mind and has already
proved itself
to be very very useful see i don't use
my google assistant
neither do i i'm interested to see what
this is i don't use it normally however
we've all got it on our android phone
and this feature is available to you now
similar features are available in apps
and have been
has been available for quite some time
however they've really nailed it
as far as the quality and the ability to
use this service
it's called what's that song
what's this song oh so it's like was it
shazam
years ago yeah but this really
really works so should we try it sure
what's this song
[Music]
it can be that bad do do
so you can hum it
oh my goodness
and it actually works and i've used it
i've i've held it up to my computer
speaker when there was a video playing
and and i it just had like a really cool
backing track or something
and it gave me the song so where does it
pull the repository of information from
google i'm wondering
could you train google to recognize the
cat5 theme song
oh well let's work on that i think you
should
it it works really really well all you
have to do is just ask assistant
what's this song you can play something
to the microphone from a speaker
you can hum it you can hold it up to a
radio
whatever it takes somebody on
on twitter was saying i can't remember
who sings such and such a song
and so i sang it into it just the hook
yep and really really miserably and it
sure enough gave me the
the original singer and gives you the
the cover art and everything
wow how amazing is that and
i wasn't even good enough to breach
copyright there
but yet google recognized what the song
was
right yes it did how cool is that very
very very useful
especially when you hear a song on the
radio in the dj because djs are the
worst
jeff you ever notice that djs never tell
you the name of the song i
always said the name of the song hey i
was listening and
all right a psa no i always mention the
song
never i i always did
because it drove me nuts to not know the
song yes but now the dj
is out of a job because i can just ask
google assistant
how cool a reminder that you can support
us on patreon at patreon.comcategory5
great way to support the content that we
create we give it away for free
but if you've got means to support that
free content
it means the world to us and it allows
us it gives us
the resources that we need in order to
keep this thing going and get stronger
and stronger every week so we appreciate
and thank you very much for your support
have a great week everybody see ya bye
[Music]
[Applause]
do
[Music]
you