covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
microsoft is warning that customers who
install the optional kb4577062 update
for windows 10 versions
1903 and 1909 will encounter issues
upgrading the newer
to newer windows 10 versions on some
devices
as microsoft says after installing the
optional update
users will receive compatibility
warnings when trying to update the os to
newer versions
if http internet access for local system
accounts
is blocked using a firewall while
microsoft doesn't mention that the
compatibility issues also affect
newer windows 10 releases users have
also seen this warning when trying to
upgrade to windows 10 version 2004
microsoft says that it is currently
working to address this issue with a fix
to be available in an upcoming windows
10 release
until then the company advises customers
if your device has access to http
blocked for local system accounts
to mitigate this issue you can enable
http access for the windows 10 setup
dynamic update do you
using the local system account after you
have allowed access you can restart the
installation of the debate
update and you should not see the
warning
kb4577062 was released last month
with the main highlight being that it
enables an internet explorer 11
notification
to inform users about adobe's flat adobe
flash's end of support
coming this december big thanks to roy w
nash and our community of viewers for
submitting stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from 5 tv newsroom
i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you