[Music]
greetings welcome to
uh community coffee break uh i'm bp nine
and uh over on the left there is uh or
over on that left
is uh issaboo give us a wave sobu and
what you see
and there's another there's peter but
below us but he's not at his chair right
now
doug was trying to get in a while ago
and uh and he's um
having audio issues so hopefully he'll
be able to come in and say hello
real quick as well here's peter all
right then so
um a couple of things uh if you watched
last week's coffee break
i was trying to figure out
how to do encrypted communications
and i was having some having some fun
with that um
and so what i i'm using gcrypt is
is the library that i'm using and what
i've figured out
i believe is that i need two public
private key sets i need one for the
server
and and i need one for
um one for the client
so the server has a public private key
and the client has a public private key
and the idea there
is that the um
[Music]
is you always encrypt
i believe with the public key and you
decrypt with the private key and so the
whole point of this is to figure out
is so the server can figure out without
any question who
the client is the identity of the client
ssl won't do this ssl at least to my
knowledge
ssl will encrypt the communications but
i don't think you can use that
to uh uh to verify who the person is
now sober if you know anything about
that i'd be happy to
to chat about that with you yeah and uh
ssl
is not a thing to use um
traffic just fine but it doesn't very
very um yeah that was my thought as well
from
everything i could read about ssl versus
public private key encryption
your background's bleeding through there
so yeah
[Laughter]
you're transporting away somewhere is
what's going on
so yeah i've also had i've been working
on a project that requires a raspberry
pi to be on the internet all the time
and uh one of the things that uh that i
arranged with my um uh with my
internet provider is to get a static ip
address well they gave me a block of
five of them
which was very nice of them because i
want to put this raspberry pi
on the internet but i do not want it to
have any access to
my internal network so the quickest way
that i could think to do that was to
put up another router plug it up onto my
internet modem
and give it the second address a second
static address in the range
it just comes up on the internet now and
then it just
it just works so um i
so the raspberry pi is on the internet
but it doesn't
uh uh it does not have any access to my
internal network
which is a quick and easy way to do it
not everybody has the luxury of being
able to say i want a static ip address
please
but um i i was able to do that and that
worked out really well for me
yeah um
i think yeah i have a static ip and i'm
i'm
paying for it oh yeah oh yeah this is
not free
this is not free but you know it works
um have you ever seen i don't know if
dells
are the only machines that do this but i
had a reason to
spin up windows 10 on my
main machine again and
yeah i know i know it came with the
machine
on its own uh hard drive
so so i
i was looking at the possibility of dual
booting linux and windows 10
but windows 10 has like half a dozen
partitions
and the main partitions in the middle of
the block so it's kind of crazy
because you you try to uh make the
connection work and it doesn't
always it doesn't i decided not to do it
that way anyway it turns out that when
the dell machine cranks up
when it goes through post there's a pf
key 12 that you can use
to um to select which hard drive you
want to boot off
and you get your boot facility without
having to
install linux and windows on the same
hard drive
so that worked out really well so now i
have two hard drives spinning up
in the in the main machine and i get to
pick which one i want linux or windows
10 and it works
by default it'll pick window uh by
default it'll pick linux
21 years ago i did the dual booting um
and my experience is that i know it's
changed
in the last 20 years but still um
i have bad experience in the dual
booting so my recommendation
for those who is able to do it is
if you want to have the two systems in
the same
system have them on a separate physical
hard drive
to separate them so
and that's exactly what i did but i
don't know if
every machine is able to select which
hard drive to boot on
when it starts up i found i figured out
the dell can do it but i don't know if
that's specific to dell or if
any machine can do that it's got to be
something built in the bios right
yeah drill biting has nothing to do with
the bios
the reason that people often have to go
to into the bios these days is to
turn off as a security in order to build
something else than their
windows or ubuntu who have
their have assigned
kernel drivers and yeah
well when i um when i start up the
when i power up the main machine um it
gives me the option during the post
cycle um
to press a function key to make
um uh to make it select
to pick which boot drive i want to come
up on
and that's where where it picks um
where i get to pick either the hard
drive that has windows 10 on it
or the hard drive that has linux on it
by default it'll it'll boot up on linux
if i don't
make a selection so that works really
well
so doug can you hear me yes i can hear
you now
can you hear me we hear you as well yes
sir
we hear you loud and clear okay good job
don't know what was wrong with my
headset
nice yeah
good so yeah we hear you loud and clear
all right so boo um what have you been
up to this now since two weeks because
we didn't see it last week
yeah since since uh last week i have
been
assigned a maintenance duty on on the
on voyage so
i found out today that um
before every coffee break and i checked
to see if
the zoom client is is in the new version
and or if the turbo is changed and if it
is i don't know then
use the new one and the new one for
linux
is a five point uh something it's an
upgrade the
major upgrade from the three point that
was available for the last
half year so now i can as you see i can
have a virtual background
so um the lights are seems to be
flickering a little bit but uh
yeah so no i've been in the whole yeah
we get that
good but what what are you apart from uh
being the technical officer on um on
voyager
what else have you been doing um
no nothing much i have
today i was i was a sound engineer
at the church service
but otherwise i'm home doing
stuff on the computer maintaining
servers
around the country so
yeah well i wanted to thank you for your
um yeah i wanted to thank you for your
help
on figuring out the resolve.conf
the problem is that
it turned out in your case it was the
network manager who
who changed it um
on each time the dhcp sensor
something so you need to tell the
network
manager to do not touch their config
file
and that there is all conf and then you
have to um
to be sure uh install a package called
resolve conf with no dot
um because then you also install um
various uh hacks and changes that uh
disables
all known um
in the guide i wrote it said that in all
the
dhcp clients and then told them to
if they need to change the config file
send it to the
diamond that you just installed and then
you tell the doctor
to not do anything so okay
okay so what that what that means to me
is that from now on even if i connect to
a
wireless network or something like that
um
i just gotta uh mute you there
i can figure out how to do that up there
it is okay
um what happened
there was um if i ever connect to a
network that's not my home network
then um i have to manually fix
resolve.conf because
from all the reading that i could do it
sounded like
the network manager it dynamically
changes that resolve.com depending on
what network you plug into
and normally that would be fine except
that the
ip address the 127.0.0.53
which is not the loopback address by the
way because the loopback address is
27.0.0.1
but the local dns address
127.0.0.53
seems to be the local address for the
network manager and then it just figures
out what to do from there
but whenever i fire up net about to say
netscape that was
those were the days weren't they yeah uh
whenever i fire up firefox
uh it just um it always
introduces a delay whenever that was uh
whenever the my 27.0.0.53
is going on um do you have any idea why
that delay because i can't imagine
why it should delay i would imagine it
would just
immediately switch to whatever the um uh
name server that was given um to
to it under dhcp i don't know
i think it asks that there is a local
demon
name names and and
it checks uh the outside service
um and uh just uh by the way the in in
the
the um the entire one two one two seven
dot
class is is localized the the entire so
you can
if you have a one two seven dot two five
or five dot sixty one
it will it will even
well i just thought that i just thought
that that was uh i just thought
127.0.0.1 was localhost
um
okay okay well thank you for that
that's that's much appreciated uh so
those are the three things i've been
working on the
dual boot the static ip address and and
the encrypt and decrypt process
which uh uh oh we've lost uh selby
no
you must be switching yeah you must be
switching uh cameras or something so
okay oh
on the left i see okay
okay okay well you've changed your
position in the grid now i have to do
all the introductions all over again now
who's the new guy all right doug joe
who's the new guy well you said you'd
have to do introductions all over again
yeah it's me uh yeah it seems that
so yeah that's always that's always been
the case whenever you
whenever you lose a um a video feed
uh when it comes back it always goes to
the end of the list
so yep and somehow i've zoomed in i
don't know why but
okay it works it's okay
i didn't do that on purpose when you
mess with the video feed so i'll do it
just
made me zoom in i don't know why so all
my
all my all my ugliness comes through now
yeah so doug what have you been up to
sir
not much technically uh just working
i work in the photo lab at walmart so i
use technology every day
but i don't not doing any personal
technical stuff right now
okay okay so i
i have a whole slew of 35 millimeter
films that i've been taking to to
walmart to get them converted to
cd-rom is that still is that still
doable
yeah the films have already been
processed
we do it through a company called yes
video which is in california i believe
or no georgia they're in georgia
and um okay they will put it on dvd for
you
or cd yes
this video you called it yes video
although as i said okay so all the
um all i mean i could bring it into any
walmart right that has a photo
um a a photo processing center
and they'll do it on my behalf they've
been doing it until now but
i stopped when the when the photo
processing lab disappeared on me
so um they i think they closed it down
but i'm not sure
so maybe they don't want it i couldn't
find it
you know walmart yes sir yes sir
that is correct well um
you can do this one or two ways either
go to a key ask it at walmart
and you can do it through the kiosk or
you can go online to yesvideo.com
and do it there but either way you're
going to get a printout
that uh if you do it online
uh at home take the printout with you to
the walmart
hand it to the person behind the counter
and then they can send off your
stuff to be transferred to dvd okay
okay i have a whole slew of them that
i've gotten about halfway through them
and i haven't uh i haven't finished them
and then you know robbie and i talked
about this ages ago
we um we loaded the uh
uh we talked about various nasa's
um uh synology versus
qnap i believe is the other one one of
the reasons i like the synology box is
because it has this application
called moments and what moments will do
without any prompting from
from you is it will categorize photos
into subjects events
um uh uh people if
if it finds faces in the photo
it will ask you just to to identify who
that is
and then any other photos where that
face shows up
that photo gets that gets tagged with
that person's name
so what does this box do
the synology box is a network storage
device
network attached storage but it does a
whole lot more than just that
right qnap also is a is a nas
but the synology um has a whole bunch of
applications that come with it
and one of those is an application
called moments
it's all local storage you're not
you're not putting anything on the net
and it's not having to go
to the internet to perform this function
for that reason it takes a while but
it's all done locally to my
understanding
so that's that to me is what sold it for
me it does not go off
it does not go off to to the internet to
go and do its thing so i was very
very pleased about that um
so yeah i was when you said you worked
for walmart i was curious to see if um
if that if that function was still if it
was still possible to
do that with with my photos all right
i'll go back
depending on how many you have there is
also a uh
scanner you can buy online that will
scan
film i tried that
very manual very very uh
time intensive i just don't have the
time for the patients
to do that you actually get better
quality
photos when you do that because that
scan i have one
um it's called if i recall correctly
it's called a maverick scanner
but you have to mount each of the 35
millimeter negatives
into a plastic frame and then feed that
plastic frame
through the uh the maverick machine
manually
okay it's it's a royal pain it really is
it's
uh it takes a lot of time to do i'd i'd
be more than happy to pay someone else
to do that for me
i can understand that when we scanned
negatives at the store we used to have a
motorized scanner you'd feed it into a
track
and then hit a button and it would go to
the first frame
you'd hit uh a button and it would
capture it
no and then hit a button it would move
to the next frame and then capture that
nice nice yeah it was it was easy
it's no longer done locally though is
that true
correct not in our store anyways right
right right
right all right well i'll go back in
there there's a couple of walmarts near
me that i can
that i can check and i can see if
they'll still do it for me
and if so i literally have a bag full of
negatives
a shopping bag yeah i'm not going to do
them all at once
i i haven't done that before what i do
is is i'll
take in maybe two or three rolls at a
time um
and and take them in that way
uh but then what i get back on the cd
is a whole jumble of pictures they're
not sorted they're not
they're not separated out in any way
shape or form
and you have to manually do all that now
all of my films have a little sticker on
them from when they were processed which
have a unique number on them
so it's perfect i can just sequence by
um by that film number and then by
exposure and it just it just works
really well for me
if you go to yes video take your
i don't know how you have them arranged
but if they're in a
shopping bag i would sort them first
into a box or something and then
write the title on the box okay
or a number number one number two number
three okay
and that's the way that's the way they
will process them
okay each of the uh
negatives uh have been cut into into
four
exposure strips that's right that's
right and they go into
like a plastic sleeve and they're still
in that plastic sleeve so
i actually send them off in that plastic
sleeve
okay and then they're just afraid that
if
if they're in a shopping bag they're
getting crinkled and wrinkled and
i understand they're in the plastic
sleeve
which is in turn in the paper envelope
that the pictures came in
when they were processed when the prints
came back in the first time
now that should help protect the
integrity
yeah and those cardboard those cardboard
sleeves are what are in the plastic bag
okay good so i don't i i have not seen
any degradation of those negatives
in all that time but i've had them that
way um and i'm well aware that
i don't want them to you know to be
touching the plastic bag at all so
no static electricity wouldn't do it to
me
there's only one film that i think had
some junk on it had some
some sort of fungus on it or so and i'm
afraid to touch it because i'm afraid
i'll
if i try and clean it off i'm afraid
i'll clean off the uh
the emulsion right off yeah right off
the field so i don't want to i don't
want to touch it i'm leaving it alone
so i may have lost that one and
if that's true that's only one out of
many yeah i'm not real sure what could
be done for that
[Music]
with the photograph we can always
restore it but
right i don't know what you could do to
restore a negative
um you could try talking to
yes video see if they have a restoration
service
right i know fuji will restore photos i
don't know about negatives
[Music]
okay peter
your your audio is uh is a bit low
um so you want to say again what it was
you were
just saying we only have a few minutes
uh to go so
people try moving them i can't i can't
hear
much better there you are
you've gone quiet again peter you've
gone quiet again
good now don't mess with it now leave it
alone
he's done it again he's messed with it
and he's gone quiet again
i don't know what's going on peter but
we hear the very first part of your
audio and then it just
fades away i
that he can hear us we can't hear him
but when he moves the headphones so that
he can hear him he can't hear us so
maybe you need a new headset
he's still trying keep trying peter move
that microphone up to your mouth so we
can hear you
now yeah yeah
[Music]
we're getting a lot of wrestling
oh wow let me know yeah yeah yeah
one of my own styles of 95
and uh yeah yeah i went to the judge
[Music]
uh
i remember that quite well did you go
all the way to london for the funeral
peter
no
microphone up to your mouth there peter
this is not gonna work too well quit
messing with it
he's done it happened again yeah
yeah yeah yeah
and uh relations are there that i
haven't seen for a very long time
you know like 50 years or 60 years i
think
a couple of them anyway yeah when i was
a kid i i could really remember a couple
of them
you know that's that but uh other things
i've sorted out the
the problem with the airplane uh problem
i had
which i managed to figure out in the end
uh
because i i wasn't complaining that the
i think for four years they they publish
the book and uh
remind me remind me peter what that
hairpin was for and
we've only got a couple more minutes so
we can't uh keep it up for much longer
so
what
oh the matching device for the antenna
the antenna
yeah okay
um won the university
[Music]
and they even once they are at
uh
[Music]
and what conditions you need to make it
work but the conditions are
it's not very anybody used anyway you
know
um you know but anyway um
we can't peter i'm going to have to stop
you there
we're we're up to 30 minutes um any
got any really quick uh end of uh
end of uh uh meeting comments there or
yeah i just have a little uh anecdote
and peter was
uh talking it has to be very quick so
and one of you he said that one of his
aunts
is uh 99 years old
one of the uh
fighters in the second world war he was
in their norwegian
[Applause]
resistance um um
ten years ago or so he turned 103
and he eventually became an informant
when he was uh
103 he was asked
the biggest news news station uh visited
and he interviewed him and asked him if
he had that and he wishes for his
birthday
then he smiled and he said that he
wished he was 90 years old he was
much stronger and much more fit than
yeah all right i i need to i need to
close it out folks
so i need to
sorry peter i'm going to go ahead and
close this out i wanted to say thank you
to everybody for um for helping out
there
and for uh hope you all enjoyed the
coffee break
this is the beginning of season two so
uh
i'm gonna do my best not to mess up the
uh not to mess up the new season so
thank you all
for your help and uh for coming in and
joining in and having some fun with me
and we'll do it again next week and see
you next week for now thanks very much
bye-bye