covering the week's top tech stores
with a slight linux bias curious if an
electric car will save you money on fuel
costs
a report in canada shows that the
average cost to charge an electronic
vehicle in canada is just 277
canadian per year which is roughly 203
usd
you switch who generated the report
looked at the average price per kilowatt
hours in 50 different countries
the average mileage per driver and the
average miles electronics
vehicles get on a full charge to
determine the statistic
using this method canada is one of the
least expensive countries to own an
electronic vehicle in
since the electricity is relatively
cheap in some parts of the country
the most expensive countries are denmark
germany and belgium
but even in the worst case we're talking
amounts of around
800 per year for the average driver the
data shows how much money drivers can
save by moving away from
powered cars if it costs around 60
dollars to fill up
and you need to do that roughly once a
month that means you're paying
more for gas in four months than the
average electric vehicle owner will pay
in a year
[Music]