covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias uk-based
computer chip designer arm holdings is
being sold to the american graphics chip
specialist
nvidia the deal values arm at 40 billion
dollars four years after it was bought
by japanese conglomerate softbank
for 32 billion arm creates computer chip
designs that others then customize to
their own ends
it also develops instruction sets which
define how software controls processors
arms technology is at the heart of most
smartphones among many other devices
including a majority of single board
computers such as the raspberry pi
odroid xu4 or rockpro 64 which also
makes it the heart of pine 64's pine
book bro
pro arm will also power apple's new
macbook lineup
nvidia has promised to keep the business
based in the uk
to hire more staff and to retain arm's
brand
it added that the deal would create the
premier computing company for the age of
artificial intelligence
california headquartered nvidia overtook
intel to become the world's most
valuable chip maker in july
until now it is specialized in high-end
graphics processing units
these are commonly used by gamers to
deliver more detailed visuals as well as
by professionals for tasks
including scientific research machine
learning and cryptocurrency
mining in our case we render all our
video in real time using nvidia's
cuda platform nvidia is also one of
arm's clients
using its designs to create its lineup
of tegra
central processing units under the terms
of the deal nvidia will pay softbank
21.5 billion dollars in its own stock
and 12 billion dollars in cash it will
follow up to a further
5 billion dollars in cash or stock if
certain targets are met
nvidia will also issue 1.5 billion
dollars in
equity to arms employees
you