Welcome to Category5 Technology
TV. This is episode number 526.
So nice to have you here. We're
about to embark on the installation
of the operating system for Sasha's
gaming rig. We've been building
this thing over the past nine weeks--really
exciting tonight as we fire fired
up for real for the first time.
Connected so that you can see the
screen and Sasha you are going
to take over that is your right
to be put in that operating system
in there we've got a gaming operating
system that's built specifically
for it. Also tonight I have been
telling you how you can download
the full season 10. The entire
season in HD video. Will stick
around here Kephart you get a free
it's absolutely free you can download
it and the full season is yours
just like that One. Cool. Here's
what's coming up in the category
5 TV newsroom. An airplane flying
nearly half a kilometer in the
air was hit by a drone in Canada.
It's easy to see through door locks
using a Raspberry Pi Windows 10
is under fire by the Dutch Data
Protection Authority hand-write
ransomware double Locher encrypts
data and changes Kinney's security
news WPATH has been cracked and
you need to hear about this if
you use Wi-Fi. Stick around the
full details are coming up later
in the show. This is Category Five
technology TV Are live recordings
of trusted only to solid state
drives by Kingson technology revive
your computer with improved performance
and reliability over traditional
hard drives with Kingston SSD.
Category5 TV streams live with Telestream
Wirecast and Nimble Streamer or
tune in every week on Roku, Kodi,
and other HLS video players. For
local showtimes visit our web site:
Category5.TV. Category5 TV is a
member of the Tech Podcast Network.
If it's tech it's here. I've got
TV slashed and the International
Association of Internet Broadcasters
cat5.tv/iaib. Welcome to the show.
My name is Robbie. I'm Sasha and.
Nice to have you here I want to
say welcome to all of our new viewers
if you're watching on Roku or Codie
or if you're watching on plaques
or through our Web site category
five TV or YouTube or even on channel
33 in the high desert. It's nice
to have you here. Last week we
got into it a little bit about
Star Trek versus the Orville and
YouTube has blown up. Really. Yeah.
Really enjoying the comments there.
I'm surprised at how many people
are very pro Orrville. Or someone
like me we're very much Star Trek
babies. It's inspired me to watch
it. I've only watched one episode
so far. I watched the first episode
of Doraville. I will get into it.
We loved it. Lee Orrville last
episode loved it. Star Trek discovery
first episode well didn't necessarily
keep coming back that's sure not
to get back into it again tonight.
But that's kind of the conversation
that's happening on our YouTube
channel.Head on over to Cat 5 TV's
last YouTube or if you want to
get there direct Go to YouTube
dotcom and just do a search for
Category5 Technology TV. Speaking
of this show now we are in season
11 this is our third episode of
the season and that means season
10 is a wrap. And finally I mean
it takes time and it's huge but
the season 10 bit torrent file
is now a little nice. You can now
download the entire season and
this time we've included extras
as well so behind the scenes put
up know bloopers. Yeah. So she's
Yamaguchi was here and she talked
about her standup comedy. We've
even in the extras included her
standup act as well. So you can
get that if you go over to torrent
doc Category5 TV and I know what
you think when thinking of here
I'm wondering if you put in the
video of me dancing. You'll just
have to download this. I thought
that I was actually thinking you
might be thinking isn't bit torrent
illegal. Not no. Exactly. I know
that you know that's why you running
it. No. You already knew. I knew
it was. It's it's sometimes what
you do with the files. But up there
that's legal. Ah. All right. So
Category Five technology TV is
a show on the Category5 TV network
and the Category5 TV network is
full of volunteers who just love
to bring you free family friendly
content and part of that venture
is to make sure that you can get
it as many ways as you can.One
of those ways is through BitTorrent
and because we own the copyrights
to the files we have every right
to give it to you. Absolutely free.
So head on over to Torent category
five dot tv if you're into BitTorrent
you want to watch it. Otherwise
you can get on to our Web site
Category5 TV there are other ways
to watch including streaming on
demand off of our Web site. There's
a great search engine there powered
by Al Ghalia. We also have. We
also have RSS feeds podcasters
we're on podcast addict we're on
iTunes we're basically anywhere
you can aggregate shows we are
there if you want to add us to
your podcast aggregator and can't
find it. Just head on over to our
Web site category five dot tv and
you'll see the subscribe button
to get the RSS feed and most podcast
aggregators can handle RSS feeds.
That's how they get their content.
So pretty cool stuff. Moral of
the story is just Cat 5 is everywhere.
Have you taken over the war in
trading your TV sets. You have
a smart. You were there. You have
a dumb TV ad there that's how commercials
are commercial. But I always got
to take liquids on TV. Stick around
we'll be right back. Whether you
shop on geek gear best be in a
photo or video e-bay or Amazon
or even if you want a free trial
of audible you'll find the best
deals and support the shows we
produce by simply visiting the
shopping sites you already frequent
by using the links on our website.
Visit category five dot tv slash
Parkers for the full and evergrowing
list and help us create more free
content like this show. Thank you
for shopping with our partners.
And thank you for watching. Welcome
back. This is Category Five technology
TV. Welcome to the show. Nice to
have you here. Please get on to
our Web site category five TV go
through the community forum there
say hello send us your e-mails.
Really appreciate receiving e-mails.
And as we get into part 9 of Sasha
Rickman's sweet gaming rig building
Tony Blair sent an e-mail with
it already Blakesley already. BLAIR
First of all so nice to know that
you're still watching the show.
You've been around for a long time
and it is great to have you joining
us and thankfully saved the universe
by telling me Hey didn't you forget
to install the 12 volt eight pin
power cable which is the power
cable for the CQ. And we did. We
kind of we're running out of time
last week and along with that it's
like OK put it together and get
it going. And we fired it up without
the CPA. So had we had HDMI output
going it would have just not fired
up.Now we had an hour but there
was no power to the CPE you or
at least it didn't have 12 volts
that it that it covered because
it's such a powerful little system.
So I put that on there. Thank you
Artie Blair for pointing that out.
It would have been noticed pretty
quickly but it could have been
noticed on the air. It would have
set us back a little bit. This
is a real serious team that belt.
This is a pretty big thing. And
if you want to be a part of the
community build even if you're
seeing this two years from now
it's OK. Go to Cat 5 TV slash CPQ
2 0 1 7. That's the year that we're
broadcasting it. And it's a really
it has been it's been a community
built. The selection of hardware
to why we selected it. The pricing
budgeting all that stuff has been
thanks to the community and now
as we get into this tonight we're
going to be setting up an operating
system that's recommended by the
community so how cool is that.
So let's get right into OK first
of all I did a couple of things
like this. A power cable that already
Blair mentioned off the air just
before the show so I plugged that
in. The other thing that I did
is I plugged in this beautiful
Kingston hyper X savage hard drive
this hard drive.No it is an SSD.
I should say to be absolutely correct.
So this SSD Sasha is going to be
your data drive. So we've got the
two that you already installed
that is your OS drive right. And
then we're going to set up the
SSD because it's a terabyte drive
screamin fast it's beautiful and
it is going to hold all your data.
So it's got a lot a lot more space.
Cool. That's like game data your
documents your pictures and somebody
said Agam Moto was looking at it
and saying why are you going so
overkill with things like the ram
and things like the harddrive the
storage space. I can understand
them not to. But why are you getting
the terabyte SSD as well because
it's pretty expensive. Well the
fact is we understand I understand
and the community understands that
Sasha is building this for Dave
as a gift her husband Dave and
it's a sweet gaming rig. I'll give
it that. If it was just a sweet
gaming rig I'm got to add 256 gigabytes
is going to be perfectly fine now
right. I understand though that
as your newlywed that this is not
only your gaming computer this
is also your family computer. Exactly.
This is the everything. This is
everything. So all of your family
photos and videos especially are
going to take up some space. Those
kinds of things are going to go
on there. So we want to make sure
that they're not only ready for
gaming and doing what they need
to do today but we're ready future
ready we're ready to be able to
use this thing for the next three
five years plus.That's the hope.
So we're going to get into it tonight.
First of all now that that's installed.
I've got to go through kind of
the BIOS setup so as I first fire
this thing up are we ready. Yes
ready. You're ready. Yes. It's
ready to go. Fired up. And what
do we find. Oh Republic of gamers.
Beautiful. I loved these boards.
So it's going to go right into
the BIOS first and foremost and
the first thing I notice is that
it's taken me to the extreme tweaker
which gives me this X MP feature
an SMP of course is extreme memory
profile from a Seuss. And basically
what that does is these settings
are going to allow me to set up
overclocking for you and Dave in
such a way that it's all automatic.
That's just warning me that we
need lots of cooling and we have
that. So as you can see it's now
going to do all the cores it's
detected are 26 66 RAM from Kingston.
That's the fury RAM and everything
is kind of auto. That means it's
going to automatically adjust the
frequencies of the RAM the you
as it needs to in order to make
it as fast as possible. So you
see it clocks a four point two
gigahertz.They're two hundred megahertz.
But if I go back to extreme tweaker
I can see that with the overclocking
it's going to go up to 40 five
hundred megahertz or 4.5 gigahertz.
OK so I'm going to save that setting.
So now we are officially overclocked.
In the simplest way possible answer
showing me what is going to change.
Can't get any simpler than that.
And now it just booted right back
into the bios so we need to look
at our boot devices and see that
our boot order is OK first of all.
So just scroll down here. I love
the interface. This BIOS utility
from from Republic of gamers looks
great. So I need to disable see
it's detecting the hard drives.
They got to they're going to disable
and then have to disable and that's
move that up and disable the s.a.a
drive as well. So now I have no
drive selected for boot because
we don't want it to actually boot
from that but I noticed that it's
not detected my U.S. bead right.
So I'm just going to save that
and unplug that plug it back in.
Let the BIOS know that hey there's
a USP drive so let's see what happens
here. See if it'll boot right up.
No. Went right back in. So here
we go. Now I know that it supports
compatibility mode you can see
CSM is there. Oh and now you can
see the data traveler is a boot
option so you can see how that
could get frustrating if you don't
know to look for this thing.I need
to select that USP drive as my
boot disk and then save and reboot.
Here we go. Moment of Truth overclocked
disable the hard drives as boot
devices they're still detected
and we've set it up to boot from
the U.S. and there it is the familiar
Ubuntu kind of loading thing at
the bottom there. That's what that
is. Perfect thanks. So the distro
that I've got here is called Ubuntu.
Game pack I was looking for a gaming
Linux distribution and this is
based on 3:44 this is the LDS are
long term support version of a
boon too which means it's supported
until 2021 I think or 2022. Needless
to say it's going to be supported
for a good long time and that means
that you're not going to have to
reinstall your operating system
every six months. Thank you. Which
is good. So then when that LTA
cycle is done we can just simply
roll it up to the next LTI us.
Beautiful but that's about it.
So this is a boom to Linux. It's
available at Ubuntu dot com. But
the particular flavor that we've
chosen is built specifically for
gamers gamers. So it's optimized
for gaming it comes pre-installed
with play on Linux. LUTER a steam
steam is something that we really
wanted to hosting is twitch on
Twitch TV is available through
your browser.So OK so I suppose
you could just bring it up in Chrome
or chromium. OK there you go. What
else. It's just it's got a ton
of stuff so this one is a spin
off of a boon too and it's available
at you a Linux dot com. So sastra
that's all that I'm really allowed
to do. I kind of want you to take
over and we want to see how quickly
we can do this and I see that it's
finished booting. We're at this
screen to either try or install
Ubuntu. So if I move the mouse
over to you. Right. And we've got
a suite gaming mouse and wireless
gaming keyboard for them as well
as we all. Are so ready for it
because this is all you. There
you go. I don't know that you're
going to need the keyboard but
there it is. Put it right in front
of us. Sasha is in control now
and she's kind of like doing that.
Like what. I'm going to put it
right up here so when I bring it
up on the screen Sasha can see
it. Our TV in front of you there
Sasha so click on install Ubuntu
click it and have an Emmy for it.
OK. So do we want to install third
party software for graphics and
Wi-Fi hardware using E3 and other
media. Absolutely. So check that
off. So that's going install like
your graphics drivers and things
like that.Hopefully I mean it'll
all work. So continue now you know
to download updates while installing
is is not an available option that
means that our internet is not
connected to this particular computer
right now. So we can run those
updates down the road or a little
bit later it doesn't matter. OK
come on now this is running from
a USP flash drive us flash drives
traditionally are quites. You know
they're not as slow as CD optical
media but they're a lot slower
than once this is installed on
the computer. So once this is on
the Umkhonto is going to be screaming
fast. All right. So next question
let's see if we can speed this
up a little bit. There we go. OK
so what do you want to do. So yeah
we want to erase the desk. Do we
want to encrypt it. I would say
no to that because your desktop
computer use LVM Absolutely because
LVM is going to allow us we've
learned this on the show before.
If you're not familiar with LVM
or you want to learn a little bit
more about it it's it's amazing
and it allows you to run snapshots
of your entire harddrive so that
you can do backups on the fly without
having to shut down. Yep that is
perf that's one of the advantages.
So head on over to our Web site
category five dot tv. Do a quick
search for LVM and you're going
to get all the instructions on
how to do that.So we're just going
to do that because if we ever want
it it's a pain in the butt to switch
to it. So we should do something
else. Now let's do something else
let's keep it you know keep it
simple. And what does it want to
do. OK. Now at the top there we
see that it's got 240 gig. Kingston
not too. Can you click on that
dropdown for me Sasha. Yes just
so we can see if it's there and
it's also detected. The terabyte
SSD. So we want to install this
on the M.Com too so that's the
first drive. The one that it automatically
selected and that is being detected
as the a. So install now. OK. So
that drive as you can see is about
a quarter of the capacity of the
VSS team. So we're going to use
those two together to get the most
blazing speed that we can possibly
get the most reliability it's going
to go really really well. Excited.
Yes. Can you believe that that
we're pretty much now just OK asking
you are you sure you want to continue
because what is this going to do
if you write to the disks you're
going to wipe out any data that's
on there. How much data is on there
right now. Well nothing nothing.
No it's a brand new system that
you just built. So you're absolutely
good to go but do keep in mind
if you're doing this on a preexisting
installation you need to think
twice at that point.And why is
that our time is out. There are
times on so that's I in New York
no highlight or just type in Toronto
because that's where we are. We're
just north of Toronto about 50
minutes. Barry Now you can do it
that way. Sure. Why is there another
way. Well triple click. There you
go. Toronto right up at the top
on Terio Canada. I think you have
to actually collect. You need to
click with the mouse girl. Oh wow.
Well goodness gracious. This is
how we learn. Just press backspace
once they know they go on Toronto.
OK. There you go. Right. Sasha
is amazing with a mouse so that
this whole process to install and
move to is about three minutes
it's going to take about four hours.
Brace yourself. Brace yourself.
Where are we at. OK. Click Continue
please. OK. You know OK English
US keyboard. That's fine that's
what we're you. OK. So we just
can continue looking for the board.
So your name. Well I don't know
if you want to put the off. Oh
yeah sure I did but you know it
recommends recommends and then
your computer name call it Rickman
would be fine. And then pick a
user name so Richmond all lowercase
all lowercase sound OK and then
under choose password I want you
to enter password. One two three.
That sounds amazingly secure that's
very secure. It's a combination
of Word and some numbers. Don't
let's not listen to me don't do
it. You need to pick a password.
You can use password 1 2 3 for
today because we can change it
down the road when we're not on
the air. OK let's just do that.
OK. It's going to tell you that
it is a fair. That's nice. Set
password one two three. Yeah. All
right. Everybody you can hack into
their computer. No problem. This
is your home computer so you need
to think about this. Do you want
to require your password in order
to turn it on now or do you want
to just make it go right to the
day we can just make it go right
to your laptop the I would say
absolutely you need that password.
I probably would have opted for
encryption as well. But because
this is your desktop computer I
mean unless someone steals it from
you. But if that happens is not
the worst thing. Let's be honest.
I might steal this. It's a beautiful
system. I know this is our new
broadcast. I'm the old one and
be like here. The new gaming day.
It's a pretty sweet reg.. I'm jealous
that I can log in automatically.
So is is an option. Yeah how to
log in automatically sorry. Most
girls it's harder than you. It's
because you don't like crossover
with the ads. Just say you know
I'm like mousepad.I stand up over
here and the keyboard I set it
up over here. So it's kind of I
am not down on site here.So. OK.
So now what is going through the
installation processing scene while
you were taking your sweet time
there. It actually continued to
install is that a dinosaur Square.
That's a school that is definitely
a squirrel. OK. I've never seen
a dinosaur with a tail that fic
and that long. I've never seen
a dinosaur. You've seen pictures.
I've seen pictures of dinosaurs
on green screen on different cameras.
So high five right now. How do
the virtual high five. Yes. Well
as I bleed into the next frame.
All right so that is installing
we're going to take a really quick
break while that continues when
we come back. Hopefully everything
is gone. Smashingly well we're
going to be ready to boot up into
our brand new operating system
too. What does it call game. Keep
a game path to game. The. Hack.
Is based on the next we're going
to be right back after this.You've
got mad skills now hone them learn
new skills or improve your existing
ones with online video tutorials
and training from Linda dotcom
through our special link at Cat
5 dot tv slash Linda learn software
technology creative and business
skills. You can use today to help
you achieve your professional goals.
Join today and start learning.
We'll give you this chance to try
it. Absolutely free with unlimited
access to all of the courses. Sign
up now for FREE. Cat 5 dog TV slash
Linda this is Category Five technology
TV.Welcome back. And tonight we
are digging into the installation
of Sasha's new operating system
on her gaming rig. Now Jeff you
mentioned that is question we came
in the chat room as we were on
break. Yeah. So Albuquerque Turkey
was watching and he wanted to know
did he see you turn off secure
boot. You did not see me do that.
OK. What did he see. OK did you.
Did he hear me when I mentioned
that it has a compatibility option.
So yes spy on us by default is
going to allow both you EFI and
legacy mode options. So your devices
are either or. Now in the BIOS.
You can select just legacy mode
which is probably what we can do
but by default. Fortunately for
us the default option is there
and it supports legacy or you find
not not one or the other. So if
you have this board you're having
trouble what does it mean what
does your boot mean. So technically
secure boot is still enabled on
this board. Secure boot you EFI
is like technology mostly used
by Microsoft Windows that allows
them to make sure that the pretense
is that viruses can't get into
your bootloader. Right. Realistically
it keeps other operating systems
from running on your operating
system on your computer as well.
In our case we want to install
Linux so we need to be running
in legacy mode. It can be installed
in UAF mode but you can you know
it's a much more complicated. So
it's still enabled but we're running
with legacy mode as the default
option in the BIOS. But check those
out there is there are options
there for the compatibility mode
as well as security settings under
the boot menu on this particular
motherboard and this motherboard
section maybe you can remind us
what it is that that you bought.
You've got your shopping list right.
You are the motherboard is the
aces. Is it our max. This assumes
I say you're wrong.I have seen
this and people say no you say
it wrong it's aces or something
like that. This is years ago when
I was building computers as an
OEM manufacturer. This is years
ago so this my first build many
years I've been working with HP
Lenovo and all that for as long
as I can remember. So when I worked
with a SUSE I talked to them on
the phone right and they called
themselves the suits.So that's
that was how do we get to the source
of this. OK.So that's where that
comes from. OK. So I think that
answers your question Albuquerque
Turkey thank you for sending it
in and we're ready to get back
into this I believe hold on before
you do that. You ever finish your
list or at least where you could
find the list.Oh well. Well the
list is what the list is on the
actual cat 5 slash CPQ 20:17 right.
Yes. Yes. That's where you would
find out how we picked all those
hard pieces of hardware how much
it cost all that kind of stuff.
That's how you can budget it and
do something you like.You can you
check out that same system that
if it goes you can use a different
password not one two three. Yeah.
But you've got to know it's password
one two three exclamation point.
Oh is that all. Well no that's
not what mine is right now.Your
e-mail password. Well as the penny
for for on line banking. All right.
So it is done. SASHA. All I need
you to do is click on restart now.
Where am I. Oh click on the mouse
once because it's gone to sleep.
It's a wireless mouse. You don't
need to save power your wireless
mouse stops working and then you
just click it single click to to
make it come back. There we go.
Well rebooting now I wonder if
this is going to end don't worry
about that error message that has
to do. Looks like a soundcard driver.
OK. So that's not that's not a
problem for us right now. We're
in a live mode boot scenario. So
hopefully that just reboot. If
not we can do a hard boot it is
running off the live media. Let's
try it. Hang in there Jack. You
ready sir. OK. I'm going to hit
reset. Blue screen Blue Screen
of Death folks we just installed
Windows XP. OK. So what's going
to happen is it going to boot from
the hard drive. No I don't think
it is. I think we're going to end
up in our bios again because we've
never set the bootloader yes order
right.So now let's go into and
I'm taking control here for a moment
Sasha to boot. And you notice we
have no hard drives enabled but
we installed that on the first
drive here. The 240 gig too. OK.
So let's now save that. So that's
let's just selecting it's not turning
on or turning off our drives and
just telling your boss which drive
you want to boot from. And Albuquerque
Turkey for the sake of your question
these are the things that I was
talking about compatibility support
module. So you can actually go
in there and you'll see the legacy
ROM is selected. And then there
is you EFI and legacy or you F-I
only That's the setting that you
were asking about. As far as you
EFI goes but as far as secure boot
right below that it has defaulted
to other OS and then there's also
Windows you EFI mode. So even though
I didn't have to do that myself
it is selected before you go anywhere
crazy with that.Did you see on
the right hand side it has the
temperature. No that's who has
a hardware monitor. Sepia temperature.
Sweet. And I started see we can
actually go into the monitor.Let's
see here and watch what happens
here. No way or motherboard's 33
degrees C 36 on the V.R. am when
we show this to you show him that.
Oh yeah I hear. And that's why
it's so quiet it has been spun
down to 548 rotations per minute
while chassis fan is it 7:46 it
is so quiet folks you can hear
you Tofel and that's all part of
this Q fan control which you can
tweak if you want to. And that
basically under high load when
you're gaming and things are getting
hot it starts spinning up the fans
keep it cooler already like if
you're gaming everything up loud
anyway or you wouldn't hear if
the computer was loud. You got
the hands on your blasting it.
Absolutely. OK. So I think we've
got everything kind of set where
we want it by selecting the boot
the hard drive as the boot drive.
And to be fair to Sasha I know
I poke fun. There does seem to
be a bit of interference on the
mouse. Thank you. A wireless mouse.
So I hope that you're not going
to have trouble with that at home
because how far is the mouse going
to be from the computer tower itself.
It's wireless right so you don't
to if it's can be 10 feet. You're
only about five feet right now.
But I've got another wireless mouse
there plus my phone plus.Right.
There's some things on the way.
So it's yeah it's possible that
that plus it's on an angle. Does
that matter. Yeah. Oh yes. Oh yes.
Oh I'm so pleased. I saw something
flash and I said you've been to
this. This looks like a black screen
Right up. Now video drivers are
not running yet because you can
see how massive everything is it
looks like low resolution like
a little tablet or phone screen.
So let's see if it did actually
load any wound any Nvidia drivers.
I don't see any hint that Nvidia
is there. So there are some things
and this is not a tutorial on how
to get Linux up and running. We've
covered that so many times before
on the show. What this is Sasha
has now built a gaming rig. We
know it's got a beautiful and video
card in there. It is a super powerful
video card that we need to install
the propriety of proprietary drivers
for in order to get the best performance
so I'll do that for you. The stuff
that you don't have to worry about
but know that you've got to go
through those steps you've got
it and she's installed the operating
system she built the computer pretty
much herself from scratch from
the parts that Jeff and I unboxed
and there it is. It's up and running.
Sasha I think that's it.What do
you think. I love it.So I get it
by installing the graphics drivers
we're going to have better resolution
we're going to have better performance.
It's prompting me that we need
a steam user. All that stuff or
whatever it is in the background
it's happening there. Let's look
at games what does it come with
so you can retire solitaire. So
definitely a gaming rig. DOS box
simulator. So that means you can
install an old DOS games so that's
things like Prince of Persia. The
class commander key commander s
space quest. Those things are all
going to run under DOS box Louris
is another kind of gaming platform
so that you can you can install
games into the system and play
them. It's an easy way to find
a lot of games that are really
in the system MYONG minds play
on Linux. That is cool play on
Linux allows you to install Windows
games on Linux.Oh that's good.
Just like wine a little bit. It
uses wine and there's a back end
but it has an interface to allow
you to install the games quite
simply. It's not with every game
to be fair because Windows games
are built for Windows to play on
Linux has cut out all the complicated
steps to making Windows games work
on Linux and you don't have to
have Microsoft Windows install
C that's good because this is our
first Linux can hear it. Are you
excited about that. Yes. So can
we say a little bit about why Linux
because I have a slight Linux bias
slightly but it's an alternative
Microsoft Windows and it's free.
You don't have to pay for licenses
you don't have to worry about their
spyware software monitoring you
and things like that. And any of
the kind of caveats that you have
with Microsoft Windows they don't
exist in Linux it's a free operating
system and it is developed by people
like ourselves who just care about
making something great and distributing
it and sharing it. And that's what
Linux is. It's something that you
can get in on you. There's that
slight learning curve because the
interface is maybe a little bit
different but there's a lot of
effort that's been put into making
that learning curve as easy as
possible. I've noticed on this
version of Linux that it it looks
like Ubuntu mat is what it's running.
That is the interface so this is
Matej not. I was expecting maybe
Gnome or possibly unity but definitely
no. So nice to see mat. I like
the interface a lot. Steam is the
next one steam we all know and
love is something that you sign
up for an account that you can
buy games go all the time at home.
They install you tell tell us about
steam them because I'm not a gamer
so how does that work.Well I mean
when you've got steam it's all
encompassing as far as games library
we can make purchases. Also the
games that you download to crunch
chronology chronology of your library
also you know depending on whether
you're really into competing with
other people are you going to badges
and stuff like that. There's a
whole new features to it with other
games. It's it's just really it's
a great compressed library for
keeping everything in one spot.
That's in a library that you can
just find games it's there you
can install them by them and steam
is cross-platform. That's correct
if you are not interested in taking
this route and installing Linux.
That's OK steam is available on
Microsoft Windows. In fact if you
install it on Microsoft Windows
and later switch to Linux it's
cross compatible. So you're just
transfer over that is is. That's
right. All right so that gives
us a good overview I think that's
a way to go congratulations you've
got to get into the game. I keep
losing the name it's game Pelion
pack game getback game pack sixteen
point four I got to come up with
a rhyme for game. No you don't.
They don't. Thanks Ashleigh. Next
week do I tell them now that you
can see you playing the first game
on it. That's all I'm going to
tell you at this moment. Stick
around until after the news I'm
going to tell you. Get more details
and if you want to see the sweet
game and re play games you do not
want to miss episode number five
27. All right we're going to head
over to our beautiful new newsroom.
What do you have for us.Here are
the stories we're covering this
week in the Category5 TV news
here. An airplane flying nearly
half a kilometer in the air was
hit by a drone in Canada. It's
easy to have secret door locks
using a raspberry pi. Windows 10
is under fire by the Dutch Data
Protection. The word Android ransomware
double Lochore encrypts data and
changes hands and in security news
WPA too has been cracked and you
need to hear about this. If you
use Wi-Fi. These stories are coming
right up. Don't go anywhere. Jeff
Weston Jubba you're building a
brand new beautiful Web site Are
you. You're a terrible actor. When
this thing comes into play I don't
know where you're supposed to act.
OK. We're building a really cool
Web site. Are you building a really
cool Web site. Just because Geoff
is confused doesn't mean you have
to be visit. Cat 5 dot tv slashed
dream host to sign up for unlimited
web hosting for your web site with
unlimited email accounts. My ask
you about databases the latest
version of HP Wordpress and more
and even a free domain name registration.
It's less than six dollars per
month so sign up today. Cat 5 dog
TV slashed dream homes. This is
the Category5 TV news room covering
the week's top stories with sleep
clinics. I'm Sasha triggermen and
here are the top stories we're
following this week. Canada's transport
minister has told drone operators
to stay away from airports after
remotely piloted craft bonked a
passenger plane during its final
approach to Ziyang massage International
Airport in Quebec City.Minister
Mark Garneau hasn't revealed the
model of the drone but we do know
that it hit a plane operated by
Sky jet aviation a charter outfit
that despite its name only operates
turboprop aircraft. The three types
it operates the King Air 100 and
200 plus the Beechcraft 9500 seats
6 10 and 19 passengers apiece which
ever type was struck it came away
with what Garneau described as
minor damage and landed safely.
There's also no news on where the
plane where of where on the plane
the drone strike is. The craft
landed without incident. We can
assume it wasn't chopped up by
the plane's propellers. Local media
suggest that the plane was struck
about 300 or 3000 meters from the
runway Oh while at an altitude
of 450 meters. All concerned are
there for reminding Canadian drone
operators of their obligation to
fly below 90 meters and at least
five and a half kilometers away
from air ports or face a $25000
fine. Authorities hope to identify
the drone pilot to remind them
of those rules in strong language.
A drone striking a propeller or
being sucked into a jet engine
has the potential to cause a very
serious incident. Wow very scary.
Yeah well I mean the fact that
it left body damage I mean it wasn't
significant but I mean that's.
So are there like are. Are there
drones that are smaller that are
allowed to fly closer or is it
just all drones.We're talking this
is three three 3000 meters from
the airport which I did the quick
math in my head that's three kilometers
folks. Yeah. And the minimum is
5.5. So they're already not only
are they flying well above the
height limit but they're also flying
very very close to an airport.
Yeah. So drones can fly that high
up like they absolutely can't.
It's a bigger thrill. Yeah this
wasn't clearly wasn't a teenager
or something like that. You know
we're talking no no no this is
we're talking about this big Drone
to give you just some perspective.
There was a guy on YouTube who
recently posted a video which was
promptly taken down of him flying
his phantom to to 3.5 kilometers
into the air. Wow. Now keep in
mind that regulations say we're
only allowed to fly up to 90 meters
in the air just a little bit over
that I think he went right. Thirty
four hundred. He was at. So because
these things have first person
view you know he might have a screen
or goggles and be able to see what
the drone is seeing and so it is
safe from that perspective it's
not like he's going to lose sight
of it and not be able to find it.
Right. But it's highly illegal.
So then the actual law the rule
where you can't fly within like
five and half kilometers to the
airport that $25000 fine.Is that
if there's an incident or is that
if you're caught flying if you're
caught flying as a consumer flier
like if I or Jeff were refiner
or drones and we were caught breaking
the rules. So these are rules that
are designed to protect aircraft
and other people. So it doesn't
just have to do with aircraft or
airports if you're flying too close
to a crowd it falls under the same
regulations so the fine for that
to be caught. So nobody gets hurt.
Nobody's nothing's damaged is up
to $3000 Canadian. OK.So that's
about $4 for you American viewers
or a point 0 0 0 0 Bitcoin point
1 0 0 is one.It's binary. Yeah
nothing. Chances are the twenty
five thousand dollars would be
for like a serious incident where
maybe a plane actually did crash
people but like maybe they did
it out today. I would hope they
say they have to crash the regulation
states that it's up to $25000.
If you have endangered an aircraft
or another person.Right. I would
hope that if somebody flying a
drone that crashed into a plane
that then crashed and killed people
that drone flyer I would hope goes
to jail like I would hope that
it's just not $25000 like I would.
That's an extreme case. It's never
happened as far as I'm aware. So
you keep a low people.Dutch electronics
engineer reckons Japanese automaker
Subaru isn't acting on a key fob
cloning vuln t he discovered Tom
women who claims to have discovered
that Subaru's electronic keys don't
use a random number. The rolling
rolling code instead merely increments
coats when behove says he's built
a cloning device which he has made
available on get hub and use it
for a 2009 Subaru Forester. He
believes it would also work on
a 2006 Bahaa Forester. Forester
models from 2005 to 2010 Impreza
models from 2004 to 2011 the legacy
sedans 2005 2010 models and the
outback from 2005 to 2010. His
test rig only cost around $25 using
a raspberry pi for much of the
functionality because the key fob
simply increment the rolling code
exchange between the car and the
key. All an attacker needs is to
be able to be close enough to capture
the code used when the owner locks
the car. Incrementing that code
lets the attacker unlock the vehicle.
Wow. I drive a Subi what why wouldn't
Subaru act on that.Well it could
be that they don't think it's a
massive vulnerability I mean actually
what we're talking about some vehicles.
What was it 2009. We're back at
this point. I don't think they
care. I mean like if it was one
of the 2000 5s are looking to go
on. It's been like 13 years because
it's always like you know in 2004
the 2005 would come out so you
know it's been 13 years or some
of them Mosul's vehicles would
be off the road. It's not like
it was the newer vehicles. My guess
is from a liability standpoint
the cost factor of patching it
doing a warranty recall switching
out keys because you'd have to
replace the keys or reprogram them
but she'd have to reprogram the
vehicles. The cost probably just
wasn't significant enough or was
too slow.So then can you just sell
something like that and get home.
What does will get hobbies is a
coating. So what what it means
when he's posted it on get have
is that is freely available. So
anyone who wants to build this
thing can download this. The instructions
to do it right and the code to
do it. You don't love that. And
I don't want to speculate too much
about Subaru not having a statement
from them but knowing that you
know as you know ethical hackers
bring out these kinds of hey we've
discovered this. There's a lot
of that because people are trying
to get the cash prize for it. Hey
there are no ethical hacker prizes
and so there comes a point when
you know companies will certainly
say no we're not doing it. Microsoft
comes to mind recently with the
compromise on Internet Explorer.
Yes. They simply say you know we're
not worrying about the older operating
systems and there was another one
in the kernel itself where they
say we're not going to patch any
of them. It's too far into the
kernel we're not going to touch
it. We don't believe it's such
a security risk as you're making
that sound. Now others made me
say otherwise. But I think it's
that they may perceive this is
a May because I don't know I haven't
spoken with them but they may perceive
as a company that it takes a certain
level of knowledge in order to
do this type of compromise. And
so they don't feel as vulnerable
because it's like it wouldn't happen
to me mentality.They're such a
small minority of smart people
in the world there's no problem
of people already who would create
a key fob hacking device out of
a Raspberry Pi.I'm just picturing
the movie Gone in 60 seconds picturing
Nicolas Cage walking around with
a Raspberry Pi just like picking
up Shelby.I just got a whole bunch
of super four thousand nine. Oh
dear. OK. The Dutch Data Protection
Authority has concluded that Microsoft
Microsoft's Windows operating system
breaches local privacy law on account
of its collection of telemetry
metadata personal data being harvested
by default by Microsoft can include
the you are out of every web site
visited. If the Windows 10 user
is browsing the web with Microsoft's
edge browser and has not opted
out a full time metry as well as
data about usage of all installed
apps on their device including
frequency of use how often the
apps are active and the amount
of seconds of usage of a keyboard
mouse pen or touch screen. Microsoft
says it gathers and processes Windows
10 users data in order to fix error.
Keep devices up to date and secure
and improve its own products and
services of course. But if users
have not opted out. It also uses
data from both a basic and full
telemetry level to show personalized
advertisements in Windows and edge
including all apps for sale in
the windows store and also for
showing personalized advertisements
and other apps. According to the
local DPA there are more than 4
million active devices using Windows
10 a home and pro in the Netherlands.
After investigating several versions
of the OS including Windows Trenholm
impro the Dutch DPA said Friday
it has identified multiple breaches
of the data protection law. Microsoft
has compiled a point by point rebuttal
on these points of disagreements.
Wow what is to tell a tell tale
about memory. What is telemetry
metadata treat. Two words. Wow.
Yeah that's it. That's all that's
always going to give you. So I'll
give them the tracking.You know
essentially I mean this is basically
information that is gathered on
your Windows 10 system or other
systems as well. Now on Windows
7 and 8 everything else but. So
they are tracking your movements.
This is how they are able to provide
targeted advertising to you know
it's under the veil of improving
the operating system because they
might notice that hey you know
people running this particular
processor are having problems opening
this application so let's manipulate
something in the code. So it's
under the guise of fixing things
helping improve things. But it
is really collecting personal information
about your usage spying on you.
Right. So is there ever. Like so
when they say they're using it
to help them. Is that actually
at all OK. That they say that.
Well that's just the guise of it's
common to improve the user but
that's not that's never the truth.
Like you could disable it.There's
always other methods and again
I don't expect you know we know
why Facebook gives you free accounts.
We know why. You know that's exactly
how are you going.This is leading
to if there's basic telemetry and
then there is full which like nothing
ok. Would it be helpful to just
do basic or should you do done
at all.You can even opt out. But
I think with some of the windows
updates you've got to keep an eye
on it because it'll reactivate
itself because you're good and
say OK with a certain I accept
the license agreement and oh that
license agreement also turn back
on full telemetry. So the difference
essentially you know the basic
dilemma is the the essentials the
bare minimum that they need in
order to kind of keep track of
your system and how you're using
it then full telemetry and everything
like this is something that a technician
could use to actually come in and
diagnose problems on your computer.
Everything about your computer
and how you use it.Right. I got
a visual. You were saying that
if that useless box like you turned
it off it turns itself back exactly
like that for much like that.In
fact before we move on the windows
club actually posted a very good
tutorial for you to help you so
that you can disable or reduce
the amount of telemetry metadata
that is shared with Microsoft.
All right. That can be found on
their Web site. The windows club
dot com slash windows dash 10 dash
telemetry. And that's going to
give you that information. I'll
check it out.Right. Crooks have
come up with a strain of Android
ransomware that both encrypts user
data and locks victims out of compromised
devices by changing pins Lucus
the fan code. The malware researcher
at security firm esset who discovered
double double laughers said its
payload can change the device's
pain preventing the victim from
accessing their device and encrypts
the victim's data. Such a combination
has hasn't been seen yet in the
Android ecosystem. He goes on to
explain double Lochore misuses
Android accessibility services
which is a popular trick among
cyber criminals. The nest is based
on a banking Trojan which means
that account compromising functionality
might easily be added. The Android
malware spreads in the very same
way as its PC parent as a fake
Adobe Flash Player update that's
pushed via a compromised Web sites.
Once launched the app for activation
of the malwares accessibility service
named Google Play service after
the malware obtains these accessibility
permissions it uses them to activate
device administrator rights and
set itself as the default home
application. In both cases without
the user's consent double Lochore
once planted on a compromised device
creates two reasons for the victim
to pay. First it changes the device's
pin effect effectively blocking
the victim from using it. Second
double AUKer encrypts all files
from the data from that device
is primary storage directory using
the ABS encryption algorithm. The
ransom has been set at a relatively
modest 0.01 three Bitcoin which
is approximately $54. The only
viable option to clean a non routed
device double Walker Ransomware
is via a factory reset. A way around
the pin lock on the routed devices
is possible if not exactly straight
forward encrypted files cannot
be easily recovered. Wow very scary
because now it's kind of it really
hits home. It's real phone it's
really it's really real.So you've
got to be careful of what you click
on because this is a typical social
engineering tactic of you know
you've installed an app that you
think is legitimate and it has
tricked you into giving access
to certain things that probably
shouldn't have given it access
to it. It's it is just social engineering
tactics used by malicious coders.
And you need to really really be
careful what you install where
you get it from. You have a rooted
device you need to be mindful the
city is probably going to be distributing
things that are not approved by
Google and the Google Play Store
so be very very careful. And if
you're not sure what that means
if you're not sure what a device
means well it probably doesn't
affect you but you do need to be
aware that malicious coders do
place things in the Google Play
store to trick you into installing
an app. That sounds great. It's
free and it's you know it's got
this this and this. But why exactly
does this chat application need
access to all of my files. And
that's the big tipoff. Now does
doesn't mean every one of those
apps that asks for access to everything
is a bad app but you're used to
it. Yeah. You usually see him you
know a couple options for whatever
you're looking for. And there's
one it's like all we know it only
needs access to your camera than
others it's everything.You know
watch out for and you got to get
like permission for fatigue or
something like I just sometimes
don't read. You got you know that's
how they get you. Right. But also
if they've locked me out of my
phone how am I supposed to pay
them.Well it'll show it on the
screen. You've got to pay paywall
on your phone that says hey it
just comes in. Oh yeah. And given
the fact that it's only $54 like
that so it's not like it's to give
us five million dollars. Most people
get five to four bucks is just
not worth going. Oh my kids photos
around here. Yeah. And if they're
going to go to like a tech center
to get their phone serviced they're
going to say oh it's a hundred
hundred fifty bucks people get
it cheaper than the service I'll
just pay it to get it a lot. Right
out of time. Can we really quickly
talk about the WPA hack that just
occurred. Yes. This is something
that happened on Monday. So Sasha
do you tell us about that.Absolutely.
Researchers have disclosed a serious
weakness in the WPA to protocol
that allows attackers within a
range of vulnerable device within
a range of vulnerable device or
access points to intercept passwords
emails and other data presumed
to be encrypted. And in some cases
to inject ransomware or other malicious
content into a Web site a client
is visiting the proof of concept
exploit is called crack short for
key re-installation attacks. The
research has been a closely guarded
secret for weeks ahead of a coordinated
disclosure that was scheduled for
8:00 a.m. Monday. East coast time
a Web site disclosing the vulnerabilities
said it affects the core WPA to
protocol itself and is very effective
against any device including those
running the Android Linux Mac OS
Windows and open BSD operating
systems. The vulnerabilities are
scheduled to be formally presented
in a talk scheduled for November
1st in Dallas. The vast majority
of existing Access Points aren't
likely to be patched quickly and
some may or may not be patched
at all.Ok so that is a scary fact.
So now some people are thinking
what is all this techno babble.
What is WPA to what is black. What
is this exploit and what does it
mean to me. If you have a phone
in your pocket that when you go
home it connects to your home Wi-Fi
or you have it set up to connect
to your office Wi-Fi your. You're
vulnerable. Yes. Now the scary
thing is you are also vulnerable
if you connect to the local coffee
shops Wi-Fi. But here's the fact
you have no way of knowing if the
local coffee shop is clever enough
to patch their device right. If
they do that's fantastic How will
you ever know. I don't feel safe
any more going to a private to
a public hotspot. Right. And simple.
So what does it mean. When I connect
to Wi-Fi usually that is an encrypted
connection. I am connected to their
Wi-Fi hotspot and anything that
I do between there between my device
and their hotspot is encrypted
including passwords and things
like that. Now throw all that away
now anyone sitting in that same
coffee shop can also see those
things that you're doing on there.
So it's very serious. It is. I
mean we're not seeing this in the
wild. So I should say it's not
something that is actively being
exploited because the ethical hackers
who discovered this revealed it
very ethically. Yes what that means
is is that they let hardware manufacturers
they let Google they let everyone
know that is in the industry before
they actually announced it publicly.
That means the day that they announced
it 7:00 a.m. that day micro tech
already had a patch for all their
routers. That's the kind of results
that we've seen from this. So now
we're starting to see Google is
starting to work on some patches
for their systems we're seeing
that a lot of hardware manufacturers
are already releasing firmware
updates but you have to install
them. Microchip is a great example
of a company that does it right
because I can just log into the
router click on Update get the
latest version is done. And if
you have a link or something even
D-W or things like that you may
need to reflash you may need to
download a driver on your computer
a firmware on your computer or
put it on a U.S. beef stick take
it over to your router do it that
way or maybe through the land you
have to do it otherwise your Wi-Fi
is susceptible you also need to
delete all the Wi-Fi hotspots that
you've got in your phone and only
start adding ones that you know
have patched against crack. Smart.
Thanks Ravi. I'm going home and
going to update my firmware update
for you. That goes for your phones
your computers as well. If you
do an app update and then an apt
upgrade on Linux you're going to
get a WPA patch already. So make
sure you make that so. NEMS has
already got the patch it's Ottery
automatically rolled out to all
of the NEMS appliances. Perfect.
So get it done update your computers
folks and read a big thanks to
radio national or community of
yours for submitting stories to
us this week. Thanks for watching
the Category5 TV newsroom. Don't
forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight
Linux bias. And for more free content
be sure to check out our Web site.
From the Category5 TV newsroom
I'm Sasheer Eckman.Thank you Sasha.
This is Category Five technology
TV and I promised a little bit
ago that we going to tell you a
little bit about what's happening
next week. The gaming rig. OK.
I'm going to tell you two things.
First of all this gaming rig is
sweet it's super fast. We can do
really high frame rate. That's
thing number one thing number two.
What is next week the Halloween
special day Halloween special.
What is it.Oh that's right. Because
Halloween is the day before today
the same day every year Japh. OK
so what in my mind.October 31.
How do we amalgamate a sweet smokin
hot virtual reality video game
computer with our desire to celebrate
the darkest day of the year. Well
at least to dress up we're going
to dress up as Starfleet officers
from Star Trek The Next Generation
once again. Oh you're on the show.
And we're going to use virtual
reality to place ourselves not
only in the Starship Enterprise
A.S.C. 17:1 but we are going to
take you on a virtual reality tour
of the Federation's star. So much
fun prizes. Don't miss it that's
happening next week. When episode
number five 27 of Category5 took.
This week that's all. We haveTo