Welcome to Category 5 technology
TV this is episode number five
twenty seven it's nice to have
you here. My name's Robbie and
Sasha is over here with me. We're
going to have a lot of fun tonight
because we are celebrating kind
of you know that's the Halloween
week special and we always do a
little something but this time
we're doing something a little
bit different thanks to the folks
over at Stage 9 what we're doing
is actually taking a virtual reality
tour of the Starship Enterprise
from Star Trek The Next Generation
that's 12:43. You want to stick
around. We're going to actually
take Sasha's gaming rig for a spin.
The first time it's ever run again.
We're going to be ranking things
up with the graphics. We're going
to see how she performs as we tour
the Starship Enterprise.That is
awesome. And here's what's coming
up in the category 5 TV newsroom.
A bot net of unknown intent has
been discovered and is spreading
at a frightening rate. Google's
Project Loon has brought some internet
to end cellular service. Hurricane
devastated Puerto Rico. Samsung
hopes to succeed where other vendors
have failed. They want to bring
the full desktop experience full
desktop Linux experience to smartphones.
Do you have an. Ultimate player
or varlets on your Mac. You may
need to wipe everything and reinstall
Mac OS because a nasty bit of malware
came with the popular software
and is giving hackers full access
to absolutely everything including
your I-pod accounts. Stick around
the full details coming up later
in the show. This is Category 5
technology TV. Or. Live recordings
or trysted only to solid state
drives. Kingston technology whereby
your computer with improved performance
and reliability over traditional
hard drives a Kingston access Category
5 TV streams live with telescreen
Why are casting in the streamer
to mean every week on Brochu coding
and other HLS video players for
local showtimes visit Category
5 Dog TV category 5 TV is a member
of the tech Podcast Network. If
it's tech it's here. Cat 5 TV slashed
DPN and the International Association
of Internet broadcasters Cat 5
TV sosh IP.Welcome to the show
everyone. This is Category 5 technology
TV so nice to see you. And first
of all I want to say hello to everyone
who's new here this week. Of course
we are kind of in Halloween mode.
Being that it's Halloween week
so it's Friday. Welcome to the
to the holiday week. We're going
to get into that in just a couple
of minutes time. Nice to have you
joining us. We had a discussion
a couple of weeks ago about Star
Trek. It was actually Star Trek
discovery versus the Orrville.
And we keep coming back to this
because it's been a hot topic on
YouTube of course. Boy a lot of
angry trekkies out there. I'll
tell you what. But one particular
comment really stood out to me.
Do you see that one there.Yes from
Razzy 13:12 that's the one. Yes.
Simply put. Imagine if the characters
in Oroville and discovery were
substituted with the characters
from any of the Star Trek series
which one fits more.See. So when
you're thinking hey is discovery
like Star Trek. It's pretty neat.
You think about Captain Picard
on the Orrville it just works on
the Discovery not so much. What
are your thoughts get on to our
YouTube channel. Linux tech show
dot com. That's going to actually
reroute you to the channel and
you're going to be able to find
that just by clicking on videos
and you can get your two cents
cents in our season 10 bit torrent
file is up to you.Yeah it's completely
all loaded now so you can watch
it 100 percent right through you
just like a hundred two gigabytes
of Category 5 TV with.Behind this
behind the scenes and extras and
things like that so head on over
to Torent Dom Category 5 direct
tv. It is a legal way not an illegal
but a legal way to download the
entire season of Category 5 technology
TV absolutely free. We provide
that to you as one of the ways
that you can that you can catch
the show. All right. Yes. Ready
to do this. I am. I want to take
a tour of the Starship Enterprise
I've been looking forward to this
since I was just a wee lad. Seriously.
Oh I said it before I grew up on
NCC 17:1. And I can't wait for
the opportunity to walk through
and actually get a look at the
at the enterprise. This is exciting
exciting. Stick around we're going
to be right whether you shop on
geek here best PNH photo video
eBay or Amazon or even if you want
a free trial of audibles. You'll
find the best deals and support
the shows we produce by simply
visiting the shopping sites you
already frequent by using the links
on our website. Visit category
five dog TV slash partners for
the full and evergrowing list and
help us create more free content
like this show. Thank you for shopping
with our partners. And thank you
for watching. Welcome back to Category
5. Technology TV it's great to
have you here on the Starship Enterprise.
Here we are in the holodeck. As
you can see and it is time for
part 10 of Sasha up build a gaming
PC Wednesday. Oh is it.This is
it. This is that main unveiling.
Well we are actually going to game
stage dash 9 dot code dot uk. Check
it out. These folks are working
really really hard to recreate
the Starship Enterprise. NCC 17:1
D. From the next generation. Now
so much effort has gone into this
using Unreal Engine 4 and it's
literally a tour of the Starship
Enterprise. Now we're using Tonight
we're on Linux and we're using
a pre alpha release. So that means
it's not even alpha yet. It's not
even ready for prime time. We're
probably going to encounter some
glitches we're probably going to
encounter weird things that are
going to be fixed but it's so nice
that they're releasing versions
that we can give a try to. First
of all it works on Linux Mac and
Windows. Cool. If you're a Linux
fan like us please get on over
to stage Dash 9 doc cocotte UK
make sure you reach out to Rob
there and let them know that you
are a big supporter of stage 9
on Linux because we really want
to see them always bringing out
versions for Linux. I know they're
going to do it but they need to
know of course that there is a
Linux gaming community as well
and we want to see how this goes.
So it's a game that we're going
to run on the gaming computer rights
but it's not quite a game yet like
we're not interacting with people
were touring the Starship Enterprise.
This is awesome.You folks ready
get into the chat room Category
5 on Friday and let us know where
you'd like us to go. Now this is
what they endeavor to do. Eventually
this is going to be stage 9 is
going to be a full tour of the
enterprise that you can walk through.
That is true to the blueprints.
That is true too. Attention to
detail based on episodes of the
show. So when you walk in the rooms
you know décor is what you would
expect it to be. So this is a really
really exciting project folks.
And before we get into it we do
need to say that it is a fan project.
Its provided absolutely free. Its
not endorsed by CBS Viacom or Paramount
and all of the trademarks to do
with Star Trek are of course property
of the copyright holders. So this
and the project itself are provided
absolutely free and both the project
stage 9 and this broadcast are
fan productions that are provided
with no monetary compensation.
OK. Ready. Yes. Let's spin the
camera around and hop into the
holodeck. So here we are you ready
to take the tour. Chat Room tell
us where you want us to go. First
of all we're going to head on up
to the main bridge and see if we
can find our way here. Now of course
we're walking down a corridor on
NZC 17:1 de senior Wences wants
us to go to Ran's corridors Rahm's
corridors. It's an option here
is now we're in a turbo lift and
the way that it is working at this
point is they've got their destinations
set up on kind of a computer type
screen because it needs to make
sense for us to be able to find
where we're going.So up on deck
one we've got the main bridge let's
head on up there we want to see
all the detail that's gone into
that And off we go. We're there.
Anyone else feel that this is like
my boy boyhood fantasy is right
here. What does that tell you about
me. All right let's get to a little
bit of a walk around looking out
here. We've got some destruction
out there. What have we got. Look
at that folks just beautiful attention
to detail. This is incredible.
Aren't going to show you before
we really get into kind of game
play and touring the enterprise
let's look at some of the options
that we have here. So first of
all we're on the gaming rig that
has been built on the course of
10 episodes. So let's look at this
low quality setting. So this is
low. Pardon me I didn't hit. OK.
That is not true. There we go.
So that's our low quality setting
which is still pretty fantastic.
But if you've got a poor frame
rate you might you might need that.
Now of course Sasha this is the
gaming rig that you've built. We're
going to try epic right. It's just
really interesting. We're also
going at full 19:20 by 10 A.D.
resolution. We've got everything
just cranked absolutely full. I
turned down the motion blur just
a little bit because I didn't want
you to get dizzy and turned up
the gamma just for the sake of
your TVs because it makes it a
little easier to see things like
the stars.So now that I've done
that now of course there are some
other things I can turn on and
PCs. So if you want to see some
some folks on the bridge and throughout
the enterprise you can actually
turn them on. They are not presently
interactive but they are kind of
cool but they can sometimes get
in the way. So we're going to turn
those guys off and let's restart
and take this right to what you're
going to see when you first connect
to stage 9. Here we are in the
turbo lift outside of the main
bridge and you'll see that when
you restart it actually resets
a couple of the settings I get
turned off and we're going to turn
on animated L cars which apparently
has a performance hit because of
the way that it's done right now.
But it performs well on your system
Sanish. Very cool. All right so
let's head on over here. We're
going to see what what was out
there originally before I did a
little bit of play before the show.
Look at that. That's deep space
nine folks. So we know where we
are. That must be bage or. That's
what I was going to say. Where's
the wormhole. OK so let's head
up here. So you get some of the
interactivity that you would from
a game. We can. Oh dear do I do
it do it do I do it. No.Should
never happen. Who is the joker
who made it so that the only thing
you can blow up is D.S. nine. Come
on. Should have been a Ranjeet
crews are out there or something
Romulans. All right let's take
it to folks. The captain's ready
room here. So you're watching category
five technology TV. And tonight
we are actually taking a tour of
NZC 12:43 D. This is the Enterprise
from Star Trek The Next Generation.
And it is powered by stage nine
and you get it. It's a free download
at stage dash 9. Dom Kotok UK there's
the captain's fish. Cool. Not yet
animated it looks like but cool
again. Great attention to detail.
Looks just like the show. It's
such an incredible job on this
show. All right folks let's see
where the turbo lift can take us.
All right so we've got deck two
is the starboard bow with data's
quarters wharfs quarters cargo
elevator escape pods and a crew
lounge. We've got deck 6 mid-ship
is the transporter room. The science
lab deck seven is the stern with
the arboretum deck 8 is the battle
bridge and we've got stellar cartography
on deck 9. Captain Picard's quarters
on deck 8. The computer core look
at all these shuttles made to and
the brig and the sell store and
the cell control which is the warp
engine control going to give us
some of their main engineering
10 forward and holiday. We've already
been to the Halid X you know what
I would love to see Main Engineering
that somewhere that Jordi and data
spent a lot of timeAnd just love.
Let's see what we can find here.
Now you'll see these force fields
through the night and that simply
means that they haven't completed
that area yet. So you can't go
there. Cool. Nice way to get to
do it. And the corridors just look
absolutely incredible geology lab.
And here we are ladies and gentlemen
main engineering of the Starship
Enterprise you keep hearing pupils
get goosebumps. It's rare that
we get a chance to do this kind
of thing on Category 5 technology
but being our Halloween special
hey it felt right. So the tour
will lift over here now. When a
door doesn't open it means that
it's not part of the network or
it hasn't been completed yet. So
you find the doors that have been
completed and eventually this project
is going to have an entire representation
of the star. Where would you like
to go. Let's go to the sick bay.
All right let's turn to on deck
12 handicap How much of your day
today did you spend touring around
me.It was more like plugging in
cables and making sure things were
going to work. OK so it looks like
the only way we can go is forward
right now this again is true to
the blueprints of the enterprise
so if you're really focused on
episodes of Star Trek The Next
Generation you're really going
to have a sense that wow they've
they've turned the set intoNatural
interactive environment. Just amazing.
So here we are in sick bay folks.
Now let's head on over to Beverley's
office. Here we are. I think we
can sit down if we click yes. There
we go. No way. Unreal engine for
beautifulGet go down there. Here
we go feeling one of the weirdest
dreams tonight. The best dream.
Where to next.Let's check out now.
I'm very interested in the arboretum
and Stellar Cartography. OK let's
head on over to the arboretum which
would be kind of like a garden
on the ship which would be Pretty
cool. Nice place to go read a book
or something. Beautiful artificial
sunlight. Now I'm looking at this
and I'm wondering what kind of
settings we're currentlyJust all
you weren't asking.Oh my goodness
folks if you thought it was incredible
before now it's just truly epic.
Wow. Holy cow I want to go back
and start over. This is just gorgeous.
I was like that's beautiful anyways.
But look at that. Oh wow.It's very
one of the things that they do
need to implement is like saving
of settings I think would be quite
helpful let's you know what can
I head back to Main Engineering
just to see what that looks like.
I'll certainly be proud Because
that's kind of a big deal. Right.
You'll learn your way around. OK
now we've got all. Was that a lens
flare. Wow. Sasha I thought this
was impressive. A few moments ago
here now look at this. So if you've
got the horsepower folks we've
got lighting effects and balloons
and things like that see. Just
awesome. Wow. All right. Let's
let's take the tour. Keep going.
Make sure you're in the chat room
Sasha and I are watching as best
we can to see where you'd like
us to go. What would you like us
to do next. Let's go over to stellar
cartography and see what things
look like over there.I'm just mesmerized
by that. It's incredible.I feel
like I've been here like it's a
deja vu feeling having watched
so many episodes of Star Trek The
Next Generation. So it kind of
feels like this is like living
the fantasy or the dream of what
Star Trek has created.So we've
got to find the right door because
only the doors that are in active
rooms are going to actually let
us in. Oh oh now don't fall off.
This looks like from generations
cool it looks like a bit of a work
in progress. Absolutely beautiful
though the textures there. This
looks awesome. All right now where's
the trouble. There is an emergency
transport feature so if you get
lost you can actually use emergency
transport or if you get outside
and you know of the enterprise
and you can't find your way back
in through a glitch or through
jumping out a shuttle bay or something
like that. Speaking of shuttle
bay do we want to check it out.
Yes let's. And we're off see how
the door opened but didn't open.
That's like one of those kind of
pre-alpha glitches.You just back
up and go go back again. Oh brigge
nice. Muffie them lower the force
field or not. I don't know how
interactive things are just yet.
It's more just for the tour of
it than anything. Awesome. Looks
like to me no way oh oh. I'll talk
to you. You're on my way. Nuclear
waste wherever it ends. OK let's
see what we can do. Open. Source.
It's I think this force field generators
are there. Wow oh now I'm wish
I didn't blow up the last night
because we go and explore it. Oh
sorry. Bad advice bad advice. Shoot
it. It's fine. Yeah. Let's see
if we can actually operate a shuttlecraft.
Can you open me right clicking
and left clicking on the pad. Hoping
that that'll do it. Oh. Oh yeah
you did it.Sweet I think once the
PC model is part of my person it
might be a little bit easier to
to see things like where my hand
is actually pointed because I'm
just aiming into space and hoping
that I'm pushing in the right spot.
There we go. All right. Take it
for a drive. How do we maneuver.
W's not going. Up. There it is.
OK w after a press space. This.
All by themselves it sounds. See
you. As. Like There it is very
cool.Wow. Now we still in epic
mode. To correct the system. I
just want to be absolutely sure.
There it is folks the Starship
Enterprise as per stage 9 So we're
taking off from a shuttle bay in
a shuttle and it's true to where
the shuttle may be located. There's
the bridge up at the top there.
Nice Get on over to stage Dash
9 dog Codein. Uk if you'd like
to check it out. Let's see if we
can find the shuttle the. There
it is. Can i Dockett Coming in
a little fast there Lieutenant
Robbie.Ice the job X X you know
how do I up. There we go Right-Click
to stand up. You open the door.
Now we're stuck in here forever
forever. You can always just press
restart if you're stuck and it
can sometimes happen. Or you can
try the emergency transporter which
is in game and your game menu which
is accessed by the escape key.
The. However sometimesIt works
beautifully. Look at that. Sometimes
the emergency transporter will
take you and place you somewhere
you don't want to be in accord
or where there's no escape. Things
like that. And we've got time for
one more location so chat room.
Tell Sasha where you'd like us
to go.But see here you do. Let's
go to ten forward as a 10 forward
is not what's being said. Yes.
Lynden Ten Forward. All right Linda
here we go.That looks like an entrance
to ten forward.I never did see
one. Oh no way. The bar. Actually
a really cool bar.I'll tie Ten
Forward is a really cool bar. Let's
see if I can. So we're in Ten Forward
we've got to pull a Reicher. Nice.
POLLNER I care. There you have
it folks. Stage Nine from stage
Dash 9 dot co dot uk. Check it
out. It's a free download. Super
super cool. Sasha you need to tell
me of all the places on NZC 17:1
D. Where would you like to do the
news from.Oh can I go to that arboretum
arboretum arboretum. We'll take
you there.Also we'll be right back
after this. Jeff Weston Jubba you're
building a brand new beautiful
Web site. What Are you. You're
a terrible actor. Well here's where
thing comes into play. Oh I don't
know. You're supposed to act. OK.
For Our building a really cool
Web site. Are you building a really
cool Web site. Just because Jeff
is confused doesn't mean you have
to be visit cat 5 dot tv slash
dream host. To sign up for unlimited
web hosting for your web site with
unlimited e-mail accounts. Majeski
while databases. The latest version
of HP Wordpress and more and even
a free domain name registration.
It's less than six dollars per
month so sign up today. Cat 5 dog
TV slashed reme host. Welcome back.
This is Category Five technology
TV and we are looking for the arboretum
on the Starship Enterprise. This
is stage nine and you can find
it at stage dash 9 dot co dot uk.
It's a free download if you want
to check it out if you want to
take a tour for yourself of the
enterprise. In the meantime there's
our shot. We're going to be in
Sasha RickmanThrough the magic
of TV. We are in the NEWSROOM in
the news arboretum. That's right.
This is where I want to be every
week now. Right here are the stories
we're covering this week in the
category five TV news room a bot
net of unknown intent has been
discovered and is spreading at
a frightening rate. Google's Project
Loon has brought Internet and cellular
service to hurricane devastated
Puerto Rico. Samsung hopes to succeed
where other vendors have failed.
They want to bring the full desktop
Linux experience to smartphones.
And do you have ultimate player
or a full X on your Mac. You might
need to wipe everything and reinstall
Mac OS because of a nasty bit of
malware that came with their popular
software and it's giving hackers
full access to absolutely everything
including your iCloud account.
These stories are coming right
up. Don't go anywhere.You've got
mad skills. Now hone them learn
new skills or improve your existing
ones with online video tutorials
and training from Lynda.com through
our special link at Cat 5 dot tv
slash Linda learn software technology
creative and business skills. You
can use today to help you achieve
your professional goals. Join today
and start learning. We'll give
you this chance to try it. Absolutely
free with unlimited access to all
of the courses. Sign up now for
FREE. Cat 5 dot tv slash Linda
this is the category 5 TV news
we're covering the week's top stories
with a. SlightLinux bias. I'm sad
you're ignorant and here are the
top stories we're following this
week as we speak miscreant's are
assembling a massive army of hacked
Internet of Things devices and
at a much faster rate than previous
butternuts. This new cyber militia
of compromise gadgets dubbed Iowa
t underscore a reaper or Reaper
by experts. Key 360 not lab can
be instructed by its masters to
attack Web sites and kick services
off line. The bought nets footsoldiers
mainly Frasse ganged Internet connected
cameras home routers and similar
gear are located in more than a
million organizations globally
claims security is Checkpoint on
Thursday. At first it was assumed
the malware the malware that was
infected gizmo that infected gizmo's
to form this latest Army was a
variant of the Myrrha I bought
it. That took over hundreds of
thousands of Internet connected
equipment in 2016. However security
researchers now think it's actually
another family of malicious software.
There's no word yet on what exactly
the botnet will be used for either
the reaper malware is spreading
globally by exploiting various
vulnerabilities and embedded devices
such as C-v dashed 20:17 dash 80
to 25 to steal and use the use
and use the usernames and passwords
of the gadgets web based control
panels. Ultimately to commandeer
them for example one of the bot
nets drones a hacked camera running
a go ahead embedded web server
on TCAP port 80 one had system
dot I and I file that had changed
to include a netcat command that
opened a reverse shell a backdoor.
In other words this gave the reaper
masters the command line to the
device. Once the bought malware
was on the computer it then attempted
to infect other equipment on the
internet and he subsequently hacked
device would also cruise up and
down the information superhighway
in search of a more and more vulnerable
gizmo's to hijack. Right now check
to make sure you're not exposing
a vulnerable device to the Internet.
Apply patches if you can. Look
out for suspicious behavior on
your network and take a gadget
off line if it's infected. Wow.
OK so my thought is OK what's the
end game in this. Is this like
leading to something where everything
will be in line and then we'll
see a major attack. Once everything
is kind of are you asking me to
create a conspiracy theory Right
or like or is it just like an experiment
where like perhaps it's very benign.
Maybe it's just like let's see
what we can do.We've spoken on
the show previously about malicious
software as a form of warfare and
we tend to we tend to not quite
grasp that as warfare to us is
more right. So to think that there
would be cyber warfare. It's really
really hard to get our heads around.
So when you talk about an infection
of this scale. So answer. These
are Internet connected devices
so home routers and cameras and
things like that that have internet
connectivity apps and don't feel
like everything now has Internet.
You know that really does. Yeah.
The Internet where if the devices
are exploited now you've got thousands
potentially millions of devices
that create. You've heard the term
bought it. So let's you know when
we hear botnet we think OK well
that's some kind of virus or some
kind of malware Well it's not exactly
like that. Think about a supercomputer
right now. What is a supercomputer.
It's basically thousands of individual
computers connected together and
created to be one super computer.
So there's the power of thousands
of other computers all connected
together to give the power of one
supercomputer. OK. So with the
internet of things being compromised
in this particular manner. Now
all of these modems and all of
these cameras and all of these
devices that are Internet connected
we've heard about in the news previously
even pop machines at colleges are
Internet connected so that they
can update things and change things
right remotely. And they were compromised
as well in a in a different attack.
So now they become part of the
bought that part of the super computer.
So why does a malicious person
or group of people create a supercomputer.
It's to be able to process astronomical
amounts of data at unfathomable
rates. Right. So in legitimate
business that's done by creating
supercomputers creating it in spot
and that's in a manner of speaking
creating legitimate supercomputers.
That's what Google has That's what
Amazon has That's what Facebook
has. They've got supercomputers.
So this is not a legitimate means
of doing it. This is a malicious
way of somebody who knows who creating
a supercomputer is it to find a
cure for cancer. Probably not.
It's not like a college experiment
perhaps.Not likely. I mean it could
be what that particular college
student when they handed in their
thesis is going to jail. So it's
not a wise thing. Right. Heard
of stories like that where someone
thinks they're going to figure
out something in security and they
end up going to jail. So that's
that is pretty unlikely.So the
only way to protect yourself is
to take your devices off line and
keep them off line. Not necessarily.
Now these particular kinds of exploits
happened because of back doors
in the systems in particular things
like leaving the password default
like one one one 1 like every password
as well when your internet service
provider shows up and installs
your internet at your new house.
They give you a modem and they
say here's the password for the
Wi-Fi and you put it in your phone.
Now you've got internet and it
works. So you're happy. But what
you're not realizing is that that
device you're using the default
password the service provider has
that password. Other people have
that password and that password
is quite easily compromised as
well. So that's one particular
instance of a device that has a
default password. You think about
the internet of things you've got
a toaster that is Internet connected
for some crazy reason. Right. Because
this exists it matches a fridge
makes sense. I mean you can put
your shopping list on the fridge
and you can and it's Internet connected.
My toothbrush talks to my phone.
There you go. So these Internet
connected devices. Do you ever
think to change the password on
your fridge. Thinking someone is
going to compromise it. Right.
We don't really clue into that
until now somebody through the
Internet has gotten through the
default passwords and things like
that. Right. Sometimes changes
the passwords so you no longer
have access.And then you're part
of this botnet which is quite potentially
to be used for cyber warfare which
is a bad thing. Wow. Yeah. Things
will change your password change
your password change your passwords
and if you if you think you've
been compromised you may have to
wipe the device and start over
with a fresh firmware. That's that's
just the nature of it. Wow. Thank
you. All right. Mobile phone data
services have been boosted in blacked
out areas of hurricane hit Puerto
Rico by balloons that were provided
by Google's parent company alphabet
Project Loon devices beam signals
between each other and to users
on the ground. This extends communication
networks and places where infrastructure
is scarce or has been damaged.
The balloons will allow residents
with LTE phones to send and receive
text messages and access the web.
However much of the country is
still without electricity and more
than a quarter of the population
lacks safe drinking water. Alister
Wesker head of surgical loon said
this is the first time we've used
our new machine learning powered
algorithms to keep balloons clustered
over Puerto Rico. So we're still
learning how to best do this. As
we get more familiar with the constantly
shifting winds in this region we
hope to keep the balloons over
areas where connectivity is needed
for as long as possible. So these
balloons are powered by a high
brightness a manner of speaking.
So you think about a hot air balloon
it can only go up or down but you
go up or down in order to control
its horizontal movement as well
because you can follow wind drifts
and things like that. So by monitoring
the air flow by monitoring conditions
the artificial intelligence if
you will it's machine learning
is essentially what it is. So it's
pretty simple as far as the algorithms
themselves go but it learns from
its own mistakes. So if it goes
up when it should have gone down
it's going to go oh maybe next
time I'll go down when I think
I should go up. And so it learns
and it evolves and it becomes smarter
in a great way. You know what.
Pretty cool stuff. So to have stayed
over. Now their first test flight
at Alpha that or X was a little
while ago and stayed up. For three
months. A little over three miles.
Wow. Without men controlling it.
Like right sort of person controlling
it. So it's pretty cool.Nice. Now
what's what does the LTTE mean
like if your phone didn't have
LTE. It's just the great of the
service. OK. Fast Internet is LTE
on your phone. OK. So if you if
you have anything less. So basically
in a in a war torn place or in
a devastated by Hurricane place
like Puerto Rico you'd be looking
at high speed Internet on your
phone like we're talking 25 megabits
per second on your phone in a place
like that provided by a balloon
that's perfect and you can let
people know where you are and that
you're safe. Very cool. My wife
made an interesting point if I
may. Yes. Because I always thought
Oh that's great. They can let people
overseas know if they've got family
and stuff and I made the comment
that if we really clicked for me.
But they can now communicate with
one another. Well the infrastructure
is there now to communicate with
people in the same town and be
able to reach out and say you know
how are you doing. Or you know
do you need me to bring anything
or whatever else. I mean phones
are the main way to communicate
so well and you've got now you've
got e-mail text phone everything
on LTE. Very cool. Speaking of
phones Samsung wants to bring the
full power of desktop Linux to
smartphones the most vile giant
announced this week that the Linux
on Galaxy project will give smartphones
the capability to run Linux based
distributions on mobile devices.
So if you dream of using the smartphone
in your pocket as a desktop Linux
PC you'll be pleased to know that
Samsung clearly shares the same
dream Linux on Galaxy will based
on the information currently available
be distributed as an app.It will
be able to run multiple operating
systems likely including a boon
to Linux distros run on the exact
same Linux kernel that Android
users and with no virtualization
or emulation involved performance
theoretically should be excellent.
But the true power will be unlocked
when used with the Samsung daks
desktop dock accessory. This allows
compatible phones to connect to
an external display mouse and keyboard
and other peripherals. The Samsung
Galaxy phone already allows users
to use Android apps with a larger
screen with a desktop style Android
UI. When docs docked with the D
E X bot while Android s is great
as a smartphone and tablet OS it's
not so hot as a desktop one. Sansome
Sam Sung's says its users who want
the convenience of their mobile
devices but also sometimes need
the tried and true desktop computing
environment especially when it
comes to interacting with productivity
tools and entertainment content
that are best viewed on a larger
monitor. Linux on Galaxy is still
in the early stages of development.
There's no word on which devices
the initiative plans to support
so I wouldn't suggest rushing out
to buy something Samsung branded
just yet. Motorola Microsoft and
canonical all tried and failed
to bring convergence to the masses.
Can the smartphone giant Samsung
succeed where others have failed.
Let us know what you think in the
comments. Wow. Now why has converge
failed if it's failed with all
of the other platforms. Why would
Samsung go ahead and pick it up.
Yeah why would they start making
something that has already failed
by everyone else so you know I
don't have an exact answer to that
I can speculate a little bit. You
think about iPhones right. And
you think about Android and Google
and these are all familiar household
names. There's a couple of different
things about them. First of all
they've got an app store that is
filled chock full of stuff. So
you're not going to just switch
phone providers to switch phone
glasses to a phone that doesn't
have all the apps that you usually
use. It just doesn't make any sense
to you. I know with me when I got
BlackBerry it didn't make any sense
because they had disconnected the
Facebook app. There was no Skype.
It just was useless to me. Right.
So. So that's kind of the same
kind of scenario I would expect.
The app store would be a big thing
but also iPhone Android Google
Samsung LG these are all names
that when you hear them you think
there are good phones. I know these
names even if you don't really
know these names you know these
names. So if Ubuntu Canonical comes
out with Ubuntu phone and it's
some obscure manufacturer that
nobody has ever heard of. Right.
We're not really going to jump
on the bandwagon and it's so it's
such a shame because they may be
fantastic phones. Who knows.But
they need the name Samsung on the
other hand is one of those names
that may be able to pull this off
just based on their name alone.
Right. And maybe enough to dig
them out of the dirt. Yeah they've
had a rough time of late. So this
would be a really good way for
them to get it.They can do it without
blowing up your docking station
would be great. So to be clear
I think I imagine just quickly
because we're running low on time
take your phone plug it into the
monitor now your monitor lights
up with the phone display and you've
got your keyboard and mouse and
it becomes a computer but it's
got Linux on it so it's not a phone
OS so you're not feeling like you
know the ones you don't where you've
got to swipe like a tablet connected
to a screen. It just doesn't make
any sense. Yeah.It turns into a
desktop operating system sort of
reminds me of like that Nintendo
switch ideology a little bit right
where it switches to the big screen
and then it's ice seamlessly. Wow.
All right. So it's going to be
an unpleasant week for some Mac
users who are facing a complete
system wipe and reinstall after
hackers stashed malware in legitimate
applications. Tim software which
makes the popular media player
and download manager has confessed.
The latest version of these two
apps came with an welcome extra
the rather horrid horrid OS X.
Proton malware the bot which was
injected into downloads of the
applications was spotted by security
shop Isa which alerted Dell Media.
A subsequent investigation revealed
miscreant's had got into the developers
servers implanted the malware into
the download files and then left
the company in fact its users as
they fetched the software. Proton
is a remote control Trojan designed
specifically for Mac systems. It
opens a back door granting route
level command line access to commandeer
the computer and conceal passwords
encryption and VPN keys as well
as crypto currencies from infected
systems. That's Bitcoin. It can
even gain access to victims. I
cloud account regardless of whether
to factor if education is used
or not. It warns that a total system
OS reinstall is the only guaranteed
way to totally rid your system
of this malware. Wow. So how would
you know if you've been infected.
That's a good question now. There
is a lot of information out there
for Mac users. So you know there
are particular files that this
Trojan leaves behind on your hard
drive so it makes it fairly obvious
that you're infected by finding
these files. Ok off the top of
my head I don't know what those
files are but you'll find those
if you go to any security bulletin
about this malware bytes is a fantastic
source and in fact malware bytes
for Mac will not only detect but
remove residual residue of this
Trojan. Oh I think he said is right
though. Because this thing has
root level access that means it
is the super user on your Mac.
Even Malware Bytes can't guarantee
that it has removed everything
that's happened because it's a
backdoor so the hackers may have
already remolded into your computer
and done other things that Malware
Bytes would have no way to know
whether or not it.So you would
be best just to assume that you're
in fact. No no. Find out if you
are by checking for those files
or an easy peasy way is install
malware bytes for Mac and run a
scan. OK if it detects the. Malware
then we know that hey we've got
it. Probably just to be safe. You
can remove it because of the nature
of this one. You have no way to
know whether or not they put other
things in their rights. That's
the tough thing here. So that's
why I use that says a system wipe
is the only way to know that you
are clean from this one infected.
That's brutal. That is horrible.
Mac users tend to think that they're
safe. Of course they do yes. Well
Big thanks. This week to ride w
Nash and our community of viewers
for submitting stories to us. Thanks
for watching the category 5 TV
newsroom. Don't forget to like
and subscribe for all your tech
news with a slight Linux bias.
And for more free content. Be sure
to check out our Web site. From
the category 5 TV newsroom I'm
Sasha Brickman.Thanks. This is
Category Five technology TV. Let's
bring back to the holodeck. All
right. Just like Us we wouldn't
have fun. That was amazing. Your
gaming computer even in epic mode
is sick as the kiddos say hi I'm
lovin it. So I'm gonna pack this
thing up and take it home with
me now.No this one is for Dave.
So Dave you are in the audience.
Awesome Yes Dave is right behind
the camera. Thank you so much.
This is both a wedding gift and
a birthday gift and it's not just
for me but it's from all of Category
5. So we've had. It's from all
of Category 5 so we've had all
of the viewers from everywhere.
Just helping pick the parts of
the computer ráby guiding me through
battling it. We've had countless
lives.I was like don't do that.
Don't put it there. No.Now now
that this is over you can watch
the entire series.You can like
us on Facebook again. Yeah. So
it's a sweet gaming rig. Let's
go over a little bit of the hardware
here just so you know what you're
getting. You is a seventh gen Intel
Core desktop. Seven seventy seven
hundred k. It's overclocked is
4.5 gigahertz. It is sweet. The
motherboard is in the Seuss Republic
of gamer Maximus 8. That's the
hero and it is also sweet. It's
a gaming motherboard. The cooling
system is like a Thermaltake contact
silent 12. Nice and quiet. The
RAM. This is beautiful Kingston.
Hyper X fury gaming RAM. Not only
that but 32 gigabytes of it. The
system can take up to 64 but we
put 32 in there so to be dual channel
it could be as fast as can be and
it gives you the chance that if
you ever need more than that which
I know you're never going to need.
You can go that route. We've got
an end to solid state drive which
is a chip on the motherboard that
sash install that's got the operating
system which is Linux game in the
can never win that game. The gaming
OS of Linux it's awesome it's very
it's based on a boom too and it
works great so that is a Kingston.
Kingston digital 240 gig SSD now
M.Com to six gigabits per second
sweet little thing and that's got
your OS but we knew that you'd
have like family photos videos
things like that that you're going
to need to be able to store on
here and and m.com to 240 gigs
is going to fill up pretty quick
so we stuck a terabyte Kingston
drive in there as well.It's an
SSD. It's the hyper X savage. So
that means it's super fast is ready
for gaming it is screaming for
you. The GP. This is a killer unit
that's the graphics processing
unit right. VR ready. It's got
several HDMI as well as display
port vr output and a DVD. So it's
ready for headsets if you ever
want to get into VR gaming things
like that. In the meantime it will
hook up to your big TV as well.
That's the GTA x 10 70 overclocked
edition and that's ready for 4
K right out of the box. Then we've
got the power supply is a dreamy
Corsair RMX 850 X. It's an 850
watt power supply fully modular
so the cables are nice unhidden
you don't you don't see any extra
cables there. The chassis is this
beautiful Thermaltake versus the
22 Black Edition. It lights up
you can change the colors whatever
you want to do then keyboard mouse
you've got a wireless gaming keyboard
a mouse that's pretty sweet. Then
we've got. That's it. That's how
it's going to get right. Yeah I
mean you don't need to mention
Arctic Silver.That's right. Boring
stuff with that little paste stuff.
Yeah yeah yeah. And we glued a
thing on nothing.So the final thing
we need to know what you're going
to plug this into when you take
it home. So like do you have a
power bar or something like that.
Yes. Yeah it's it's like a surge
protector power bartering like
bar like in words when you bought
it you didn't really know what
you were looking for it just had
enough outlets to plug your TV
in.Yeah yeah. OK so that's why
Category 5. And viewers of Category
5 come together to get you a Cyberpower
CPE 1000 AVR U.P.S.. So this is
a battery backup that you can hook
up your new computer to it. Also
you can plug your TV into it as
well. This has five battery backup
ports and nine surge protected
ports. It's guaranteed that it
will protect your data your fire
your hardware. I should say from
lightning and surge protection
and it's got the LCD it's got auto
shutdown software all the works.
And I got one that was nice and
small even though it's a thousand
volt helps. It's small. So it can
fit behind your TV cabinet and
things like that. So folks your
donations your contributions to
their kind of wedding gift fund
for this project also went toward
this. So that's the thousand volt
amp Cyberpower with AVR.So that's
automated voltage regulation. So
that means if the power Brown's
out it will also protect nice things
going.You still watch TV when the
powers that be nice.I want to absolutely
personally thank each and every
one of you for your kind words
your support your advice your donations
your time. Thank you. It was fun
so much it was a blast. It was
a scary blast. It was a blast.
And so this thing with their own
hands so just so you know and I
watch the video to see that if
you haven't seen the series yet
you're wonder what are we on about
this sweet gaming rig that we played
on tonight. Is it a beautiful gaming
computer Sasha built it it's her
first computer build. And I just
kind of oversaw things to help
make sure that things went in correctly
and the right way around and stuff
like that. You can find out more
about it you can see the entire
series and find our shopping list
at Cat 5 dot tv slash CPQ 20:17.
It's all there folks so hope you
enjoy the game. Have fun. Hope
you enjoyed the show folks and
we'll see you next Wednesday night.