welcome to category 5 technology tv this
is the kickoff of season 14.
how exciting is that that the 14
season 14 i know in our 14th year and
and
season 13 is behind us i was reminiscing
well
it's nice to have season 13 behind us
yeah because season 13 had a whole lot
of challenges that came with it
uh but i was reminiscing with somebody
today about
the first season of category five and
how
there wasn't a studio like this it was
a webcam a 320p webcam we've come a long
way
a long way my name is robbie ferguson
it's nice to have you joining us
and i'm jeff weston that guy i'm happy
to be here
me too it's good times hey make sure you
click on that subscribe button that's
going to make sure that you get notified
as soon as we go live or whenever we
post new
exciting videos and for season 14 we've
got a lot of exciting stuff planned for
you
we are booking ahead and uh and we were
talking before the show
like we are booked into december that is
how much content we have
coming your way and it's just going to
grow and grow this
this year is going to be absolutely
incredible and i'm so
very thankful to have you along with us
um just a note as we kick off season 14
with season 13 behind us that means
you can download the entirety of season
in 2k ultra hd ultra widescreen glory
via bittorrent head on over to
torrent.category5.tv last i checked we
had
several seeds there and you can download
the entire
season not only that you can download
all seasons all 13 seasons you want to
see
season one where i was just sitting in
front of a webcam
crazy hey the content has changed a lot
since then but so much so
make sure you get over to
torrent.category5.tv
download that enjoy it and see how far
the show has come even in the past year
i mean season 13 was a time of
transition for us
yes moving into this great new studio
here at studio e
and all the changes that have come
because of the covet 19 pandemic
which have really you know that's forced
a lot of businesses to change the way
they do things and and so
we're doing the same we're kind of
evolving with this new landscape that
uh that is before us and learning how we
can broadcast
uh in this kind of uh in in
a new broadcast realm in a way i mean
interviews are different we're not
having people into the studio as much
we we're going to be doing a lot of
stuff remotely and
and you're going to see some incredible
stuff coming your way and we're going to
do our best to make it
really really good and really exciting
speaking of uh really really good i love
your shirt
thanks man oh yeah shirts are new that's
nice
that's snazzy and here i've just i've
got my suit jacket oh that's your thing
that's your thing man that's like that's
that's your look
yeah all right all right well hey
tonight we've got a fun
show for you uh we have our theme song
that
we've used since season one and when i
started this show
with that webcam in front of me and the
rode nt1 microphone in front of me
i actually played the theme song out of
speaker
so that the microphone would pick it up
is that how you did it didn't have the
technology to
like we didn't have mixing consoles and
right
oh yes so these days however
we've stepped things up a little bit in
the technology department yeah but it's
time to freshen up the song as well
so today we're gonna jump on fiverr
we're gonna find
at least a few artists that we
like okay and we're gonna see what it
takes
to get a retro 8-bit remix
of the category 5 theme song that's
coming right up stick around
[Music]
here i am on the bridge of the category
5 tv network this is where it all comes
together
this is where the magic happens this is
where i do all the editing of category 5
technology tv and everything else that
goes into
such a broadcast we've been on the air
for now well this
kicks off season 14 and from seasons 1
through to season 12 we used a track
called
cupid's migration by my buddy mick
griffin
as our theme song and for season 13
mick himself remixed it for us but here
we are season 14 kicks off today
and it's time to spice things up a
little bit
so what are we going to do we're going
to get on fiverr and find ourselves
a remix what i've done is i've uploaded
it to
my github so i've created a new
repository called cat5 tv
underscore theme song and it has the
original dot
mp3 from nick rippon and i've then
cloned that to my server so category 5
dot tv slash cat5
tv underscore theme song slash original
dot mp3 happens to be
that same track so we're going to be
able to send this link
to uh to anyone who is going to be
producing
on fiverr let's get a peek here okay so
i've created
a file here that is going to tell them
that's where the file is
all right couple of key points here
let's jump back over to gold wave
as far as the intro goes
backing up all right that's cool so
key points
kind of builds right here this is where
it starts
but i want it to i want our focus to be
on this guy
all right so that melody comes in at
29 seconds okay so i've
asked for that to be emphasized um okay
i'm looking for a remix
that makes you
want to uh that puts a spring in your
stack
give it a good groove
[Music]
breakdown starts at 1 14. it'll be for
our intro
of the webcast so the build should be
pretty pronounced
but happen rather quickly i can always
cut pieces up and move them around but
imagine a quick verbal intro
where we say here's what's coming up and
then our logo flies in and the melody
drops
etc all right
now if you're not yet familiar with
fiverr think of it like an online
classified service but
instead of buying and selling goods
we're buying and selling within the gig
economy
so you're hiring freelancers who will
share their talent and their skills with
you
or if you want to sell your talent and
skills within the gig economy
fiverr is a place to do that now as a
partner of this video
you can actually use our link and i
would appreciate it if you would
because that will give us a bit of a
kickback but go to cat5
dot tv slash fiverr and that will take
you to their website and you will
receive
20 off when you sign up and place your
first order
if you use our link cat5 dot tv
slash fiverr so let's head there
[Applause]
and i'm gonna do a quick search because
i know what i'm looking for
i want chiptune oh i accidentally put an
s in there but it corrected it for us
first option is 6.99 let's give it a
listen
that is not a chiptune gangnam style
here's one for 50 bucks
okay that's pretty good but let's say
our budget is
50 altogether so let's say
we want to spend because i want to have
more than one to choose from let's say
between one and eighteen dollars
this is 14 bucks
and this is lincoln park in 8-bit
get ready for it my very first collab
with osison because this is happening
it starts with one thing i don't know
why
it doesn't even matter how hard you try
that's cool
[Music]
let's skip up to the chorus
do you hear that
that is awesome let's check out what
else they've done here
[Music]
definitely a good vibe not what i'm
looking for but
right
[Music]
[Applause]
oh that slide
[Music]
nice
okay i don't know how you're gonna get
that on an 8-bit computer
that kind of flanging going on
so not quite authentic but that is
[Music]
let's just meld two eras together here
beautifully done really i mean so what
i'm sensing from
aussies in aussies
is a real understanding for that
chiptune
feel but then has kind of adapted some
more modern
uh effects and some of the things that
couldn't have been possible back in the
chip's tune days
um and i'm talking like the early days
of 8-bit nintendo and things like that
but i love that first track so i'm going
to set this one aside definitely for 14
bucks that's worth going back to
this this one we looked at yeah okay
and this one's got mario bros not
8-bit
that is so again we're melding two
different eras here and i'm not i'm not
digging that
[Music]
i love what emma ement has done here is
that
there's an echo that gives the sense of
a more modern effect but it is still
using what was possible at that time
so we've created something they've
created something here that
i haven't heard before but shirley is
[Music]
authentic
okay what else have they done
i love that
[Music]
that insane vibrato
oh they did it again that
like bringing in this echo that
is so authentic but yet so fresh
well done
[Music]
now we've got some stereophonics going
on here
that we didn't have in the 8-bit days
but i do like it
[Music]
[Applause]
oh i could totally groove to that
[Music]
see that's got that you know you're
walking
[Music]
and you just got a spring in your step
it's a little bit low tempo for what we
want but
it has that
[Music]
okay now we're getting into elevator
music but what i'm hearing and what i'm
liking is the ability to take
authentic sounds and put a spin on them
like that echo
effect it's not delay it is actually the
the instrument being re-resampled re
repositioned and and uh put into the
sequence
in such a way that it sounds like an
echo but it is just part of the sequence
i really really like that and while i
want this to be an authentic
8-bit chip remix i kind of like what
they've done there with adding some
stereophonics to it i think that works
really well and it brings it into
2020 in such a way that it still sounds
authentic
but it has a bit more fullness than just
being straight down the middle
monophonic
so i dig that a lot i'm going to keep
that one open
i like that
so authentic but yet has like a really
good groove
very modern sounding that's awesome
breakdown yes dude you are a time
traveler
where were you in the mod cracker day
seriously
oh oh i just want to hear through to the
end
okay litterae squirrel knows what
they're doing
definitely a musician all through and
through all right what else you got for
[Applause]
[Music]
us
all right not into that
[Music]
that first track okay this has got more
more of a vibe
[Music]
literary squirrel again has put one
instrument
fully on the left and then the rest is
kind of
in space here but that base is
now it's moved into the middle okay
that's pretty neat
lots of
[Music]
i demos the arpeggio
it kind of felt like it was going to
build and then it dropped off into like
a churchy
kind of sound to it which i didn't
really like how it dropped down rather
than building up
okay we've stepped too far outside of
the genre that
first track from literary squirrel
though was so good
that i and the price is seven dollars
that i have to hear what literary
squirrel is going to do with our
with our uh theme song let's move on
there's such a fine line between
fidelity
and authenticity and i think that that's
what i'm hearing is that
i i'm looking for something with higher
fidelity
higher like production quality but the
authenticity of that
is fantastic it's just too
like ultra compressed it's like the
levels are just straight across the
board
just it doesn't have the dynamics that i
hope for
[Music]
it's so cute
i wasn't looking for cute though
wow he's playing it
[Music]
i just imagine that most of these folks
are sequencing but he's actually playing
it
hello hello my name is gabriel perez
gabrielle
nice to meet you pose and produce music
for your video game thank you
play it for me okay that is
way too epic
can you imagine category five all right
there we go
[Music]
was that supertax
i got to back that up is it just me or
was that super tux let's jump back on
that
[Music]
hello
what's that watermarked in the
background that is
super tucks nice 10 points for
open source but not quite the sound i'm
looking for
sorry but it was nice to meet you
gabrielle
no i don't need lessons i'm nico and
what i'm talking to you today
is to create a fabulous video game free
mix of your song
sounds good it can be a 16-bit remix or
an
8-bit rings
thank you
[Music]
i kind of dig what nico's doing
[Applause]
yeah not into that one
so those first three are kind of what
i'm you know
thinking but i i nico is seven dollars
so i want to give nico a chance to try
this out
and see what he can come up with so i'm
going to go about
placing the order let's see what these
four
musicians can come up with
[Music]
[Applause]
uh okay this is one that has basic
standard and premium
so basic is high quality audio file
commercial use one instrument
one instrument isn't enough standard
a one minute long track unlimited
instrumentation
commercial use one revision
35 bucks though it's gonna push us over
budget
i can't wait to hear what amnet comes
out with though
let's do it
[Music]
okay and on to azeez and
think with aussies and they've nailed it
they've nailed that
like creating a track that has that
authentic feel
and i don't really need to make much as
far as comments go i like what they're
doing
so let's just move forward
if you're enjoying this so far please
give me a thumbs up i'd appreciate that
very much and in the meantime i've
placed
all four orders and when we come back
we're gonna hear our first results stick
around
[Music]
[Applause]
um so let's take a quick look at some of
the ones that have been
submitted so far so literary squirrel
you remember
has an exceptional demo track
and has sent me a couple of demos so far
and let's give a quick listen to the
most current because the first one that
he sent the melody was a little bit off
and i had said
um maybe take a look at the melody give
a listen to my track and then come back
to me
with uh with a new demo and see how
things look so let's give a listen here
to what we've got so far from literary
[Music]
squirrel
you feel that it's got that bob
definitely nailed that kind of
groove that i was looking for
[Music]
now the intro is getting a little bit
long but i can cut that up
nowhere okay
so what i'm hearing there is we're still
having trouble nailing that lead melody
and what i realized through my
conversation with literary squirrel
is something that i never thought of
before because i very much
hear music by ear i'm not a sheet music
person at all i don't understand
notation at all but when i hear a song i
can tinker it out on the
on the keyboard and come up with a melod
like i can recreate the melody because i
play by ear but
i feel like literary squirrel is not one
of those people who plays by ear but
rather plays by sheet music by notation
and so
i had suggested maybe what i can do is
i'm gonna i'm gonna
film my hands tinkering this out on the
piano at home so that you can see the
notes that
that it should be because we're not
quite there i can i can hear that he's
he's hitting the the the right like
timing
but the notes are off so let's let's
[Music]
listen
see what i mean
[Music]
so he's just not hearing at the way that
those of us who
play by ear hear music so it's just a
little bit different and it's kind of
interesting isn't it
um but he's nailing the the the overall
kind of concept of what i was looking
for i really dig
that groove it feels good to like
i'm just kind of i want to go like this
as i'm listening to that but as soon as
the melody comes in it should be the
uh so in his case let's let's hear
because he's playing it in a minor
[Music]
i'm going to play it on the piano
tonight let's switch to that clip
[Music]
so the next one in line let's see here
and i'm just on fiverr here so
mnet has submitted a couple of versions
of the track as well so let's give a
quick listen
[Music]
again we're just a little bit off on
that melody
just a touch
nailed like everything else i'm really
kind of digging that
um i am hearing it's a little bit too
full for a chiptune like to be genuinely
8-bit
we were limited to 4 tracks back in the
day so
there's a lot going on there when the
beat comes in there's like
that just feels a little bit too much
for the
for that era i feel like there's just
too much going on
so i'm going to request that uh that
eminent
kind of pulls that back a little bit i
feel like
he's really nailing kind of the
reminiscence of the original but
it's got to have something a little bit
fresh there like it's a little bit
i guess i would say on the fence of
being a little
too close to the original like if you
listen to that
i'm just gonna push play again here
like that just feels a little bit
too close to the original almost like
it's like a
like just a a one-to-one
kind of recreation i'm looking for a bit
more
of a remix so we'll see what uh what
mnet can do with that
all right so let's move on to our next
one here
and that is nico igorovich
nico what do you have for us here we are
here is nico's
submission let's give it a listen
[Music]
take it off
nico took me literally and put footsteps
so we got literal footsteps there not
exactly what i was talking about when i
said like picture yourself taking a walk
nailing a lot of it but that lead melody
there was just that one point where
it was just a little bit off so i'd like
you to kind of rework that a little bit
nico
um and and maybe what we'll do is
instead of fading out the end there
just kind of end it on like a or some
kind of a downbeat
of some sort i'm starting to hear that
where you know so i'm envisioning how
this is going to be as like an
intro video or something like that so i
kind of want a little bit of a
quieter intro and then the melody
and then a so that it's right into all
right
welcome to the show and we're we're
ongoing so
maybe if nico could implement a couple
of those things tweak that melody just a
little bit
we definitely have that 8-bit vibe going
and i
love that niko agorovich is charging me
in total after all my fees and
everything else 9.77
canadian which blows my mind
let's give a listen to nico's latest
submission
here it is
[Music]
much more reminiscent of the original
yet
very much 8-bit
[Music]
yes
nice so then it's straight into the show
welcome to the show
i'm robbie i heard one off note there
in the melody line
see what he's done there he's gone
[Music]
so going down on that note um so i'd
like to have him
take a quick peek at that that's a
really simple revision though i would
expect
dragging one note down as long as he's
not actually playing this out
on a keyboard and having to redo entire
bits but it seems to me like that's
probably something that he can just pull
together in the sequencer if he's
sequencing
so here's hoping uh all right i've also
got another submission from
emnit and amnet um has been a joy to
work with
and uh all of these gents have been um
but eminent
is like so like right in tune with my
mentality as far as like good customer
support he's always like
thank you so much for your great
feedback and
all this kind of stuff so like over the
top really good customer service as well
as a very talented musician
um let's give a listen to what he's done
after
i've kind of so my requests have been
with regards to
like really kind of pulling back um it
was a little too busy because it felt
like
even though it had that 8-bit sound it
was doing
so much that it was like 16 tracks
versus the four that we were limited to
so let's see
how he's been able to simplify that pull
it back this is eminence new submission
for us
[Music]
oh nice
[Applause]
[Music]
staccato
[Applause]
[Music]
oh i love that arpeggio
that's fresh
[Music]
sweet
so like nailing the nuances of the
original track while bringing it into
the 8-bit era
i just want to see that hear that ending
changed
to end on a downbeat no fade outs i know
the original had that
and maybe that's unfair because that
wasn't part of my original specs
but i'm gonna ask eminent to do that
anyways and see what he comes up with
because now as i'm hearing these demos i
start to understand
more of what i'd like to hear because
i'm hearing some of the things i like
and some of the things i don't like so
it gives me a chance
to really evolve my vision for this
well i'm sure you can feel it as well as
i can we are so
close now i haven't yet received a
submission from jose's and
however he has been in communication
with me just to let me know that
life is a little bit too busy right now
and he's
asked for an extension so i'm fine with
that i understand that
you know it can be really really busy
and i would rather
lean toward um quality than speed
so let's give him an extra day and see
if he's able to come up with it for us
i'm perfectly fine with that so i think
as you go into fiverr you know
use use those dates that they give you
initially as a bit of an arbitrary date
unless you're
really really in a hurry then make sure
you are very very upfront with the
artists
or whoever it is that you're hiring to
say look i really need to achieve this
deadline can you do it because
i have found i mean like these are
freelancers people that are working from
home
in a lot of cases these days and uh and
so it's a
you know you've got to be upfront and
honest and i think i've been that and
i've let jose's know
hey if you need an extra day take it i
really would like to have it done by
then because i'd like to do this feature
uh but if you need more time i'd rather
lean toward quality
so take your time take all the time you
need and keep me posted basically
so but in the meantime i've received
three other submissions
and revisions since the last time i
checked in with you
so first of all nico igorovich has
submitted his revision which is
super super simple you remember this is
the one where he went up one note where
i wanted him to go down
so let's give a listen and just see if
he nailed that
yes see
such a simple little thing one note and
now it just feels like he has nailed it
so i'm going to approve that one
litter a squirrel i'm curious if my
clinking around on the piano
is good enough and he actually replied
back and said yes
i needed this thank you because i'm not
able to notate music i can't write out
like the notes on
sheet music because that's not me and
and as i explained previously like
the best i can do is just tink away on
the piano and
hope beyond hopes that that's enough for
you who plays by sheet music
to be able to translate that and i think
you're able to see which keys i'm
hitting just enough
that you'll be able to nail that so
here's hoping now let's give a listen to
literary squirrels new submission
utilizing my tinking around on the piano
to see
if we've nailed that melody
nice i love also what literary squirrel
has done there
i hear it i don't know if you hear it do
you spot this um
i was very much on the like on the beat
he's kind of like a added like a din
like it's a bit more like a bit i don't
know like
skippy uh i don't know the technical
terms because
i'm not a professional musician but it's
got that kind of like
uh swing to the to the melody a little
bit
listen again
[Music]
see he's hitting those like notes in
kind of the in-between spot so that it
gives it a bit more of a vibe and i
really dig that
finally the uh oh and so i've approved
that
of course i mean he's nailed it well
done um
mnet has also submitted his ending
to kind of wrap up our
view of these three i said to eminent
like everything else is perfect but i
just really want it to feel like it
resolves and right now it's just kind of
you know fading out dying off and not
really having a
firm solid ending i really want that so
let's hear what eminent
has come up with with no other direction
than that here it is
[Music]
so
yes oh that is so
authentic like i just beat the boss i
beat the final boss
and we're at the end of the show and
game over i love it absolutely
absolutely stellar
well done gents i'm also looking forward
to jose's submission
and i'll come back with that as soon as
it's in the final submission from azazen
is in let's give it a listen
[Music]
welcome to the show this is what's
coming up blah blah blah kind of a
little bit of a lull there
you catch that
you know what's awesome now you watching
this you've seen
that i love that halftime breakdown
and i let literary squirrel know that i
loved it when he did it
i didn't say any such thing to jose and
yet he's picked that up
in the song and and done that kind of
halftime
beat and i just absolutely love that
[Music]
and there's that breakdown from the
original
[Music]
she's kind of changed it a bit but i
like it
oh nice that is jose's submission
uh you know what's really been a lot of
fun throughout this process
is having the opportunity to hear how
four
talented musicians on fiverr have
taken the same song and interpreted it
ever so slightly differently and each
track is
the same it's got similarities it's from
the same original track but
it's completely different in so many
ways as well
i don't think that i personally feel
that there's a clear winner
i feel like i'm gonna get use out of all
four of these versions
of our theme song and in fact as i went
into this i thought we were getting
a new theme song for the intro of the
show but now i'm picturing like
a new version for the extro with the
credit roll
and a new version when we transition and
we've got four different versions that
are brand new
for our theme song but which one is your
favorite we had nico agorovich
litterae squirrel
m net
[Music]
[Applause]
and of course mosasan
comment your favorite below and don't
forget to give us a like
big thumbs up and to subscribe if you
enjoyed this video i'd greatly
appreciate that
and don't forget if you are thinking
about trying out fiverr whether you need
a new logo or somebody to design
something for you create some music
there are just unimaginable amounts
of talent as far as like the level and
the eclecticness of the talents that are
available on fiverr
if you'd like to give it a try you can
save 20
on your first gig by using our link
cat5.tv
fiverr and of course that will also
throw a little tip in our tip jar for us
as well
thank you so much for watching hope you
enjoyed
here's what's coming up in the category
5 tv news room
white hat hackers had the run of apple's
corporate network for months
an optional update to windows 10 breaks
its ability to upgrade in future
misleading pin puzzle ads have been
banned in the uk
apple's new iphone lineup has been
announced and the bbc micro bit
mini computer is getting a big upgrade
making it powerful enough for ai
applications stick around the full
details and this week's crypto corner
are coming up
this is the category 5.tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
for months apple's corporate network was
at risk of hacks that could have stolen
sensitive data from potentially millions
of its customers
and executed malicious code on their
phones and computers
sam curry a 20 year old researcher who
specializes in website security said
that
in total he and his team found 55
vulnerabilities
he rated 11 of them critical because
they allowed him to take control of core
apple infrastructure
and from there steal private emails
icloud data and other private
information
apple promptly fixed the vulnerabilities
after curry reported them over a
three-month span
often within hours of his initial
advisory
the company has so far processed about
half of the vulnerabilities and
committed to paying
two hundred and eighty eight thousand
five hundred dollars for them
once apple processes the remainder curry
said the total payout may surpass
a half million dollars kari sidon
said in an online chat a few hours after
posting a nine thousand two hundred
dollar word
to 9200 word write up about their
findings
if the issues were used by an attacker
apple would have faced
massive information disclosure and
integrity loss
he explains attackers would have access
to the internal tools used for managing
user information
and additionally be able to change the
systems around to work as the hackers
intend
among the most serious risks were those
posed by a wormable cross-site scripting
vulnerability in a code parser
that's used by the icloud servers
because icloud provides service to apple
mail the flaw could be exploited by
sending someone with an icloud.com
or mac.com address and email that
included malicious characters
the target need only opened the email to
be hacked
and once that happened a script hidden
inside the malicious email allowed the
hacker to carry out any actions the user
could
when accessing icloud in the browser
in a statement apple says as soon as the
researchers alerted us to the issues
they detail in the report
we immediately fixed the vulnerabilities
and took steps to prevent future issues
of this kind based on our logs the
researchers were the first to discover
the vulnerabilities so we feel confident
no user data was misused
microsoft is warning that customers who
install the optional kb4577062 update
for windows 10 versions
1903 and 1909 will encounter issues
upgrading the newer
to newer windows 10 versions on some
devices
as microsoft says after installing the
optional update
users will receive compatibility
warnings when trying to update the os to
newer versions
if http internet access for local system
accounts is blocked
using a firewall while microsoft doesn't
mention that the compatibility issues
also affect newer windows 10 releases
users have also seen this warning when
trying to upgrade to windows 10 version
2004.
microsoft says that it is currently
working to address this issue with a fix
to be available in an upcoming windows
10 release
until then the company advises customers
if your device has access to http
blocked for local system accounts
to mitigate this issue you can enable
http access for the windows 10 setup
dynamic update do you
using the local system account after you
have allowed access you can restart the
installation of the debate update
and you should not see the warning
kb4577062 was released last month
with the main highlight being that it
enables an internet explorer 11
notification
to inform users about adobe's flat adobe
flash's end of support
coming this december the uk advertising
authority has put a stop to those
pin puzzle ads arguing that the frequent
advertising misrepresents the gameplay
of each title
the advertising standards authority
regularly weighs
in what does and doesn't apply for game
advertisements in the uk
meaning it's important for game
developers to keep up with the
authority's decisions in order to ensure
their own ads don't end up
on the chopping block the play rick's
ads in the asa's crosshairs this time
around might be familiar
to anyone that regularly dabbles in
mobile free-to-play games
or scrolls scrolls through social media
each depicts a puzzle that requires
players to slide a variety of pins in a
certain order
to save a cartoonish character from
certain doom
only as the ad regulator points out the
gameplay seemingly featured in those
advertisements is nothing close to
what's actually found in the bulk of the
match 3 games they're advertising
the complaint itself sprung out of two
particular facebook advertisements
one for homescapes and one for
gardenscapes that followed the
pinpointing format
and aimed to lure would-be players with
phrases like only five percent can solve
this and
think you can do better among others in
response to asa's investigation
playwrights argued that the puzzles
shared thematic thematic similarities
with the gameplay and narrative
players could expect in the actual games
the asa however isn't having it
making it clear that those who click the
ad and install the app are expecting
gameplay that reflects what is shown
in the ad the authority has decreed that
play rix's ads are misleading despite
playwrx's inclusion of a disclaimer
that not all images represent actual
gameplay
the offending advertisements can no
longer run in the uk
and playwrx has been told to ensure
their future ads actually represent the
gameplay of the titles they are linked
to
hopefully we'll see these annoying false
ads stopped in other regions as well
i i like that the uk authority has
gotten in on this
because this type of ad has driven me
nuts for a while now
anyone else seen this like anyone else
falling for it i see them all the time
but i find that youtube is not youtube
sorry facebook is particularly bad
for false advertisements like so many
computer
app games that i see they're like oh
check out this
you know this is the game you got to
play it and it's
not the game it's it's video from
another video game
isn't that nuts well it's almost like
they've created like a video
yeah i don't know if you've fallen for
this i actually installed
the game when the ad started oh okay
because i thought oh that looks really
fun
yes the ads make it look really really
the game wasn't nothing nothing like it
yeah what the ad showed and in fact it
was like a really bad
topographical kind of like war
simulation
yeah what does that have to do with
anything
yeah absolutely completely misleading
it's unfortunate though that it's only
the uk authority that's gotten in on
this i think
well i don't know that it is but i mean
the as far as the ruling that's
yeah that's what we're hearing anyways
that's what's breaking the news right
now
i hope that it it catches all across the
globe because these kind of ads
drive me nuts and as as a father whose
kids are now getting into
apps and games they see these ads
and they're like oh dad i want to
download that i want to play it yeah
but i'm now questioning going is what
they're seeing actually the game yeah
and that makes me think i mean it's good
that the authority is putting their foot
down because
if like where's the line yeah if if they
are allowed
if they were allowed to post these ads
that are completely not what they're
advertising what
what's the line what could it be that my
kids are actually installing and i'd
say my kids because that's the example
that you use but i mean it annoyed me
yeah because i was laying there on the
couch thinking this looks cool i'm gonna
install this
could you imagine if we advertised as a
tech show on cat 5 but really we're a
car show
i couldn't imagine that like that would
just drive you all nuts you tune in it's
like
i got to hear about cryptocurrency to be
fair we have the linux tech show and
people say why are you talking about
windows
okay fair enough i don't know so to be
fair
those are close enough yes but yeah i i
false advertising for apps and games has
gotten
so crazy yeah there needs to be
something
done about it and so i'm glad to see
this story me too it's good
all right apple's new iphone lineup has
been announced and the bbc
micro bit mini computer is getting
big upgrades making it powerful enough
for ai applications becca has these
stories coming up plus robert's here
with the crypto corner
don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner i hope
you're well
today i have got two different things
for you you probably heard
that the bank of england started warning
yesterday
their customers that interest rates
might go negative
next year and most economists are
warning that that's
a very bad sign for the economy
and at the same time i would like to
show you
something out of our industry which is
saying that crypto banks are going to
swallow fiat banks in three or even
less years and why is that case
because crypto banks can compete on a
complete different level they have offer
by far bigger products than a
traditional bank can do
because everything is being reinvented
as you saw
in the last few presentations that i did
and also the cost i mean they don't have
any buildings and
no employees it's all software that's
doing this year so the
traditional banks have got absolute
chance against our crypto banks
and so that's going to be a very
interesting development which is great
because it gives you
as the user a lot of independency
in an area which is desperately needed
and this one can see
the increase in users and and value
of money that has been locked into 35 is
increasing steadily
even at this moment of time where we had
some down
trend in the in the industry the other
thing i'd like to show you
is so-called non-fungible tokens
non-fungible tokens
are assets that have different prices
and good example is artwork
if you buy picasso and then every
picasso has got different price
depending on provenance
and and then many factors and uh
these things are coming up now in our
world too
and as you can see here there is
somebody that's uh trevor jones that
created this piece here it's digital so
it's not a physical piece of art
and it's called the picasso's bull in
bronze he created 25
of those units started selling them at
a piece and he's now making or the
current owners making four thousand two
hundred dollars
by uh selling that and this is something
that will
grow bigger and bigger it's got the huge
advantage that with these things you
don't need a certificate of authenticity
or you don't need any provenance because
that's all
part of the blockchain so you don't need
to have that separately
you know where that painting is coming
from up to the originator
another example is land
and i've got here an example called
decentraland which is a virtual world
with streets
and then you've got districts like the
financial district or the
asian district or the african district
and you can buy properties on it the
light blue ones are the ones you
are currently able to buy this one that
i
chose that was sold in 2019
for 1.2 million mana that's the currency
in this land
which is around 180 000 and
at the current price of eight cents or
seven eight cents
for per mana there's something that
why is this so interesting it's not for
kids no um
it can be but the interesting part is
you probably remember the presentation i
did on the cardano summit
a few months ago which was completely
virtual
and those things will happen here so
you'll have like a university and you
then walk into the building
you see the different halls you've got
everything that you see also in a
traditional university
you'll have that also here from that
aspect
that point of view or conference
halls fashion districts uh we we've seen
that also
in other areas so this is something that
will happen this has been developed for
many years
it's still in its infancy but it
it will come and the link to the
traditional world
is also there and i'm showing you this
example here
although one has to be careful because
there is a physical asset which is in
this case the property
and you don't have a real link between
the digital property and the physical
property because you can't put
a building onto the blockchain so the
law has to change in order for these
assets to be really
um part of a decentralized economy but
here in this case you can buy a property
um one zero zero four eight creighton
boulevard
creighton street for sixty five thousand
and forty four dollars
and the token price is fifty uh dollars
so you can buy part of a property
uh without ever having been there
without knowing what area that is and so
on
and that property is being rented at the
moment and you then get a part of that
uh rent revenue it's an idea that
they're trying it a lot of properties
have been sold this way already
because it's an interesting investment
so
as you can see there are a lot of things
coming on to this market too
it's a different market than the d5
market of course
there is a website called openc which is
i find the best one
to find out where to find these
non-fungible tokens and just play around
with it
yeah i recommended it to you in the defy
sector just play around with it just buy
some
defy tokens uh get a loan
and just learn and the same you should
do here
although it's all not financial advice
as you know but it's just what
i did so rarible or x infinity
super rare is is a great website you
just click on this here and
you're here so it's a directory where
you can see what's going on and how
what art is currently being sold or what
are they currently selling
so that's it from me this week i hope
you learned something i
hope you found it interesting and i'm
really looking forward to see you next
week again
so thank you very much for watching bye
bye
thanks robert just a reminder that we're
not providing financial advice but only
sharing what's happening in the
cryptocurrency market
always remember that the cryptocurrency
markets are ever-changing and
always volatile now back to becca in the
newsroom
thank you robbie apple unveiled four new
phones
tuesday which are equipped for faster
technology with 5g
wireless networks the pandemic
temporarily paralyzed apple's overseas
factories and key suppliers
leading to a delay of the latest iphones
from their usual late september rollout
the company also closed many of its u.s
stores for months because of the
pandemic
depriving apple of a prime showcase for
its products
now the new lineup has been unveiled the
iphone 12
12 mini 12 pro and 12 pro max
range in price from about 979 dollars
canadian
to upwards of 1550.
the tech giant said the new phones will
also be more durable
in a move that may annoy some consumers
apple will no longer include charging
adapters with new phones
the company says that will mean smaller
lighter boxes that are more
environmentally friendly to ship
apple however separately sells two
models of power adapter
which are likely a required purchase
since the included cable is not
compatible with the traditional usba
style
wall wart apple has one of the most
loyal
and affluent customer bases in the world
which has many analysts betting that the
next wave of phones will sell well
the iphone remains the foundation of
apple's business
apple boasted about the 5g capabilities
and brought in verizon ceo
hans vestberg to champion the carrier's
network
5g is supposed to mean much faster
speeds making it quicker to download
movies or games for instance
but finding those speeds can be a
challenge while telecom operators have
been rolling out 5g networks
significant boosts in speed are still
uncommon in much of the world including
the us
the iphone models unveiled tuesday will
launch at different times
the iphone 12 and 12 pro will be
available starting october 23rd
the mini and the pro max will follow on
november 13th
okay i gotta i gotta ask why would they
not include a charger
they're saying it's more environmentally
friendly jeff
but the fact is is that you gotta buy
the charger anyways yeah it's gonna come
in separate packaging yeah this is why
uh there's a bit of an uproar about this
i think it's a total
price grab and i mean apple
i know right shocking but i mean apple
phones are
already any apple products already crazy
expensive as it
is now yeah um
now they're gonna make you pay for a
charger sure they are
like this is ridiculous that is supposed
to be
commonplace just like a pair of wired
headphones
you say that but there are times jeff
when i think like when i buy
a monitor for my computer yep why do
they throw in a dsub
cable it makes no sense
fair enough and that to me is wasteful
sure right right but you don't charge
your monitor through a dsub cable
right but there will come a time when
they're right
when everyone does have a usbc charger
that's a fast charger
yeah you know but because we all use
usba a lot i
i generalize but a lot of us use wall
warts that have
like a usba which is the you know the
fat thin one
that you have to try three times before
you plug it in that's right yeah
um but but there will come a time when
we all have usbc chargers yes and i know
that that's
the that's the goal like they're trying
to transition everybody on to the same
connection yeah
um but still it seems kind of ridiculous
that you'd buy a phone without a charger
like i don't know that's the story
and the other thing is is four different
models of phone
they got you got the pro you got the pro
max you got the mini
the mini is smaller it's the
same i poke fun it's like the same nuts
and bolts just different size
like essentially like oh well no i make
i mean good for them for for bringing
out
a new product during a pandemic i mean
that's great
yeah it's hard for for companies to
manufacture right now
sure absolutely it is and i mean the
fact that they've
they've had shortage of supply because
of factory shutdown and all that and the
fact that they can roll this out that's
great
uh i just he's not a fanboy you can tell
no i i am very anti-apple like
yeah i just i mean if
ugh
i would probably lose it in the store
but if you had an android phone it's
usb a to probably usbc
yeah so you're you're fine because you
have that yes charger already you're
probably
but that's the issue so
we'll just we'll just leave it at that
and head back to becca
the bbc micro bit mini computer used by
millions of school
children around the world is receiving
its first major update since
2016. formerly a bbc-led project it is
now led by a foundation that aims to
make coding
accessible for children the bbc microbit
is designed to inspire young people
providing the key knowledge
understanding and skills to become
creators
not just users of technology
the latest version of the microbit has
all the features of the original
and some fantastic extras so you can
learn and play
in new and exciting ways the new model
includes a speaker and microphone as
well as a capacitive touch sensor
the device will be released in november
with prices starting at 11 pounds 50
a bit more than 14 u.s gareth stockdale
chief executive of the microbit
educational foundation said the purpose
of the microbit is to help children
unlock their creative potential and
learn how to shape the world around them
he believes that learning coding and
computational thinking can enhance
skills
that will help them in their careers in
the 21st century
since its launch the microbit has been
designed for education
with an estimated 25 million children
learning computer skills on the device
in over 60 countries the previous model
launched in the uk in 2016 with the bbc
giving away a free micro bit to every
grade 7
student it is now used in most secondary
schools as well as primary schools
universities and libraries
the foundation has also donated 5 000
devices to families in the uk
to help with homeschooling during the
covet 19 pandemic
the micro bit is a palm size circuit
board with an array of 25 lights that
can be programmed to show letters
numbers
and other shapes and a bluetooth chip
for wireless connectivity
as the hardware is most powerful sorry
is now powerful enough to run machine
learning systems
the foundation has plans to expand into
this area
in future big thanks to roy w
nash and our community of viewers for
submitting stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
well that is episode one of season 14
in the can jeff i love it we did it it's
good show made it through the show
and and the technology is coming
together and it's been quite a go as we
mentioned season 13 was
you know it was a lot of change and a
lot of transition and now things are
working a lot better because
we took those couple of weeks in order
to dedicate some time here at the studio
to getting things set up the way that
they should be so i'm very very thankful
to have you here thank you to our
supporters our patrons at patreon.com
slash category five it means so much to
know that you're supporting us
and of course we give you some exciting
content
as well so if you enjoyed today's show
for example
just know that there's about another
half hours worth of content that you
didn't get to see
that is there and available exclusively
for patrons oh that's like some of the
best stuff sounds fun eh
behind the scenes also you can follow us
on twitter it's at category5tv
and i hope you will have a wonderful
week everyone we'll see you next
wednesday
[Music]
you