covering the week's top tech stores
with a slight linux bias xiaomi has
announced a new charging tech that can
fully charge a depleted smartphone
in less than 20 minutes but it does it
without any wires
fast charging has become a key feature
of many smartphones in recent years and
for convenience sake
wireless charging can be really great
but of course wireless charging
typically charges a phone with between
10 to 15 watts of power
some phones like the oneplus 8 pro have
wireless charging up to 40 watts
but xiaomi's new charging tech promises
a whopping
80 watts of wireless juice
what does that mean in practical terms
well according to the announcement
unveiling the 80 watt me wireless
charging technology
a smartphone with zero percent charge of
a four thousand milliamp hours battery
will charge ten percent in just one
minute fifty percent in eight minutes
and be fully charged after 19 minutes
finally
a charger that will charge my phone from
zero
to 100 right in like my lunch break
see that's nice that's a game changer
can you imagine
i think about my kids and how we have
like phones everywhere
obviously i mean this is going to take
like the latest and greatest tech but
it's always a case of oh i forgot to put
my phone on the charger or it doesn't
last
long enough for the entire day and now
that you know with the pandemic of
course
my kids are being homeschooled now kind
of by force
and everybody's on their devices the
whole time so we've got
zoom meetings happening on phones and
and
it runs it depletes the battery yes but
what i like
is that it's wireless it's not just
wiring
that's amazing yeah it's wireless that's
huge like
the idea that i could take my phone not
have to worry about chargers and just go
just set it down set it down 20 minutes
later i'm good to go
that i love the other thing that i love
about it
the the concept is that um
i think about as you just did if i could
set it down on a table
what if you could set it down on a
restaurant table yes because a lot of
restaurants have
gone the route and i'm using restaurants
as the example but a lot of places have
gone the route of
embedding usb yes so that you can plug
in your usb
cable to charge your phone but then all
of a sudden people got
wise to the fact that oh those usb ports
could be malicious
because usb also carries data or that's
right who knows if it's
too many volts and that you know maybe
it's got a short or something like that
and could fry my phone
so then all of a sudden we're afraid to
plug into the usb port because hey it
could be
something bad that's right well wireless
charging you
set it down it charges and you pick it
up and you're done yeah
but you can set it down for like three
minutes and it's given you enough of a
charge to get through most of the
afternoon
which is incredible awesome i i think
just as a i mean you look around now and
you've got all these charge stations for
electric vehicles it would be great to
start seeing little pop-ups
in public places with this kind of stuff
where you can literally put your phone
down for five minutes
and have enough to have a phone call to
get help or whatever
and it's all wirelessly i just pictured
like a stretch of road
and embed the receiver in the car and it
recharges the
autonomous car because it drives over
this thing whoa
we're getting into the tech now folks
[Laughter]
still i like it i'm excited about it the
crazy thing is just
in conclusion is that while what i just
said
is very sci-fi like when we were growing
up that was like the future
it's totally doable it's possible now
that's
ridiculous thanks for watching the
category 5 dot tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon
dot com slash category five from the
category five dot tv newsroom i'm becca
ferguson
[Music]
you