the uk government is looking into the
national security implications of a deal
worth 40
billion dollars that has us-based nvidia
purchasing british chip designer arm
holdings
we've got the latest in a moment but
before we get into it
don't forget to subscribe to our channel
like this video
and click on the bell so that you get
notified when we release new ones
with uk-based computer chip manufacturer
arm holdings being sold to the american
graphics chip
specialists nvidia for 40 billion
dollars
just four years after japanese
conglomerate softbank bought the company
for eight billion dollars less
here's becca to explain arm creates
computer chip designs that others then
customize to their own ends
it also develops instruction sets which
define how software controls processors
arms technology is at the heart of most
smartphones among many other devices
including a majority of single board
computers such as the raspberry pi
odroid xu4 or roc pro 64 which also
makes it the heart of pine 64's pine
book pro
pro arm will also power apple's new
macbook
lineup nvidia has promised to keep the
business based in the uk
to hire more staff and to retain arm's
brand
it added that the deal would create the
premier computing company for the age of
artificial intelligence california
headquartered
nvidia overtook intel to become the
world's most valuable chip maker in july
until now it is specialized in high-end
graphics processing units
these are commonly used by gamers to
deliver more detailed visuals
as well as by professionals for tasks
including scientific research
machine learning and cryptocurrency
mining
in our case we render all our video in
real time using nvidia's
cuda platform nvidia is also one of
arm's clients
using its designs to create its lineup
of tegra
central processing units thank you becca
now seven months following the original
purchase announcement
digital minister oliver dowden said he
has issued a
so-called intervention over the sale
he says quote as a next step and to help
me gather the relevant information the
uk's
independent competition authority will
now prepare a report
on the implications of the transaction
which will help inform any further
decision
nvidia for their part don't believe the
deal poses any national security
problems
they say they have been and will
continue to work closely with the
british authorities throughout the deal
from a competition standpoint the nvidia
deal puts a
vital supplier to multiple silicon chip
makers
under the control of just one company
arm is not just about smartphones and
single board computers however
they're a major player in global
semiconductor manufacturing
and according to the government that
underpins critical infrastructure
in britain including within technology
related to defense
and national security matters they added
that officials from the security
community had informed the decision
to intervene the competition
and markets authority will now assess
the competition
jurisdiction and national security
impact of the deal with a report due by
the end of july 2021
at that point dowden will make the
decision between
allowing the deal to pass or pursuing a
more
in-depth investigation should that be in
order
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom
you can become part of our fleet for
exclusive bonus content
at patreon.com category5
i'm robbie ferguson see you next time
[Music]
foreign