[Music]
this week we're looking back at some of
the highlights from the category 5
community coffee break and i'll be
tearing apart my laptop with the hopes
of replacing the noisy cooling system
becca's got your top news stories
including a warning to samsung blu-ray
player users
apple is moving to arm processors for
the next generation of macs
and microsoft is killing off mixer but
contrary to their statement to the
public
they're really burning the hard-working
staff who made it possible
the crypto and crypto finance market is
blowing up
and robert koenig is here to tell us
what's going on with the explosive defy
marketplace
this is all coming up so strap in it's
time for the tech
[Music]
our live recordings are trusted only to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
revive your computer with improved
performance and reliability over
traditional hard drives with kingston
ssds
category 5 tv streams live with
telestream wirecast and nimble streamer
tune in every week on roku kodi and
other hls video players
for local showtimes visit category5.tv
well hello there everybody my name is
robbie ferguson it's nice to have you
here with me again this week
and it's good to be here at studio e
that's our a b c d e fifth
studio our fifth studio studio e
and it would not be possible without
your support
i want to especially say a big thanks to
bp9 scott barkley ron morissette
jerry kowalski jonathan garvey
jens nissen ameridroid also nomen5
and bill marshall as well as nycad
and everyone else who has supported
category 5 technology tv
through this entire time
this year has been an odd one 2020
kicked off january 1st and my resolution
was to lose some weight and i've done
well
lost anywhere from 14 we'll say 14 to 18
pounds
so almost 20 pounds but it's kind of
like yeah it fluctuates a few pounds
here and there
but i've lost some weight that's my new
year's resolution you remember that
at studio d um i purchased a new scale
a smart scale to help me to be able to
keep track of
that weight loss process and and my
progress and it's been cool to see the
graph
and those of you who picked up one of
those scales know that it is really
really neat to be able to pull out your
smartphone and see
the trends and and see and and it's like
a challenge for yourself a bit of an
encouragement just to know the numbers i
think has been really really helpful for
me
that's how the year started off so hey
one good thing came out of 2020 so far
and then we found out that we had to
move
category 5 technology tv at the end of
february so that was not too far into
the year at all
made the announcement and we held a
kickstarter campaign which
was successful and i thank you so very
much for your support
and we had to move at the end of march
but as you know
of course this whole pandemic thing
kind of took off mid-march so here in
canada it was it was a couple weeks into
march when things really started getting
serious
and so we moved everything in as best we
could but i couldn't have my team here
really helping to unpack or get things
set up and so it's been
that kind of struggle to get to the
point where
we're up and running at full capacity
and we're not there yet
i can't wait until henry bailey brown
can be here in the studio with me
probably
like on another camera over in the far
corner but
he'll be here jeff weston will be here
sasha rickman
has had to move across the country to
newfoundland
but she'll be here in some way or
another and one of the cool ways that
sasha
has been able to participate in our
community even through this time
and how some of our community has been
able to keep in contact and
and kind of keep up to date with what
one another
are up to is through a program that we
host called coffee break
and our category 5 community coffee
break
is held in general once a week
we do have the occasional exception
including this week because i am going
to take my
wife and kids away for the weekend and
i'm really looking forward
to a little bit of downtime i think we
all
need a little bit of respite every now
and again and this week
it's it's time for for me to get the
kids out of the house and
and and go somewhere and just kind of
relax and and spend some time together
to just playing board games and things
like that
having campfires really really looking
forward to that and tis the season we
can't do everything that we normally do
we can't go
window well we can go window shopping we
can't go you know taking the kids into
all the stores that we normally would up
in cottage country and all that kind of
stuff and
can't do our grocery shops the same way
that we used to
what a world hey i posted on twitter
this morning
with my mask on at work that
who knew when 2020 started that i'd be a
a ninja or at least i'd look that way
but um so with the rare occasion where
we're not actually holding one um
typically it is once a week that we hold
the community coffee break
and the whole purpose behind that and
i'm talking about
you know this is all that's been going
on and
i know that everybody's been affected
differently throughout the pandemic but
the coffee break was set up specifically
to give us
a place to go just like i'm going away
to the cottage this weekend it's a place
for you our community the category 5 tv
coffee break is a place for us to all
get together
and just go just get away from it all
just have some respite some time to
hang out with the community members and
just
be ourselves have fun chat about random
things the technology that
has us excited this week and not talk
about
the things that are bringing us down
that's the category 5 community
coffee break and let's take a quick look
at some of the
many highlights of the category 5
community coffee break
and i'd encourage you as you watch these
clips
to check in and and visit the category
five community coffee break by going to
our website
category five tv is category five
dot tv and when you're there scroll down
on the home page and you'll see the
schedule
for the coffee break and i'd encourage
you to be a part of that
it's a very small tight-knit group right
now
and i know that our community is much
much larger than what's represented
in the coffee break and that's part of
why i wanted to show you because maybe
maybe you don't know that you can join
it too and i'd love to have you as a
part of it so let's take a look at some
of the
some of the highlights there have been
wow i think it's like 63
coffee breaks so far wow right
so among those are some gems
and somewhere we just sat around just ah
just hanging out but among those i've
pulled some clips just to show you a
little bit about
what goes on on the coffee break so here
you are
[Music]
a really cool thing about the pine phone
is
that um it is completely modular
well you know as much as most phones can
be
um it's got a removable battery oh yes
that's a dangerous that's a standard
samsung j7 battery so you can
get them really easily even though this
one's branded or it's just a standard
battery
uh this is the the module that does the
wi-fi bluetooth and
no what timing wi-fi bluetooth and what
i'm glad it wasn't just me
you dropped out there bo he said this is
the wi-fi bluetooth
and gsm so that's a
it's a quick tell module so this
actually runs
a stripped down version of linux on it
so that's that's the only uh closed
part of the entire phone is that
that module right there is it just me or
is this like mark shuttleworth's dream
coming to light in a lot of ways
let's see if i can get close enough here
and annika really wanted to do the
ubuntu phone right and this is
this is a linux phone folks so you can
i don't know if you can see it but these
are our dip switches right here
those are our hardware disable switches
for
different things this little white label
next to it tells you what they are uh
it's
modem wi-fi bluetooth microphone rear
camera front camera and headphone
that's what you can turn off
do you sell those at ameridroid we will
be as soon as they're available
um this right here is uh
our pogo pins so these are
uh i squared c interface to the phone
oh nice wow so people can make
a uh you know like keyboard cases or
extended batteries or
anything that does i squared and see
and this is like how much is a is a pine
phone remind me both
uh it'll be less than two hundred
dollars wow
and uh so here here's manjaro running
so it's not running android it's running
linux
let's see uh i'm trying to do this
backwards oh yes
so uh
anyway i'm not sure exactly what i'm
doing because i
yeah i want one even more now on the
back is really absolutely
that i was planning to show you
yesterday but i didn't find it
and then this morning i remember that oh
i have one box tucked away in another
room that i didn't
look inside
is that i thought it was a game and
watch
oh my goodness liam come see this
can you make a noise for me oh there it
is making a nice
peaceful an actual game and watch
yeah um pre-nintendo so that was what
created the nintendo yeah it's it's from
1985.
i've had it uh i've had this one for uh
20 years
ago and i understand like if if that
didn't happen
if that guy wasn't such a pushy salesman
it nintendo might not have happened
wow wow that's awesome and it still
works
so fresh but it's for the for today
no that was pre well they might say
nintendo on it does it
yeah yeah it does okay yeah because
there were
two uh uh two vendors um
and i don't know they remember the name
or the other one but it was
a clone of nintendo
and i i used to have one of the clones
and i had
the one um it was
um breaking breaking up
out of prison um it was a a searchlight
going all around and you had to avoid
the searchlight and you had to avoid
uh two guardrans and then you had to
walk up to the
fence and then the first one had to
knock a hole in the fence and then
escape
and yeah i think i had my uh all-time
high
was uh almost five five
five hundred points and after that and
i'm
closing passing 400 points there
searchlight was really going fast
i had that for three or four years and
then
if we moved on i haven't seen it since
uh if i recall correctly i think game
and watch was
a device out of japan that um
nintendo didn't they didn't create
nintendo already existed but nintendo
would have folded if game and watch
the guy who was selling game and watch
came to them and said please carry this
so they've slapped their name on it and
it became a nintendo product
and made nintendo
what what they became i guess well
you're calling it a gaming
and what okay so how does that thing
convert to a watch
because it also has a watch
so does it have a clock at least yes
there you go
what's gw doing down there we can't we
can't see what you're working on because
your mic isn't gone
i see that this yeah this is my gaming
system
nice nice this is a little one uh
this i built three of these this is the
little one there's a medium sized one
that i built because
my nephews were fighting over the fact
there's only one controller on this
thing
uh and then there's the full-size arcade
cabinet that i built for a friend after
they saw the other two
sweet uh liam wants to show you guys his
retro gaming console
oh is that the new one is that the new
one right up to the
that's the uh games uh this is the sega
genesis
do you want to put on like sonic show
them how cool it is
yeah it's got like 2 000 mega games on
it
i was hoping to get one of those new
droids but i gather it's back ordered
hold it up to the camera oh he's got
sonic running for
you guys copyright infringement right
here
oh boy you guys see that
yeah nice
it's really hard to see on camera isn't
it yeah it's slightly or something
it's actually these things are awesome
that's cool
nice buddy those things are awesome it
takes an sd card so you can pop a rom on
it and it will it will boot
hey uh guess what happened this morning
guys you'll never guess
i i got to work where i am now
and maybe 10 minutes later
15 minutes after i got here i got a
phone call from our alarm company
that our alarm was going off at the new
studio
i was gonna say the alarm went off i had
a feeling it was something like that i
was gonna
i was gonna say it jokingly but i'm glad
i didn't
so i my initial thought was okay well
there must be
a false alarm like you know we just had
it installed on saturday right so
sometimes there's some kinks to to work
out um
so i emailed the alarm company and and
asked them to send me a copy of the
manual so i can
reprogram the terminal thing just in
case it was a false alarm
and i and i went there and everything
was fine so i called off the police and
told them we didn't need anyone because
it was a false alarm
um and then i went back over my
surveillance footage just on a whim
and sure enough 8 37 this morning
my door opens wide and the guy walks in
looks around looks around and then the
alarm starts going off and then he
quickly gets out
and how did he get in exactly so
that was my thought so i'm sitting there
watching this surveillance video
and i'm and i can't see his face i can't
see any
because i haven't set up the
surveillance yet so it was just
the camera in the in the office
happened to be pointed toward the door
so i saw the door open the guy walk in
you see kind of
his right side and he's looking around
and then he gets
and the alarm goes off right so as i'm
watching this footage
i hear somebody rustling on my door so i
jump up and i run to the the door of the
studio and i whip it open and i say you
can't come in here
remember i'm just watching the
surveillance and i see this guy
turns out he's one of the maintenance
workers at the con
and he didn't when when they leased out
our unit they didn't mark us
as a as a lease unit they have because
they're short staffed right because of
the covet 19 they've been closed
so we're moved in we've got our alarm
set up but they didn't mark it as
uh as uh not vacant so
he thought it was empty he thought it
was empty and he's going around from
all of the empty units he's got a
clipboard of all the empty units and
they do an inspection at the beginning
of every month
um i guess presumably to prepare them
for
you know that months you know tours and
trying to rent it out but
uh so he had walked right in he had a
key obviously he just walked right in
set off the alarm and he's just freaking
out and of course
my his first impression of me is me
yanking the door open
so i'm like oh man i'm so sorry i had no
idea who you were or what you were doing
all i know is that the police are here
my alarm
went off this morning i got to call the
alarm company and get them to reset the
code
and yeah so that's how my day started
wow yeah and that happened this morning
happened this morning yeah before i got
a voicemail i got a voicemail from the
property management company all
apologetic and they're going on about
how you know it'll never happen again
we've marked
them at least we're so sorry
wow wow so i'm just hoping what's that
i'm really hoping i don't get a bill for
a false alarm
a good point because if the police get
called out they'll
uh they'll charge you for that so and
you want to know what's neat is that
um i got there within 10 minutes and the
police were already there
oh yeah oh yeah they were uh i don't
mess around with that stuff
i poured myself a coffee in this
particular mug
as a reminder to let you know
that uh andrew andrew lloyd webber
is broadcasting the 25th anniversary
stage
production of the musical on youtube
this weekend
so it's a limited time thing it's for 48
hours i think in the uk
and 72 hours in the rest of the world
i believe because of copyright so um
i posted the link to that under um
i think i forget what the videos channel
is on discord i think it's called like
interesting videos
or channel on discord if you click on
there it's the last video that i posted
but it is limited it's only this weekend
if you want to see the stage production
which i think is cool because growing up
being such a fan of the phantom of the
opera
as a child having seen that pantages
theater when i was in grade six
and then like following the musical for
years after
that um i always wanted to have
a recording of the the actual stage
production
rather than the movie the movie came out
and that was something but it wasn't as
good
so it's nice to see a proper produced
stage version of the show
so that's really really cool i went to
see it in a smaller theater so it was
not as majestic as it would have been in
one of the larger theaters
um and i did get the uh original
um uh cd of the original
cast uh request so with but not
original canadian or uk
this was a uk i believe okay
yeah i can't remember i can't remember
his name
i would as soon as i as soon as i hear
it i know here
no that wasn't the right one no from
ireland was
was the phantom here in canada okay so
i know that you're talking about and i'm
trying to find the cd
and i don't i don't just don't see it
often i want to say kevin or brian or
something like that but it's i
i can't think of it maybe i'll switch
around my camera
and i can like give you a little bit of
a walk through of what i do this place
yes if i can okay so let's see i'm i'm
really new at this getting really dizzy
wow
okay here we are here we go so have you
ever
um taken carpet adhesive off of uh
uh floorboard it's horrible very
difficult oh yeah i've been using
that iron on steam
and just steaming the vegetables out of
that
if i go to the other side of the attic
obviously there's still
like lots of work that needs to be done
up here this is like a horror movie
yeah when you move really quickly
this is going to be my cat 5
office there's plenty of room
is it insulated though i mean what's it
going to be like in the middle of summer
that'll be hot well it's really stinking
hot right now
i'm not surprised no insulation in the
rafters
no none at all in the um
yeah you're gonna have to insulate that
whole area there so for that to be
reliable yeah that
is my washing machine uh this should be
my office down here
yes you really need to make this part of
your part of this your office it's
far more suitable yeah and yeah and in
really hot days it will be a very cool
little bit cooler
yeah in my house oh this should be
cool
what i think we've decided on is making
a cluster of independent
so a cluster as in uh multiple devices
but
independent as in each one will have its
own distro
uh raspberry pi unit
that will each have uh the
raspberry pi os and zoom installed
and each one of those has an hdmi output
so
then each raspberry pi becomes a camera
source
essentially for zoom so i'd have
one raspberry pi dedicated to jeff and
that would be hdmi out into his capture
and then when i push the button
on the on the stream deck it would
switch to his camera basically
uh and then have one for sasha and one
for henry and however we want to set it
up so
it's just like one raspberry pi per
person
it might work so that's kind of where
i'm sorry
i think i missed what it is you were
meaning to do with that raspberry pi
being able to have it have them come in
remotely through zoom ah i
see okay because for the show we
obviously don't want this grid layout
and we
can't have it so that it's switching
back and forth every time someone speaks
and but you need to you need a separate
input for each of them so you can edit
them post as much as
any way you like and even live we need
to be able to switch to the person who's
speaking manually
and i and and people may not realize but
um zoom cannot be running on the
broadcast system because it's
broadcasting
so that means the good camera that i use
is
out of it basically so during the
interview or during the conversation i
would be on my phone
and you've done you've done this before
though as i recall
because you you did the same thing um
alive oh good point yeah okay
live changes yeah i was about to say
this
wednesday we found that out when my pine
book pro
would not work for the feature and then
so then signed off rebooted
changed the way i connected things i
plugged the uh i plugged the
atomos ninja flame into the pine book
pro and pushed the cord
worked flawlessly so so we need about a
half a dozen raspberry pi for eight gigs
yeah exactly so well i think four would
do it because
four is as many inputs as i have oh
that's still fun
so then we just so basically that would
allow us to treat
each person on their zoom connection as
a
as a camera source so i think that could
work and it's probably a pretty good way
to do it on the cheap
on the cheap it's gonna cost like you
know four raspberry pies here in canada
it's like 600 bucks
so you know what it's like two dollars
american right
that's ridiculous robert said to me
because robert's in florida right and
he's like oh yeah raspberry pi it's only
75 bucks for the new one
really 110 dollars here just for the
board
plus you got to buy the power supply
plus you got to buy the case
i'm not even sure i would use it i'm not
even sure i'd use a rasp
for that anymore right probably you've
already
already been talking about the navy
you've already been talking about the
odroid um
uh what was it c4 i believe
yeah i don't know i haven't looked yet i
don't know if they're any cheaper
i need to hit up a miradroid and see
what they've got but
maybe that's an option
you've seen this too right um you've
seen where the
raspberry pi if it loses power uh
potentially that sd card yeah it's
corrupted
you can't afford that especially
especially not live
so you know maybe maybe that's an option
but
i don't know what the price point is
though so maybe maybe just a bunch of
xu4s with
uh with emmc
with the desktop yeah i like i like what
you're thinking and it's got hdmi out i
was strictly thinking
you know i i just need a sbc with some
hdmi output but you're right it doesn't
have to be raspberry pi
no um you need for it to work
especially when you're live you can't
afford to be having it break down
unexpectedly not just not to say that
they will
but um if you lose power all of a sudden
then yeah you're going to have a yeah
but if you know what our
and the sd card corrupting is the least
of your problems
if my ups is so weak it can't power four
raspberry pies
i'm in trouble because that r510 is
going down well you've got a
beeping at ups don't you i do yeah
i gotta get new batteries in that thing
well yeah it's a good point
yeah i threw it out there for in case it
would be
you know just as a as an option so
yeah i like that idea uh xu4s or
uh the new c4s any of those would
probably do just fine
it's really just plugging them in and
and then seeing how they
how they operate with zoom in full
screen it's been so much fun
getting to know certain members of our
community
and i'd encourage you to become a part
of our community coffee break as well
just a great
um usually weekly place that you can
come together on a zoom meeting
and be a part of our community in that
way
so i'd encourage you to check it out
category five dot tv just scroll on the
scroll down on the home page
and you'll find the schedule there the
past videos everything else
and if you have any questions join our
discord and that
is found by clicking on interact and
then you'll see join our discord server
there
at category 5 dot tv we've got to take a
quick break
i'm going to mosey on over to the bridge
and from there we're gonna get into my
laptop and
finally finally fix the cooling system
in that bad boy
stick around
[Music]
welcome back all right so what i hope to
achieve
today is to demonstrate that there are
some minor repairs that you can conduct
yourself this is my laptop it's a
lenovo thinkpad it's a great powerful
little laptop
big laptop i should say
but the cooling system went all kinds of
bad
so the last time i used this laptop was
during an interview
and when i conducted that interview we
had
all sorts of problems
i couldn't hear the question oh i'm so
sorry dude this is really frustrating
i'm sorry dude
oh patrons i've got and i've got you on
100. it just stopped all the way it just
stopped
are you good you can hear me now yes
okay so that noise was something else
and when you're doing live tv you really
just don't need that kind of stress
you know what i'm saying so i
got this open and i had a look and even
though this
fan is spinning fine and everything
looks okay
this cooling system is on its last legs
maybe it's about to fail maybe just the
bearings have gone whatever it might be
it needs replacing
but it's a big apparatus it's not just a
little fan
it's got this whole pipe cooling system
going over to the cpu
so i had to get online and place an
order
for an identical replacement
so the laptop while
i might have thought okay it's dead
the cooling system is gone it's going to
be a lot of work or money
possibly i mean if you took it to a shop
it might cost you
you know take the price of parts mark it
up a bunch and then
add another i don't know
a couple hundred bucks for labor but
what if i told you you could do this
yourself
pretty straightforward so that's what
i'm gonna set out to do and we're going
to see if this is going to make
any amount of difference and kind of how
tedious
this is now i've already already had
this old one
kind of removed so i've tightened things
up again just so that the
thermal compound wouldn't have a problem
there are a couple of screws all over
the place here
you're going to need a really really
tiny screwdriver so
every laptop computer is a little bit
different
of course you can you can guess that
however um the concepts
that i try to instill are that
from piece to piece from component to
component from computer to computer
you can do this it's not that difficult
you just got to find the problem
and be very gentle i always say like
just take your time
if something doesn't seem to want to
give it's probably
you've missed a screw or something you
don't
have to pull so right now for example
i'm noting that there is a
there you go uh a wire that is
not wanting to give and it's because
it's actually part of
the computer not part of the fan
assembly
so you gotta be mindful of that kind of
thing never yank never pull
and be patient gentle and patient now
before i get too far into my maker tech
let's get our maker on
so this is the central processing unit
the cpu
of our laptop computer so just like your
desktop computer you've got a cpu
you've got that brains chip of your
computer
now ideally you're going to have
something like a lint-free
cloth or perhaps some cotton or
something like that to clean with
in pandemic times we're steampunking it
out
and i'm using paper towel because it's
all i got and it's all i can get
because the stores are hard to get
access to
so i just need to be careful that i
don't get lint on that so
i do have 99 alcohol this is a
solvent that is going to help me to
clean off all of this
thermal paste so you can see how there's
a bunch of sticky gunk
on there which is the thermal compound
that is a conductive
uh a heat conductive
compound to help to dis to make that
good thermal
contact between the heat sink and the
cpu so with
some good strong 99
isopropyl or rubbing alcohol i'm just
going to very gently dab that off
so we're just cleaning off all of the
old
thermal compound because we're going to
be applying
some new so this again is a
see that this is a task that you'll be
able to do yourself
and you can be confident as long as
you're careful because i don't want you
to break stuff okay
you can be confident in doing this now
it's always a good idea to start with
if this is your first computer repair
start with something cheaper than a
lenovo thinkpad you don't want to do
this on your main
production computer start with things
like a raspberry pi
this is one of the things that makes
single board computers like here's a
an odroid xu4q well get yourself
one go get one take that big old
heatsink off the top there
and play around with it and don't be
afraid to break it because they're super
cheap
get yourself a raspberry pi which is
even cheaper because
it's not as powerful and don't go with a
raspberry pi 4 because that's not going
to be cheap
go with something like a 3b and just use
it as a
test bed to be able to play around
and no don't be afraid to wreck it it's
okay to wreck things
but don't wreck your good laptop
you want to be mindful of that
but you know single board computing has
really given us a platform
that we can screw around and we don't
have to be afraid
of busting things up all right i'm going
to give that just a
quick little dab dry and i'm being
careful
not to leave like chunks of paper towel
behind because paper towel is not
the ideal thing it works some people are
saying oh don't use paper towel well
it works it's makeshift it's pandemic
but it works and there is my cpu now so
it's
nice and clean and it is ready to
receive the new cooling system
and some good new thermal compound
all right so here's our cooling system
that i picked up online
and incidentally buying the parts myself
was significantly cheaper than getting
the parts through a local
computer shop and i'm not afraid to goof
around
there we are again don't force things
take your time there it is so here's the
original
here's the new one can you tell the
difference
all right so we want to take a peek at
this it looks like they have some
thermal compound
added to the block
but it has a piece of plastic over top
i believe i'm just going to confirm that
maybe not maybe it's like a
a solid kind of thermal sticker
yeah it is so what i want to do
is i actually want to grab a tube of
thermal compound that i've chosen and
you can pick up some of this like online
or at your local computer shop if
they're open
and you just want to get some dabs on
there right on
the processor this is going to give us a
good
thermal contact between the two
whoa did that ever come out fast that
was not intentional
it doesn't really matter you want to
just have a little tiny doppel there
because as soon as i stick that down
that's just going to go
which is fine but it's a little bit
messy
all right so now i want to remount this
the new one so i'm mounting the new one
exactly as the old one came out
and that is going to go let's see here
right over top of the cpu
let's grab our screwdriver and start
screwing that down so that that can
get a nice thermal
linkage between the processor and the
the copper cooler
so i'm just tightening them about a
third of the way just to get it
affixed and then i'm going to tighten it
right up there we are
see there's nothing overly complicated
about this type of repair
things like upgrading your ram you can
see that i've got an extra ram module
slot here so if i wanted to i could buy
an identical ram
dim here and put it here and then i'd
basically get twice as much ram if you
wanted to do an upgrade
this is my hard drive if i wanted to
upgrade the hard drive put an ssd in
there
i could replace that with an ssd and
then reinstall my linux mint
what else could i do here's a battery
for the cmos the
the memory so i could replace that if i
ever start losing
memory which happens after the battery
gets old
this is the wi-fi chip here um what else
do we need to see like it's like there
are so many components here that are so
easily accessible that i could repair
myself which is brilliant
all right so now i need to just give
this a little bit of a
a shimmy there because it's never been
in a computer so it's just a little bit
off on its fitting
but it looks great perfect fit really
if i can get this final screw to go in
oh
remember just take your time it's not
like you're doing a tv
show and you need to make it look like
you know what you're doing
there it is so that is strapped in okay
so now we've got
our fan in place we've got this guy here
which we need to
so this is the cable that was affixed to
the other one it looks like they've
already included like a double-sided
sticker here an adhesive to reapply that
to the new fan that's kind of cool so
they've thought of it all
and then that's going to go right here
whatever this is it might be video or
audio or some crazy thing
connecting into the board i'm not too
sure
as long as you put it back the way it
should go
you're golden
just like anything as you disassemble
something make sure you observe
how it goes back together and now here's
the
fan power and pwm
for the power management and i'm just
going to carefully
plug that in where the old fan
unplugged
and that
that is a problem because the fan that i
ordered has
two more pins
or it's just a different adapter let's
count the cables so let's see
we've got one
one two three four five
and on the old fan we've got
one two three four five okay
so i'm going to have to do a little bit
of a modification here in order to
get this fan to be able to connect
to this power supply which is fine
except i have a problem
i'm operating in pandemic mode
and i in this studio space
have not yet unpacked my soldering tools
so this feature which is meant to be
just finished today
is going to end up being a two-part
because i'm going to have to solder
these wires together
so what i have done is i've removed the
incorrect header and i've separated out
the wires they are all color coded so
i'm good to go
and i've got the correct header right
here from the old fan
so what we're going to be doing is we're
going to be connecting these wires
together correctly
but i need to heat shrink tube them
heat tube shrink them i don't know
i need to connect those together with
solder
and i need to shrink tube them as well
to protect the cable
so unfortunately i don't have the tools
at my disposal
in order to do that right now that said
i will have and we'll be able to
complete this
on a very soon future episode
but everything else fit perfectly it's
just that header
which is unfortunate i had hoped that
we'd be able just to pull this off very
easily tonight but it does turn into a
bit more of a maker tech solution
doesn't it since the
since we do have to do some soldering
which is unexpected and not
necessarily normal either
they must have changed the header at
some point or made some kind of change
to that header to make it so that it's
not
the right size but we'll fix that and
that's one of the things too is that you
can take cables and you can
splice them and and make them work
together and that's
one of the exciting things about doing
maker tech is that you can make
things work that generally otherwise
would not work and then you can make
them you know you save yourself a
boatload of money when you can do it
yourself
but at this point we've got to call it
quits on this so
watch our channel category five dot tv
for part two of the fan
replacement series
[Laughter]
and on part two i'm going to be
soldering these cables together we're
going to be shrink tubing them
and we're going to fire it up and see
how things work
and see how that cooler has improved
in the meantime we've got to head over
to the newsroom so here is
becca here's what's coming up in the
category 5 dot tv news room
samsung blu-ray and dvd players around
the world are bricking themselves
automatically fifa 21 will be the most
realistic yet space exploration company
spacex applied for a license to offer
satellite-based service to rural areas
in canada
google has quietly launched an
ai-powered pinterest rival named
keane apple is moving to arm processors
and microsoft's mixer streaming platform
is dead
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5 dot tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
samsung users unplug your ethernet
millions of samsung blu-ray and dvd
players are being
bricked all around the world
entertainment has become one of the
biggest tools for keeping sane during
these trying times but while many
companies are aggressively pushing their
streaming services
others still prefer owning the media
they buy in physical form
that mostly means dvds and blu-ray discs
which of course require appropriate
devices to play them
but what if those devices all suddenly
stopped working for no apparent reason
that's the rather eerie and frustrating
situation that owners of samsung blu-ray
players are now experiencing
experiencing around the world with no
answer or solution yet in sight
there doesn't seem to be any common
denominator other than the fact that
it's happening across a number of
samsung's wi-fi or ethernet connected
blu-ray and dvd players
it doesn't appear to matter which model
the most common behavior reported is
that the players reboot themselves after
a few seconds
causing an inescapable boot loop others
have reported hearing noises as if the
players were reading
empty disc slots given the mysterious
and sudden appearance of the bug
some people have different theories on
what caused it
some blame an overnight firmware update
but the range of devices covered is so
wide and random that it seems less
likely
some believe it may be an expired ssl
security certificate in the firmware
which
could explain why no amount of resetting
the device to factory settings
seems to work unfortunately samsung
remains unresponsive despite the growing
number of complaints
possibly due to how it happened during
the weekend
given global conditions it's
understandable how owners are not so
amused
especially if it will require them to
turn in the device for manual servicing
fifa game developer ea sports promises
that the next generation version of fifa
21 will feature new technology
to make it the most realistic yet the
fifa series remains one of the most
popular video game franchises in the
world
next year's entry will release for both
existing consoles as well as the new
xbox series x
and playstation 5. but ea says the newer
consoles will take advantage of more
advanced technology
despite regular criticism that the
annual game is often very similar to the
previous year's entry
it had sold over 260 million copies
as of 2018. ea says its newest title
will feature more lifelike player
movements
which it says will be the most authentic
character behaviors
uh ever seen in sports video games
the next generation editions will
feature significantly reduced loading
times
and the ps5 version will take advantage
of haptic feedback on the consoles
dual sense controller new rendering and
lighting techniques will also help to
increase the overall realism
of the game fans in the stadium stands
will also be more interactive
even participating in celebrations fifa
21 will be released worldwide in october
before the new consoles launch the ps5
and xbox series x versions with their
advanced features will be available
later
but ea is off a path
to players who buy the game on the
previous generation
early sadly nintendo switch gamers won't
get to experience any of the franchise's
new models or gameplay innovations
the lower powered portable console will
instead get a legacy edition release
that will include only new kits and
teams and an updated menu and overlay
system
ea has promised to reveal more about the
game in the coming months
elon musk's spacex has applied to offer
high-speed internet to canadians living
in remote areas
using satellite technology last year
spacex has launched more than 500
satellites into earth orbit to build its
starlink mega constellation
which aims to make satellite internet
available from practically
anywhere on the planet spacex applied
with canada's telecom regulator
the canadian radio television and
telecommunications commission
crtc for what's known as a basic
international telecommunications
services or
bits license that's a requirement for
any company that wants to offer what the
crtc calls
telecommunications traffic between
canada and any other country
if they are successful in getting a bits
license that means spacex whose formal
company name
is space exploration technologies corp
could theoretically try to offer more
wireless telecom services down the line
such as voice and data plans but for now
the application focuses
on high-speed internet beamed directly
into rural homes and businesses via the
company's
existing network of so-called near-earth
satellites canada is far from the only
place spacex is trying to offer internet
service
the company is planning to offer
high-speed internet services
in the united states later this year
through a subsidiary
known as starlink before rapidly
expanding to near global coverage of the
populated world by
2021 as they say on the company website
crtc data suggests as many as 40 percent
of canadians who don't live in major
urban areas
do not have access to high-speed
internet and what is available is often
prohibitively expensive
the issue has taken on increased
importance during the kova 19 pandemic
as millions of canadians find themselves
working from home
with seemingly no end in sight the
application was filed in may and
debt and the deadline for public comment
was last friday
more than 1200 canadians have weighed in
on the proposal
a large number of them in support of it
elon musk
says the new service won't require a
special installer
there's just two instructions and they
can be done in either order point at sky
plug in starlink hopes to make its
services available worldwide
and you can receive a notification once
it's available in your area by signing
up
at starlink.com google has launched an
artificial intelligence powered
pinterest killer
at least competitor called keen
also apple is switching to arm
processors and microsoft is shutting
down its
mixer streaming video service becca's
got those stories coming right up
and also robert koenig our crypto
correspondent is
here with the crypto corner don't go
[Music]
anywhere
welcome to the crypto corner this week
we've got some interesting news for you
but as usual let's start looking into
the market
how did the market perform in the last
seven days
as we can see no big changes here last
week it was a draw on
274 billion today or currently it's 278
billion
bitcoin had an increase of 2.4 percent
in last seven days
but if we sort this year by seven days
we see suddenly compound
increasing by 292 percent the over 20
coins
that had an increase of over 15 percent
and on the downside only two coins lost
more than 15 percent
so what happened here why is there
suddenly such a big change
and if we look into the d5 market cap
because compound
is part of the d5 market we see that
most of those changes
are coming from uh compound so last week
i showed you this
uh this chart and it was a 2.3 billion
now it's
6.7 billion as you can see most of that
is coming from compound now let's dive a
little bit deeper into this here and
check what happened
and if we take a look at the compound
plat platform so compound
dot finance we see it's basically like a
bank so you can
supply money to the environment or you
can borrow money
and in the case of let's say bit basic
attention token
you will receive 27 and if you borrow
money you have to pay 34
so far everything is fine now
last week a compound was listed on
coinbase and that
caused a huge increase in price and
because of that
this environment went absolutely crazy
and the reason is
that every time you take out a loan or
receive money you'll be compensated with
comps
which is the native token of this
platform
so you receive money in other words if
you take out a loan
and to check that there's another
website called
predictions.exchange and if i
say i want to have 1000 here so enter
basic attention token and i do calculate
then i see that
i will receive on top of those thousand
dollars i will receive
17 interest so i don't have to pay
interest i will receive 17
interest now some people are clever and
they take that money
and put it back into the system and
that's called
yield farming and with yield farming you
can achieve
[Music]
interest of over a hundred percent now
i have to clearly say at this stage so
it's a huge disclaimer
what you're hearing here is not
financial advice
this is a very young industry it's
guided by software
and there are plenty of bugs in software
and also it can be hacked so it's a very
risky
uh environment and if you don't
understand
the details of what is happening here
please do not invest any money
even small amounts can be dangerous
because the fees
uh can be as high as 15 for one
transaction
so just to give you an example of why uh
one has to be careful here's somebody
that put
uh money into the system and took out so
he was doing yield farming
and then suddenly realized that he had
much less money available and the reason
is
that he was liquidated because of the
interest
that he didn't consider and this is a
hard environment it's guided by software
and if you don't have enough collateral
in the system you will be liquidated
there's nobody that will call you and
say hey
you need to put money in this year so
you're not you're not liquid you're not
being liquidated
and that's why you have to be really uh
please be careful i'm showing this to
you
because defy as such is a market
that is uh coming as you can see it's
completely different
to what you are accustomed to as a bank
customer
but it's the future yeah it's
decentralized which means
there is no entity behind this here it's
completely
autonomous from any federal
institution or financial institution and
it's global
so everybody in the world can
participate here in other words you can
be your own bank by putting money into
it and taking money out
but as mentioned you need to understand
what this is about
and so as long as you don't understand
things like what is avei what do they do
what's
wbtc rapt btc ran btc
dydx uh wrapped eth all those things if
you don't understand
what is happening here please don't put
money any money into that um
there's no there's no customs service
that you can call
in case something goes wrong
but as mentioned this is the future this
is where finance will go to because
uh it cuts out the middleman it cuts out
the bank
and you can do business directly and
it's secured because it's secured
through the ethereum blockchain
so um more more is to come in this in
industry more is going to be invented
and
yeah anyway that that's it from uh me
this week i hope you enjoyed this
uh short uh excursion to the d5 market
the news
of on what's happening there and uh
thank you very much for watching and i
hope to see you next week again
so thank you bye bye well thanks robert
always appreciate your insight
uh just a reminder for those of you
watching at home we are not providing
basically financial investment advice
what we're doing is we're giving you the
information about the cryptocurrency
market
and leaving it up to you to make the
decisions and now
back to becca thank you robbie google's
area 120 team an
internal incubator that creates
experimental apps and services
has launched keen a would-be pinterest
rival that draws on the search giant's
machine learning expertise to create
topics
available on the web at staykeem.com and
on
android co-founder cj adams says keane
aims to be an alternative
to mindlessly browsing online feeds
adam writes in a blog post on keen you
say what you want to spend more time on
and then create content from the web and
people you trust to help make that
happen
you make a keen which can be about any
topic whether it's baking delicious
bread at home
getting into birding or researching
typography
keen lets you create the content you
love share your collection with others
and find new content based on what you
have saved
pinterest has already captured the hobby
focus side of this market with its
pinboard style visual design
two characteristics that keen is trying
to imitate but keen has google's
expertise in machine learning which
adams says will surface helpful content
related to your interests
google has never been able to break into
the social space a venue of online
activity that generates scads of
lucrative data for targeting ads
a pinterest style social network would
really allow it to hone
in on users interests and gather this
information
and it does seem that data collected by
keen is being collated with
everything else google knows about users
you log into keen using your google
account and clicking on the site's
privacy link just points you to the
google wide privacy policy
it's interesting to see google push its
machine learning systems into more
varied applications
especially those that seem like they're
trying to foster users interest
in rewarding hobbies rather than
algorithms that drive people to greater
engagement without caring what it is
they're actually engaging with
will you give kane a try are your
interests such that you don't mind
google knowing what you're into
comment below if you're watching online
or hop onto our website to post your
thoughts
on episode 648 just seven weeks ago
we talked about how apple plans to drop
intel for its own processors for future
macs
but it came as a surprise monday that
these processors will be
arm-based it's a big move and perhaps
the biggest addition the transition to
arm-powered chips brings
is the ability for ios and ipad apps to
run natively
on mac os in the future apple says most
apps will just work
meaning you'll be able to run native mac
os apps alongside native ios
apps side by side apple is promising new
levels of performance and far
less power consumption when it with its
move to in-house processors
apple is designing its own range of soc
for macs
with unique features to mac but a common
architecture
across product lines microsoft is
working on office updates for the new
mac silicon
and word and excel are already running
natively on the new mac
processors with powerpoint even using
apple's metal tech
for rendering apple has always been also
been working with adobe to get their
photo editing
editing apps up and running on the new
chips
mac os big sur will also include a new
version of rosetta
apple used rosetta previously for the
power pc shift to intel based max and
rosetta 2 will automatically translate
existing apps at install time
this means that even if developers
haven't fully updated their apps they
should still work without modification
apple is also using virtualization for
running versions of linux on these new
macs
apple's transition to arm follows a
similar move by microsoft
to experiment with windows on arm nearly
a decade ago
microsoft started this work ahead of the
windows 8 release in 2012
and even released the windows rt
operating system that was designed for
arm-based hardware microsoft has since
transitioned windows 10 to arm as well
apple will release the first mac with
apple silicon at the end of this year
and it expects the transition to take
two years new intel powered macs are
still in the pipeline so apple isn't
moving exclusively to armbasemax
just yet microsoft is shutting down
mixer
its video game live streaming platform
in a move that will affect streamers
from tyler ninja belvin's on down
in a statement released on mixer's
official blog on monday the streaming
service announced that it will be
shuttering its operations side and will
help mixer streamers transition
to facebook gaming starting on july 22nd
mixer.com will redirect to fb.gg
in a similar statement on its blog
facebook gaming noted that mixer
streamers that choose to move to
facebook gaming
will be matching partner agreements as
closely as possible
most famously ninja had signed an
exclusivity deal with mixer in august
2019 for reportedly around
20 to 30 million dollars per year
in an interview with the verge
microsoft's head of gaming phil spencer
said that the move to shut down mixer
was a strategic one
spencer said it wasn't as much about
return on sell
it was about finding a partnership
partnership that was the best things for
the community and streamers
we think this is it and it gives us a
great place to launch more xcloud
content and give gamers the ability to
play from there
while media is focused almost entirely
on the result to streamers
the fact remains mixer is closing down
without so much as notifying its staff
trust and safety staffer jazuki said on
twitter monday
guys we had no clue i found out with the
rest of you
i am devastated i have dedicated all i
have to this platform and this
hurts immensely according to microsoft
mixer's intellectual property and staff
will be transferred to the microsoft
teams division on july 22nd
but suzuki make it sounds like that's
not the case at all
she's tweeting a call for employers to
reach out to her if they're looking to
hire
a strong-willed empowered female who
focuses on efficiency
and high productivity with a team
mentality and she re
retweeted i am brandon who said there
are a lot of people out of jobs now due
to mixer closing
during a pandemic what the h-e-l-l
launched in january 2016 as beam mixer
was renamed after its acquisition by
microsoft
in 2017 the platform's attempt to
compete with twitch resulted in the
signings of major twitch streamers
such as ninja and shroud for huge
monetary deals
despite these moves mixer was unable to
significantly approach twitch's larger
audience numbers
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patreon patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
we're on twitter at category 5
tv i'm personally on twitter at robbie
ferguson and i follow back
don't forget you can find us on all of
your favorite platforms if you've got
roku hey do a quick search in the
channel store for category 5 tv you'll
find us there
also we're on youtube as you can expect
what show
isn't we're on bookface i mean facebook
as well so just do a quick search for
category 5 technology tv
i'm sure you'll find us on your favorite
platform
and of course everything comes together
on our website
category 5 dot tv i appreciate you being
here
again with us this week and i'm looking
forward to seeing you
again next week as we get back into our
microtic
series i'll see you then bye
[Music]
you