what i wanted to show you
is simply a clock that i've been working
on i know that sounds crazy but
one of the things that i've been trying
to achieve
with this space which is our basically
our producers room
is to make it as functional as possible
but also try to give it some eye candy
as well
i've been using just a standard analog
clock on the wall because it has
tick tick tick tick and i can count the
seconds but i wanted to take it one more
like a step further because quite often
when we're producing video especially
live
we have to meet markers so there's a
countdown
usually i have a walkie-talkie if i'm
producing somebody in the other
room and i'll be communicating back and
forth
in order to let them know the countdown
so you've seen it on tv i'm sure so
you know five seconds three
mark you know so we're punching in that
way but it's not always ideal to use
just a standard clock
so i set out to build something a little
bit different and it's powered
by today anyways a raspberry pi
3b plus i am not at all satisfied with
the performance of that which you're
about to see
um however it's given me a development
platform to
play around with now i may have to
install it on something
that can handle better graphics well why
do you need
graphics for a clock robbie because
i want to so this is what i'm working on
i based this on the aries jquery
dashboard so you may be familiar with
that but what i've done is i've actually
created a functional clock
out of this system so um so i've taken
that it's basically a template
and then i've created a jquery clock
counter countdown disk check that uses
ajax to php to be able to check my
network to see if there's any hard drive
failures
or or hard drives that are full in our
array um
and i'll show you also it'll it even
shows when we're live on the air so
that's pretty cool right now it's not
connected so
we've got studio e up here these are the
only things that are not functional
these are just eye candy right now
um from the original theme i've left
them in just to make it
so that there's some filled space there
no point in removing them and having
having it not look symmetrical so
um so with this we can ignore those
things
here we have the actual functional clock
and i've got greek
for time there according to google
translate
[Laughter]
so we've got 9 46 is the time and we've
got a seconds counter here
10 11 12. so you can see how janky the
video is that's because of the raspberry
pi 3b plus not being
uh it's the graphics processing not
being able to keep up with the
with the visual effects that i've
created it runs
stellar on my linux desktop um
so that's the actual time nothing fancy
there except i wanted to
separate out the seconds rather than
having them
in line like you'd normally see like 9
colon 46 colon 38
i wanted to move that 38 up here and
it's counting in real time using jquery
so every second there's a timer that
updates the time
then taking it one step further quite
often
in production we count backwards so
when we're looking at 10 o'clock the
time
we're counting down to it so we're
calling
60 seconds 30 seconds
10 seconds 5
and then everything goes black and boom
we're live
so that's how it works so what we have
is now now we've seen that it's 9 47 we
can
really easily calculate that we've got
43 seconds left
but if we look down here we actually
have a countdown that says time will be
9 48 in 35 34
33 you can see that jquery timer is a
little bit off
that's also the raspberry pi that's not
that's not the system
itself it's that the raspberry pi
unfortunately can't keep up with it i
was really thinking this was gonna work
on
on a single board computer i tried it on
an asus
um tinkerboard and it was uh
it was so unable to handle the graphics
that it actually wouldn't even load them
the raspberry pi 3b plus at least loads
it but not
well enough so i'm going to try a couple
of different sbcs
reason i'm trying the raspberry pi 3b
plus right now is simply
it has wi-fi which makes it a little
easier to set up
because i don't have i haven't unpacked
my ethernet cables yet
over here oh and this is not functional
either this is just fake
part of the template oh i should point
out up here so
as i'm recording this as we mentioned
we're not actually broadcasting live
today this is all
we've produced this behind like after
the fact so
um this shows the video feed is off the
air but as soon as we go live
this will actually shift to say on air
so that also serves a double purpose if
we're here
producing and and broadcasting a live
show
we'll notice that presumably i mean if
we look up we'll see that we're off the
air something's going on even though we
think we're on the air
this will actually show that then this
is also functional
so this shows disk usage my disk usage
is not actually that bad although it is
close
what this is looking to do is it's going
to connect to samba
shares on my server and it does a disk
check every 15 seconds to see
how much disk usage there is and this
will move automatically
the only one right now that's currently
connected because i have not created
those samba connections
is the sd card so you can see i'm using
about what looks like about ten percent
eight percent of my sd card so these
will move in real time
the animation is so much better on a
computer
so i've got this little box here that
i'm thinking maybe i'll turn that into
my clock but
part of the idea is i want to create a
setup here that's
very low power consumption yet has some
eye candy
and is also functional so this serves
many purposes from the
time to the countdown um to the disk
usage warnings
and even showing us whether we're on air
or off air
and it will even tell us if there's a
problem with the api if the api is not
responding this will go red
and it will warn us of that right here
you see an empty box and that's because
i have not yet plugged
a microphone into the raspberry pi this
is a spectrum
analyzer um so that
will actually show the the spectrum uh
in real time of
audio that's flowing through the
raspberry pi so i'm thinking maybe we'll
pull that off of our mixing console
so that we can actually see the audio
levels on the
on the dashboard so that's pretty cool
so that's my new clock
it's much more than a clock it's a
functional dashboard and going to be
growing over the next little while as i
develop it
it's not really ready for mainstream use
right yet however if you'd like to check
it out you'll see
a repository called studio
on github.com cat5 tv
my github page and the source code for
this
and everything is there and you can
check it out if you have a pr for me to
make it even funkier i'd love to see it
and i'm going to be working on figuring
out which platform which hardware
platform is going to work the best
i don't really want to put it on a pi 4
i
figure it probably will run better there
but that's a very expensive clock
very expensive clock so so
maybe though because there's dual video
output on a raspberry pi 4
i could offset that cost by running my
nem server on the fourth screen
so that gives me some thought so maybe
i'm going to tinker with that what are
your thoughts what system should i run
it on what one do you think is going to
perform best as far as the graphics go
the processor is doing just fine it's
able to do all this but it's the
graphical end of it that the raspberry
pi 3b
plus just is terrible at so
uh i'm curious what what single board
computer is going to be
the best one for this use case so check
it out github.com
cap5 tv slash studio and
the folder that you're looking for for
this particular application
is screens slash dashboard
and you'll also see screens slash the
orville which is actually a screen
from the set of the orville provided by
tom costantino
so that repository is basically anything
that we do
that i do for the studio like api
connections and
things like that that's where i stick
them so if you want to check out how we
do things
that's a pretty cool spot
github.comcat5tv
studio
[Music]
you