at category 5 tv we trust our files to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
whether for your server laptop or
desktop computer
you'll experience improved performance
and reliability
kingston is with you get ready it's time
for the tech
welcome to category 5 technology tv
everybody henry bigley brown
everyone thank you so much so much for
having me he says it's good to be back
this is your first time here
what you talking about i was here what's
what is this madness oh yeah it's my
first can you believe this is your first
time
in studio e welcome you know what yeah i
know you guys you guys had to beam me up
from earth but when i was like
from the teleporter room i was able to
walk on over here it's all futuristic
the technology here is over the top i
know i was
i was able to walk by the jacuzzi and
then like we were walking by
the other rooms and it was
it's great i i love it it's henry
approved oh fantastic
you know it's good now it's good to see
you man how you been this whole madness
we haven't gotten to
have you join us on the show yeah it's
been unfortunate i've missed everyone
here
um it feels really good to be back um
but yeah like um
my industry aviation is kind of weird
right now yeah he's a pilot
so i my arms are tired but i get
arrested what do you do when they ground
all the planes
i gotta fly drones i i stop my drone
company so that's doing well but at the
same time it feels good to be
actually seeing real people again and
not just my drones i can actually talk
to
he considers me a real person this is so
nice this is great
it's great to see all of you wonderful
faces i mean like it's
it's it's great to be back i've missed
you all and it's nice to see this
amazing place so you've been flying your
drone yes what are you doing
in 2020 that's a little bit fresh a
little bit
well robbie let me tell you about the
future here oh the future
i'm not just taking photos anymore oh
i'm not even take taking videos
not even just just videos anymore yeah i
know there's
the future is now robbie wow let me tell
you something wow
you guys heard it here the future is
photogrammetry
photography and i'm not taking photos or
graphs that's that's not what it's like
you're taking photos of your grandma i
am taking
photos and turning turning those photos
into something called
a 3d object a 3d file a
3d environment made from just photos oh
henry i wish there was some way
i wish there was some way you could show
us this i know i wish there was some way
i recorded a feature
and send it to you and brought it with
me yeah with them on an sd card so it's
here
tonight and we're going to be checking
it out now this is a really cool
tech it is absolutely fantastic and the
really amazing
part about this is how available
and accessible it is to everyone and
that's what i really love about cat5 is
that we're showing a lot of open source
stuff we're showing a lot of really
accessible things for viewers
well all the programs that i use
in this feature the free trials are out
there so if you want
you have a drone you're safe to fly you
can do it at home
which i absolutely love even 3d printing
aspect but we'll get there
when we get there but know that you too
can
make your house a 3d model and print
that 3d that is cool
so we're going to actually be checking
that out in a couple of moments before
we get into the feature though folks
i want to remind you hey if you love the
kind of content that we produce here at
category 5 tv please make sure you click
that subscribe
give us a thumbs up and click the bell
that's going to make sure that you get
the notifications every time we post
new shiny videos to our youtube channel
and if you haven't found us on youtube
yet hey head on over to
linuxtechshow.com
and that's going to actually reroute you
to our youtube channel
and that's a great way to find us so hey
thanks to everybody who has been
subscribing
we you know a couple months ago i was
like hey we can hit 25 000. we can
do it and now we're like 27.5
thousand it just like smashed it yeah
keep it coming folks keep it coming
one of these days i'm so far off from a
plaque henry
i'm so far off that's what they all say
and then you're going to wake up and
then it's suddenly
it's going to be this is the feature
this is the one henry come on
get us 1000 subscribers tonight we're
going to have it
right here it's going to be nicely
centered
and we'll just remember tonight this is
where it began this is
this is it folks this is it so hey make
sure you click that subscribe that's
very
very important all right henry let's
jump onto that sd card and see what it
is he got for us let's do it
today we're going to talk about a really
new exciting segment on
photogrametry what is photogrammetry
glad you asked
basically we can take our drones now and
we can produce
3d images so we can make 3d models of
real world objects
so whether that's a building a field
your house
your business whatever you can take your
drone
take photos of your property and make
that into a 3d
image or in this case 3d model with that
being said we're going to take it one
step further
and we're going to take that 3d model
and 3d print it
so then you have your house in the palm
of your hand
what use is this i'm glad you asked an
example of what this can be used for
is if you're a real estate agent and
you're trying to sell a house but
somebody has a hard time seeing they
could be blind
etc what you can do is that you can 3d
scan the property
3d print that property and then they can
actually feel the house with their very
own hands
how cool is that now stay tuned for this
exciting segment as we go over how to
3d print as well as 3d capture using
photogrammetry
let's take a look
[Applause]
[Music]
so now that our drone's safely back on
the ground what we can do is head back
to the studio
upload these images to the cloud to the
software
that will then stitch it all together
into our 3d model
so that's pretty cool let's go take a
look at that
let's go all right now we're back in the
studio here
um i know this is a different building
than we used before but this one's a
really nice example so we're going to
use this uh
provided example here so let's pretend
we're we've finished flying we did our
little grid pattern or whatever we flew
now we upload our photos to
your provider in this case it's drone
deploy but it could be pix4d
or dji um and then after
it processes you get something cool
looking like this
so again we have our ortho mosaic
so it's like a giant 2d map so kind of
imagine this as a more high definition
google maps or
satellite image right so this image here
that you can see on this overlaid map
this is made of hundreds of images
stitched together
to make make it look like it's a
satellite image which is really really
cool it's a really cool program but of
course with this since there's gps data
within the files so again we have our
geolocation data
we can do cool things such as measure
distances
we can do different spot heights we can
do different locations you can pin
things
but this isn't just everything i'm going
to show you right now
no what we really want is this
and that is the 3d model of the
environment
all right this is what we're looking for
this is the cool
looking 3d map the 3d
model that we have been able to create
using our images that we've uploaded to
our program
so pretty much again we take our photos
the program stitches everything together
and it's able to create this
cool 3d file this 3d model
photogrammetry really is the future and
again it's not perfect like again going
closer into things we do have like a few
little weird nubs and a few little uh
errors
but again you can correct those in
blender or if you
pretty much the more advanced drone you
have also known as the better camera
if you have fleur or lidar or anything
that makes
a much better high resolution image a
more accurate image
but again today we're just using uh
standard off the uh
off-the-shelf drone so hey that that
that's still a pretty nice those are
some really sharp looking lines
so now what we can do is that we can
actually download this map
depending what program you're using and
we can
export this as an obj file or another
readable
3d file format and we can actually
import this into a 3d printer
so let's take a look at some images that
robbie gave us
of him converting one of my files i did
into a 3d model
all right so before we turn into a 3d
model i just wanted to show
what model i gave robbie so this is a
house we shot a few years ago you can
take a look at this on sketchfab.com
under air support aerial photography
that's my company
um but as you can see it's a really nice
looking home you know the resolution
is actually not that bad this was shot
with a phantom 3 professional
um again there are a few errors like
this section right here
so this is there was a tree right here
so we weren't able to get proper
photos that's why the program kind of
freaked out in this corner here
but everything else is pretty uh it did
a really nice job
and again the uh algorithms have become
a lot more accurate
uh these past few years so chances are
if we did this again it would be a lot
more accurate
even if we still use the phantom 3
camera and of course you can add other
details in like right here
just in blender or other programs so
let's see how
robbie's program takes this dot obj file
and turns it into a 3d printer readable
file
let's take a look thanks henry we're
going to dig into the software that's
used to convert henry's aerial
photogrammetry into a 3d printable
object
and we're going to send it to our 3d
printer right after this
[Music]
done
the software that henry is referring to
is called ultimaker cura
it's a free program it's available for
windows mac and linux
and you can follow the links at cat5.tv
slash
3d printing in order to grab that what
i'm going to do is i'm going to open the
file that henry was showing us there now
keep in mind henry was looking at a
textured file so it had like the
the brick overlay and everything all the
coloring and all that stuff
what we're about to see is just the obj
so the object
just the actual 3d printing file
and bring that into cura and let's see
what we find now we got this little itty
bitty
like what is this a house for ants
all right so it's put it up on its end
you can see how that is so what i want
to do is i want to rotate that
so i'm just going to click on it click
on the rotate tool and bring it down 90
degrees
there we are that's going to put it flat
on the surface but it's still this
itty-bitty house for ants so let's
increase the size of that as well and
boop there we are so that's awfully big
like 200 millimeters let's bring it down
just a little bit
okay so the first thing that i notice
here is that we've got a lot of ground
see the earth around the around the
building we've got some boulders here
some shrubs
and this guy here looks kind of messy
what i'm going to do
is i'm just going to lower the position
of the house a little bit
so that we can push that ground into the
build plate
on my printer i don't want to go too far
because we don't want to like submerge
the house we just want to
pull back some of that that landscaping
there so that we're not actually 3d
printing
the dirt and that looks
pretty good we've still got some
anomalies like over here you can see
this
little uh triangle here which is
probably a rock or
some kind of something on the on the
landscaping we're going to have these
little
see this little guy right here that's
just going to print but it's
you know not going to be it's something
that we keep it's just going to be a
discard you could clean this up like if
henry wanted to he'd be able to
take this into like tinkercad or
whatever cad program he's using
clean it up first fix up the texturing
of the windows because these are going
to come out
you know looking pretty pretty odd um
and there's that area where i think
that's is that where the
no yeah that's where the tree where
henry was showing us the tree is
and it looks like a cave so that's going
to be rather interesting
but how cool that this is done i mean
the actual like
design you can tell it's you know what
it is that this is done with a
with a quadcopter taken a whole bunch of
pictures
and generally speaking that looks pretty
cool so
um other than that a couple of quick
mentions
is you know typically when you're 3d
printing you're going to need supports
if anything overhangs because
otherwise it's just going to droop and
and you're going to get this stringing
coming down
so i'm looking for anything here that's
going to overhang and i don't really see
much there is this overhang here
and kira is showing me some red to to
tell me that
this might be a problem but i think
because it's such a small
uh overhang i think we're probably going
to be okay to do it without supports
we don't need supports you might think
well we need to support the roof because
you know the roof
is like this and if it's a hollow thing
then it's
uh it's going to you know completely
cave in
but the way kira looks at this when it's
slicing it is
it treats this as a solid object so
rather than supports for the interior of
the object that's actually called infill
so there's a couple of things that we're
going to set here so if we did need
supports we're going to click on
generate supports
i don't think we're going to if i
preview that
so i've just clicked on generate
supports and then slice
and i'm previewing i just want to see
where it's going to stick supports
just to see how badly kira thinks that
we need it
yeah see the whole outside has now been
basically
covered in supports so that would be a
lot of stuff to trim away
wow i think we're going to have a
real problem with this area where the
tree was
see how it's completely filled in that
that area
that could be a problem i think because
of the jaggedness of it
this particular object is not going to
print well with supports i mean you're
going to
how would you ever remove so many
supports and i think that's because of
the fact that being that it's a 3d scan
using just a standard camera
the edges are not quite perfect as
you've as you've seen there
so that's something that henry might
might want to clean up
before trying to 3d print let's turn off
the supports and i've got an infill
density of 20
and we're looking at about 14 hours to
print with supports my fear is just that
that's a lot of supports to remove
it might be very difficult now it's not
but it might be worth it
uh it's a hard thing to call uh this is
what it looks like without supports but
what i'm looking for is the infill
density
to make sure that this the roof is going
to be supported so i'm going to pull
down my preview here
so that i can see inside what's being
printed
so you can see that with a 20 percent
infill density
that is placing these kind of
their supports to hold up that roof
as it prints but without using you know
100 infill
and wasting a whole lot of filament
that's going to take about 10 hours and
67 grams of filament
so if you're wondering well how much is
that going to cost to print at that
scale
just go into your calculator and i know
that i paid forty dollars for the
one kilogram uh of filament so it's four
cents
per gram and we know that this is going
to be 67
grams so that's 68 2.68
to print at this scale and that's pretty
big considering my under three
bed is 220 by 220 millimeters
so what you're looking at there is uh
you know it is
let's see 143 millimeters
by 112 millimeters so it's pretty big
so do we print it with or without
supports that's the question
i think we're gonna get a better print
if we give it supports
especially in that kind of janky area
where the
where the tree was
and i think that's going to make it
worth it i know it is
it's just the additional four hours and
the amount of work to remove
all those supports it needs a lot of
them
let's see what happens if i change to
just build plate
see if that changes anything and change
the overhang angle to
um i don't know 60
and see how that changes things
so it's not going to give me as much
support in here
so that's going to save a fair bit of
filament and three hours
um yeah that looks a little better so
there are there's still going to be a
lot of support to remove and i feel like
with the way this is
um with the way the scan is that you're
probably going to have some trouble
figuring out what's a support and what's
actually part of the scan
so i think that's what we're going to be
up against so
for that reason and for the sake of the
the demonstration i'm going to try
scaling it down a bit
so that the overhangs are not as big
as they would be if it was 143
millimeters wide
so i'm going to make this about 50
millimeters
width and see
how that slices up with no supports
so it's going to be a lot smaller but
it's going to
probably do a lot better without
supports because
we don't have such a pronounced overhang
and let's give that a go i'm going to
send that over to my printer
and we'll see how she comes out
there it is this is my tiny house oh
it's so
cute i have always wanted to live in a
tiny house everyone who knows me
knows i'm a tiny house kind of guy and
this just proves it right here
in all seriousness though henry the the
reason that i printed it so small
as i mentioned was i wanted to see if it
would print without support and it did
and it printed quite nicely and it looks
pretty good
but it's very very tiny it is so i did
decide to take it to the next level for
you and throw something on the printer
and i sent another file and here you go
what what do you think
okay that's so cool check that out folks
yeah and i'll hand it to you i just want
to kind of show the b camera here just
so that you can
kind of see i know that is pretty robust
i printed it in
white filament for you because i thought
hey maybe you'd want to prime it and
paint it
um but then i realized as i was running
it that the cameras kind of don't like
white filament
because they white balance yourselves
and overexpose
themselves yeah it's like what are you
doing to me here yeah
that's tough that's tough our poor
camera guy is just like ah i don't
get it seriously like that amount of
detail that you managed to get out of
that 3d model that's pretty
amazing eh well you took your drone up
and just kind of it
software took it around and flew
overhead
yeah so like literally from the future
what you're able to see
is that literally we just did our kind
of grid patterns we were able to take
those photos
mash them all together in a blender and
out comes this now how hard was it now
when you sent me this it was an obj file
it was already a 3d ready yeah pretty
much ready to print as you saw yeah
pretty much how hard was that to put
together oh no no not at all
from photos yeah literally because the
program that you're able to see through
the feature
even if you use another one i use drone
deploy i've also used pix4d there's so
many
awesome programs out there but literally
just
download as and save it as obj i believe
there's a few
other file types you can do but obj is
the more
widely written it's pretty universal
yeah you can even open it up in blender
things like that right so it's it's
great so
um so hold up yeah if you can open it in
blender that means you could take this
house that you scanned yeah
and put it in a 3d movie that you create
you can you can even you could have a
real engine
you could put yourself in it you could
so you put it you could put it in a game
yeah so i've actually had this exact
same model in unreal for running so like
i could have like little fires around it
not that i'm planning on anything or you
could have like a sky box
so there's so many applications for this
cool i mean like again besides the 3d
environment so like video photo
film things like that yeah um i think i
mentioned this before to you
that if i'm a real estate agent and i'm
trying to sell a house to someone
right and maybe they're blind how do you
sell a house to someone blind and
describe the exterior
yeah you mentioned that that it's like
okay well you can actually feel it
exactly now you can literally 3d print
your house
or the house or whatever and you can
feel
what it looks like feel and is that
legit like
do people like it maybe if some of our
our folks that have
uh vision problems would that be a
benefit to you would that be a selling
feature
for even just education things like that
right like being able to do like
historic monuments or things like that
i think see from my perspective henry
yeah this does a couple of things
um in that it captures buildings or
whatever it might be maybe landscapes or
whatever
in such a way that it will last forever
as you say you can throw it in an unreal
engine with the textures
exactly it will even if the building
disintegrates
it's forever captured well that's the
thing is that there's a there's a lot of
famous stories about people going in the
middle east and as you know there's a
lot of conflicts over there
but before a lot of these buildings and
stuff were destroyed yeah
um people actually went in with uh
photogrammetry kits
and they were actually able to capture
all these older monuments all these
older
uh beautiful places so they were
destroyed so yeah
they're they're they're going to live on
forever now in 3d format where future
generations can go and say
yeah this is like this place at the very
least they can see it in like virtual
reality yeah exactly
and it's literally i'm really excited
this is just the start of this
technology it's it's fantastic
wonderful well thank you so much for
sharing that with us henry that's really
really cool stuff
thank you for printing it it's it looks
a lot
more realistic in real life than it does
on a computer and when you brought it up
when you brought it up with the textures
and everything it was it was
very very real-looking that was really
fun and that was with an older version
of that program that
that the model that we used for this was
around three or four years old
okay so the methods that the programs
use now their algorithms are actually so
much more accurate and i'm using an
older drone right so phantom 3 pro
my friend uses a maverick they have a
matrix as well so like a 10 000 drone
wow imagine how that looks having like a
full
dslr camera unreal is this the same tech
like when i see on google earth yeah it
is it actually is
so um a lot of people think that um you
can even use lidar or like floor things
you which you can
and it makes more accurate with using
lidar and fleur
but yeah so google maps bing maps those
guys
um they literally just use
photogrammetry so they have multiple
pictures from satellites yeah up in the
grape view blue yonder
and they have similar programs are able
to stitch that together they're using
satellite imagery to do what you're
doing with a drone it's pretty much this
but on steroids yeah so instead of
using a drone they're using satellites
and using uh
amazing data putting things together
and yeah so how do you see your house on
google earth and of course there are
some
ai um like some
ais are fixing a few errors here and
there but
when it comes down to it yeah that's the
basics of how
a lot of these companies are doing
things now cool stuff so yeah
i'm really keen to see how this brings
real world objects into
same here things like video games like i
really think
with virtual reality to be able to well
we actually already see this um a famous
one that just came out is the new
microsoft light sim right that
the entire 3d world is just big maps
but it's just in a 3d environment and
for years we've always had flights in
google earth where you just use your
arrow keys but
that's not a flight sim but it's it's
amazing to see where we're going with
this technology
very cool so yeah very cool uh where can
now i understand this model is
proprietary so this is something that
you shot professionally and this is
owned by the people who own the house
yeah so just just for privacy and
copyright reasons i'm not going to be
releasing this
variant of the model yeah however i do
have um another one i'll get to that in
a second
you can look on free websites uh one of
them that i'm featuring personally is
sketchfab.com
all right um it's a 3d file sharing site
you can get free files you can
buy files on there you can do a lot of
different licensing
opportunities as well but there's
there's a lot of very unique projects on
there um i might make one of mine
uh free to download soon as well i did a
local school
um public property you know during the
summer but
uh it's it's a great ability to have
just download play around with it even
if it's not my file but somebody else's
file like just
play around with it if you have a 3d
printer if you have a 3d program just
take things apart stitch things copy
paste have fun with it that's what this
technology is for but that's cool it's
exciting you can tell i'm excited sketch
fab dot com they're awesome so free
resources there it's like a
photogrammetry version of thingiverse in
a way not not even but like
even if you're just into designing 3d
files and you want
to freely distribute or if you want to
sell them your own
there as well unreal um cool but not on
real engine what
um but we keep name dropping yeah i know
right it's hard with technology now
because we have so many different uh
pieces of
[Laughter]
well hey thanks man that is really
really cool thanks for having me comment
below
hey folks what do you think of aerial
photogrammetry
that's a new word for me did i say it
right it's cool yesterday you're
teaching me new words here so
yeah hey here you go comment below
all right thanks henry uh we're gonna
head over to the newsroom becca's
standing by with our news for us this
week
here's what's coming up in the category
5 tv newsroom
a major release of the is on its
way and you can preview it now
work is beginning on what is thought to
be the world's first major plan to store
energy in the form of liquid air
hyperloop has carried its first set of
passengers
microsoft teams users are under active
attack
and tim berners-lee hopes to improve the
privacy of the internet with his new
company
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5 dot tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight
linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
a new development version of the gnu
image manipulation program is available
for testing and get ready
it's a game changer 2.99.2 may be
considered
unstable but it's a huge step towards
the long-anticipated 3.0 release
which promises to be the most
significant release of the free image
editing tool to date
3.0 will be based on the gtk 3 ui
toolkit which will bring many
improvements over the current gtk 2 that
currently uses
3.0 and the 2.99.2 preview for that
matter include multi-layer selection
and support for applying changes to
multiple layers at a time
it also promises to deliver a faster
more responsive user experience
leveraging render caching within the
interface
2.99.2 is an unstable release
that means it's intended for developers
bug hunters and enthusiasts only
and is not recommended for production
use some of the features on the roadmap
are a work in progress so there are
bound to be many bugs throughout
that said you can download 2.99
too now if you'd like to take it for a
spin
windows users can get it on the
developer download page and linux users
can grab it through a flat pack
on flat hub's better channel there's
also a continuous build
app image on the official github
repository
sorry mac users it's not ready for
testing on mac os
just yet there isn't a firm release date
for 3.0 but the devs hope to have
it ready for release sometime in 2021
work is beginning on what is thought to
be the world's first major plant to
store energy in the form of liquid air
it will use surplus electricity from
wind farms at night to compress
air so hard that it becomes a liquid at
-196
celsius then when there is a peak in
demand in a day or a month the liquid
air will be warmed so it expands
the resulting rush of air will drive a
turbine to make electricity
which can be sold back to the grid
the system was devised by peter dearman
a self-taught backyard inventor from
herbertshire
and it has been taken to commercials to
commercial scale
with a 10 million pound grant from the
uk government
dr dearman said his inv or mr dearman
said his
invention was 60 to 70 efficient
depending on how it is used
that is less efficient than batteries
but he said the advantage of liquid air
is the low cost of the storage
tanks so it can be easily scaled up
also unlike batteries liquid air storage
does not create a demand for minerals
which may become increasingly scarce
as the world moves towards power systems
based on variable renewable
electricity batteries are really great
for short-term storage mr dearman said
but they are too expensive to do
long-term energy storage
that's where liquid air comes in mr
dearman had been developing a car run on
similar principles with liquid hydrogen
when he saw the potential for applying
the technology
to electricity storage he is now a
passive shareholder in high view one of
the firms building the 50
megawatt plant the 50 megawatt facility
near manchester will store enough energy
to power around
50 000 homes for up to five hours
that is really amazing just to think
that a few thousand years ago we were
taking buckets of water up a hill to
store them and then use that water as
energy
we were i remember oh yeah i know just
back in the day right it's just getting
like coffees and everything
no but it's it's remarkable in the sense
that we're able to use this natural
thing that we breathe every day
yeah and use that to store energy i
think that's absolutely fantastic
talking about a green energy source
what a clever idea but like how much
pressure
is this thing under more than me
whenever i had work but still oh boy
um no but it's it's a remarkable idea
and
i really like how they really focused on
the idea of green energy because again
unlike batteries where you have to have
all these minerals everything else dug
up
you're able to use this it's just air
it's it's under compression and it's
able to store energy yes and thinking of
batteries not only do you have to
obtain the resources but when those are
depleted
when they're no longer able to hold
exactly the waste everything else
yeah yeah that's exactly right one less
thing to worry about and
it's just amazing these technologies and
i'm curious
to see what they think of next i i love
the idea of
an energy source that is able to kind of
recycle itself
yes and that's kind of what this reminds
me of i've thought about and i know it's
not practical and i know that it's
probably not even possible but
um putting like uh you know you know in
a water source something that can pump
the water because
and and generate electricity at the same
time there's so many neat ideas out
there
this is something that's actually coming
to pass well that this is the number one
thing because
with in respect to green technology the
big the largest thing that's been
lagging behind
is definitely being able to store that
energy because again we do have these
advances in solar power wind power
but the issue is where do you store all
that where do you put it yeah so this
can definitely be one of those solutions
that can help us
help turn our economy our world into a
more greener place
down the road so this this is really
really cool here can't wait to see what
comes of it
yeah or hears of it or smells of it
i'm trying to think of air puns but it's
not working so
we tried
virgin hyperloop has trialled its first
ever journey with passengers in the
desert of nevada
the futuristic transport concept
involves pods inside
vacuum tubes carrying passengers at high
speeds
in the trial two passengers both company
staff traveled the length of a 500 meter
test track
in 15 seconds reaching 172 kilometers an
hour
you may recall from our past coverage as
far as 2018
that the top speed for the hyperloop is
said to be a thousand kilometers an hour
and while this is only a fraction of
that ambition it's a big step toward
hyperloop transportation becoming a
reality
virgin hyperloop is not the only firm
developing the concept
but nobody has carried passengers before
sarah lucian director of customer
experience was one of the two on board
and described the experience as
exhilarating both psychologically and
physically she and chief technology
officer
josh geigel wore normal clothing rather
than flight suits for the event
which took place on sunday afternoon
outside of las vegas
miss lucian said the journey was smooth
and not at all like a roller coaster
although the acceleration was zippier
than it would be with a longer track
neither of them felt sick she added she
said that their speed was hampered by
the length of the track and acceleration
required
the concept which has spent years in
development builds on a proposal by
tesla founder
elon musk some critics have described it
as science fiction
it is based on the world's fastest
magnetic levitation trains then made
faster by placing the train
inside vacuum tubes the world record
speed for a maglev train was set in 2015
when a japanese train
reached 374 miles per hour in a test run
near mount fuji
the hyperloop has already exceeded that
speed but never with passengers
critics have pointed out that hyperloop
travel systems would involve the
considerable undertaking of both getting
planning permission
and then constructing vast networks of
tubes for every travel path
miss lucian acknowledges the potential
difficulties saying of course there's a
lot of infrastructure to be built
but i think we've mitigated a lot of
risk that people didn't think was
possible
in speaking about the infrastructure
challenges she pointed out
that while governments can continue
building up yesterday's transport
systems
people are looking for new solutions the
transportation of the future
microsoft teams users are under active
attack and tim berners-lee
hopes to improve the privacy of the
internet at large with his new company
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert is here with the crypto corner so
don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today we're going to spend some time in
ethereum 2.0 i'm going to explain to you
in a very simple way
what ethereum 2.0 is all about and to
start
we're going to look at the fees so the
fees that you pay
when you do a transaction on the
ethereum blockchain and this year is
2018.
in 2018 the fees were fairly low and
then suddenly a project was started
called
cryptokitties everybody complained about
it because the fees went absolutely
through the roof
now that was 2018 how does that same
picture look today
if i expand this here to today
then here this is the little blip with
cryptokittles the fees
that we had to pay because of d5 not so
long ago
were significantly higher and if you
consider that we are how many people are
we using the ethereum blockchain
let's say 100 000 200 000 it won't be
much more than that so if 200 000 can
already
bring the blockchain uh in regards to
fees to a halt
how would that look like if we have got
certainly 20 million people
using this chain it will not be feasible
any longer and that's why
um including also some other reasons a
long time ago
the idea of ethereum 2.0 was started and
it taking it's it's taking its time and
why
because coding and programming is not
simple yeah if you have got a company
like apple or google where everything is
under one roof
everything is coordinated in a different
way you can have
a different type of transparency and
and also objectives but if you have got
a team of 400 people that are
coordinated
through something like github yeah so
this github is where everything
happens in regards to ethereum then it
looks very
it's very complex and so everything has
to be done very meticulously
because we're talking about money here
in this case
money transfer so big mistakes will cost
a lot of money as we've seen
in d5 and we've got over in the ethereum
current
blockchain we've got over 244
repositories over 500 people
uh programming uh so you can imagine how
complex this whole thing is yeah there
are many hundred thousand lines of code
that need to be coordinated that's why
this thing takes
so long now looking at the roadmap
this is the roadmap of the
of eth 2.0 so this is the current chain
here so this is
1.0 that's the ethereum you and i know
and soon we will have the beacon chain
which is the start of ethereum 2.0
and this here is like the current chain
without proof of work so proof of stake
and you will not have any smart
contracts in this
uh phase zero from there we will start
with the fa with this
smart contracts but we'll have shards
and charts i like
just imagine in a very simple way like
sub
blockchain so you'll have a chain for
let's say
uh d5 you'll have a chain that's that
needs to be secured in a special way
then you've got a new chain for uh
gamers
so when something happens like with
cryptokitties where suddenly
the chain was blocked it will be only
that chain that will be blocked at that
time
and the fees will not go through the
roof so there are
lots of little improvements coming also
along uh
with this er 2.0 and the roadmap in
detail
just the ones that we hear today and we
will start soon
uh phase zero uh phase zero means
um moving away from proof of work to
proof of stake
and that's done by having a deposit
contract because you need to secure the
network not through miners so people
that are mining you need to secure it
through value
and um that for that the deposit
contract was now
created and the time is running now
until
the 7th of december where
then the beacon chain will be started
from there we will then go over to phase
0 and then much later phase two
and phase three and at this stage you
there will be also no more proof of work
so the current
blockchain that you know is point zero
will be more or less switched off
that's not possible i know but it it
will not continue everything will happen
in the new uh ethereum 2.0
and um for the transition from the
current stages to ethernet
phase zero they created a very good
website launchpad.ethereum.org
where when you want to become a
validator you can get started here and
they'll run you through
some questions and so on and they
explain to you what that really means
um you will get some money so for
everything that you
stake so in other words you put up with
security
you'll get some money as a reward at the
beginning it will be of course higher
because we're starting
but and over the time it will go down
and
here this is the status of how far
people have committed already to this
new chain where at 10
i guess that around the first of
december this thing
should be filled more or less because
all the big whales will be coming
in um into uh staking because they get
the rewards are not bad at the beginning
so
this is um ethereum 1.0
explained uh 2.0 sorry played in a very
simple
way and i hope you liked it and i hope
you enjoyed it
and i thank you very much for watching
and i'm looking forward to see you next
week again so thank you very much
bye bye thank you robert just a reminder
that we're not providing financial
advice but only sharing
what's happening in the cryptocurrency
market always remember that the
cryptocurrency market is always changing
and always volatile so only invest what
you can afford to lose
and now here's becca thank you robbie
microsoft teams users are under active
attack
in a fake updates malware campaign
attackers are using ads for fake
microsoft teams updates to deploy
backdoors
which use cobalt strike to infect
companies networks with malware
microsoft is warning the customers about
the so-called fake updates campaigns in
a non-public security advisory revealed
by bleeping computer
the campaign is targeting various types
of companies with recent targets in the
k-12 education sector
where organizations are currently
dependent on using apps like teams
for video conferencing due to covet 19
restrictions
cobalt strike is a commodity attack
simulation tool that's used by attackers
to spread malware
particularly ransomware recently threat
actors were seen using cobalt strike in
attacks exploiting zero logon
a privileged elevation flaw that allows
attackers to access a domain controller
and completely compromise all active
directory identitive
identity services in the advisory
microsoft said it's seen attackers in
the latest fake updates
campaign using search engine ads to push
top results for team software to a
domain controlled by the attackers and
used for nefarious activity
if victims click on the link it
downloads a payload that executes a
power shell script
which loads malicious content cobalt
strike beacons are among the payloads
also being distributed by the campaign
which give threat actors the capability
to move laterally across a network
beyond the initial system of infection
the link also installs a valid copy of
microsoft teams on the system
to appear legitimate and avoid alerting
victims to this
to the attack malware being distributed
by the campaign
include predator the thief infostealer
which pilfers sensitive data such as
credentials
browser and payment data microsoft also
has seen a backdoor and zed loader
stealer being distributed by the latest
campaigns
microsoft is recommending that people
use web browsers that can filter and
block malicious websites
and ensure that local admin passwords
are strong and can't easily be guessed
admin privileges also should be limited
to essential users
and avoid domain wine service
domain-wide service accounts
that have the same permissions as an
administrator
according to the report they advise
organizations to limit their attack
surface to keep attackers at bay
by blocking executable files that do not
meet specific criteria
or blocking javascript and vbscript code
from downloading
executable content well microsoft teams
it takes a team to be hacked
yeah it's uh you can get independently
hacked very easily yeah well no it's
it's a scary thing really because
without
being seen so much not just
organizations but if you're an educator
if you're a teacher student etc um and
it isn't
well you're talking about teachers and
stuff i'm thinking about how
these folks have been thrown into having
to use microsoft teams with no
experience
this is something totally new and then
all of a sudden you get a little
little window that says hey you need to
update it's okay
right and you think well this this is
what i'm using for my classroom so i
better get that update
oh no it's like children make sure you
install this update
well like we're just talking before the
show it really is a form of social
engineering
absolutely because it's it's so easy to
fall into the trap this is where
phishing scams
have like we think oh well i would never
fall for a phishing scam because you
know i don't use that service or this
service or whatever but
it's a it's a like a if i
throw enough phishing scams out there
that pretend to be the royal bank of
canada
yeah i will inevitably land in the inbox
of some people who bank at the royal
bank of canada so
if i buy ads that are pretending to be
updates for
microsoft teams even though i personally
robbie ferguson don't use teams
somebody out there you might yeah
somebody else might and and social
engineering they
they trick those folks into installing
this malware and we're talking
ransomware
so ransomware is the one that encrypts
your
files and goes out on the network that
you're connected to
and encrypts all the files that it can
gain access to and as we know
from zero logon that is every
file on the entire network if you're
like like a school network you think oh
well we're locked down
it's safe no zero login
zero logon allows them to have
administrator credentials
just like just like your it admin so
like these are serious exploits
and social engineering they're using
that to get into these systems that
could be a back door into the network
well exactly i'm also scared for small
businesses right
yeah so again everyone's working from
home now so again if you have
employees who aren't aztec literate or
but henry
who would target me i'm just uh i'm just
a work from home
you know person who no nobody would
always target me see
yeah false insecure security right yeah
we've become
complacent absolutely the fact is is
that these are
non-targeted attacks these tools
are built to find susceptible systems
yeah and attack them yeah just a wide
net that's all it takes
like you said one email spam it out yeah
so
maybe a pie hole which is an ad blocking
dns
server suddenly becomes not just
something to block your advertising but
also something to
like your ad blocker becomes something
that's going to prevent
malware yeah they bought ads on google
i mean like come on i've seen it happen
on facebook i've been on facebook yeah
and
a java i think it was a flash virus at
the time tried to install through an ad
well they have like a hundred dollar
free like ad credit thing if you sign up
for google ads now so
they got a real good deal i'm not just
kidding that's not sponsored so be
really careful when you click on folks
be very very careful and
almost to the point of skeptical all
right
it really does show how the world is
developing away from ads though like i
know this is going to be kind of a
little bit off topic now but it just
add ads being so intrusive hence why you
have other platforms like patreon and
stuff that you can support
sure yes and things like that right
because whenever i'm on youtube i'm like
yeah i have an ad locker
i i rely on ad revenue in order to
survive as a
as a broadcaster on youtube exactly but
it's just like it's a balance now right
because it's like
is this ad gonna try to sell me or try
to affect me try to trick you into
getting an infection of ransomware yeah
so just like i want to support
small businesses and channels and stuff
but how do i balance that with safety
now
it's it's such a hard thing to talk
about it's a very good question i don't
know that there's an
answer immediately sitting there ready
to be given
so it's really just down to be very
cautious be
skeptical when you're clicking on stuff
online and know that even in
somewhere like google maybe the ads
contain malware so watch out
and be careful inventor of the world
wide web tim berners-lee is having
another crack at fixing the internet's
biggest problems
with the launch of a new enterprise
server
the inrupt enterprise solid server is
the first product from a company the
inventor started two years ago
in response to the problem of personal
data online
where tech giants like facebook and
google build vast databases on users
profiles
and sell them to advertisers to make
massive profits
inrupt has worked on a series of new
standards that allow individuals to
store their personal information in pods
whose access they control the
decentralized approach allows for the
free and fast sharing of data
but with control in the hands of its
owners the project is called solid
and after two years of work at mit the
team behind it has released an
enterprise service
the goal being to move the whole idea
from concept to reality
the enterprise server will allow
organizations to build applications
using others data pods
that can do useful things like draw
comparisons across users
or build greater context around user
data while keeping the user in control
of their data for many businesses it
will be a chicken and a conundrum where
it won't be worth investing
in the solid system until there is
sufficient data and users of the system
and users won't bother providing their
data until there are sufficient
companies and applications with new
regulations like gdpr and california's
privacy law
a system like solid would make it
significantly easier
easier for companies to gather and use
data without having the weight of
administering it at
all and being responsible for constantly
updated permissions
in a blog post monday berners-lee
announced the numbers of big name
partners that will run pilots
including the bbc nat west bank the
national health service
and flanders government the pilots are
small and the intent is to spark greater
awareness of the technology
and grow adoption big thanks to roy w
nash and our community of viewers for
submitting stories to us
this week thanks for watching the
category 5 dot tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category 5. from the category 5 tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
all right welcome back from our
commercial break and today was an
excellent show thank you so much robbie
thank you so much
everyone for having me back henry it was
great having like that feature
it was so cool to see you in the field
like these days we can't
send a roaming reporter out to do stuff
and yeah it's it's great to see an
actual person again thank you for seeing
me
even if we're socially distanced it's
great to be out of the basement but no
it was really fun hopefully some of you
out there can play around with those
models and
play around with the programs that we've
used tonight yeah for sure
but no thanks for having me back yeah
thanks for being here man i've been
having a lot of fun with a 3d printer
and that was a great opportunity
for me to do something fun uh don't
forget our series at cat five dot tv
slash 3d printing
so your video will be there and uh all
the videos of anything that we do
on the 3d printer are going to be there
as well there's going to be
it's going to become a really great
repository of information
just just a knowledge base of just
everything
i admit that i'm a new 3d printer like
i'm new to this you know what we all
need to do hobby
during uh these days you know so why not
get into it now so let's learn together
let's enjoy the process
and uh and follow along and i'll i'll be
taking you along for the ride
i want to say thank you so much to our
patreon supporters you can follow us and
become part of our fleet
at patreon.comcategory5
we greatly appreciate your support it's
how we're able to do
the show that we do and we couldn't do
it without you
and thank you everybody for subscribing
on youtube and for being a part of our
community
we've got our discord server where you
can chat with other people in the
community we've got a ton of ways
to interact and make sure you go over to
our website
and you'll be able to follow along
figure out uh all the different ways to
interact with us at category 5
dot tv oh and i should mention there's
years worth of video what i can binge
watch all 14 years now you probably
could
enjoy that especially season one it was
dreadful
uh hey you take care have a wonderful
week henry you guys great seeing you man
high five
[Music]
[Applause]
you