welcome to the community coffee break
everybody it's nice to see you it's the
6th i believe of september
2020 the 6th of september
already yeah yes wow i mean
for such a weird year it's really flying
by fast isn't it
you guys feeling that as well oh yes oh
yeah i mean
i know i i'm super busy with everything
that's been going on here but
it's like it just seems like it's just
go go go go go and now the kids are
going to be you know going back to
school in just a little bit
whatever that means crazy
that is crazy now i can't see
who has been able to join us today so
bp9 can i leave it to you to
give shout out absolutely let me let me
do that as soon as
oh there's a couple of others good okay
all right let me uh
let me do that so that is um
uh give us a wave robbie that's robbie
over there
and give us a wave that's robbie over
there he's he's running
he's running this whole party and then
we've got sobu here in
my bottom left-hand corner but of course
that doesn't mean anything to you
there's peter with mary's name on it he
must be using
thank you peter he must be using mary's
computer
then you've got reed hello reed
doug we haven't seen we haven't seen
doug in ages hello doug oh yes
working on sundays hey doug all right
and we're we're missing your kitty cats
i don't see any kitty cats over there
doug
but uh i tried to join last week and
nobody was here
that's right really yeah
there was nobody oh and you probably
tried to watch the show on wednesday and
nobody was there too
there were nobody really either
what happened sorry what's that
what happened last sunday robbie so last
sunday okay
so i mean it is what it is um
i have to be available in order to do
the
uh the the coffee break
because i i have to start the feed and
everything but
um so anyways long story short family
stuff came up uh
visiting family we haven't had much
opportunity to do so throughout the
pandemic
um opportunity came up to be able to uh
to visit my in-laws and uh as
terrible as that sounds it was really
really nice
um because the weather forecast align
do the church service from the studio on
a sunday morning but
um the pastor was not back from vacation
in time so
they were going to upload a pre-recorded
sermon instead so
so it just freed up and so i i said to
becca because becca was like oh i wish
we could go and see my parents
absolutely
and so i said oh well my community will
understand it's it's important that we
get some family time in there too sure
sure so so that's all it was so i saw
some people saying oh i hope
everything's okay and i was like really
quick to get into the chat and be like
no everything's great yeah just visiting
with family so
but it was nice to get an opportunity to
do so i was i
asked the whole internet thing had uh
reared its ugly head on you again
no that was the previous week oh my god
no two weeks prior uh
that was brutal and we're still dealing
with that bp9 i mean like
like to the point where like they they
screwed up so badly that they're
like refunding us for a full month worth
of service oh wow
okay but then in doing so they also
billed my credit card twice
oh no the the screw-ups just kept
compounding
and so then they so then they said they
were gonna reverse the
secondary payment so they charged me
twice for the payment
um and then i so five days later i
messaged them and i said i still haven't
gotten that reversal i'm looking at my
visa statement they said oh we sent you
a check
snail mail snail mail it's like what
who does that normally let alone like
wow
when you screwed up and double charged
me when you were supposed to be
reversing the charge
wow yeah still still waiting for that
check to arrive
as you can see so and then wednesday
came this week so wednesday came this
week
and um the studio was completely torn
apart um
so you can see how things are looking
right now
and i know um you haven't yet so those
who
support us um haven't yet seen a vlog
and that's because it's like a multi-day
process to get everything up and running
so i
lost you robbie i can't hear you we lost
your audio robbie
you can see you see you just found your
head is moving and then
but there's no sound yeah we lost your
audio
hear me now
[Music]
where'd you lose me so i said uh i've
been recording video for the vlog yes
for kickstarter and for patreon it's a
multi-day program such a multi-day
process
yeah so the status on wednesday when i
was meant to do the show
uh well actually backing up a little bit
it takes about six days to produce one
episode of category five tv
so the problem with that is come
so six days the sixth day would be
tuesday right
right so um but by tuesday i should have
already spent two days preparing for
the following show which airs on
wednesday i need to start
i need to write the news on monday so
this
so a couple weeks ago i did the show
with jeff and
come tuesday i still had not finished
um that episode so so i was two days
behind already on the following week's
episode so then wednesday came
we still didn't have news we still
didn't have our feature recorded we
still didn't have
anything aligned for and and the studio
was completely torn apart
handy dandy lte backup that
um that you that you also
have when you when your internet goes
down
i i i still have it
um and we thought about maybe setting
that up but
remember at studio d we could run it we
could run a cable into the foyer
and there was a tower right across the
uh right across the road
so that was easy breezy here i'm in the
middle of a concrete
room basically so whoops you saying your
ultimate doesn't
you saying your lte doesn't work then i
haven't tried it
i don't imagine it would be very good i
don't imagine it would be very solid
that was one of the selling points for
your internet connection
oh yeah the backup yeah that was a fail
yeah they gave me the lte backup i don't
know it it didn't work
um okay just ask you like i mean
no no by the way it got me on a deal it
got me on a deal to sign up for it so
so i'm paying less um so that said
this problem that resulted in the
internet being down and everything that
was not that the internet was down on
the wednesday we could have broadcasted
had we been able to but because i had
lost an entire
week there was no prep like again i i
can't i can only do so much right
yeah of course yeah do we want to just
turn on the camera and say okay we've
got internet now let's sit here and
you know just know like there's a lot of
work that goes into a single broadcast
so you had no show set up creation yeah
like there's there's two days worth of
writing and plus
usually i shoot some like overhead
camera
stuff or stuff like if we're going to do
a setup or something we pre-record that
so that i can
accelerate the boring stuff you've seen
me do that
so i'll play music and make it so that
it's speed or something
like that so all those things have to
happen before but when
when the week comes and goes so i hope
i'm on the air on wednesday
this week you need another person who
can
either do their prepping for
each week or two or who can do the
editing afterwards
yeah all these things would be very very
clever maybe that's something sasha can
do remotely who knows
yeah with her dreadful internet connect
connections can you imagine trying to do
4k videos
oh wow over google drive yeah i'm
impressed
i'm impressed actually that she when she
joins the zoom it's reasonable
zoom does a pretty good job of
downscaling the video so
but uh yeah that is what it is have you
have you seen her
on zoom since she moved oh yeah
yes yes she's going on a couple coffee
breaks she took us for a tour
of her house uh okay when it was under
construction
so go back and look at the coffee breaks
and see
usually there's a thumbnail that shows
the picture of everybody who was
involved in that coffee break yeah
look for one uh anywhere there's there's
a female
it could be sasha yeah i know thumbnail
yeah uh so
so i've just gotta get you know we've
gotta get through this time and and you
know what i've been
trying to i've just been trying to be
cool with it you know like yeah
because anyone in my situation where i'm
so busy trying to delegate things
for the construct like the the base it's
very basic construction but it still
takes time and it's got it takes setting
things up we're getting led lighting
um retrofits for all the horrible 3500k
lighting that that is in here so i have
to coordinate getting them in and
everything too
um so all this stuff while trying to do
a show and prep for a show and then edit
a show and publish a show
is very very difficult so so i'm just
trying to be cool because i could be
really really stressed out right now
it's not worth your health robbie it's
not worth your health
and i think and i think when it comes
down to it
being able to kick off season 14
stronger
than we would if i was stressing myself
out is going to be better
because well i will i can take a
wednesday off
on occasion as needed as i did this week
and what did i do
i was here putting up the sound sound
isolation
tiles i was here putting up i put leds
behind the tv
and i got these lights up on the ceiling
now as well so the lighting in here is
so much better
if i can interject something here yeah i
would say
you've done an awesome job through
everything that's been going on with
covid and all this other stuff um
you've kept up as much as you could and
i think you've just done
wonderful thank you so much yes sir
absolutely wonderful
yep thank you so my goal is to
hopefully have things
established well enough that we can have
a good video production routine going by
the start of season 14.
season 13. season 13 has just been
like what 2020 has been for everybody
right so
um so i i should say too that i i
greatly appreciate
you guys and the community at large
um how you've allowed me to not be
stressed out over it
because i could be i could be really
stressed out but
you know where we we know here and we
kind of joke about you know we're going
to be shocking jeff with the
the labor pains and everything like
these things are going to happen
shooting jeff with the paintball gun
it's going to happen but it's like
who saw a pandemic coming so just
knowing
knowing that you guys um
understand is so oh
it's such a relief for us because
especially for me we're all in
tech robbie and we all we all get you
know
what what you what you get what you're
dealing with yeah yeah
and so that is yeah there's lots of
lots of things that you could say here
about the situation that a lot that a
lot of folks are in with this covid
and i'm just super thankful that that
that i'm in a position where
you know i my job doesn't change
matt where my job changes right i can
still dial into work i can still vpn in
and carry on do a full day's work just
like
the video of course you were
i think i lost you there you know what
is painful when i lose you guys
is that the recording doesn't get you so
if you carry on
if you carry on the conversation it's
like it it just jumps to the next
segment it's all right robbie for a
video why are you surprised right
i'm a member of uh an organization
called
a norwegian unix user group and they
have a monthly member meeting
which is uh videotaped and streamed live
and in
[Applause]
march of uh 2012 and we had a video of
uh what is uh now called a debian
edu it's a linux installation um
primarily meant for schools
um and he had a
question on announcement session
afterwards where
someone was asking if he could comment
or expound upon a
blog post that he had about a problem
they had uh
uh releasing a new version um
and at that time he was debugging
the debian installer it is the current
installer that
ubuntu also uses uh which doesn't ask
200 questions um
and then they have the authentication
scheme they have
users care bearers
i don't know how i don't know how you uh
say it um
but that's a package when it's installed
it is not satisfied with pseudorandom
numbering it has it needs a true true
truly
random so it's um it needs uh something
to happen
either you have to type on the keyboard
or there's some that this has to
do something or uh in some cases
network traffic um but he but he didn't
know that so
it would he started the installation and
it will do
and if you just hang for
or something so he started um
going to a tt shell that you can do
during installation and then he started
debugging and then he uh
thought if he found the problem it
started working so he implemented the
solution and he
installed once again and it would still
hang
and then he was uh i mentioned and then
he thought that maybe something is
waiting for some input and it's not
displaying on the screen and he
tried for several hours no nothing is
waiting for anything when
when pgp when you used to generate a key
with pgp it was the same thing you had
to type on the keyboard or you had to
run the mouse or whatever yeah but they
would put up a message on the console to
say
give us some random data by typing the
keyboard or running the mouse around
yeah but
then you you had a console open that
would
tell you these things you can't generate
a pgp key otherwise
yeah but um in the most uh the gui
applications
yeah if there is our console message it
would not show up in there if you just
show yourself
yeah you just throw a pop-up on the
screen i mean that works too right yeah
if
you if it is important enough and they
have accounted for
this particular pop message
to show so i would think hanging i would
think making the process hang
is important enough to put a message up
to say give us some random data
yeah but um interesting yeah but this
was the problem he was debugging and he
found out that there was not enough and
the colonel had uh
run out of uh entropy
and so he was working to figure to
thinking about what would generate
entropy and that is
either typing on the keyboard uh or in
the disk
right or read or in some selected cases
and
network traffic but in this stage of the
installation there is no more network
traffic
it has already downloaded all everything
it needs to know so yeah
and what's the purpose in it what's the
purpose in the installer being so
secure that it needs that much entropy
it's not the installer it is it is a
package
who needs a truly random number in order
to generate a key
for kerberos yeah
um which is like ssh it's like
generating keys like ssh does yeah or
pgp
yeah okay
and then he and um and and then nothing
is
generic in in uh reading or earning
to the disc because everything is
waiting for something yeah
was the last step and he figured out uh
eventually he figured out that all he
had to do was to change the tte
a few times that was enough because you
were tapping on the keyboard in order to
do that
so the solution that he came up with
which is i think that they are still
having in the uh debian installer and in
the ubuntu installer and all the
derivatives there is a process running
that is checking for um
a certain um proxies uh something um
wherever the available entropy is listed
and if it's below us a certain number
um he have uh here um
a command is flushing the disk
and it starts uh a fine command on the
slash root
yeah that'll do it that'll do it
whatever he did in order to debug it
worked it was subversive yeah
so yeah encryption keys are they can be
pretty long
that's crazy i just think like for a
password or something i'll just take the
micro time
and shot 256 it and cut it off at 32
characters or something
yeah like it's random enough
so pretty unlikely for you to replicate
it
or i could add a salt or something throw
salt on there
and then what are the chances of
replicating that right
wow well i think i've mentioned that the
uh
that the pine phone is um looking a lot
better now after its latest update
now it um properly um
keeps track of the time which is just
fantastic
finally keeping track of the time next
time you can they can take calls on your
phone
yes i can i can do it and the voice goes
through it's not a problem
although at the moment again i don't
know if you can tell but both the
um both the indicators for the network
show
that it's not that it's not getting a
signal oh there it is the phone just
came up
the phone icon just came up so that's
good
did you program any of that the only
thing i had to program
program was the credentials for the uh
for the hotspot for the wi-fi router oh
um and it it will correctly connect into
that although the icon right now doesn't
say
doesn't say it is uh putting a new
putting a sim in there i put a
pay-as-you-go sim in there
based on one of our networks here and it
just came right up
i didn't have to do anything and it just
literally came right up
and i started getting text messages
right away to say your new phone number
is and
uh battery life is still is still
a bit iffy it won't last more than more
than
maybe eight nine hours something like
that so
um that's still that's still working the
camera works now
i can um the camera wasn't even working
previously
but um if i turn the camera on then it
will actually
uh it will actually at least show an
image i haven't tried taking photos or
any of that but
it was it was just a huge leap just to
make it
see images to make the camera let's see
how much stuff do you have running
not much uh i can't make it i'm still
trying to make it connect to a
uh card dab server doesn't i can't see
any way to make it do that
i still can't make it connect to a
caldav server
so i i don't have any way to keep to
manage contacts and i don't have any way
to manage the calendar
which is what i would like for this
phone to do how about bluetooth
wi-fi all that stuff
wi-fi no problem um and i don't expect
any problem with bluetooth although i
have not tried it yet i don't generally
use bluetooth so
i haven't really been um too worried
about that but
i'll certainly try that for sure and i
will let you know when i
get further um there's this really i'd
really like to see
caldav and carddav work and i spoke with
or at least i messaged
bo from ameridroid and he kindly
responded
i wanted to know how to ssh into it
without
using the wi-fi or um or any other
part of the um i wanted to use a wired
method
to um to connect in he said well you
just get a usb
which is what a usbc which is how you
charge it
usbc to ethernet done
and then really bring up a it just come
up on your on your network
once you once you plug it in yep so it
has that's my next
that's going to be my next purchase otg
very cool otg what do you mean by that
isn't that the technology that lets you
do ethernet or something
oh no i'm thinking video i don't know
what otg means
i don't know what otg means but i can't
remember this is just a usbc
yeah this is just cool never thought to
plug a
ethernet cable into a phone but that's
really cool well i do not want to be
um sshing into the phone
with yeah over wifi yeah or over the
telephone connection i can secure it i
can lock it down pretty tight
yeah sober you and i have talked about
that use public private key
all that stuff and i'll definitely do
that uh i would very much rather do it
wired
than than over then because i don't want
drive-by opportunities right and i want
somebody to think oh
there's an open ssh connection let's see
if i can see if i can get into that
i do not could you do that within your
own vpn
[Music]
could you tunnel in through your own vpn
well
uh well i'd have to establish a vpn on
this phone
and then sucked is
pretty darn good but not as powerful as
a regular laptop
i can't run code for vss code on it for
instance
but i can i can develop with vi and c
scope and c tags and all that
that all works no problem just don't try
to run a
ui like you know an ide like um uh
eclipse or or or uh i idea intelligent
intellij idea or any of that just use vi
uh don't try to run vss code it's just
too slow
and i don't expect it
you can use nano if you want yeah but
the key point though
the key point though is that you use
make
you build a make file and just use make
to build the whole project
and uh uh peter you'll be happy about
this
i had reason to install lazarus and free
pascal
on my linux box because i was building a
um
an application that was that was written
in pascal
it had a make file so i was able to type
make in it and it didn't make but what
it does
is it calls the lazarus ide and then
caught and makes the ide do the build
instead of doing all the build in the in
the make file like it should do
so if you don't have lazarus the
makefile won't work
wow makers make loaves a lot easier
yes they do they give you the tools they
use
[Music]
should not should not be calling an ide
to perform the the build process
it should be yeah calling the compiler
right we just imagine it's just
compiling in the command line yeah
there's a lot of um
but the makefile just calls lazarus and
says hey lazarus go build this project
so you know if you don't have pretty
much
yes
i was using it to i was using it to
build a project that i pulled off github
i'm not planning to make any changes on
it but
the version of that project that was in
the
in the linux repo was too old it didn't
have all the functionality i was looking
for
so i had to build it from source so
that's why i had to um
that's why i had to to to uh
grab the latest source off of github and
then just build it that way
so well dan it is wonderful do what
you're gonna do we're gonna have to wrap
up for the week
and uh everybody else had it
nobody else had a chance to talk we
needed like a
like a four-hour coffee break just to
make up for all the time
okay let's do that you guys and uh i do
hope to see you wednesday
i've got some really exciting and fun
things that i want to show you yeah
uh we'll see how everything goes so wish
me wish me luck
you'll be fine have a great week
everybody you'll be fine good to see you
guys again
i'm sorry i'm sorry you guys didn't get
the chance to talk
who did mary did yeah is she okay
not really well and broke up on
[Music]
and they don't um
uh peter let let mary know we're
thinking of her and i
wish her a speedy recovery
very cool yeah this is a part for your
drill press or something
yeah yeah you see i'll put a piece of
glue up on the thing
i put a like a uh metal uh
square underneath there to strengthen it
upside so
when i wouldn't bring this guy don't
break it
when that's right well i'm glad you
figured out a solution for that because
it's like i can't 3d print anything for
you although it's neat to see that you
can order 3d prints online but
it's good that you got a solution there
nobody does anything and they never
heard us reading printed out where
they're in the
the dark ages
i mean i mean cows that girls are
potatoes that's badly available
i mean you understand uh uh
but i want tall rude because uh you know
there's a go on here but i could say a
few things they wouldn't like
uh uh you know you understand what i'm
saying
no i i very difficult and um
well we're thinking about moving as well
but
that that that might be in the bottom or
maybe not we don't know yet
he's staying at home with you now or is
he still in the hospital
um at the moment
anniversary as well wow congratulations
yeah but uh we both had something
organized and
we're gonna marry at an accident
just just like sigh relief and just be
like okay
forget 2020 yeah yeah 2021 we're going
to celebrate
just making it through this crazy year
and
and it's going to be the best
anniversary party that you've ever had
absolutely i think it's everybody yeah
you know just got to do our best to stay
positive you know but i do hope that she
gets well
very quickly peter it's great to see you
guys i do have to run
um wish you all the best all of you and
uh look forward to seeing you again soon
guys
take care
sorry you guys didn't get to talk
reading doug
sorry that was fine okay