next in our microtic series is how to
assign a static ip address
to a device in your dhcp in your dhcp
pool so i'm going to just sign into
web fig here on my laptop
and i want to show you how easy this is
to do so
click on ip and click on dhcp
server and click on leases
this is an important thing to do because
you're you're going to need to have
static ip
addressing on your network for things
like servers
in my case we're also looking at pi hole
for example
so my pi hole server is in fact set as
10.0.0.2
that is a static reservation in my dhcp
pool
for on my microtech so any of these
devices so these ones are
dynamic see these dynamic
d the ones that are that have a d
button that button will actually convert
it to dynamic but they are currently
static
so let's look at i've got a
let's grab my phone there's my pocophone
so i'm just going to click on that
and it's currently assigned to
10.0.0.107
so i'm just simply going to press make
static
and now it has been assigned to
10.0.0.107
static but if i close that
now you'll see 107 has that d next to it
and no longer is it dynamic
so now if i open it by single clicking
on it i get all these new options
and now i can assign it its own ip
address something that
is not currently in use on my pool so i
can assign that 2.88
and hit ok and now my pocophone
is 10.0.0.88
there it is see how easy it is to
configure a static reservation on your
dhcp pool on a microtech device
is fantastic quick follow-up question in
our discord from the foo
who's asking shouldn't reserved ips be
outside of the dhcp pool's dynamic range
and while technically true in
an in a different type of scenario where
you're not using dhcp
that's not the case here i'm going to
explain why so
traditionally us sysadmins are
basically it's it's ingrained in our
minds to always assign the dhc
uh the static address outside of the
pool the reason for that is
if you let's say you install a new
printer on a network
and you go to that printer and you type
in
the ip address and you put it within the
pool
now your dhcp server doesn't even know
that it exists
because it did not assign the ip address
so what we're doing here is completely
different what we're doing is we're
setting the reservation
in the dhcp server so that printer is
still
just getting the ip address from the
dhcp server
so does it have to be outside of the
pool now no
the reason it would have to be if i was
typing it in manually onto the printer
is because
when the dhcp server then assigns that
ip
address to another device on your
network it's going to cause an ip
collision conflict so you're going to
have two devices
sharing the same ip address and you're
going to get all kinds of like arp
attacks warning
arp attack warnings things like that
because you've got these collisions
occurring within your network things are
going to go slow all of a sudden
that's a problem because i am assigning
my ip address from the dhcp server to my
device
or to my printer i can set it to
anything that is not already assigned
and it will dish it out through the dhcp
and it doesn't matter whether it's
within the pool or not
you