hello welcome to
category five coffee break i'm bp nine
hello
and uh if my view is correct then above
me is soul boo give us a wave sober
thank you very much thank you sir and
then to the right
is uh to his right is doug give us a
wave doug
and then uh next to me uh oh i got it
wrong again there it is
and there's brian hello brian hi guys
sir good to see you all right not much
going on for me
i'm um i having a hard time getting
motivated this week so
um um you know little things that i can
show you
uh that i did get the uh the pogo pins
for the um for the time for the pine
time
and what that means is that now i can
program it much much easier because what
happens is let's see if
see if it'll focus on it doesn't look
like it will but those pins are fine
enough that they fit
exactly on the they fit exactly on the
um on the pine time pins and so you
literally just
stick them down on the pins and then
program them on this side
so i've i got it there's the adapter
cable but i haven't actually
done anything with it so i need to
i need to program the um the prime time
and get it
get it running it's been sitting there
it's been bricked because i
i unlocked it so that i could program it
but then i didn't do anything with it
so because i wasn't able to hold the
pins
you know i had four pins that i was
trying to you know man handle
manually and i couldn't do it it just
wouldn't those pins wouldn't stay there
long enough for me to
successfully program it so uh so yeah
that's what i've been up to not much
else going on here just just
lots of stuff at work and and that
doesn't matter here but um
just yep just fun and games so uh solibu
you want to go first
yeah i've been uh mostly at home uh i
don't remember
actually doing anything um i do remember
i um
i had a story to tell but um now that
the day has come
it's completely gone from my brain
you should have written it down solely
or told me the story at least
yeah if i could remind you
i did manage to i did make some
progress with mail server with postfix
and dovecot
but i started swearing at it
and the moment i start swearing at it i
know it's time to go away
it's time to just go away from the
keyboard walk away
and and worry about it some other time
um
i'm following your advice sobu and that
in that i'm putting the mail
into um male files either mbox or male
der
i prefer male der
it doesn't have to look through a huge
big
file in order to find those certain
methods
yup yup yup um so i prefer
i prefer milder for that direct for that
reason
but my problem is that the um
is that dovecot and
postfix disagree on where
where they should put mail and where
they should find mail
not sure why don't know what's going on
with that so i may have to do a bit of a
work around around that but
um yeah the thing is that the postfix is
putting the mail in a certain place and
then you need to
tell postage to look in that same place
you mean dovecot yeah yes
right i understand i understand that um
and it's it's just i'm just having
trouble getting them to agree where they
where they should
put mail in and retrieve mail from so
i'm i'm pretty sure i'm close so
as i said i just started getting
frustrated with it and i walked away
and i felt like that was the best thing
to do is just walk away so
you should do what uh sheldon does when
something that doesn't go his way he
works as strongly as
a strong liberated letter so maybe you
should write a strongly worded
mail to your mail server
the spam filter will probably catch it
for uh for
uh excessive swear words
yeah speaking of email and uh
my old man i was at my parents for
dinner
yesterday um he has um
yeah we talked about his things
around uh because he has stopped and he
is uh retired but
at the old job they are still paying him
to help them maintain their systems
it's almost like it's an all
he is maybe the only one left to know
how to handle this and they
still need that that is scary when
you're the only one left
that is very sad yeah and then he but
he has um yeah kept
he never delete any email
yeah and so he but yeah he deletes spam
i think and i think that's the only
thing uh that he actually deletes um
i've even got to be careful about spam
because you can even get useful emails
in your spam folder you better
um he doesn't yeah there is no automatic
filtering he manually deletes any spam
that comes in
yeah okay this means and he has had
emails since
about 1990 when he started at the
campaign oh yeah he has
he has 31 years of email
and he has everything yeah i'm not
surprised
i'm not surprised nice
does he use inbox mailbox format or
inbox format
i think he uses outlook well
oh so does he use pop to retrieve them
all back to his machine
yeah okay so outlook probably uses a
database or something i don't know what
it uses
whenever you need to start using a new
type of email client
that usually has been due to the company
changed
it takes his time to import all his old
emails
and he does not check email on the new
um system
until he has made sure that
everything is reported
he'd have to be very confident that he's
got everything imported correctly then
i don't know how he does that wow
nice nice yeah
i uh at work we use outlook as well but
uh all our
all our mail is on their server and our
folders just sync to their server much
like i
uh imac i'm not sure it might even be
using imap under the covers i'm not sure
so um but yeah i
i have no expectation of privacy on a
work lap on a work issued laptop
so so i have no problem with that so
it's all good
mr doug what sort of trouble are you
getting into sir
well your new raspberry pi is working
well it isn't i gave up on the raspberry
pi i'm waiting for the x4u to arrive
and it should be here the eighth of this
week uh i'm sorry april 8th which i
believe is
wednesday right okay wednesday or
thursday
yep okay so we'll uh we'll see about
that probably next saturday i'll
see what i can do with it very nice
very nice i won't ask you if you got it
from ameritrade
yes i did
i didn't i didn't want to put you on the
spot there dog so
so what do you think you're going to uh
how what are your plans then in terms of
operating system and applications on the
x4
i'm going to go with ubuntu
at least i bought an emmc that has
ubuntu already on it
oh nice i also bought it
emmc burner so i can change it if i want
to
oh that's a good idea where'd you get
that from amazon
no that all came from old droid amir
droid sorry
droid oh i may have to hit him up for a
um for an emmc burner
and or reader i think that'll come in
very handy
because i put my mc in my main machine
but um the one that was intended for the
laptop
that i returned to dell and they did
give me my money back which
i'm pleased about um the
uh the laptop uh ended up not
it wouldn't even power on um after a
while and i just i just
have once again started getting really
frustrated at it
sure the the initial problem of course
was that it would not recognize the sata
drive no matter what i did
um and i refused to send it back to dell
for them to pay them
to estimate what it would cost to fix it
it's a brand new machine and they
wouldn't budge off that position
so i said fine take it back i'll have my
money back thank you very much
and yeah they did so i am not paying
them for
for them to estimate a brand new machine
to figure out how to fix it
yeah repairing machine still under
warranty yeah yeah exactly
so i put the emmc that was destined for
that machine
into my main machine
however linux doesn't see it and the
reason linux doesn't see it after i
uh search the internet for a while the
reason linux doesn't see it is because
um it's that the bios
have the hard drive set up as raid not
um
ahci or whatever the ychi or whatever
the
alternative um setup is so i need to
configure the bios to be ahci i forget
which way
those letters work but once i've done
that
then i should be able to boot off
windows
of the existing hard drive i think i
have to do this a very special way
because the windows drivers
that are on the hard drive now are
right now on a configured for raid
so they won't see any of the drive if if
i switch to bios without
doing these special steps in windows
first then
windows won't even see the the main
drive or the emmc
and and and i'll brick the machine so i
don't want to do that
so and there is also i have the same uh
issue with the my uh
rack mounted server that i bought a year
ago
um i had a new drive that i wanted an
additional drive that i wanted to put
into it and it didn't see it
and it turned out it's um hardware
already
configured um yeah and someone told me
uh not too long ago that um
he had the same machine and he had to
turn off uh
uh hard and uh red and he had to turn it
off
somehow in the uh in the in the bios
configuration
but he also said that uh any drive
that was already formatted by that same
system
um you would not see anything again on
the drive unless
unless you turn the hardware in back
home so if your window system
was installed using hardware raid and
you turn it off in the bios then
you still can't see anything of that
file you have to format and start
from this yeah so i don't think i
don't think these steps require
reformatting the hard drive
they do require that you load certain
drivers in windows
before you switch the bios back to hci
or whatever it is
so as long as you take those steps in
the correct order it
should should work yeah but it also
depends on how the
red controller talk to the drive
and because it um it uh
if it is how the file system is um
is uh formatted it's the the red
controller uh
when it is in the hardware red mode it
does something
to the drive so you uh so if you have
say for instance you have a system with
the
two drives in red one and um and the
system crashed for some reason
you you can't just take those two drive
out and put it in another system unless
that other system
has the exact same type of hardware rate
controller you can't just use software
and then read them
you want to i never even realized that
the um
i never even realized that the bios was
set up for raid and i just moved my
um moved my sata drive from
my old desktop into this one booted up
linux and that's all i ever run on this
machine
yeah i only switched to windows just
every now and again
but it found and booted up on linux
without any problem at all
so you know every day i don't boot it up
every day and
i normally leave the thing running 24 7.
um but i never have i never had a
problem it never even occurred to me to
look at the bios
to see if it should be uh to see if it's
configured as raid
or whether i should move it to anything
else but i found this article
i'll follow those steps and i'll see if
i can find it i'll share that article
with you as well solbu so um
uh you know maybe it'll work for you on
your on your rack mounted server
so stormy welcome i just wanted to say
hello
i wanted to give brian a go first and
i'll let you have a go okay
so uh brian welcome good to see you
yeah um nothing
major here just as we say same old same
old
each day i go out for a walk every
morning listening to podcasts
and then i come back to this desktop and
get go down rabbit holes
day after day i'm very good at that
yeah i've been experimenting the last
couple of weeks with um
a piece of software called etisync
e-t-e-s-y-n-c
okay which is something yeah it's an
encrypted it's basically for syncing
calendars
contacts calendars and tasks okay
it's an open source uh pc what i've
normally done
um do you mean that you're running it as
a service on your machine that your
other machines sync to
well you you can't you can run it on
your own server
but i'm actually on etisync have
a server set up and you can use that
and what you do is you get a free trial
for a
14 days a couple of weeks and then they
charge for it but it's nominal i think
it's like a dollar a month or something
you pay your 10 years but i still don't
want to
um i still don't want just to rely
on anyone else's computer for me
i would rather run something like
davical
on my local linux machine and that's
exactly what i do actually
i'm on davical that that hosts my
i run davico on my local machine that
has my calendar and contact list
and all of my devices phone ipad
laptops all of them they all sink to
to that davikel instance and
it just works it just works
so um
so yeah i would if you've got a machine
that you don't mind leaving running even
if it's a
well i wouldn't recommend a raspberry pi
or an extra for you for that
necessarily hello peter
i wouldn't recommend a uh a raspberry pi
necessarily although i have to admit
the raspberry pi that i've got running
here has been running non-stop
for as long as the power stays on has
been running non-stop for
uh for uh for weeks even
so you know there's no reason not to use
it except for
your data is there um and
uh and you're going to want to make sure
that your data is safe that's the whole
point
this desktop this time gets backed up
all the time so
that's the interesting thing with et
sync though it's totally encrypted
um so when you set it up you have the
keys
so etisync or anybody else even if they
got the data
it's just a blob okay but the problem is
if they go away
if they disappear for whatever reason if
you lose contact with them or if their
server shut down for any reason
your data is gone no well it's not it's
it's also on your own
like i've got is it's shared between my
evolution
and my phones etc so even if their
server went down instantly now
i've got copies on my devices you can
then
export that as a normal ics file
um and you know and import it into
something else
have you tried that yes okay
okay so i've got daily backups of all my
data
so far around good i'm good i'm glad to
hear that interesting as i say what i'm
going to do
is i'm going to subscribe to it because
my i'm on my second week of the trial
um and then i'm going to try
because i've got this this main desktop
computer is is
it's more or less it's server sorry
hardware it's on
most of the day the only time it goes
down as a as i suspend it in the evening
you know it's a midnight till
seven in the morning or whatever but
it's only because i use this as a plex
server as well okay so i'm going to try
and uh run an 80 sync my own instance on
this
machine as well would you mind sending a
link
to um to their website i'll post it in
the show notes
please yeah yeah or etisync
um for anyone who's interested in in
using it
um me i'm i'm not interested because
i've got a local solution
that works fine for me and it keeps my
data
in my network where i believe it belongs
so
um but yeah other folks might be
interested so yeah i'd love to see that
um
put it in discord or so if you don't
mind
stormy do you prefer stormy or do you
prefer
ian either one works okay
what's going on with you sir
nothing okay
[Laughter]
yeah not much going on um i i'm
trying to get my minecraft bedrock
edition world to load up
on my uh i i'm using this this like
rapper
thing that someone developed which
allows you to run the android version of
minecraft
i think the bedrock version on top of
linux it's a really
hacky workaround but it does work
interesting
i found a book somewhere that said you
could modify
minecraft or build or build
uh mods for it if you use the other
forge version of minecraft but i've
never been able to get that working so
yeah well this works fine by the time
you fiddle with it and mess with it you
could have just gone and bought a copy
of it anyway right
so what is it like 20 or 30 bucks or
something so
yeah i just have a problem sending money
to microsoft that's all
yeah yeah yeah i
don't really care much for microsoft
either they'd even
but
yeah but um
we've got about three or four minutes
left so
um so i'll give peter a go real quick
unless you've got anything else
for me okay not a problem
peter you came in last man you only came
in like 10 minutes ago
oh yeah i know i forgot the time
i even gave you a warning i even said
4pm
gmt how could you miss that i didn't
look on the
uh on anything
i've been doing other things
okay okay well you've switched to
daylight savings now so
you've got no excuse anymore i know that
budget that the
greeks really wanted everything went
weird
i understand i wasn't sure how many
people were going to jump in because it
was
because it's easter sunday so i'm glad
you all made it
yeah i i i i
the uh the boxer didn't work from
amazon we don't talk about uh i mean
i managed to make a uh uh we're putting
into a box so we
and we managed to make a uh a buffer
board for it
uh that indeed we definitely build on it
so
we put that in the box and do that after
each do we think
uh so you're literally fixing it
yourself
yeah yeah it is already needed without
the help of transit
to be replaced
put to the airport to the socket and
then we plug in
another ball time i designed that
to make sure that uh it worked and uh
so i've been doing a little bit of that
and a bit more electronic shift
oh good and uh and bobby you remember
the uh
the the front situated i showed you with
all the
buttons on a long time ago well
we also built a buffer board for that as
well and we had to get one
for what's coming out of it at uh
between
all five meg so that was quite good
uh we had a couple uh uh attracted to
australia warming up transit slightly
too much
but we got around
which i could vary up and down which uh
uh which is a far better way of doing
things okay it makes it wideband as well
yeah when we test when we test circuits
we typically limit the current
quite a bit so that uh you know you
don't just feed full current into it
especially if they're older
uh older circuits and you do that on
purpose so that
if there's a problem you're not going to
destroy anything so
they they come today i've got so much
light coming in from the back
peter from behind you from the window
behind you that i can't even see what
that is
it looks like a crystal or something
it's about
russia i bought some very
[Music]
they gave me the box it came in a box
and
around the box was a lot of fake
newspaper
and on the go on the newspaper there was
about gardening
and they were selling onions at 23
rupees whatever that is
and uh guess what color what type of
onion it was it was a red onion
at the beginning i said at the beginning
no politics but still you skirt the edge
don't you
can't help yourself all right then
we are believe it or not we are at 27
minutes can you believe that
and that's right about where robbie
wants it to be so i'm going to go ahead
and
shut it down so um have a great easter
for the rest of the rest of you have a
good easter
um take care stay safe and
and i will see you next week i enjoyed
it thank you very much
bye bye everybody
[Music]
you