good afternoon well good morning
whatever it is hello
welcome to cat 5 tv coffee break
i am bp 9. um and i have
sol boo in the top left hand corner uh
give us a wave subway thank you
i have peter give us a wave peter thank
you very much
doug hello give us away hello and sasha
i haven't seen you in ages
[Music]
and of course i'm bp 9 over here um
doing my best not to mess up so we'll
see what happens
i'm just double checking i am recording
and uh
muted lights are on we're good to go
such as a screenshot it's not looking
like a
construction zone no
although i will say i
i found yeah i found a sweet spot in my
house where like
the internet is not so bad it just
happens to be in my messy bedroom
but at some point if you're interested
i'll show you some new developments at
the house
absolutely because i want to know that
was one of the questions i had was i
wanted to know whether
the house was ready for winter because i
suspect
winter has well and truly arrived am i
right
yes now let me see i know i can switch
around my camera
so i can show an outside view nice see
a little tiny bit of snow happening yeah
i
love that i love that view sasha i mean
yeah
look at my wood stove i am on the top of
a hill
hold on i'll bring you to the the best
view of the house
yeah i do see the stove there's my
wooden stove
oh just installed it
and then you can see out this window
here
down the hill you can see the ocean
it's on the horizon i am so jealous
i'm so jealous it's so amazing
because we're not all right we started
australia when i lived in australia
um i used to live right near the water
because in melbourne
pretty much all the cities are on the
water they're
on bays or or on the seashore and so
i used to fall asleep to the sound of
the surf
and i missed that i'm nowhere near
uh water here so i don't get to hear
that and i do i do miss that
no you're landlocked yes sir absolutely
i don't mind not with all the hurricanes
and tornadoes and all the rest of it
flowing through i i'm
quite happy to be in you know further
inland but um
i do not like um i i do miss
the the surf that is true yes
have you seen any icebergs sasha when we
first got here in
april it was iceberg season i suppose if
there is a season
um but now it will be again in the
spring
yeah we're right in iceberg alley so we
get to see a parade of them
go by in the spring did you see me after
you moved in
yes so we were quarantined for the two
weeks
and um during that time we could see out
of the
living room window these massive big
icebergs
floating but they were big enough that
we could see them like their
majesticness from
as far away as we were and then when we
were able to get close to the ocean
there were hundreds of little guys
so it turns out they're called growlers
if they're not a certain
size right and and then they're
and then so there was tons of growlers
and then a lot of
icebergs as well that's almost very cool
and then
even the even the growlers can mess with
um with shipping right or no
yeah that's i think what took the
titanic down was a growler not
oh really oh i i thought it was a bigger
yeah because
i think it wasn't a bigger or if it was
a bigger it it hit below
right it was like one of those ones
where it wasn't detectable enough
for them to notice as they were powering
ahead
right right right so
and then we there's tons of whales here
and it turns out that there's a lot of
sharks too
so like my friends who get to go out
on the weekends fishing because here you
don't need a fishing license to fish
on the weekends they'll go out to the
ocean and they'll see tons of sharks
there too
so now there is there is not much in the
way of population
on uh on that island is there
or no so is there any restrictions on
hunting
um yes you need a license to hunt moose
i don't think you need one i'm not sure
if you need one for rabbits
um i think rabbit hunting you're just
allowed to do
um and ducks you want a license i don't
think anyone cares too much about
rabbits
unless they've got mexico they're pretty
good at repopulating themselves
that is very true
[Laughter]
um oh fish the fishing you're allowed
five fish per day per person
three days a week so 15 fish if you're
allowed
yeah wow and can you get that many fish
out of the
out of the sea you can get it within an
hour like
david only went out he only went out one
day
because of just the way the timing went
for his work and
we don't have a boat so we had to use
the generosity of friends to get out
there
he went out one day and within an hour
he had all five of his
so wow wow well
if he goes fishing and then once a week
can he then uh if you shop at 15 and
all the quarter for a week at the time
i i think just the the five each day so
you could go three days in a row
and get your 15. well what would i say
they bring
all bachelor oh god
it is um salmon and
yeah route is it trout trout fishing
does that make sense to you
yeah yeah it would be nice too
okay
someone who is not seen the cfe in quite
some time doesn't know how
fish works i enjoy walking by the sea
i enjoy you know the beach
um i enjoy the sound of the surf i do
not enjoy fishing
you know to be honest i will one day
fish i'm working my way up to it but so
far i haven't done it
so it's just like with any other hunting
activity
um it's not even the catching so much
it's the the gutting and cleaning and
all that messy stuff but
i'm just yeah
on a much more beautiful and peaceful
side i will tell you we have
a zillion blue jays that come to our
property every day it's
they they eat us out of uh bird seed
constant well if you put
you know bird seed out they're gonna eat
it right so
yeah are you putting bird seed out we
are but mostly because of the beautiful
birds there are now they're
fat beautiful birds they're practically
just blue turkeys
they won't be able to take off when they
get ready to leave in spring
oh my so how are the house renovations
coming along i saw that you
you pointed out the um the wood stove
um yes last time we saw your house all
the
plaster was off in the kitchen
especially
yes so we had a electrician friend come
in
and fix up the electrical now you'll
have to forgive me because
i do need to do dishes um
because i made so i made soap today
i made soap in this crock pot i made
soap
and you're not going to be including
that you're not cooking food in there
yeah
i have two crock pots that's my food
cooking one
down there mix them up mix them up
whatever you do yeah
so there we go this is the kitchen now
oh yeah but i see that i see all the
nice plaster but did you fix all the
stuff behind
it yes our well our electrical
our electrician friend ryan did
okay so that's good yes um
and we got a new sink that actually
drains
oh this is my dinner for later
is that a veggie burger is that what
that is it is it's a veggie burger yeah
it's like one of those impossible
burgers
yeah not real food yeah hey now
i don't know i don't know i've been um
pretty happy with uh robbie's suggestion
he likes to
he suggested to me when i was when he
and i were talking about roasting
veggies in the oven
i like to take eggplant and mushrooms
and
[Music]
cucumber and i'll slice them all up into
small
chunks olive oil and balsamic vinegar
and then put them in the oven for 30 or
40 minutes
nice awesome very good yeah i need to do
that more is the problem
because that's you know how that works
i i know i'm not exercising enough
that's my problem
we were given a great big huge amount of
swiss chard
like during like the harvest of it and i
ate
i ate so much of it all at once and then
i told our friend who gave it to us i
was like i ate that in like three days
it was amazing i was frying it up with
onions
so they gave us another big batch and by
the end of that i was like ooh
i am charged i'm done with charge
i bet it's like if you go to hospital
and the people who visit with you think
if they bring your favorite foods in
right
to the hospital then then you know
you'll feel better but no
that just means i associate my favorite
foods with the illness that brought me
into the hospital
in the first place that's right fun
that's no fun i remember when i was oh
so that's all right i'm sorry i was just
going to let some other folks have a go
at talking because we've been uh
we've just been sort of chatting and
ignoring the rest of them sorry about
that so
sober you have a go you you tell us what
you've been up to
well um i've been uh switching um
and i mentioned uh earlier this year
that
in the in uh that i had bought two new
systems uh
for using down downstairs um i had to
uh one of them was so noisy and it
turned out that it was almost as old as
one of the systems it
replaced that um the fans of the new all
that
system was so noisy and it made me mad
so i finally gave up and i um the
biggest uh
of the old systems are whenever i
brought back and i just swapped the
drives around
so now the living room is
nice and quiet as it should be yeah
i have a i have a high performance
um uh amd machine
an amd athlon machine which
unfortunately keeps shutting down on me
which is why i bought this
this other high performance desktop
machine
and when i took when i took it apart i
discovered that the
um uh the the
paste between the processor and the
heatsink
had dried out and so i think it was
shutting down because it was
it was overheating so i i've got some
some thermal paste now to put on it but
now i've got to figure out how to
put it all back together without making
a huge mess so
and also um
a few people might know from the chat
room
um i am one of those people who and i
host my own
my own email server at home
so um all my
my emails comes directly to my
server server in the basement my
internet connection is not
strong enough for me to be able to do
that reliably that's that's my problem
because you have to have a 24 7
connection all the time
it has to be contactable all the time
doesn't it
no um it has to be connected connectable
uh
at least at least once every uh
five days uh because at the most um
email server
send and receive email yeah because most
email servers are configured by default
to
attempt to deliver for five days and if
you can't deliver in those five days
then it will be returned
so if you have an intermittent
connection um every now and then that's
that's not up so
so up to five days but how often will it
try
during that five days i'm not sure once
an hour or once every
30 minutes yeah it's um configurable and
um
a few a few of them big
hosting providers like gml and
yeah yeah okay they will try uh uh
once every 12 hours i think um
um so in my old place
i had did not make
an ip um and it was no problem
i had a script that updated my uh dns
record so that every time the ip changed
and it
would update i have a static ip so i
have no problem with that
the only problem i have is that my is
that my
internet modem the modem provided by the
network provider blocks all traffic
by default um incoming traffic
which is nice but i i have to
set it to bridge if i want to do that
control the problem is that
that the internet provider can see all
of the machines internal to my network
but of course what i've done is all i've
done is plugged
routers into the um into that
modem so that all they can see is
routers not the actual
machines internally i do the same that
um
my mail server also serves as my router
um and i i don't have a in any wireless
capabilities
um i have a wireless router that is
permanently disconnected i only connect
it when i have the
visitors who need to use the internet um
yeah
so what about your phone or your ipad or
whatever else you have in the way of
tablets
how do you how do you connect to you
to your internal network that way
that looks like internet that looks like
an uh not a smartphone
is that uh i don't like smartphones
really i have uh i have two um i have
two devices um
that i use for uh i um they do not have
a sim card
um um it's on a
galaxy four and galaxy um
s4 and s4 4k but i use them to
uh store pictures uh when i'm out about
and
uh notebook and and
if i need to connect something to them i
uh plug in
a usb cable and i transfer manually
i don't trust smartphones i go
i go old school i have notes
yeah i have a few of those as well
um what difference does it pin
what difference does it make whether or
not your ip
provider can see your machines on your
network
um the ip provider
if they can see any um any machines
on the network they will attempt to
connect to things like shared drives
stuff like that um and so they'll have
access
to uh the content of your
of of whatever is shared by your
machines
and also if the internet provider can
see it the rest of the internet can also
see it
yes
so my router is uh my
mail server is also a router and i have
a switch
connected to it and i run the
cable the cables from downstairs up to a
switch here
and i run a cable from this week's to a
switch upstairs
um i would i would like to catch up with
you later about that because i want to
talk about
running your mouth one more thing i want
to let some other folks have a go as
well i did one small thing that i
had to uh turn on uh
i run my own um dns
and then my own main server but i had to
enable uh the sps um
spf
the thing that tell the email servers
what servers are allowed to send mails
on my behalf
because at gmail after i moved here i
have to uh
my esp blocks outgoing 425 so i have an
external server that i am forced to use
um that i control but yeah and um
this server is not uh trusted by default
by gmail because uh an organization
equivalent of
eff electronic function they have all
their mail servers
on this server so they send out quite a
lot of
bulk emails one of the lists i think
have 1500 members
so um um so i have to tell them so i
have to tell you the
dns record that this server um is
allowed to send emails on my behalf and
i i definitely want to catch up with you
later so i'll
talk about that later whether we do that
on zoom or or some other way
i'd love to um pick your brain some more
about that
and you just look like it looks like the
reason i turned that off
but i had to turn it off is that uh
after i moved here i it turned out that
gmail started to throw all my emails in
everyone's spam folder oh nice and after
i
enable that this server is allowed to
send on my behalf it no longer
it in another in it shows up in
everyone's inbox instead which is
what was what they were supposed to do
so
so doug it looks like your cat wants to
be part of the party as well
oh yeah this i had two cats my older cat
died
while i was served yeah so this is the
one that's left her name's madeline
for short oh
so she's loving on you because because
she's oh she's a cuddler
oh yeah yeah i know mine mine's the same
well she would be if she felt like
coming out saying hello but she's
she's not coming out today she said no i
don't want to i don't want to play
so this cat is very gregarious she uh
she comes out for company and really
oh yeah she's got to be the center of
attention
mine will mine will go crawl under the
bed if anyone
if anyone shows up my other cat did that
okay
she may show up later especially if
everybody stays reasonably quiet because
she does not like a noisy
household oh yeah we blew through here
uh a few weeks ago and we lost power for
two days i think it was i had to open
some windows to let some cool air and
fresh air through the house yes of
course the central air wasn't working
and of course there was a lot of noise
outside you don't realize how much
noise gets insulated by the windows um
but yeah the um uh poor old poor old
kitty cat she
she was hiding under the bed most of the
time she was freaking out from all the
from all the noise that was going on so
well we've seen her jump up on your
computer table oh sure yeah she she
doesn't care
she's okay with me um not so much with
visitors
so right so peter what have you been up
to sir
what sort of trouble have you been
getting into is your new antenna working
okay
no oh um
the wings broken you can bring that
microphone closer to your mouth there
peter you'll be fine
no clue yeah the winch is broken
um the the wind's clear as i have to buy
a new winch
oh no and i no you'd sabotage i think
the same people who did the uh
we did the world indeed to build a
flavor tonight was wrong oh
jeez peter i'm sorry that they would
jealous from my antenna because it's a
big one
you know yeah yeah yeah so i just uh
yeah but i'm still now i'm gonna buy one
tomorrow i've got i've got one
on older one that people want to order
tomorrow i've got to hang i've got to
hang my long wire back up again i've got
a dipole that's a long one
i'll do what
[Music]
you know i have a tuner i have i have a
tuner in mine
um but it's lying on the ground right
now so a tuna even a tuna won't tune
that
[Laughter]
but 132 feet that's the only problem
oh wow yeah but uh yeah yeah i put one
up like that
oh my god it's longer than 32 feet but
it's
132 feet oh okay that makes more sense
that's about right for mine as well but
i've also got two
really long ropes and i've got it strung
up between two trees on one end of the
property to the other
so i've got my my mind on a very large
poplar tree
which grows like so a foot a year
yeah but it works very well if you want
information i'll give you information on
it
yeah i'll give you the information uh is
that why contacting you well we'll do it
we're not going to do it now we're about
ready to shut it down
that's what i mean yeah that's what i
mean yeah we can talk later for sure
uh
[Laughter]
oh nice okay here in the states we have
like ham radio outlet
and other places but i can give you the
name of it you know i'll give you
tonight
i've got to go and go and put the name
right here link to it put a link to it
in the in the chat if you want
um no i give a phone number as well
because i'll give you the phone number
but yeah
no we don't need to do that just give us
a website or something like that
yeah they need to advertise them that
strongly
well well i've already i've already
advertised it somewhere else
all right all right we're about to close
it down any closing comments from
yeah speaking of uh antennas i have a
fun story that my old mountain told it
it's a short story quick
quick he is a hammer the ham radio
operator
30 years ago yeah
in the 80s he was a a very active
operator and he had uh
an antenna and as big as uh peter's i
think uh maybe his was even a little
bigger
but um he lived in a apartment complex
and they had uh a walkway uh between
the apartment blocks
and on the other side of that walkway uh
he had his
antenna set setup and the antenna cable
was uh out from his living room window
down and over and just laying on the
grass and laying on
um and they mounted it and we put your
friend
and then the winter came and they they
were starting to
blow away the snow one day he was at
work and his
wife called and said that uh he had to
come home because
something had happened and what had
happened was
this snap blower um had catched the
antenna cable
oh no yeah and then it was
fully stressed out um
he said i can just see it i can see it
in my mind's eye i can already tell
his equipment was uh mounted inside a
shelf
much like the one
behind you and that was uh
took off across the living room and then
on the in the wall
and the antenna broke four meters away
doug what you got any closing comments
before we shut this
really okay sasha
thank you enjoyed enjoyed visiting with
you so
so glad you came and dropped in to say
hello
i love you being a part of this thank
you
you're always welcome sasha just come
visit any time you want you're always
welcome
so we'll do all right good deal
all right hey all your friends in one go
larger because
okay we're out of here have a great
afternoon everybody thank you good to
see you again sasha
i'll do that for you now okay
all right yeah bye bye