welcome to
category five technology tv coffee break
uh i'm bp night hello and uh on my top
left is uh doug
doug give us a wave sir hello and then
peter give us away
good job and that's peter so that's it
um
we're missing sober i don't know he
usually shows up but uh he
didn't uh he's not here yet so maybe
he'll show up we'll see what happens
so uh let's see what all's going on
uh some something for you uh uh uh peter
we talked about um we talked about
docker versus virtual machines a couple
of weeks ago do you remember that
oh yeah yeah yeah do yeah so i ended up
using docker
after all that um and it's working out
really really well
i'm really pleased it's totally it's
hardly using
any cpu at all which is fantastic
the limitation with docker i run linux
here at the house
all over the limitation is that
any docker machines that i start
have to be linux
machines because they use the same
kernel
as the host machine they also cannot
write to their own file system
that's one of the one of the things that
make it so protective
but what you can do is you can set up
um uh uh
shared folders or directories that you
can effectively mount like you would in
nfs and you can mount them to the host
machine and you're good to go at that
point
if you were to run docker on a windows
machine you could only
create windows docker
docker machines you would not be able to
run linux on
on a windows docker and you would not be
able to run windows
on a linux docker machine you know on
docker that's running on linux
so not even in vain in wine
wine um emulates windows as much as
possible but
it doesn't make a complete virtual
machine
it just emulates those windows calls
and then translates them to linux
equivalents effectively
it's also windows 7 as well of course
because it's got windows 10 calls
the and he doesn't do it 100
all the time yeah right exactly exactly
for me if i were to write a program that
needed to
act as a as a gui on
linux and on windows i would use
a um a toolkit like gtk
in my case i've had good success with
gtk2
and as long as you stick with the
library calls in gtk and don't make any
native calls directly to
x windows or to to the windows um
system it should work the key is you
have to compile the program
with the version of gtk for that
environment so for linux you have to
uh you have to build um
you have to build you have to leak your
program against gtk for linux to make it
run
as a linux native binary and for windows
you have to compile it under windows
against the gtk
for windows library can you do that
within the gtk can you say that again
peter
good day um can you do sound to type
things in gtk
sound yeah um probably the
only i'm not sure i have not i've not
explored sound
on on on gtk it's i'm sure it's possible
i'm pretty sure what you can do is is
say to gtk go play this
but i know we've mentioned this before
peter in in previous coffee breaks
and i think that you have to um
i think it depends on whether you have
the appropriate programs
on the box you're running on to actually
play the audio you might could make it
beep
that's probably all you can make it do
that's not very good but that wouldn't
do me more than that but anyway
well yeah i know i know but and my
answer's the same
now as um as it was then in that
i'm not sure um
what all you can do yeah i see him
i'm not sure what all you can do sober
so peter i'm not sure what what more you
can do apart from just beeps
on uh on on yeah i mean on
any machine today yeah yeah um
so yep that was it for that's it for
docker
i know i've already talked about code
coverage
with uh with elk have i talked about
that before
i know we talked about test harnesses
and stuff like that so i may have
already did i have to talk about word
stuff
do you recall i did
yeah i think you did did i mention did i
mention word
there is actually there is actually a
native linux
program uh that is a word star clone
that runs
under linux that does all the
that does all the things that words do
well a lot of the things that word star
does
and it's called word pizza
w-o-r-d-t-s-a-r
reality's bleeding through there so boo
it's not working so well for you
oh that's scary because now your eyes
are even showing
through the um exactly
part of your head is disappearing into
your back yeah exactly
your um your uh uh your hair is all
um gone transparent on us so yeah we're
looking forward
to the engineering team about this
and the holodeck is uh not
doing uh wow today wow wow
problems on the holidays
yeah because uh uh i far from that land
are you adorable
uh about
an hour to the flight north
yeah how many miles seven kilometers how
many kilometers
800 maybe i was a long way yeah
it's a long ways back about yeah yeah
that would take more like that would
take more like eight hours in my ear
playing solo
800 miles you said right no kilometers
oh 800 oh that's about 500 miles so yeah
that's going to be about 5 hours
i cruise at about 100 miles an hour
assuming no wind
yeah good luck with that
what no wind yeah why is that
this weekend there is a lot of wind so
uh oh well well so
i'd have to adjust i'd have to adjust it
appropriately for that so
all right dad your turn sir what's uh
what's going on with you
oh nothing much just working as usual
working as usual nice nice
well actually one thing i did try to do
have you ever heard of ventoy
veentoy no t-e-n-t-o-y
it's a program that's supposed to allow
you to put multiple
isos on a thumb drive
uh i can do so that you could so that
you could boot from the one that you
want
but what it allows you to do is that uh
you're supposed to be able to just copy
them to the thumb drive
rather than burning them to an
individual partitioned
on your thumb drive so what i'm saying
yeah but an iso is just a it's just a
file although it's an
image of a cd it's in it's a cd
page so once you've burned it to an iso
it can be just a file but
if you just copy it to your thumb drive
it's just a file to the thumb drive it
doesn't care
you can't do much event then toy allows
you to choose the one that you want to
run
and i think that i haven't gotten it to
work yet but i think it
starts it up almost like an executable
interesting i know that in linux anyway
i don't know if you can do this with
windows
you can actually mount that iso image
as a uh as a as a drive
and it will and it will you can then
browse it and look at it
of course it's read only because it's a
a it's an
image but you can look at it and see
what's inside it
um i do i do not believe i've seen um
i i don't believe there's any way to
manage it after that i
i thought and i thought it's like a
deadpool because uh
i discovered the type of zip file that
would read it and
uh you could own uninstalled one on one
take the bits again
and i can't think the name of it at the
moment i'm trying to think of the name
it's a well known one as well it's not
there but it's a well-known one
and uh yeah yeah yeah so you can
actually take the thing to beds
i did that on the desk once you have to
look at something to try oh sure
yeah that's certainly possible now
whether you can mount it and execute it
the way doug's explaining is another
thing
i mean i've only ever seen i've only
been able to execute it when i can mount
it
and then somehow reboot it or put it on
an sd card or something
but it's only one at a time i could i
could put multiple
isos on a thumb drive but you can't get
each one to run individually
you know you can't choose which one you
want to run unless you partition that
thumb drive
as separate drives themselves right now
is ventoy software or hardware
software okay okay so it acts like a
bootloader or so
on on the sd card i yeah it might
kind of work like a grub that will start
each iso
as you want
just like you would install on a brand
new machine right so
yeah i don't know how right but i know
that
then grub you can uh set up group to uh
where you can have a configure a few
isos and
they will uh you can configure them as a
menu as
what to to boot into it um yeah okay
yeah yeah right but whether you can boot
right directly into an iso with grub i
don't know
so that's what i'm talking about yeah
that's interesting
i don't know how you do it right right
right right right
peter what have you been up to while you
talk
while you talk let me go get the stuff
that i need
to show off what i was what i was
talking about i'll be right back
oh good way i'll tell you when i come
back
it's gone again well i haven't said
anything yet
um i got it all fixed by the way um
uh uh some
some odd relation on my distance and
this simulation came
it was a farmer decided to memorize me
because my wings decided to break and uh
the problem i'll do he's got me back i
can hear him
and the problem was um was that
the winch clutch decided to back up
basically um we took it the best and
cleaned it all up
and uh the things started to work okay
so i've got everything sort of working
again i think
but we haven't got it we haven't got
quite up here but uh
really won't choose your wednesday we
think about doing it
are going to get uh you know right the
way to
do boys club again but uh do you know
how much they wanted to pay for
that they are probably putting on
discord but
uh the two clutch uh things are
made of uh uh conducting carbide about
size of an old english penny
you know about an inch across you know
and uh
13 pounds and you know what they wanted
for postage
something like 45 pounds wouldn't it yes
i mean those texas amount of money
and uh i'll find these i'll find the uh
uh uh australia to put in the jeffrey
bag
and uh and tended to be a cheaply
i was okay oh yeah oh
you got that as well
[Laughter]
well she she jumped up to say hello and
did you look at that antenna yeah you
think it's about it too
old opposite all right as i said i
already have a dipole
to um to hang up on that would you be
dreading that area you know when i
say two yet last week uh i i
i saw it but i don't think i'll put it
up there i mean i'll i'll
stick with the night bowl that i have
better the air work better than a dipole
could do you know
it would yeah yeah yeah yeah okay it's
got gain on
uh the upper bounds uh a lot
yeah yeah but uh
you're going to get loaded you can't
have any you can't have my coffee
[Laughter]
[Applause]
anymore
so peter we've we've joked about this
before and i'm not sure that you
actually believed
that i had one of these so you already
know about this right we've already
talked about this many many times we
don't have to keep talking about that
but and i already mentioned it has a
serial port on that you see rs232
yeah the next time you talk about this
you better have a doom running on it
yeah no not going to happen
just so that you can so i can prove it
actually does have
[Laughter]
peter i know peter's going to laugh
about this because he uh
wow he just loves he just loves the
the naughty words so uh you know
stop it peter enough no no don't do it
peter don't do it
but what it is it takes serial in so it
just
it just plugs on db9 on the other side
right
and it just uses uh sd cards it just
pops in
you just pop an sd card in there and it
you just write files to it like you
would a disk drive
from the model 100 quite good yeah works
on cpm as well works like a charm
so is there the size of the sd card you
can use dependent on
the size of the drive that the the
operating system you're using is able to
handle
i don't know that there's an operating
system as such even on that particular
machine
and as far as the as far as the
cpm os is concerned the hardware device
inside this model 100
allows you to have a 3.5 megabyte
a floppy floppy disk which is
magnificent it's wonderful but i can't
fit three and a half meg on this 256
k 256 well yeah i can of course i can
hello i thought it was 256k
it's 256 meg
but i can only to my knowledge i can
only store
individual files on on on this
sd card i think i think that the um
the units called rex cpm
i think it has a facility for backing up
the entire
um image the entire 3.5 as a as a
as a disc image similar to the isos we
were talking about earlier
um but uh it takes
it takes hours apparently to do that
through the serial port so oh yeah
but uh but i did to tell you mfj to the
aerial as well by the way in the stage
oh yeah mfj yeah
they do it do get the big one if you get
the beat at 100 uh
yeah yeah it did work i'll warn you
um but yeah mine's on the ground at the
moment so it wouldn't be hard to
um it wouldn't be hard to string up a
brand new one so
well that's what i'm trying to say is
that uh you got multi-band and uh
you got gain and uh the thing has got
three tvs anyway over the typo anyway
yeah okay no no it works well well um
yeah i have to get a ladder to make mine
about i
have it soon you're gonna scare us to
death one day
one day you're gonna you're gonna fall
off the ladder and you're gonna break
your arm with you
i've been trying to borrow a ladder
because uh not me
but uh i what i got is i i don't go up
the ladder what i got is a couple wins
a couple uh pulleys up on one on the
tree or one's on a
on on a post one side of that and i
pulled
yeah and i just needed to
un gangl one side at the bottom so
let me just need to go up and take or
something and then i could pull it
straight
um yeah it really does work well i heard
australia the other day by the way on
there yeah i know you mentioned that you
mean i did it
i did it today as well oh good nice yeah
yeah we're going on yeah yeah yeah yeah
so
uh so sobu i see you're being a ghost on
voyager right now
you're doing a fine job there very
we good see right through you literally
[Laughter]
nothing inside no no no no
so what's been going on with you sir um
i've been hunting
[Music]
this week i discovered
yeah mice
oh i discovered last week that in my uh
kitchen there is um behind the drawers
and
um shelf on the floor
behind there is a space behind um it is
a building but um one of my
most uh was uh i'm hiding behind there
okay you know if there's one
you know there's one there's going to be
more yeah i don't know for a fact there
is
and i knew for a fact that there is only
one but
um but when there is only one
uh you have to do you have to find it
quickly or uh
soon there is uh not convenient the only
one yeah
like much
already in inside you just remove on a
plastic thing
and then you activate it by
pressing on on the back and then i put
in here and put it in
one of the the bottom drawers that i
knew
i emptied everything out and then 10
minutes after i put it in the door bang
oh wow okay and it was quiet ever since
oh so you think you just got the one did
you put another mousetrap down just in
case yeah
i have another one but there is no more
accuracy it hasn't been oh good
well done very good that's what's over
we advice as well you last weekend uh
the funny thing was that i was sitting
here the other day doing some work with
a file
file in some bits of stuff and there's
the box that i could
rattle so i go over the box done he
detects he stuck it up
looked at me a lot faulty towers when
the biscuits in at the very end the
other one
and and the flipping thing looked at
based off we've got the ambulance
through the armor attic
we put poison down and uh we found them
dead in the
air in capital bloated and horrible no
you know that's the way it could give my
wife and on that note we'll finish
up
no we won't um what else so
what else you've been up to um
[Music]
not much not much really yeah it's been
a quiet week
speaking of it you saw a video please
tell me you saw a video
this story is not about the video oh no
i was visiting
[Music]
some friends of mine
yeah and it's already melted away which
is which is probably why
uh you've got rodents coming into your
house where it's nice and warm right
yeah yeah yeah there's no way
it was about to come so
yeah when the snow has actually arrived
they are not long they are no longer
sinking inside because uh underneath us
now it's um
that's warm yeah but um um
yeah her father and they had been
visiting
them over the weekend and last weekend
um he had in one week
he catched 135 mice
he needs a mousing cap is what he needs
wow
in one single day and then he lined them
all up
and in a few oh no he didn't and
it took pictures
can you imagine setting up all those
mouse traps as dominoes
and seeing one snap off and
i think that he did that at one point he
did actually do that
i'm not surprised the worst thing he
writes
about the words we've gone here as well
we've got rats
from the river yeah yeah yeah big big
thing there
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah nasty
nasty all right i want to
i want to check the last comments
because uh we're
pretty much ready to finish up so i have
one video story i knew there'd be one
somewhere
there's not a single coffee break goes
by that there isn't a video story yeah
if you mentioned it
i could be fairly quick though yeah you
mentioned that they're
copying and backing up the uh huge
uh one point something megabytes
[Laughter]
the time to do that um i saw a video um
a youtuber who is uh making videos of
the old operating system and all the
computers
um here um you mentioned that uh
a friend of his uh back in the installed
uh
windows 95 from uh from
floppy disks
three or four hours yeah yep that's no
surprise
i have a copy of os2 warp lying around
somewhere
that's all floppies no cds and so
um i've been trying to try to install it
on a virtual machine or something
anything at all but i can't get the
first disk to read through
so it won't it won't it the install
fails because the
the first disk uh won't read through so
you still have floppy drives yeah i
still have i used to have machines that
have floppies
yeah oh wow no i know it sounds odd but
yes i do
i've even got a uh um a tray system
where i can mount
um hard drive into the tray and then
slide it into the
uh into the case of the machine
to um so okay if i want to run if i want
to run os2 i actually label the drive
os2
or the tray os2 i slide the os2 tray in
there
turn on the machine it theoretically if
i could ever get it to start up it would
it would start up
that's what i do as well i do the same
thing yep works like a charm works
really well
it looks if you look at the back of the
tray
um where it connects into the into the
frame of the um of the drop of the
receptacle that it fits in the old
centronics
the connectors is what it uses to um uh
to make a connection to the
uh to the actual machine between the
drive and the machine seems to work
really well
so so yeah there you have it
my dial swappable so i have to keep
turning the machine off if i have to do
that you know
oh sure yeah you can't you can't pull
the drive while the machine's running it
would be the same as
it would be the same as the drive
failing so yeah yeah a friend of mine he
had uh
in uh and not sure if it's
everywhere but um in
scandinavia at least
power supply units on the back of back
of our computers
it has a switch where you can switch
from 240 and 110 volts
oh i see what's coming you haven't
switched the wrong way right
you know here no no um
this is 25 years ago yeah yeah i've been
there i've done it he flipped the switch
while the machine was running oh no i
have not done that
oh no i've had it switched the wrong way
and it promptly blew up
but um yeah so these days of course
approached by but i mean what didn't
work after that
i'm not surprised i have a i have a
radio board for a garage door opener
that i have to
that i have to uh replace some
components on because lightning struck
here um a long time ago now
i've just been too lazy to fix it but um
but lightning struck and i can see
the big one watt resistor that's in
there that just this carbon
you know uh carbon traces all around it
where it uh
where it blew up from the lightning
strikes so
i don't know if it's just everything
else seems to work because i can
manually close the contacts and the
garage door opener will work
but the actual radio card i think is
what's failed so
yeah the best friend our neighbor when
he first moved in
to the in in he and his wife moved into
the house uh
19 years ago i think it is now um he uh
uh befriended the neighbor
across the road and he had this neighbor
he had
three machines running xp and
and they had set up uh automatic uh
backup
of their machines to the two other uh
computers it ran automatically
yes so one power search takes all three
out right yeah it did you just
yeah lightning suck and they lost
everything
no surprise there yes
okay a very quick one peter because i've
got to go
uh i somebody a friend of mine offered
to repair his rig
and as one of the first japanese
transits to things that came in and
serpentis
and uh uh he wants to connect up to his
upper fire because we build an amplifier
so he talks we're taking the uh 1500
volts out of this thing and uh
to connect up to his amplifier but uh
the japanese
doesn't understand that uh plugs are for
plugging in and sockets up where the hd
goes on they did it the other way
around so the plug on on the rig was on
there
and i liked it and i did i said some
very bad words
they they these girlfriends and himself
was giving me brandy to to get me
recovered so i saw across the room very
quickly
and and all right folks
we have to finish up it's been 30
minutes so robbie's already getting
already going to give me a hard time
because we've gone 30 minutes so
so i'm going to finish it up enjoy
enjoyed it thank you so much
as always it goes way too fast yeah
so thank you so i'll be good to see you
even if you were late
again
no we can we can watch your kitchen we
don't care
[Laughter]
all right have a good day everybody
all right have a good day everybody bye
[Music]
bye