this week jeff and i get into it about
how the internet is bound to change in
the coming years
and will break down two-factor
authentication for you in an
easy to understand way becca's here to
share some of the tech stories we're
following this week
including a hyperloop in canada adobe
deleting user files with their latest
update
and wsl-2 back-ported to windows 10
1903-1909
plus robert's here to help beginners
learn to research cryptocurrencies
stick around it's time for the tech
[Music]
our live recordings are trusted only to
solid state drives by kingston
technology
revive your computer with improved
performance and reliability over
traditional hard drives with kingston
ssds
category 5 tv streams live with
telestream wirecast and nimble streamer
tune in every week on roku cody and
other hls video players
for local showtimes visit category5.tv
welcome to the show everybody great to
see you nice to have you here jeff
good to see you good to be here having a
good week i had a great week
oh good yeah what about you i'm doing
pretty well yeah it's been
quite a couple of weeks yes yeah we had
to skip last week
yes that's true and for those who are
wondering about that
we were battling with uh internet
service provider
and so that caused some issues that uh
i had to make the call last week to
forego the show
which is a really really hard call to
make but
as you know we we do try to do the show
live and
you know such a way that we're able to
broadcast to you at home
uh that that unfortunately put a kink in
our plans does make it hard to go on the
internet without internet
yeah this whole internet without
internet thing
is is really really tough first world
problem yeah i don't know how it works
now it isn't i mean maybe they're
probably not related but it's funny the
last week
my internet at home has been dropping
probably every hour
it's been it's been weird here like
we've had some weird
issues and and even um so much as the
local isps
had uh dns outages really
dns it's all it's it's dns wow
yeah so you know we're trying to get
online and
and accessing websites and and
everything else and and there's no
dns responsiveness from the isp
so but but only at certain points so
only if you're trying to access certain
areas of the web you say well but you
use pi hole so
that should be able to bypass that
because i've got
my own internal dns server but the
problem is is that
the routing still has to go through the
isp that's right yeah
so if their internal dns is not
responding then
all of a sudden it breaks down somewhere
in toronto
and uh and and here we here we are yes
and i understand there's been some
issues with uh aws amazon web services
in the uk as well
um so if that's affected you that's
really tough and and it's a
it's an interesting thing like we're
we're so cloud-based
now and you say you know what is the
cloud well really it's just a grouping
of
very very powerful servers aws being
one of the world's largest because
amazon is huge and
aws is their cloud platform for host
like hosts um so you know my websites
are
largely you know our back end is powered
by amazon web services so uh
fortunately here in canada uh we weren't
affected
but those who are hosting on aws
i believe it was in the uk that i think
that's correct
it was down so their servers are
completely down
so you've got infrastructure that is
built upon this platform that you expect
is always going to be up
and it's not that's right necessarily
google had it happen where a lightning
strike
actually took down some of their cloud
that's right a couple years ago
yeah but it resulted in like a 0.0001
percent i don't know if that's the
actual number but
data loss at their data center and so
that's it yes but when you consider the
scale of google
yeah fair enough okay it can be huge
right that's true
so and the advantages i guess with
cloud hosting is that well partly
you've got a little bit of an out if
something goes down
yeah as a as a provider as a service
provider you're able to
okay well you know there's a pretty
large
amount of sites that are affected by an
outage
at amazon web services for sure yeah if
you self-host
and your server goes down there's no
excuses
it all falls on you but there's a
certain level
of i guess like community understanding
that hey
oh well if aws is down in the uk
and i can't access your uk-based website
that's hosted there then
uh it's amazon's fault it'll be back up
tomorrow
yeah exactly it's tough but that's
that's the infrastructure of this
internet
do you ever sit there some days and i i
realize i'm like going off on a tangent
out and just wondering already
we're not even a minute but you ever
wonder what's going to be like the next
iteration of the internet the next
iteration of the internet
yeah i think the next iteration as we
see the technology progressing as far as
bandwidth
capacity goes okay and we're going to be
learning a little bit about
some of the advancements there with the
newsroom today
because there's such a high demand for
bandwidth right now
yeah people who are working from home
understand
that your your you know your dropouts
may be the result of
all of a sudden the isp is handling a
lot more traffic because people are now
working from home
you think about an office so let's say
we've got an office with 50 people
working
that's one internet connection that
everybody's sharing and so if there's
problems it affects that one office
right if however you've got now all of
those 50 people working from home
we now have 50 internet connections and
those internet connections are doing
what
any guesses when i work from home what
do i do
stream netflix i do that
game but i tend to remote
in yes that's right so that one
internet connection now at my office
that used to have
50 people sitting there has now got
potentially up to 50 people remoting in
from home accessing that same internet
connect
connection to be able to work from home
and remotely access their files and
their computers and things like that
so you've got this whole kind of like
bottleneck happening on the internet so
what's next for the internet
as as things get faster as things get
like
richer as far as the available bandwidth
goes
are we going to see improved well
improved performance
automatically turns more impressive
services
yes when high-speed internet came along
changed the world yes but netflix that
you used to be able to order a dvd and
they would mail it to you
and you could you would rent movies from
netflix this is how they got their start
so it was it was like a website that you
would order a dvd
and they would send you that dvd you
would watch it just like you rented it
from blockbuster
and then you would return it that's
right then
it's all online then high speed internet
came along and you know what netflix is
now
yeah so what is going to progress how
are things going to change how are
things going to improve like what is
next
it's all you know who knows what's going
to improve
what's going to change i keep thinking
it's going to go completely wireless
if you can remove that physical cable
are we there yet are we already there
to some degree i mean i use the wi-fi
yeah the tech is there but i think from
an infrastructure standpoint
we're not there there's a whole lot that
would have to come in place to make that
more reliable but at the same time
you've got
um is it a tesla working on their
satellite network it's going to hit the
globe not tesla but
spacex yes spacex sorry yeah same
same ceo yeah that's right same same
twitter
same shenanigans that's right but yeah i
think it's going to be wireless and i
think it's going to allow bandwidth to
go so much faster
it'll be interesting to see how it
progresses over the years and what
changes what's uh what's really kind of
catching my my eye is this covid app
that we've got in ontario actually i
think it's across canada
for that randomly connects with
bluetooth
so that if you've walked near somebody
that has tested positive for covid you
get an alert that goes
hey you don't don't interact with that
person well no you get an alert that
says you recently interact with somebody
who's been tested
positive oh wow so this is happening all
in the back end on your device and
and so i was thinking about that going
this is just with bluetooth
is there a way to have almost like
hot spotting as you go with mobile
phones that would allow this
constant wireless network to be like
so interesting i mean a couple of things
come to mind jeff would you first
first of all when you start talking
about wireless i start thinking about
man that would be so expensive
but the interesting thing is that with
the progression of technology
and the the betterment of the underlying
infrastructure the cost to the end
consumers goes down
yeah so we're going to see that price go
down so
maybe my my smartphone and the ability
to connect to
five 6g internet is going to drop
and when that happens now all of a
sudden autonomous vehicles become
much more autonomous that's right
because they're internet connected
all the time with a high-speed internet
connection yeah
and and then we've got all these new new
technologies that can just open up
that's right and things like these apps
that that communicate but then
the second thing that comes to mind is
now you've got everybody calling big
brother
oh of course you're there to help yes
yes but where is the line where we say
okay well we want big brother to some
extent
i want google to be able to tell me if
an earthquake is going to hit
in california absolutely if i live in
california that's smart
and and so there comes a point where you
say okay well i'm gonna
i'm going to allow google to have access
to my
telemetry yeah but then how much trust
are you putting in this company
so so there's there's yeah there's there
are all these considerations
i think in general the human race uh
as a broad brushstroke so not everybody
but as a broad brushstroke
i think we're always going to go with
the times of advancement i mean you look
at when
as a whole as a whole yeah i mean you
look at when facebook came out and it
changed the way that we do
online permissions it used to be you had
to give permission to access your
information
yeah and with facebook they said no no
you need to give us you need to tell us
what you don't want us to share
and now and we're gonna and we're gonna
change that every six months exactly and
you're gonna have to
be on top of that because otherwise
you've basically opted in because you're
using our free platform
that's right and it's changed the
internet now everybody does that where
it's like you tell us what you don't
want us to share
you tell us what you don't want us to
have access to and i think in general
most people
again general broad brushstroke most
people are like you know what
it's the convenience of it i'll deal
with it and they just
they they seem to want to ignore it
that's my sense of thing so i think
if we get to that point where it's like
all of that information is just kind of
bouncing between phones i don't know if
too many people are gonna care
it's gonna be interesting so i i've
often been of the mindset where
it's like i don't do anything that i
would be a afraid for somebody to know
about
right but there's also
like identity theft and and tracking and
and the ability for you know the big
brother
to see you know the trends of my
lifestyle
where i go where i buy my coffee at what
time
which then boils down to okay well now
you know where i'm going to be
right now all the data would say wow
that guy sits on the couch
a lot oh yeah
i practically get up and stop at
starbucks and
and sit at my desk for 10 hours ever
since
my day and then i'm at the studio
working work and work yeah
yeah yeah anyway didn't want to take us
on a tangent what are your thoughts i
mean it's it's an interesting discussion
i mean because this
is it's a transition that is happening
and is going to happen and i think
the pandemic has also kind of pushed us
to need
change in regulations in the
infrastructure
and in the technologies that are there
and so
you know how is that going to impact us
as a society
as as people as individuals and and
you know what are what are your thoughts
comment below it's a good discussion to
have with the community
oh for sure absolutely it is
anything new as far as tech goes jeff
for the first time in like 12 years i
bought a laptop
you did i finally bought a laptop he's
bought
a laptop phone i know when everybody
else is like ah we don't want pcs
anymore
and finally jeff is like okay i'm gonna
buy a laptop i
i know it sounds stupid that like i just
bought a laptop but i've
the the laptop that i bought last was
and i have kept that thing on life
support for as long as i possibly could
i'll say because i it's like it you know
windows got too clunky so i put linux on
it
then it started to not be able to handle
the linux so i put a downgraded like
lite version of linux and and i just but
now it's at the point where it just
doesn't want to start up
it's dead but i i for some reason i have
this weird mentality where it's like
i want to get as much as i can out of my
tech as possible sure
and you know why just put more e-waste
out there and i know that there's ways
to recycle and whatnot but it's like if
i can
which has become progressively more
difficult now as well
i i've got e-waste in my house from six
months ago i can't get rid of because of
coved yeah
it's like i don't have covid but i want
to get rid of it
top so really really tough yeah it is so
yeah that's
i bought a laptop very cool yeah and
thinking about laptops and
and also the progression of internet
connectivity and the ability to remote
in on things
the way that my paradigm has shifted
is that i've taken a different approach
i imagine you've probably bought a
reasonably powerful laptop
yeah that's a middle of the road it's an
i7 okay
uh 12 gigs of ram i think middle of the
road
middle of the road oh yeah yeah yeah
it's an i7 with
hyper threading and eight cores and
12 gigs of ram and okay
i wanted to get like you know it's got
to last you
exactly i wanted something like if i buy
a laptop every 13 years
sure lucky 13.
so how is the paradigm shifted for me
well for me
jeff it's a two hundred dollar pine book
i see and i find a problem to go that
way super sleek
right like look at that if i if i hold
that just right it disappears
yeah pretty much you can't see it um and
what i do with this is i tap into that
new style of infrastructure so i have a
very very powerful desktop pc
that's right yeah and i access it from
this laptop so anywhere that i
am i'm able to bring up davinci resolve
video editing
yeah and working with the power of an i9
9900k with
64 gigs of ram from a pine book pro
yeah so on the screen it feels like i'm
working on an i9
but meanwhile it's this lightweight 200
linux kit that's powered by an arm
processor and i
wanted to go that route simply because
i've been drooling over
those since they came out but for
what i need to use it for it's just not
powerful enough
um and this is it like so that's why i
use it to
remotely connect into my more powerful
devices
i don't have a more powerful device so
so it's just a change in the paradigm
it's just shifting the paradigm and
realizing that
and and then using single board
computers so i've got raspberry pi's and
odroid xu4s i've got lots of those
because those are probably my favorite
board as far as like the universal
debian server goes yeah with usb 3 and
and everything else um and and then
accessing them from there
and and i've got access to as many
systems as i have
i'll tell you what i'll trade in my
laptop and i'll get a pine book if you
let me access your own name
yeah and i yeah perfect
it's a win-win but see when my internet
goes down now i've lost everything yeah
i am i'm a fish out of water i don't
know like what do i do
when i have no internet connectivity
because now from my pine book i can't do
anything that's when you go
darn it jeff's so much better than me
jeff can i borrow your laptop
good times for me i've been
i've been teaching myself how
to use a 3d printer and also it's
arrived
well no well this is the thing is is
my my experiment
is i want to know if i were to
get a 3d printer is it going to
be so onerous for me to learn how to use
it
that it becomes another one of those
technologies that i purchase and then
never use
right because we fall into that that's
right a cool tech comes out and you want
it
and you buy it and then it's too hard to
learn and you don't have time and it
just sits on a shelf somewhere
and then it becomes obsolete yes so i've
taken a different approach and said okay
i'm going to learn how to 3d print first
okay and then i'm going to
make that decision so yes working with
design very cool so i use a tool
at tinkercad.com which is made by the
autodesk folks
and it allows me to use my
web browser to do 3d designs
cool so what ideas have you come up with
so my original ideas
are very very basic jeff as you can
imagine i mean i'm just learning
the ropes but so so
and i mentioned this two weeks ago when
you were here that i was going to do
this and i've done it
is that uh in my laundry room
i wanted a place to hang face masks
because
we have we've got three kids at home yes
and we all have
five or more of these i think i've got
like 10 of them myself because i'm
working in the field and the kids each
have five yeah face masks
but we bought the washable ones
and you don't want to put them through
the dryer so
right i want to make a rack for them so
i've designed i haven't printed because
i don't have a 3d printer
but this was the experiment can i design
the the idea that comes to mind which is
a
half inch piece of pvc pipe hanging in
the unfinished laundry room so i've got
access to the rafters i can just screw
right into them
and so i designed the um the mech
well the mechanism the plates to put the
half inch pvc up on the ceiling okay
hanging
and the hooks that are going to hook
onto that to allow us to hang as many
masks as we
want very cool so it is kind of cool so
it feels like something that
i hey i'm i'm actually designing i'm
actually creating
based on a need based on something that
i probably couldn't just walk into a
hardware store and buy
and probably doing it a lot cheaper
there's the cost of a 3d printer
but as bp9 mentioned in on on the
discord earlier today
the the fact is is that even though
there's an investment in the 3d printer
which is pretty cheap these days
you can go to our website category5.tv
click on shop you'll see an ender 3 v2
there
and they're not very expensive so the
the
initial hurdle of like the investment
is there but fairly quickly as
you design and print things you're going
to make that back
of course that's the idea yeah and that
makes sense i'm really seeing that as i
l as i look at things in online shopping
and think could i this is the challenge
that i've given myself
could i create that myself with a 3d
printer
and then i start looking at okay well
that thing
would cost me 20 and i could print it
for 20 cents
right so how quickly could i make that
back
it's an interesting experiment but but
i've proven to myself that
one i can design things i can take my
ideas
very very basic right now folks you can
see the designs that i've done
at thingiverse.com
ball nerd you can see my designs but
you'll see the hooks that i made and the
the mounting apparatus for it and then
i've also
taken it one step further and i've taken
other people's designs because you can
get onto thingiverse.com
you can find things that are close to
what you want
then load them into your software in my
case
tinkercad for now and uh and yeah tweak
it
modify it change it make it so that it
suits your purpose
very cool it is kind of cool so i'm at
that point i think where it's like
yeah i can i can do this so now when i
do make that investment when i get the
3d printer and i and i
set that up and and i'm ready to print
i'm ready to print i have designs
i've proven that i can design and uh and
i'm good to go
i like that interesting right so tinker
tinkercad.com is the software that i'm
using
for now it's probably rudimentary in
so many ways but it's really really easy
for me to get my feet wet when it comes
to
3d printing you got to start somewhere
and then i talk with boleknowski from
ameridroid and he's telling me about
how he programs 3d designs
he uses software that is so much more
sophisticated than what i'm
i'm doing through my web browser right
and is able to actually tweak things by
adjusting numbers
in the in the program and it that is but
that's why he's able to now
he's able to do things that i can only i
can imagine but i
i'm not capable of yet right right
that was a cool guy yeah oh yeah
thingiverse.com
baldnerd check out my designs we've got
to take a really quick break uh when we
come back
jeff and i are going to have a
discussion about two-factor multi-factor
authentication
for those of you who are wondering hey
what is this thing that
my service provider keeps telling me i
should activate on my
login we're going to have a quick chat
about about why you might actually want
to consider
setting up two-factor authentication
stick around
[Music]
welcome back everybody just to note if
you
are a participant in the category 5 tv
coffee break it's a community time to
get
together and have a chat and we try to
do it
every sunday and and we do that
faithfully now this
coming sunday uh unfortunately it is
um it's cancelled so there will not be
a category 5 community coffee break this
coming sunday but
watch the website we'll be updating the
calendar there
the schedule so that you know exactly
when the next one is
which will be a week from this coming
sunday so just keep that in mind if
you're planning to be there this coming
sunday there will not be
a coffee break you can still make coffee
though oh that's okay please do
yeah pour me a coffee folks that's right
in this quick in this quick discussion
uh we we want to help you to understand
two-factor authentication what it is and
why it's critical
critical and uh why it's not actually
as complicated as it sounds right
so we all know this is
robbie hi uh so robbie what's your
password
my password jeff should i really tell
you yeah you have to
winston 2075 really really easy for me
to remember because winston is the name
of my beloved cat
who left us a year ago i remember
winston he was a good cat
uh but i don't get the 2075. 2075 well
that clearly jeff
is the uh the year of the linux desktop
oh clear
clearly oh clearly oh burn
[Laughter]
well i guess that makes perfect sense uh
okay so
now that uh you know our viewers of the
show
you and i we all know each other um
if we kind of walked uh down the street
we see each other
i would say hey uh i'm robbie what
yeah yeah yeah that's am the bald nerd
and uh
you'd say um i don't think so and i'd
say but really i am
my password is winston 2075.
uh which obviously is correct right yeah
um
but know this but you still don't
believe
that i'm robbie so uh there's one thing
that i didn't think of and that's the
fact that you know what robbie
looks like and you know that
clearly i'm not him
i couldn't grow a beard like that if i
tried
when you sign into your online account
you've got typically a username and a
password right
so that's basically so that the server
can tell that it is you that is logging
in
right your username is often something
that is
publicly accessible so that could be
your email address or
in my case like it could be baldnerd
right
so that username is not something that
is a security factor whatsoever of
course anyone can get that so
um anyone who knows your password
can say okay well my username is
baldnerd and my password is
winston2075 right so now they can access
your account because
those are the only factors that you have
basically just the password right
the plot thickens if you've got the same
password on other services as well which
so many people do
don't do that yeah and that's why we say
do not have the same password on other
services because
if you get compromised on one you're now
compromised on other
but on others but the other thing is
that let's say they're
able to get into your email yes
something like that
right so now all of a sudden uh
they can go on to other sites your
online banking and things like that and
they can click on forgot password
and they're going to be able to reset
your password and gain access to those
services as well
so with the username and password
combination
the server itself so the connecting
server whether it's like
your online banking or twitter or
facebook or whatever it is you're
logging
into it has no way of actually verifying
that the person who's logging in
is in fact you right
they know the username and password and
so they're
given access right so two-factor
authentication
sometimes called multi-factor
authentication uh it can be
intimidating it can sound kind of
complicated but
really it's just a way for the online
server to recognize
that when uh when someone is logging in
as you that it is in fact
you you right um so the server is able
to say
yeah that's the right password but i
know robbie and you're not him right
okay so then how do we do that and
really it comes down to that the easiest
way
is something like this something you
already own
your smartphone right how many of us
have a smartphone sitting in our pocket
right now
exactly you might be watching the show
on your smartphone
you've got it on you all the time that's
right that is probably my wife's biggest
complaint about me
is that it's literally on me all the
time but that's convenient when it comes
to this
absolutely it is because even though
somebody might be able to obtain your
password
and your email because that's not really
impossible
it's a lot harder and less likely that
they're going to have physical access
to your phone so with two-factor
authentication enabled
once you enter your password uh and your
login for the account
you'll be uh prompted to obtain and
enter a code from your phone it could
come in through text or
you know maybe through an app whatever
but you know your phone becomes that
second factor in the authentication
process
which makes it two-factor authentication
so it's not really as complicated as it
sounds online services
um such as google drive gmail is
is part of that we we talk about amazon
and aws
that's right twitter facebook your
online banking
they all support multi-factor
authentication so
you want to look online and check your
settings and see if you can set that up
and
if you're having trouble finding the way
to set up multi-factor authentication
just reach out to the service provider
and they'll be able to give you help
yes it's a really like it's not the
end-all be-all
solution but it's an excellent way for
you to better secure your account so
that as
somebody else tries to access your
account with your username and password
if they ever
get it from a phishing scam or by a man
in the middle attack or something
along those lines well they're not going
to be able to access your account
because they don't have your phone
yeah that's right it's a really really
smart thing to have and
one of the things uh because i've run
into the two-factor authentication
with my kids yeah um
when we upgrade our phones we'll hand
our old phones to them it's
their gaming device their whatever but
because there's no longer a phone number
attached to it
sometimes with some of their services
every once in a while it's going to want
a phone number and so for the longest
time i was giving them
my cell phone so i'll be at work and all
sudden i get a blue
and it's you're trying to log in here's
your code and it was like
i got to call one of them right now
obviously you know you have to
look for the services that you're going
to enable
this road that i'm about to mention but
i found a service
like an application that gives you a a
digital phone number
where it will then come through to your
phone even though you don't actually
have cell phone service
so you don't i might like my kids don't
have a physical phone number
but they have a service on their phones
sms yeah so they can get text messages
to a phone number so now they can put in
their own two-factor
authentication right now if you're gonna
go down that road because maybe you
don't have a phone but you've just got a
tablet or something
if you go down that road make sure that
what you're using
is a trusted source because otherwise
an untrusted source is going to have
that number yeah they might be able to
do a man in the middle on your side
that's right
and you don't want to do that so you
want to pay attention to the sources you
use
and in our case uh it was magicjack
okay because you can get a magicjack
phone number for free
yeah a u.s number so that's what we used
oh neat
yeah magicjack is trustworthy we've been
using them for
gosh 15 years now wow so cool you know
now my kids have the magicjack app and
they put a phone number in and
interesting okay so i've taken a
different approach and i use the google
authenticator app
okay which one the app wrote yeah and so
with that app it uses what's called otp
or one-time
password so when i log into any of my
two-factor authentication enabled
services
it then prompts me for my multi-factor
authentication code
my otp so then i bring up the app and it
shows me a one-time password that i now
need to enter
into that service in order to access it
which has the same effect of okay well i
don't need to have
them texting me right i don't have to
worry about that man in the middle
attack there's so many different ways to
set up two-factor
it really is but really what it boils
down to is just the fact that
you know somebody is not going to have
access to the sms messages going to your
child
somebody's not going to have access to
my phone with that
authenticator app so it's just finding
one that works for you
and setting it up so that you've got uh
that multi-factor authentication so that
you're protected
because really i mean these days wow
it's incredible how many phishing scams
are out there
yeah i get emails just to put it into
perspective i get emails
that appear to be from my boss okay
from my employer with
links to click here and and
enter my info and these are called
spear phishing scams so these are
some hacker or somebody is trying to
gain access to my account
and so they've researched me and they've
learned about me and they've learned
about
who my employer is to the point where
they can now
send me an email masking and pretending
to be
my employer and saying hey click here so
when you put that into the perspective
of an auto shop
and the service technician gets an email
from the boss
and maybe is not as um
security conscious well security
conscious but also just
like i am i know what to look
for yeah that's fair you know so i i
know
okay this is definitely not coming from
my boss and i'll look at the email
headers and things like that because i
understand them
yeah but what if
that and just using the shop technician
as an example
okay what if they fell for it
what if the accountant opened that fake
invoice that gave them access
to the username and password for their
email again they can use that
the hacker can use that to then gain
access to other accounts because they
can do forgot password
that's right or they can send email as
that user and and take it even further
and this is how ransomware happens and
things like that
that's true so spear phishing is where
they learn enough about you or your
company to be able to make it look
completely legitimate and that happens a
lot so
what happens if that shop technician
falls for it and gives out their
username and password
well if they have two-factor
authentication enabled on their accounts
yes the spear phishing attack has now
got your username and password however
when they try to access it
it's going to prompt for that two-factor
authentication so in the sms
example the shop technician is now going
to receive a text
yes and they're going to say well i
didn't request a login that's right
that's weird um or in my case
it's never even going to i'm never going
to know about it because they're just
going to be
notified that they need to enter their
one-time password that's right
and they're not going to have it because
they don't have my phone that's right
so some food for thought when you're
thinking about two-factor authentication
multi-factor
authentication just set it up it is
absolutely required these days you got
to stay safe
and really there's no excuse not to
really isn't
we all have a phone in our pocket jeff
that's true and if you don't
for some crazy reason there's that
there's an app for that
there are ways you'll find it out and
that's why i say talk to your service
provider because they will tell you
um the various ways that you can set up
multi-factor authentication
yeah it's true very good all right we've
got to head over to the newsroom here
is becca here's what's coming up in the
category 5 dot tv newsroom
an update to adobe's lightroom app for
ios has
wiped user photos with no chance to
recover
wsl-2 is now available for windows 10
1903 and 1909 users
the world's fastest internet can
download the entire netflix library
in less than a second hands-free driving
could be made legal on uk roads by
spring
and a hyperloop may be coming to alberta
stick around the full details and this
week's crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5 dot tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight
linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
the latest update from adobe's lightroom
app for ios
inadvertently wiped users photos and
presets that were not already synced to
the cloud
and adobe has confirmed that there is no
way to get them back
the issue first cropped up on the
photoshop feedback forums last week when
the lightroom app
on ios was updated to version 5.4
a user posted asking why all of his
photos presets and watermark data had
been removed after updating to the most
recent version through the ios
app store this was followed by replies
from other users saying that the same
thing happened to them
whether or not they were subscription
based or free
one user posted to reddit's r slash
lightroom subrevit
reddit saying that they had lost two
plus years of edits
after the update having spent more than
four
hours speaking with adobe customer
service they report that adobe finally
said
the issue has no fix and that these lost
photos are unrecoverable adobe provided
nothing more than an apology
confirming the user's claims adobe
officially confirmed the issue on
wednesday
explaining that customers who updated to
lightroom 5.4 on iphone and ipad
may be missing photos and presets that
those photos and presets are not
recoverable
and that they sincerely apologize to
users who have been affected by the
issue
version 5.4.1 has already been released
fixing the issue but it can do nothing
about the lost data
this serves as a strong reminder for
photographers to always have a backup of
your images in multiple places
so you're never subject to a single
point of failure mistakes like this
happen
even at some of the world's largest
companies
microsoft is easing the requirement for
windows subsystem for linux 2.
instead of only working on windows 10
2004 or higher
wsl is also now available for windows 10
and 1909 users windows 10 users who
wanted to work with the new windows
subsystem for linux version 2
needed to have the latest feature update
for windows the windows 10 may 2020
update
aka windows 10 20 2004
but on august 20th microsoft made a
surprise announcement
wsl-2 has been backported to windows 10
1903 and 1909 as well
as it turns out microsoft has been
working on bringing sl2
sorry wsl-2 to 1903 and 1909 for the
last few months
they said in a blog post that the goal
is for the back port to make wsl2
available to more windows users
the back port will be for x64
systems only those using arm 64 still
need to use windows 10
2004 to get wsl2 wsl-2
is a much reworked version of the
original wsl
it changes how linux distributions
interact with windows
as officials noted in today's post each
linux
linux distribution running on windows 10
can run as wsl1 or wsl2
and can be switched at any time
according to microsoft wsl2 provides a
full linux kernel built into wsl2
improved system call support for all
linux apps including docker fuse
rsync and more and improved file system
and
performance to get wsl 2
for 1903 and 1909 users simply need to
check for updates via windows update
a team of university college london
engineers have set a new world record
internet
speed and you won't believe how fast it
is
they've been able to achieve internet
transmission speed a
fifth faster than the previous record
the
the research team led by dr lydia
galdino achieved a data transmission
rate of 178
terabits a second that's 178 million
megabits a second compare that to the 50
megabits you're getting at home
at 178 terabits per second it would be
possible to download the entire netflix
library in less than a second
the record which is double the capacity
of any system currently in use worldwide
was achieved by transmitting data
through a much wider range of colors of
light
or wavelengths than is typically used in
optical fiber
current infrastructure uses a limited
spectrum bandwidth of
4.5 terahertz with 9 terahertz
commercial bandwidth systems entering
the market
whereas the researchers used a bandwidth
of 16.8 terahertz
to do this researchers combine different
amplifier technologies needed to boost
the signal power over the wider
bandwidth and maximize
speed by developing new patterns of
signal combinations that make best use
of the phase
brightness and polarization properties
of the light
in this way they were able to manipulate
the properties of each individual
wavelength
a huge benefit of the technique is that
it can be deployed on
already existing infrastructure by
simply upgrading the amplifiers that are
located
on optical fiber routes at 40 to 100
kilometer intervals
it would be shockingly cheap to perform
such an upgrade
upgrading an amplifier would cost around
21 000 or about 420 dollars per
kilometer
if we upgrade it every 50 kilometers
compare that to installing new optical
fibers which can in urban areas cost up
to three-fourths of a million dollars
per kilometer lead author dr galdiner
dino a lecturer at ucl and a royal
academy of engineering research fellow
said while current state-of-the-art
cloud data center interconnections are
capable of transporting up to 35
terabits a second
we are working with new technologies
that utilize more efficiently the
existing infrastructure
making better use of optical fiber
bandwidth and enabling a world record
transmission rate of 178 terabits
a second the speed achieved is close to
the theoretical limit of data
transmission set out by american
mathematician
claude shannon in 1949. i want that
bandwidth
right install that at my studio you know
it was it's
it's interesting i mean there's two
things that kind of jumped out at me
about this story the first one
uh what becca was kind of getting to
about um
24 000 i think for 50 kilometers
or per kilometer whatever it was um to
to do the math was there yeah it was
there we've butchered it so far but
that's right but significantly cheaper
significant make this upgrade
than to lay new fiber well yeah and so
interestingly enough
uh this summer or i guess this spring
when when
covid kind of brought the world to its
knees uh
at our my church we were looking to
stream
uh once we started getting back into the
building we had
really slow internet like half meg
upload ouch
yeah right so we reached out to
different isps and we said okay
what would it take to run you know first
we looked into fiverr then we looked
into dsl then we looked into
cable the one kilometer actually i think
it's 0.8 kilometers from
the junction box at the corner to where
our property line was and every quote we
got was
six figures or more yeah and i'm like
we're talking a kilometer
and then i'm hearing this and i'm like
this is amazing but at the same time the
fact that it's utilizing
light and i mean here we are in a studio
with light bulbs all around us now
they're all led
so that's not quite the same thing but
how neat would it be
if this technology could be advanced to
the point where we're getting our
internet off a light bulb
if it's if it's through like how neat
would that be
like it's gotta be a little more refined
than that i mean
fiber optics are i i agree but you look
at where the internet was 25 years ago
yeah like imagine 15 years from now you
flick on a light and boom
like oh jeff your predicament that you
have at your church or that you had i
presumably you've found a solution at
least to get your body
oh okay so you're wireless so you're
getting about 20 megs
per second uh 20 up 45 down yeah okay
so that's not bad that's pretty good no
we could stream that's good expensive
yeah wouldn't it be cheaper this is just
a crazy thought but
buy the property on the corner that's
near the junction box
buy the property and have them run
a six foot length from the junction box
to a little tiny tower and put a
ubiquity antenna on that
that is pointed at your church that has
like air fiber you know which is like
gigabit a second you know what's funny
we have we actually have
our sign there that we rent from the
person who owns the property
so put a little ubiquity antenna on top
of your sign
connect it to the fiber and you'd have
to have like some kind of a box that
powers everything and
keeps it secure from it's got a powered
light anyway well there you go
so now put it free so then beam that
beam that to your church you can get
gigabit per second internet
for the cost of a six foot length of
fiber run i actually think the box is
like a foot
from the pole well there you go that's
your answer
where were you six months ago i don't
know nobody asked me
i mean this is what came to me just now
but hey
lots of more exciting stuff coming up
hands-free driving could actually be
made
legal in the uk i mean like legit wow
hands-free driving
uh also speaking of transportation
a hyperloop could be coming to canada
what in alberta
oh becca's got these stories coming up
plus robert's here with the crypto
corner don't go
[Music]
anywhere
welcome to the world of cryptos and
welcome to the crypto corner
now as you probably know that there is
not one boring week in kryptos
but let's take a look at it where are we
standing today
so if we look at our favorite website
which is uh coin gecko
and we see that the market is going down
a little bit since yesterday two and a
half percent
uh we're 373 billion uh us dollar
uh bitcoin went down uh since last week
by six point four percent it resolved by
seven days
we've got the usual picture a lot of
coins going up over
i mean in this case 145.2
in a week and on the downside well this
time it'll be a little bit more than uh
last week but nevertheless i mean i know
that
everybody of us goes and he listens to
um
so-called influencers people that
pretend they know what they're doing and
and well and recommend you this coin or
that coin and
you see that suddenly that coin went
through the roof and you say hey
why am i not in this year well it's very
simple these people are all
are good guessers they do some research
but there's not really one expert that
can tell you where the market is going
or what's happening
you are reliant you have to be relying
on yourself so you have to do your
the research yourself it's good as i
mentioned to you last time
to listen to other people and see what
their thoughts are
but at the end it's you you have to do
the research
and i promise you today i would show you
how to do research
so the first thing and i've got i
prepared it's a small
uh uh image here the first thing you
have to do is you go on coingecko.com
this is
dot and because they're the best they
have got the most information and their
information is fairly reliable
so this is where i would start and then
you select the coin that you heard
somebody shilling recommending whatever
and let's take here for example
algorand you heard that that coin is a
very good one so
you get a lot of information already on
this page here
like uh on the on the right hand side
you get market information price
information
that is very valuable when was the
all-time high
the all-time low
on the left hand side you've got the
usual chart of what's
happening the market volume but here
you go you see some goodies so you see
the website
so first thing i would do is i would go
on to the website and see
what the website is telling you you
don't have to understand the technical
details
most people don't understand it but just
see whether that makes sense whether you
would like to put money into somebody
that is promising you something that
you're interested in
so that's the first thing i would do
just browse around the website
they're all the same there's they're all
very flat
you don't see many different things in
here that might go into some technical
things
but you can ignore that at the beginning
next one is the community
so that's where other people are voicing
their opinion so you go into reddit
um and see what's happening there
so here we see that something was posted
23 hours ago
um this one here okay this is an ad
one day ago one day ago so it seems
fairly populated so things are happening
here
next one is twitter twitter is the
central point
of communication in the crypto industry
so twitter
is a must you have to go in here and
just check
what the official algorithm team in this
case are grant
is doing so they published something 18
hours ago
then here 23 hours ago then august 22nd
so that's
uh now three days ago so they're pretty
uh active in the market here's an
interview just listen to what that
interview
uh has to what was discussed in that
so that's a good indicator next one is
telegram telegram
is where people like you and i are uh
talking and um so just open
the download the telegram telegram app
and um and just look into what other
people are saying
i mean you see a lot of people in there
with some stupid opinions i mean you see
in this case there are 9200 members in
are online that's a good indicator
and just just browse to that uh telegram
and this card
is similar to telegram and a little bit
more complicated a little more complex
last but not least click on github
because that's where you see the
programmers uh working doing their job
and you see here somebody updated a file
one hour ago 10 hours ago so you see
they are very active also in what
they're doing
now this will give you the basis of the
information
on um on how you can take a decision
whether that's a coin that you would
like to
invest money in similar things you do
with cars similar thing you with a house
you don't buy a house if i tell you
you have to go in 43rd road you don't go
there and just buy a house
you do your research the same way and so
do the same thing here
it's very simple it's much easier than
in the traditional stock market
as you can see there are only few areas
where you can go and
really do something so yeah that's it
for me to this week so
i hope you liked it i hope you learned
something i wish you
another fantastic week and hope to see
you next week again thank you
bye thanks robert just a reminder that
we're not providing any financial advice
here just sharing
what's happening in the cryptocurrency
market always remember that the
cryptocurrency market
is always changing it's always volatile
so only invest what you can afford to
lose
now back to becca thank you robbie the
uk
government has said hands-free driving
could be legal by spring of next year
the department for transport has issued
a call for evidence into automated lane
keeping systems
such technology controls a car's
movements and can keep it in lane for
extended periods
although drivers need to be ready to
take back control
the society of motor manufacturers and
traders claims it could reduce the
number of accidents
the technology for a car to steer itself
and stay in lane even around curves
already exists in some modern cars but
the law says that drivers must
remain alert and ready to take over
instantly
tesla's so-called autopilot is one
well-known example
it is considered level two on the five
defined levels of self-driving cars
the next step level three would not need
the driver's attention at
all times and in theory the driver could
do other things
such as check email or even watch a
movie
until the car prompts them to take over
again introducing those systems would
require
changes to current legal framework
something the dft
says it is now considering while the
technology has been approved by the
united nations economic commission for
europe
it is limited to traffic jams at speeds
of up to 37 miles per hour
the change could give the go-ahead for
speeds of up to 70 miles per hour in the
uk
potentially making long stretches of
tedious motorway driving
a thing of the past the uk government
wants to hear from people within the
motoring industry to decide
how to safely implement the technology
the consultation closes
on october 27th the government in
alberta canada
is backing the development of a
high-speed hyperloop
between edmonton and calgary albertans
could be among the first canadians to
travel by high-speed pods between cities
after the government of alberta signed
an agreement with canadian
transportation tech company transpod
to develop and test a high-speed
hyperloop between edmonton
and calgary though no financial
commitments have been made by the
government alberta will support
toronto-based transport
by sharing data identifying land and
participating in discussions with
potential investors
according to the news release the
project involves a short-term
feasibility study ending in 2022
research and development ending in 2024
test track construction in use between
2024 and 2027
and the construction of a line between
downtown edmonton
and downtown calgary to begin in 2025.
there are a handful of companies
developing this technology
which allows pods to travel at high
speeds in a low pressure
tube with various projects in the early
stages around the world
this would be the first such project in
canada
the vehicles would travel up to a
thousand kilometers per
hour with an average speed of between
400 and 600 kilometers
per hour alberta's hyperloop line would
stop at the edmonton and calgary
airports as well as red deer he said
and the total moving time of the full
line would be a half hour
the system would be powered by a mix of
solar panels and electricity
and would mainly transport passengers in
time-sensitive goods like
mail or e-commerce products the 6
billion to 10 billion
project would create jobs in a province
where many oil and gas workers have lost
their jobs in recent years
and position alberta as a potential hub
for technology
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom don't forget to like and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.comcategory5
from the category 5 dot tv newsroom i'm
becca ferguson
[Music]
well thanks for being here with us again
this week everybody just a reminder
there is no
category 5 community coffee break this
sunday as previously scheduled
and uh it's been great having you all
here yeah
nice having you here again jeff you know
what i feel like i should probably just
start coming back
yeah yeah and we're figuring out how
things
can work yeah through this current time
jeff and i are kind of physically
uh distant from one another we've got
about six feet between
um between our heads
and if you see him leaning in you see me
leaning back and
we do our best and and try to remain
socially distant here at the studio and
wear our masks when uh when we can't be
yeah
um and and figuring out kind of the
technology and how everything
is going to work and i think you're
going to find that this week things are
looking
better than ever certainly they're
sounding better than ever and
that is largely to do with ameridroid's
easy portal having been installed in the
studio now we're able to get
the cables between the studio and the
bridge and so our audio receivers for
our microphones are now
here in the studio with us rather than
going through
a steel studded wall which was causing
some interference and some dropouts here
and there
occasionally throughout the show so
that's why things are sounding a lot
better
as far as looking a lot better we're
doing uh well our lighting is now
almost set up so we're about fifty
percent there um
so what we are seeing now is a lot
different than what you've seen in the
past those of you who support us
on patreon or on kickstarter you already
know kind of
how things are looking here in the
studio but beyond the camera
we're seeing lights mount well you can
see all the shadows yeah
notice how many shadows there are of my
arm so there are lights everywhere
and we do have some some soft boxes
mounted on the ceiling and and so
lighting in here is
significantly better five six seven
seven lights and then that weird
u-shaped thing
the weird u-shape oh with that thing
yeah
and it's actually got an led uh point
down on it that's actually reflecting
back
to us so that's what's giving us that
there was a natural light
and we've been able to turn off the
fluorescent lighting
here yes which is that's a big
difference here so
when you think about um lighting uh a
production studio
um having like sunlight balanced
white clean light is very very important
yes um so
when we first moved in here of course
we're using the the built-in
lighting which is like 3500 kelvin so
it's like really really poor lighting
for video yeah
um and now we're starting to starting to
be a little bit better so
so where are we at with that um really i
mean
jeff is looking around and saying oh
well why haven't you turned on that
light why haven't you turned on that
light
and that's because the ones that are
mounted um that are going to be dmx
controlled
haven't yet been wired in and that's
because we're still waiting on hardware
they're still um mount um electrical
hardware that has to come in right
because things take a while to arrive
it's true i love the boom like you can't
see it but there's a boom for the
overhead camera for product reviews yeah
we've got a jib crane
that has an overhead camera that we can
move around
it's pretty cool so that's going to give
us that overhead when we're doing
unboxings and
product demonstrations and things so you
can see from above
and that's going to be quite a bit
better than anything we've ever had so
that's going to be cool so speaking you
mentioned kickstarters
where's the tens machine
i've had three people say this week i'm
sourcing one that goes up to 11.
yeah i three people have approached me
this week they're like when when are you
doing that labor thing oh yes
yeah so i i think i think
my wife is starting to like poke people
and be like hey you need to ask jeff
all right because i'm trying to make
everybody forget about it i'm going to
talk to
to your wife no you know what she's busy
don't worry about it but i need to talk
to her about it and you know why
is because we have to be socially
distant it's such a weird time
so where we we could just put this off
it's okay do you really think i'm gonna
give him the controller and say okay
jeff
shock yourself i i can make it with a
really long cable
i can make it look really good on camera
i'm going to connect it to a raspberry
pi gpio and give you access to be able
to control it
bp9 is going to be like
yes crank that up to 11.
oh i can't wait we're going to have a
lot of fun folks we've got a lot planned
and
everything in our world has been kind of
put on hold but
throughout this process we've been doing
our level best to
make sure that we we're still bringing
you a show when we can as best as we can
still trying to um to bring you good
content every single week
and and really when when it comes down
to it when
when things all come together and
they're coming together
it's gonna be like a sigh of relief and
now
let's broadcast let's do the show the
way the show
is meant to be from studio e it's going
to be incredible and i can't wait
and i'm thinking hey with season 14
coming it's going to be a really cool
clean slate to say okay season 14
let's hit it yes hit the ground running
it's gonna be a lot of fun you know we
need to do
we need to stream like an unreal
tournament party
i'm really looking forward to that and
and maybe we'll do that with the tens
machine
maybe that'll be something that any time
any time
you you anytime you get a head shot on
me
i'm pushing the button i'm just gonna
camp in the corner
he's not there he's not there whenever i
see the redeemer flying around with
jeff's
name above it i'm just gonna push the
button that takes
that's gonna be brilliant can't wait
good show been great having you here and
i look forward to seeing you again next
week take care everybody see ya
[Music]
you