[Applause]
[Music]
covering the week's top tech stores
with a slight linux bias if you enjoy
your weekly tech news with a slight
linux bias become part of our fleet
choose your rank at patreon.com category
5.
let's get into it the official.com
domain for pearl programming language
was hijacked last week
that's coming up but first oneplus
co-founder carl pay has revealed next to
nothing about his new company
but we'll tell you all about it carl
pay left the company last year and has
already announced the founding of a new
one
which he calls nothing yes you heard
that right
nothing though the company's first smart
devices are expected to be released in
the first half
of this year pay hasn't yet said what
they will be
nor which companies they might compete
with what he has said
is that nothing's mission is to remove
barriers between people and technology
to create a seamless digital future he
went on to say
we believe that the best technology is
beautiful yet natural and intuitive to
use
when sufficiently advanced it should
fade into the background and feel
like nothing in an interview with the
verge pay explains that plans for
nothing are to create numerous products
with the intention of gradually
accumulating accumulating
a uniquely branded intertwined and
here's the keyword
seamless internet of things pay says
right now the team is being built so we
want to focus on simpler categories
but as our team gains capabilities and
skills we want to start moving up
the ultimate vision of having everything
connected in a seamless way
that can only happen when you have
multiple categories of products that are
connected
in recent years one of the main
criticisms of oneplus
pays former company was that its
smartphones in particular
had seemingly become carbon copies of
phones released by its well-known
competitor
oppo there's a reason why a lot of
products on the market look quite
similar
pay says it's because they share a lot
of the same components and the same
building blocks end quote nothing on the
other hand will be using custom-made
components from the get-go so it won't
be re-labeling somebody else's products
the unique designs aren't merely
intended to be different for the sake of
being different however
the intention is for them to not be
noticeable at all
pay explains i kind of envision a grass
field with people having a picnic and
there's no screen
there's no laptop screen there's no
phone screen
there's no smart watch screen there's no
billboard screen
that's kind of the end state he does
admit though that it will likely take
several decades to get there
to a future where technology looks like
nothing
what would such futuristic technologies
entail are we talking holographic
screens
or ocular implants post your comments
below
what do you think could be on the
horizon from nothing one can only
imagine
but pay has a knack for building hype
that's for sure
he's given us just enough of a glimpse
of his vision to wet our appetites
get us talking but we're going to have
to wait and see if this will be much ado
about nothing so we got to talk about
nothing yeah
it's i i like the fact that he called it
uh and what could it mean well exactly
but i mean as as becca was
you know walking through the story you
start to understand that
nothing is more than just the name it's
the
it's the essence behind the it's
actually clever
yeah it is you know it's it's like what
do you need to make this happen
nothing because it's going to be so
seamless it's really it's no different
than uh elon musk and his boring company
yeah i think so it's like the name is
boring oh yes
it's for play on words yeah exactly so i
i
like that and i mean this is an
interesting concept uh to have
everything run
so seamlessly across multiple devices
it's not a new concept
it's been in sci-fi since the 80s right
yeah but what he's looking to do is
so interesting because everybody else
right now piecemeals
their internet of things so it's like oh
we'll connect with this we'll connect
that
but you have to do so much in the
background like if you have say an echo
from from amazon yeah it's like you have
to install the skill
and then it connects with that it's like
there's so much setup
it'd be neat to see how this all plays
out and i mean he says
what was it 20 to 30 years i don't think
it's going to be that long
i mean look how much technology has
changed oh sure
well you know what's going to happen is
we're going to see the initial
you know what what are the first devices
yeah for sure that we'll probably
see within the next couple of years and
and as we do we'll start to see the
vision that
uh that carl pay has for nothing
yeah that's gonna be just a funny play
on words for the
for the next while for sure but one day
this is going to be
it's like google when google first
started it's like it was such a silly
word
right but then now it's like synonymous
it's being used as a verb for searching
the internet
and it's so much more than just search
well and google's a great example
because there's so much going on
in the background with google yeah that
you don't know
yeah like if people knew truly how much
google was impacting their lives
and the background that goes on with
like the the search bots and the
different
algorithms and whatnot they would go oh
my goodness like there's
so much engaged here and so so google
help already has been doing this
a little bit but not to the point of it
being an assistance in life
yeah it's more so in assistance with the
internet
so it's going to be interesting to see
how this plays out but it does what i
mean
for me the one thing it brings to mind
is um privacy
if everything is so seamless to the
point that you don't even have to worry
about it because it just takes
care of itself is there a privacy
concern
and is there eventually going to be
pushback on that where people are going
hold on this is so seamless i don't
actually realize what it's doing
and so that's going to be an interesting
development over the years to see
where does that take us and is is it
crossing the line it's an interesting
point and and look back at this video
you know five years from now and say hey
jeff called it right
um because as companies develop
technologies that require
less and less user intervention to get
things like setup done and
and you mentioned the echo devices and
it's like it has become a very seamless
process i mean i bought a light that i
simply plugged in
and it showed up in my in my app and it
was like and
automatically connected and i could
start using voice commands to control it
because it's on the same wi-fi as my
echo device so it was able to pick it up
and detect it and
worked so but as
things get more and more easy from the
end user perspective
to set up and to use it does take away
our ability to understand the technology
but that's where
we're going to have to surpass that
point where we've crossed over into
now we no longer understand the
underlying technologies of the things
that we're using day-to-day
yeah we're already there but there is
that push back that's right
and so that's and that holds up
innovation and as innovation pushes
toward that
there is going to have to be something's
got to give yeah yeah for sure going to
be
we'll see we'll we'll tell you about
nothing later
that's right sorry we've got to wear our
masks because of a lockdown here in
ontario canada but
we are all smiles today that's true my
eyes are squinting
you have to look really closely at my
eyes all right becca
the official.com domain for the pearl
programming language was hijacked last
week
for the past 24 years pearl.com has been
used by veteran pearl contributor
tom christensen to provide information
about the pearl programming language
but the famed domain was suddenly taken
over by someone else
and promptly began distributing malware
as it turns out the domain was in fact
quietly quietly stolen last
september while registered with network
solutions
and on christmas day was transferred to
a registrar in china
since the party responsible for
hijacking the domain continued to point
the dns to the actual web server
it remained online and nobody appears to
have noticed
then a bit more than a month later
january 27th to be exact
pearl.com went down and was pointed to
an ip of a known malware distributor
while the pearl team says that there is
no news on the recovery of the domain
they're doing all they can
they've set up a temporary url to allow
users to access the site until they get
the domain back
which is the obvious hopeful outcome
they clearly weren't thinking of news
coverage when they created the subdomain
however
which is now pearl.com.pearl.org
to be clear that's pearl d-o-t-c-o-m
dot pearl.org for now stay clear of
pearl.com
entirely becca is absolutely bang on
correct there that you've got
to at this time avoid that.com
oh for sure like i ca i couldn't believe
they put that in the name like
pearl.com.pearl.org
just weren't thinking of us um the the
thing is you may think well i don't go
to pearl.com
i never bring up my browser and head on
over to pearl.com maybe you do maybe you
don't
a lot of us are pro programmers but
there is the fact
that a lot of us use perl and a lot of
us therefore use cpan
that's right and cpan is like an
installer archive
system for uh perl applications and
and if you use that it may be tapping
into
pearl.com in its back end so when you
think about that and you start to
realize oh my goodness
they have the power now to replace
legitimate packages with malware
yes so as i'm installing things with
cpan
well guess what it's not actually coming
from the officialperl.com it's coming
from some malware distributor who is
known
to be a malware distributor yes so then
we've got web projects and servers and
third-party projects that use those
resources
and that's a scary situation 100 really
can be
but the other side to this story i mean
you're looking at it from the
perspective of
a pearl programmer you know a user in
that regard
as a general consumer somebody who
i have my own websites sure i'm sitting
here going
this is a reminder that you want to make
sure that your account security for
your hosted web domain is secure
that you're using a reputable hosting
company that
uh your domain registration information
is you know secure so that these kind of
things don't
happen like how did they get access to
controlling the domain
i think you just got to keep a closer
eye on it like use nems linux and
sure and monitor your domain because i
don't think it really even comes down to
are they are you with a reputable
registrar because they were
right but the thing is i mean perl
they're all programmers
yeah they're people who know the
programming and the things yeah for sure
and they still this slid under the radar
and for a month
another entity owned their website and
they did it so seamlessly
so this is a to me it's a good reminder
pay attention to your websites if you
are
you know especially if you're you know
you say you're hosting a wordpress we
know how many times we've heard about
wordpress sites being you know hacked
and taken over
that's just this is a whole other level
absolutely it is this is
like if you're gonna host a website make
sure that this information you
know what's going on and it's protected
it's locked down
speaking of locked down that comes to
mind that if you register a domain
make sure with your registrar that you
lock it
because there's a little toggle that you
can flip there on your registrar that
says
lock this domain and what that means is
that if anyone
ever tries to compromise it either take
it over or transfer the ownership or
transfer the registrant profile
um it will require your intervention in
order to
allow that if it's an unlocked domain
and they get a hold of the
transfer the register and transfer code
they can conduct that registrant
transfer no problem that's right so
lock your domains yep please don't miss
the other stories we're following this
week
first did spam cop block your email this
past weekend
you're not alone plus elon musk has
augmented a monkey's brain with a
wireless implant so it can play
video games subscribe to our youtube
channel to make sure you catch the full
stories
from the category 5 tv newsroom i'm
becca ferguson
thanks for watching
[Music]
you