[Applause]
[Music]
covering the week's top tech stories
with the slight linux bias if you enjoy
your weekly tech news with a slight
linux bias
become part of our fleet choose your
rank at patreon.com
category5 let's get into it
microsoft has fixed a bizarre windows 10
error that's coming up
but first while a mario theme switch has
been announced we all hope for the
release of a new 4k
nintendo switch pro this year mario
themed news keeps flowing out of
nintendo as they continue celebrating
the 35th anniversary of super mario bros
which took place in september we've seen
the revisited nintendo game and watch
and now nintendo has announced the new
game
super mario 3d world and bowser's fury
which they promise is a bigger and
badder version of the game originally
released for the wii u
but our focus this week is on something
a little different
and a whole lot bigger we talked about
it way back on episode 604 in april 2019
but now it's ready the first ever super
nintendo world theme park is opening at
universal studios japan
on february 4th of this year a newly
released sneak peek video
tour by shigeru mayamoto creator of
mario donkey kong and the legend of
zelda
walks you right into the atrium of
princess peach's castle through a
portal-like
shimmering green pipe from there
mayamoto shows you how to use decorated
smart wristbands to collect
coins all throughout a colorful
life-size version of the legendary world
just as in the classic super mario bros
game
punching up on each question mark block
encountered along the way
will release the coin straight into your
wristband replete with a satisfying coin
collecting ding
this wearable wristband technology is
linked to your smartphone
and unlocks the interactive gameplay
experience of the park
combined with the augmented reality
experience of themed rides this promises
to be a magical experience for visitors
of all ages
one such adventure bowser's castle is
sure to delight with its heavy stone
walls
looming staircases burning wall sconces
dungeon-like doors
and an enormous statue of bowser in its
depths
which as rumor has it just might be
animated
here you'll find the entrance doors to
an augmented reality mario kart ride
called koopas challenge
where participants will be able to toss
shells and steer about the mushroom
kingdom
thomas garatti senior director
innovation and global executive producer
for mario kart explains
guests will put on their headset which
takes them through the mario kart
universe
to experience never-ending excitement
and thrills
chock-full of the iconic landscapes
pipes castles and the beloved creatures
and characters of the super mario world
this 580 million dollar project is part
of an effort by the kyoto-based games
company
to increase falling revenue by expanding
its franchises
the park was initially scheduled to open
back before the 2020
summer olympics in tokyo but both were
delayed due to the covet 19 pandemic
while they are doing augmented reality
what i found
really intriguing about this video is
that it appears like the park is all
physical recreations of the gameplay
which is totally awesome and i was
expecting a nintendo theme park to be
like
filled with screens and you know
nintendo gameplay and everything else
but it's literally taken the uh
like the mario theme and turned it into
a real life
park that you can walk through to the
point where one of my favorite parts
that were shown in this in this preview
was that
um at one point you shrink
like mario shrinks yeah yeah because the
though
all the surroundings become huge that's
right yeah triple in size
and it's like oh my goodness the effect
is so
cool like you want to bring your
smartphone and start taking some
pictures
now i wonder if there'll be some sort of
like you know hey you can't film this
for i don't know i doubt it no something
like this it's meant for kids
well that's meant for
it's meant for 80s kids boomers will say
yeah
[Laughter]
to take their zoomers with them
and uh and and show them what you know
it's pretty magical i i mean
i'm not a huge theme park person i mean
like i remember going to disney as a kid
yeah and i was like okay it's just
another
place for attractions and rides sure but
this is probably the first
theme based park that's legit theme
based yeah
um that i would probably go to
and simply because it is mario and and
the idea behind it
is mind-blowing like so the fact that
you can take
a video game and turn it into a place
and then they hit those elements
yeah it's so cool and and i like that
they've got
um that interactive component yeah with
hitting the coins and and
all that kind of stuff because it's not
just about going
and and experiencing it it's about
experiencing it
which takes it to another level we went
to lego world years ago yeah
and and that was fun you can go onto our
website and do a search for
for lego and category 5 tv if you want
to see it but we took our kids there and
it was a lot of fun and it kind of
reminded me of that where you're you're
walking into a world that is
just lego that's right and you're
walking into a world that is just
you are basically transported into these
video games that you and i grew up with
yeah it's so magical now what i can't
wait to find out is
who's the first person that's going to
slip on a banana peel
do they get away with saying oh part of
the experience don't sue us
the interesting thing about opening a
theme park
at the beginning of 2021 of course uh
you know like uh
japan you know last last i saw were
uh friday they were at about 8 000 cases
yeah and and so you know how are they
going to
do this uh two years ago when they first
announced
this theme park there there was no
pandemic in sight
right but i mean at this point the
capital has been put in to build it
and maybe that's it like it's ready yeah
and when everything is behind us
then okay we can all go but will people
go
regardless probably not like not
travelers but
locals well i mean we sure would we just
got stats
as long as there's social distancing and
safety sure is put into place which
there will be but look at the christmas
holidays here in canada
stats just came out that from was it
canada or ontario alone
4 000 people went to hawaii over the
christmas holidays
okay and that's in the midst of a global
pandemic so i can imagine
people people will people are going to
go oh no
okay so stay safe i'm i'm absolutely
certain that uh nintendo will
um and universal studios in general will
have
um safety precautions in position and be
following the rules and everything else
but
uh something definitely to look forward
to taking the kids to
uh when things are a little bit safer
for sure absolutely all right becca
future plans include the opening of
super nintendo world parks at universal
studios
in orlando florida hollywood california
and
singapore microsoft has fixed windows
10's 60 seconds self-destruct
after upgrading to windows 10 20 h2 with
the october 2020 update
some windows 10 users experienced a
bizarre windows 10
error without warning a prompt would
appear on their screen to alert them
that they had only 60 seconds to save
their work
before their system would automatically
shut down and restart
there was no option to cancel or dismiss
the restart and if a user happened to
have stepped away from their computer
at the time of the alert they risk
losing important
unsaved data by not being quick enough
to do anything about it
microsoft confirmed this back in
november explaining that some windows 10
updates caused critical issues for
certain configurations with the local
security authority subsystem service
this was reportedly a filing conflict in
the system triggered by changing your
local username
especially the main admin account name
if your particular device was affected
this mysterious prompt might have
appeared and rebooted your system
these type of issues cropping up
following a windows update can be very
frustrating
have you ever had a windows update cause
you to lose data or functionality
tell us about it in the comments below
robbie have you ever encountered such a
thing
oh becca i tell you what uh jeff do you
remember our
season 10 pilot episode uh
where we shot four years ago yes but
you'll remember
because it's the it's the episode where
we shot the entire thing
in 360 vr video oh yes absolutely you
remember that yeah
um shooting and
producing vr video is very taxing on
your computer
yeah oh yeah you had a ton of work to do
a ton of work
the rendering process of that episode
was more than 24 straight hours
just to render out a one-hour video i
remember that and
windows 10 rebooted mid-stream
i forgot about that it did and
you know i'm not i don't work full-time
at the studio and especially then it's
like you're there once a week
and you expect that okay everything's
going to be ready and no it was sitting
at the login prompt and i had lost
everything yeah because you can't just
continue halfway through the round no
oh no it doesn't no you had to start
over so
needless to say yes becca i have been
through similar situations
um and i used to use like things like
notepad i'd have like
notes and everything up on my screen
about the show as i was editing and
things like that
um and then i'd head home for the night
and i had that lost a few times as well
and and finally i
realized okay this is not a this is not
for me so i saved
save my work always and yeah hopefully
never have a render
interrupted like that oh man wow
well at least this mysterious 60 second
self-destruct issue was finally resolved
on january 7
2021 the fix was pushed out
automatically
so you don't need to do anything as long
as your windows 10 device gets its
windows updates
however if you are working with custom
media or have updates paused
make sure you update your os 60 seconds
that's not enough time i mean
i would be furious thankfully thankfully
my system did not have this issue
yeah but for a while probably a year my
system wouldn't even do updates
oh really it would try and do it and
then it would crash every time oh wow
and then like a month and a half ago it
started working so i didn't have to go
through this the worst thing is when
that update comes up on the screen and
you can't get out of it
it's like full screen and it blocks
everything so you're in the you might be
in the middle of something
and suddenly yeah you're locked out now
this is a case
once again where microsoft has
updated windows 10 and introduced
a problem that previously didn't exist
yeah and that i mean i don't have to say
that bugs me i think that
that bugs all of us that that kind of
thing still happens
yeah but we we've you know we've been
through this
it seems like it's a recurring theme
that microsoft keeps doing this where
they're breaking
systems and at least they're consistent
you know what you're getting
bugs you know what you're getting this
is where that
slight linux bias comes in and we say
hey check out linux mint
check out ubuntu check out ubuntu mate
yeah what else can we say debian
definitely debian just about anything
just not centos yeah it's
i don't know why this stuff doesn't get
caught first by windows
like i i gotta hand it to them i mean as
software developing
uh as software developers it's it's
virtually impossible to think of every
sure every case of every scenario um
sometimes it has to do with the
particular
graphics drivers you have and like they
just can't test
everything but you know in it
one of the one of the practices that we
have is
okay we're going to make a big change to
the network we have 1200 computers
we're going to push this out to five
isolated systems first
we're gonna see how it goes and then we
wait it out we see
how everything goes right great okay a
couple of days of
have passed let's push that out to 30
systems
and let's see if any complaints or
problems come in and as we
work through those things then we feel
confident and we can push it out to the
1200 systems
right but you've got windows is on
probably billions of computers
right so why do they not have a test
well why don't they run their update on
all of their systems one percent
of those ten systems yeah let's
release this update to one percent yeah
let's see what happens
but could you i'd hate to be the one
percent
yeah but at least then they could fix it
before
pushing it out to billions of people
yeah and i mean i'm sure that this kind
of
i can exaggerate you know like it was
isolated cases
i mean i say that sure loosely it wasn't
every system yeah
but imagine if like a a government
defense computer was running windows and
they were middle of
something important that's like you've
got 60 seconds it's like
yeah what uh-huh like enter the disarm
codes now
you have 120 seconds to disarm yeah you
have 60 seconds before i reboot
oh boy yeah it's unfortunate but at
least they got it fixed
quickly i will give you know microsoft
that is they fixed it
quick so hopefully some of their other
issues hopefully you didn't lose
anything yeah
don't miss the other stories we're
following this week first
mozilla's privacy vpn service is now
available on mac os
and linux plus intel's newly announced
12th gen chip hybrid
is set to compete with both arm and
apple silicon
subscribe to our youtube channel to make
sure you catch the full stories
from the category 5 tv newsroom i'm
becca ferguson
thanks for watching
[Music]
[Applause]
you