hello
this is cat 5 uh coffee break
uh rather community coffee break and uh
my name is bp9 hello and uh up on my
well that side we've got uh lance man
over there
and over this way we have peter give us
a wave
thank you so good to see you all just a
quick bit of um
a quick bit of uh administrative
this will be the last coffee break for
um since the cat5 studios are going to
be shut down
over um over uh
the christmas break so the two weekends
around christmas
that would be next weekend which i
believe is the
something like the 20th and then the
the weekend following which is um
the 26th or something on 27th something
like that
just checking the calendar real quick
just to make sure
so yeah sunday the 20th
um is no coffee break and sunday the
27th
is no coffee break and that's because uh
that's because robbie has the studio
shut down for those two weekends
around christmas time so just bear that
in mind
so uh peter no need to ask if there's a
coffee break
what about because there weren't then
what about third of january i do expect
to restart the coffee breaks on the
third of january
yes so that would be so you know we'll
all be a little bit
from from new year but if we're
if we're sober and somewhat upright then
we'll then we'll do coffee break on the
third
i plan to be there on the third we'll
see who else shows up right
okay with that out of the way um
i have not made any progress on this
peter i'm still
i this is the uh do you think the
government i made about uh
i did yeah i did and i understand your
comments about the opto isolator and i
absolutely agree that would be
critical because the last thing you want
is any kind of voltage leaking through
from uh from the main side back into the
arduino
good and good as well yeah yeah and i
don't want that so i absolutely agree
with you
the interesting thing is this thing
doesn't have any opto isolators it has
the relays
but further up go back on there because
i've got anything in the way hold on
um no not okay you're not going to be
able to see it very well
anyway but but the these are all
uh here these are all relays they're not
up to up isolators
and i don't know if the relays are
locked if the relays are locked either
what
would that do i have all that a couple
of down by uh
there is one down by the great relay
look on the other side the grey relay
you're talking about this little uh i
see right here
yeah it was number one but you got four
legs
uh yeah i haven't been able to identify
what that chip is
actually dropping a couple of those do
you think so
i think you're fine
oh i can't i can't see it because i'm
old now
i hate getting old i think you'll find
that tomorrow
i'll pick up that okay all right
that'd be good because it looked like
one anyway
that would make sense that would make
sense do you think that would uh that
would be between the
relay and the rest of the relays and the
rest of the circuitry then
yeah but there's only there's only two
legs uh
how does how does it drive three relays
they might be coming from the input from
somewhere else i would say to isolating
that ball from
the world um but uh
did he have a 12-volt power supply with
it as well
how did he drive the electronics buyer
as well oh no it's
it's it's mains voltage coming into this
thing
but some of these some of these pins
have mains voltage on them
yeah i know that but do you have the
electronics you don't want electronics
the main voltage
no absolutely not no you're absolutely
right so
um there has to be a there has to be
like a voltage regulator and i actually
thought that that
four leg um device was actually a
voltage regulator could be it could be
could be you could have one drive as
well yeah
so i'll keep looking i'm going to try
and reconstruct the circuit i have no
idea
um how to do that from the circuit board
oh yeah by the way
yeah do you see that
they are like magnets
yeah okay they're natural magnets they
come
from they come from africa they come
from a
uh river bank river um
a part of a part of africa that portugal
run at one time
and it's a natural magnet and they were
very strong
and what are you using them for i i
bought them because i thought they were
interesting
and then and i like the shapes of them
because they're they came to exit
extraction okay yeah they're rather
annoyed
i thought you i thought you were using
them for a project and you're going to
shoot into an explanation of what the
project was but
you bought them because they were
interesting well that's a good enough
reason to buy them
andy by the john schools where the top
one is anyway because you know the jobs
cause where the rocks are
of that shape hexagonal shape so uh yeah
yeah
yep but they do apply
a quality of portugal which i can't
remember which one it was
but i think it's down then their motion
big direction knock off
okay i'm trying to remember whether
you've showed those to us before because
i have a
curious feeling that i've seen those
before somehow
i don't know why am i done am i done
you might have showed them off i lost
them for a very long time
and they came up in the box recently
anyway
that happens to me all the time all i
have to do is go buy
more and i'll find the original ones
every single time after that
i got wiped i've got a wife the odd
things as well because she's blowing she
puts everything away and you can have a
long
time yeah or my cat she'll find stuff
if i lose something i guarantee you that
cat will find it she'll figure out where
that stuff
is every single time yep i've been there
done that just
just yesterday i lifted the sofa
because the cat was digging for
something under there
um and what she had what what she likes
to do
i don't know well uh doug you'd know
what these are the ritz crackers you
know the packages that the ritz crackers
come in
well i i tie a knot in the middle of
them and pull them into
like a bow shape and then i just toss it
on the floor for her to play with and
she just bats them around plays with
them
well she kicks them up underneath the
sofa every single time
i looked under there yesterday there
were half a dozen of them under there
and she was digging she was she was
trying to grab them she was trying to
get to them
cats are a trip i'll tell you oh yeah
crazy cat
you would think that she would you know
think oh i
knocked it under there or she would know
not to knock it under there but i don't
know
they got a good sense of smell and a
good tread division as well
that's true yeah yeah you're right yeah
exactly well
so um i've been working some more on or
studying some more on the
on the uh client server that uses
encrypted
ss not ssl tls
using gnu tls we made fun of the
of the new name a couple of weeks ago
and as far as i can tell the the
program that i'm using as a model as a
reference implementation
as far as i can tell it does not use
public private key it seems to use a
shared key
and i'm not happy with that i don't want
to i don't want a shared key i want to
use
a um i want to use the public private
key
so i'm i'm going to first get my
reference model working first get it
just working with whatever keys it
thinks
it needs to make it work make sure that
i understand how that works
and then i'm going to change it to
make it use a real public private key
so that you have to have the public key
on the server
and you have to have the private key on
the client or otherwise it won't
it won't connect even though it's uh
even though the the channel is encrypted
that's fine i'm okay that's what i want
but i also want to
unequivocally identify the
uh the the person who's running the
client
and i do not want to and i do not want
to rely on username and password which
is what i
believe the reference program is using
so
um i want to use a proper public private
key because that's how you're gonna use
pgp
uh yeah that's how you generate the keys
absolutely
right i assume there might be more than
one version out there
so uh well good to you
yeah gnu tls includes all the
functionality to generate
the public private key just like just
like pgp does
so i don't have to generate pgp keys but
i do need to generate
um uh i do need to generate the
uh uh public private keys using the gnu
tls
command line arguments which is the same
functionality as um
uh as uh a
pgp i've used i've used pgp and i use
thunderbird
um but i haven't found anybody who wants
to
exchange encrypted emails
if you send them encrypted emails i'll
say what what what is this
remember that old tv show i remember it
well
that was a funny it was a british tv
show but they all had american accents
what's up with that
i don't understand that what was that uh
thunderbirds
the old tv old tv show from the
60s or 70s as i recall
and it was it was marionettes it was uh
it was all
um puppets believe it or not but
um pretty realistic well yeah as
realistic as
marionettes can be so
it's an old old tv show they've done a
animated series since then and they've
done a movie since then
so the the concept is great
i always worry when when the people who
get in trouble
you know they they tear up a plane or a
plane crashes or something
and their solution
[Music]
oh yeah
i know i was worried about that i
thought oh oh i've lost my internet but
no it looks okay
so yeah what i was saying was that the
the people who get in trouble with the
thunderbirds always seem to think that
the
solution when the plane goes down or
something like that is to
send another one and see what happens
one of my friends a professor friend of
mine uh
uh wanted to get a client which was uh
an email client which was safe but he
got fed up with the windows
windows version so i sent him the
version and i put the bare music on the
end of
it oh no yeah yeah yeah those every time
he was told he was getting the
thunderbird music
he did laugh at it because it was quite
funny so every time he got an email he'd
hear the thunderbirds theme song
yeah yeah nice i gotta i gotta do that
i'm gonna do that but see
i won't i won't do the whole webmail
thing there there are lots of folks who
are happy to do the google mail and the
microsoft mail and all the mail stuff i
won't i won't do that maybe i'm just
old-fashioned but
um i don't want all my email to be stuck
on someone else's computer you know
and so i mean sober pointed this out
himself remember way back when
um a few weeks ago he he hasn't showed
up even though he did respond in uh
he did respond in discord so i thought
he'd be here but oh well
um in any case uh uh
you know a friend of his got locked out
of google because of something he said
or whatever it was and
why why do that why lose access to
everything you have why leave it on
someone else's computer that
doesn't make any sense to me so i do my
best to make sure that
all my assets are all on my machine it's
called political correctness we did a
lot of rubbish but then
now careful now peter we've talked about
this
we've talked about this but i
yeah i i get what you mean though and
yeah i
i well i think it's more convenience
more than anything else
i mean uh back in australia my um
my sister does the same thing she said
yeah but we just leave all our email up
on
on google or or whoever the internet
provider is because it's so easy because
we can get to it from every device that
we have
i said yeah but if they if they choose
to throw a switch you lose access to
all of it everything and in the case of
gmail
it's not just your email it's your
photos your documents and everything
else that you've got
in um in gmail do you really want that
i use it for uh just for
uh chatting to friends rather than
anything which is important you know
so if you lose it you don't care no i
don't care no
well that synology box of yours that you
that you don't like very much hosts an
email client as well
that you can use as a web-based email
client just like you do gmail
if you wanted to try that yeah well
think about it i have not tried that yet
i'm still
still wondering whether that's uh i'm
still climbing up poles and things all
the time but uh
i've seen by the end of by by next year
i should get installed today
and then get the idiots won't come and
sabotage be again
i'm looking bloody happy about that one
you know
i'm sorry you know anyway um yeah yeah i
i i didn't know that about technology
books but
i will look at it next time anyway well
you got it
you got a synology box didn't you you
didn't like it
i didn't like it i just felt that you
couldn't do anything with it because it
was also
a bit like a bit like apples
it's true that you are locked in there
um in their
uh you know in their little world
yes i want to say ecology or something
like that but um yeah
you know you're stuck with them there's
no doubt about that and
if you like that then okay i don't mind
it because i'm prepared to put up with
the functionality that
um that moments gives me
where it where it categorizes photos for
me automatically without me having to do
anything
manually it does it all locally but i'm
prepared to put up with that
without using all the rest of it in
terms of using all the rest of it i just
leave it alone
i might use shared drives um but that's
about all i will do
what about if i took the uh actual
bulldog from and i got a i found talking
about finding things
i also found to buy a raspberry pi i
wonder if i could use a raspberry pi as
a uh
server in there in instead you know yeah
you absolutely
well not in that unless you took the
thing apart
and replaced the box replace the insides
of it
but they're driving they're driving the
dead drive to be the problem i think
it would i would talk to um uh i would
talk
to robbie about that because he's
actually done something just like that
i'll talk to you about it yeah when i
get married he seems to be busy at the
moment though very
well well yeah absolutely he's been
crazy busy building
um building shows for category five so
i really like that you know yeah
you know he wanted to make sure that we
all understood he wasn't just taking a
break over the last two weeks
he's actually he's actually been very
busy so
yeah so we shouldn't we should not give
him a hard time for that
i think i may i think i made a comment
about putting those two grindstones and
doing too much work
uh if they go on uh on whatsapp you know
yeah yeah yeah yeah don't overdo it in
other words
well exactly so doug what have you been
up to sir you've been doing anything
exciting with that raspberry pi
well i'm waiting for the fan to come in
oh really okay i'm getting a
case with a fan built in and it's going
to have a heat sink
and do you have the heat sinks for it
yet or not
now they're coming with the it's all in
the kit
okay okay so is the fan going to be
attached to the heatsink or is it just
going to be part of the case in it
and it blows cool air
that's the way it looks anyway the heat
sinks are separate
uh-oh you have a you're being visited by
a cat again
yeah i'm gonna have to install the heat
sinks
you know thermal paste and all that ah
sure yeah
and uh then the fan
is above the heat sink it's part of the
case okay
okay nosh
what are you pointing at peter my wife
would just come in
aren't you just telling me
tell your wife merry christmas and happy
and happy new year
yes from both of us yeah you're doing
the happy christmas time
thank you merry christmas to you i don't
know if she can hear me because uh
you've got your head set in haven't you
but tell a merry christmas
and happy new year happy new year
thank you very much appreciate it i'm
doing a minute
i've got a teacher i've got to go on all
right no worries
we're about done anyway so
so uh yeah did you
plan to do any kind of programming doug
or you don't think you're going to do
that
i've never been able to grasp
programming
yeah we sort of talked about that we
sort of even even basic or anything like
that
yeah i've tried basic and it
just doesn't make sense to me oh really
okay
so you still think you're gonna run uh
uh plex or something
on there is that the plan um i'm not
sure about that
in the united states it's illegal to
copy
um anything that's got digital rights
management
so if i was to put anything on a hard
drive
that i would run through raspberry pi
it would be illegal to do that huh
okay they'd have to rip it right
which is a form of copying and you have
to crack the copyright to do that
okay okay it's going to be breaking the
law
okay we could move to canada
um i don't think i'm going to do that
[Laughter]
it's always an option too cold in canada
well it's about the same latitude as
you're in peter isn't it
yeah but they got it but they got a
colder weather because
it's uh a big landmass they felt golden
and they could as like europe it's a lot
colder because they've got a big
landmass
we went on an island to proceed around
there so we got bloody warm by the gulf
tree
so is it true that it's still crazy that
it's crazy windy over there in ireland
and in england
yeah you get a lot of wind over there
yeah we ever get a lot of wind
all year round no no
between october and about january time
for every time
huh okay okay 60 millimeter sounds like
our pacific northwest
yeah yeah
when the weather gets bad it gets really
quite nasty and horrible out there
you know i aren't really quite enough
then horrible weather i don't want to go
out there
but i think so we'll get colder weather
than we do because they're in the
landmarks you know because they're on
they're in finland yeah that's further
all for me i think he is signing
i don't quite know where he is but i got
opinions further enough for me when i
was asking where he was
would you near that land i think it's
further than enough for me
uh that's uh sobu yeah yeah i think we
would be
yeah and i pinned so we went discord and
told him we were ready to go
but and he responded but i think he's
fallen asleep again
and i can't do anything i don't know
can't take him anywhere
well we're um we're up to almost 25
minutes so
we're not going to stay on for very much
longer
robbie requested that we that we keep
these around 25 minutes so i just threw
him under the bus i hope he doesn't mind
i'm such a bad person i'm really really
such a bad person
i really don't have very much uh very
much else to uh
to add i have not um done anything with
the
with the uh pine time it's it's still
it's still bricked i i haven't messed
with it at all it's still just
might be you're broken they leave it and
done
one day you gave a brain wave and
exactly that's exactly what i've done
and if i leave it long enough somebody
else will come up with a good
with a good program to load into it
which is exactly what's happened
so i'll probably just load their program
into it and if um
and if robbie ever decides to uh fire up
his own pine time he says he got
he says he got it but um hasn't done
anything with it
well if he chooses to uh to move forward
with it he can just load that destroyer
but it's a learning curve you know you
learn every time we do
it is it is and and i would love to i
would love to
get in there and figure out how to
program the thing but the hardest part
with this
is the the physical connection that
you've got to make to these
right there are four tiny tiny little
pins in there
that you have to get just right and have
it there for a good
20 30 40 50 seconds whatever it is
in order to make sure that every single
bite that you send down the serial port
makes it into that unit and if you don't
have it
set up exactly right it won't program
correctly and it won't start
so it took me ages just to unlock it the
first thing you have to do is unlock it
they probably don't protocol as well
oh yeah there's absolutely a protocol
involved but
um there's a physical connection of four
pins that you have to
that you have to set uh pins on that you
have to set
um uh uh connectors on and they have to
have good connection for the whole
programming process or otherwise it just
won't work
so yeah yeah yeah you've got i go under
the electronic blockers go to the kto
plug in usb and put the thing underneath
you can see the thing big
and change it that way you know and
that's another way of doing it you know
if you're looking at
wii stuff because uh my eyes are not
good anymore though
you know i'm glad 200 times
boy i can relate to that
i could so relate peter
i don't know what job is about no i i
think he's a devil wasn't tough yet to
play with
like i'll keep well away from it yeah
yeah i don't like surface mount either
i'd rather work with some
i'd rather work with this kind of stuff
and i'm i'm already
you know hardware challenged when it
comes to dealing with this stuff as well
so you know this is not i did
tell you um i was doing the same thing
um
as you know i've got three endeavors on
my mouth
and uh i've got three coaxes on my mask
coming down so i've got one of these
twitches as these four ways which you
think
and i was going to put four relays in
the box
and then i would use about the other
raspberry pi or some sort of uh
way i could switch it you know each one
on
whatever uh that's the problem i've got
his waterproofing
because it's so wet around here yeah i
was gonna say
that and you it sounds like a
pretty complicated project in terms of
you know having to to do a lot to make
it
switch these relays i might also suggest
for such a simple task i might also
suggest an arduino
instead of a raspberry pi because if the
power ever goes out
on the raspberry pi you might lose that
sd card and then you're done at that
point
okay but an arduino will just keep on
trucking
uh even if the power goes out it will
just crank right back up again
roughly the same price are they
uh yeah yeah in fact they're probably
cheaper i think the um
i think you can get an arduino these
days for like 20 or 30 dollars
i have not checked the price lately so
don't quote me um
but the equivalent uh raspberry you know
a raspberry pi which is a much more
powerful machine of course
it's more like eighty dollars to get so
i think once you
don't only input output on here
all the input outputs are there apples a
mechanical switch in the end
and uh i decided to do it easy
just have a mechanical forward and it's
got a knob on it
and on it it's got like a a
line down on the knob with uh
you just gotta you just gotta watch out
for uh lightning strikes
oh yeah yeah very dangerous so that's
what i'm that's what i'm dealing with
right now with this thing
did you know i don't either drive where
i used to live in
down in april i was up on the downs up
up between banks of tokens uh and
four marks yeah and uh i was very i
happened
to do quite well up there as well and uh
i we had a line in strike in the next
field which was run by
my relationship yeah and they have to
get close peter they don't uh they don't
have to hit you they only have to get
close and they'll do that
we've got to get ready to close this
down because it was it was the static
field that
dropped a deck right after the field
from from the lightning bolt
and it probably was about to go 40 feet
away
and you can glove it it globbed my
prayer
it would absolutely right folks
here we go um i've got i've got to close
this down
so remember this is the last coffee
break
for 2020. there won't be a new one until
the
the next coffee break will be the third
of january
2021 so two weeks we're taking a two
week break
okay so let me let me take the
opportunity to say
merry christmas to all of you to both of
you and happy new year
stay safe merry christmas and happy new
year to you thank you i appreciate that
thank you
and youtube peter everybody who's who's
watching after the uh
after the live broadcast or the live the
live zoom meeting
merry christmas to you as well so yes
thank you all um i've had i've had a fun
year so far and looking forward to
many more maybe i'll get some more stuff
done before right
before the next one we'll see what
everyone
will be better than this year was oh i
certainly hope so
i certainly hope so all right everybody
have a great
uh have a great break enjoy your break
and uh we'll see you next year take care
[Music]
bye
you