oh oh did the server glitch it just
froze oh oh that oh our first glitch
our first glitch dang it's actually
pretty impressive when you consider that
we've been playing for over an hour
um i wonder if it's the world gen cache
just flush to disk
because i am just using a micro sd card
we turned a raspberry pi
4 into a minecraft server
if you haven't watched that video yet do
that first
after more than an hour of multiplayer
gameplay
this is the discussion that followed
this feature is brought to you by
ameridroid.com get your raspberry pi 4
or other single board computer to power
your minecraft server
at ameridroid.com american-based
electronic sales
shipping and support visit
ameridroid.com
i think it's a mission success my friend
hooray
so the next step for my raspberry pi in
order to boost the performance even
further
is i want to get an nvme
to usb 3 uasp adapter
so that's going to give me a solid state
drive that i can run
the minecraft world off of right so that
when it does that flush
the the the storage in this case
the sd card doesn't get choked right
because an sd card especially
on a raspberry pi which does not have a
really great
uh micro sd card uh reader writer it's
pretty slow
by by contrast to nvme for sure right
it should get rid of that bottleneck
absolutely so that's going to be the
an interesting test and i mean this was
done on a raspberry pi 4 with 4 giga ram
yeah
i i can only imagine how much better it
would be on an 8 gig ram
because possible yeah i mean we i don't
we didn't tax out the ram at any point
no and i was watching that buffer
i was watching h-top there and and just
kind of keeping an eye on things
cpu got pretty hot at some points and
because i only overclocked i was a
little conservative in
in my case overclocking to 1.95
gigahertz
um you could go higher than that but
then you risk stability issues and
things like that or
the the single board computer crashing
uh but the other
opportunity that we have is is with the
raspberry pi uh
400 which does have a stock 1.8
gigahertz
processor which we could then bump up to
maybe 2 or 2.2 gigahertz
that would make a difference so that
might be cool too so i mean you can do
this on
on the same method can be uh
translated to any single board computer
it's just making sure that you've got
enough power and enough ram but the fact
is it worked
it worked and it really wow really well
and i mean having com
i mean we didn't do the comparison on
the show but having done it on a pi
3 and an android xu 4 i was expecting it
to not go well
and you mentioned that it or more timer
mentioned that it it's even working
better than the online services
yes yeah and i i would agree with that
like
especially i mean at the top of the show
we were talking about uh or i was saying
how i'd use some free services
and the free services performed
worse than the pie and so you mean the
pie
performed better than the free services
yeah and even some
i like to put a positive yeah even the
paid services
uh you know like five bucks a month
stuff like that like you know the bottom
end
uh i would say that they were comparable
maybe like the pie kept up fantastic did
well and yeah
uh you know that was there was what nine
of us eight of us on there
something like that isn't that unreal
folks like and we did not tax it out
like there's
room for more so hey let's let's do it
let's land party
i'm game check out the links below head
on over to ameridroid.com to get your
single board computer
raspberry pi 4 with four gigs of ram is
what we tested on
tonight and uh anything as jeff is
saying
get the eight gig if you want and you're
going to probably even see better
performance than we saw which is
pretty astonishing and there are other
single board computers and other
products there as well
and the links below also contain
my script to set it up more information
as well so
if you're not seeing that if you're
watching this on cable tv or anything
like that
head on over to our website category5.tv
and just do a quick search for minecraft
raspberry pi
and you'll find the video with those
links and the instructions and the
script to install it and everything else
oh yeah fantastic stuff well bald nerd
i've just uh
threw up a bunch of torches in a couple
of paths thanks dude
are you still down there oh yeah i'm
finding all of the dark
dark areas and lighting it up yeah nice
not a bad spot cool
should be a good mine yeah lots of
resources lots to work with
i think
i think he'll be good
do you guys have any food i could eat
uh there might be some potatoes in my
place
if you can get back to my base you can
have any of the
veggies that are in the garden oh thanks
just uh make sure to save something so i
can replant
i'll take the wheat cause it drops wheat
and seeds and then i'll replant the seed
oh look we got a zombie here with a
shield and a sword
could i have the shield
it dropped the shield
nice you still have some torches i'm
flat out i do nice
this is a sweet cave yeah man it just
keeps going
if only i had a pickaxe
i don't want to hurt one of you guys so
i'm trying to hang back a little bit
oh did the server glitch it just froze
oh oh that oh our first glitch
our first glitch dang it's actually
pretty impressive when you consider that
we've been playing for over an hour
um i wonder if it's the world gen cache
just flush to disk
uh because i am just using a micro sd
card
yeah yeah
ooh an enderman i'm gonna kill this
you're going down into the deep dark
because there's an enderman and a
skeleton and a creeper
did you pick up like some armor and
stuff ow
oh crap i just fell down a deep hole
but i'm good oh no
i might die that hurt
okay i'm at one heart could you guys
help
um all i have is rotting flesh
i mean i i'm holding them off with my
shield i need help
i don't really have anything i'm like
i'll put on my
yeah i'm down to one heart creeper got
me
i can hear zombies i'm probably gonna
die
okay
i don't even know where you are more
timer
i'm in your cave well i know that but
it's an awfully big
there we go did you
how far down did you go like i don't
even see you and i don't have any
torches or anything
i just got out of your of your cave all
right
that is one impressive cave thanks
[Applause]
[Music]
so
you