[Music]
welcome to the world of cryptos
and welcome to the crypto corner now it
has been an interesting week hasn't it
let's take a look at it if we look at
coin gecko which is
my current favorite directory then we
see that the market cap has increased
since we spoke last time
to 364 billion with a small decrease at
the moment of 2.7 percent
which is normal nothing unusual there if
we look at the top coins also nothing
unusual here well we've got chain link
with minus eight percent but
it had an increase of 40 already 40 in
the last seven days
and as always we sold by those seven
days and then the picture changes
significantly
normally we have got around 15 to 20
coins that achieve more than 15 percent
this time we've got over 50 coins
achieved more than 15
and i guess that one or the other of you
is uh contemplating in investing in
cryptos now
and there i'd like to just uh give you
some recommendations
the first is if somebody recommends
something to you
just be very careful because um not
everybody has got
your best interest uh in mind
and um and you can do the same research
they are doing so let's take a look at
here band protocol that's an oracle like
chain link
and if i click on this one here i'm just
showing you how this
this system works then we have got here
the current price uh here is the website
so if you click on this you
it will be read you will be redirected
to the website
medium.com.publications uh
etherscan this is an erc20 console based
on ethereum
um then you've got the writ reddit
twitter telegram so that's whether you
see
the community talking about this coin
and if we scroll a little bit further
down
then we've got the numbers of this coin
so um in the last 30 days band increased
by 600 percent
um currently we've got a retracement of
uh also i would say this is normal here
and if you're interested
in buying something then there's some
interesting numbers like for example
example
what was the all-time high it was 17
so that's uh uh one day ago
as you can see here one day ago we
achieved all-time high here
and the all-time low which was november
25th on
2019 so nine months ago it increased
seven
639 percent from that day
so that's interesting statistics so
probably i would not invest in something
that
just had its all-time high because
i assume that short term there will be
no significant growth in it
if you're interested in any way buying
then you click here
on markets in markets you have got
all those exchanges listed that are
that are trading where you can trade uh
banned so
on binance you have got two or three
possibilities one band with usdt
with tether with bitcoin and with the
binance coin
here you see the price so of course
there will be all
more or less the same and then you've
got the debt the debt
means how far can you go before
there is a significant impact on the
price
yeah so if i go for example in to hot
bit no idea what type of
exchange it is and i want to buy four
thousand dollars
then i will get significantly uh higher
price
than those thirteen dollars thirteen
whereby if i've got thousand dollars to
invest in binance with finance
then it will have no effect of this the
price i will get
so this is how you read the my plus two
percent and the minus two percent it's
uh
it's an interesting number if you want
to invest in coins because some of those
coins
that people are recommending as the next
big thing
have got absolutely no liquidity and
then it's difficult to buy
something and it's very difficult to
sell also something
yeah and and once you have bought
something
i my recommendation is always not your
keys not your coins
so um my the recommendation is as always
to put it either on a on a ledger
which is this year or on a trezor which
is this year
um because that's uh currently the state
of art in regards to
the security of of cryptos
if you're planning to buy one of those
then go only to the original website
um and buy there don't buy it on amazon
because you can
i heard sometimes uh some of those
uh hardware wallets have been
compromised so always go to the original
it takes you probably
four weeks or three weeks longer to
receive that
device but i think that investment is a
very important and very good investment
otherwise be very careful in where
you're investing
do your research don't trust i mean
listen to what experts have to say
whether they recommend band or
channeling or whatever they recommend
but then do your own research
i showed you how to do that so you go
into every website
and see where you want to put your money
there
and last but not least also be very
careful with exchanges because they're
exchanges that
are dangerous so i mean finance
uh coinbase and so they are here from
the western world you can
more or less trust them although i would
never keep i said never keep any coins
on those exchanges
um but but you never know if you have to
do kyc in other words you have to
give your passport picture or driving
license address telephone number to
these exchanges
you don't know what they're doing with
that like in the case of coinbase
they said that they're going to sell
your data so i don't know if that's in
your interest
anyway that's it from me today so i hope
uh you enjoyed you learned something i
wish you a fantastic week and i really
hope
we'll be uh seeing each other next week
again thanks
bye bye thank you robert and just a
reminder that we're not providing
financial advice but only sharing what's
happening in the cryptocurrency market
always remember that cryptocurrency
markets are ever changing
and always volatile so you should only
spend what you can afford to lose
i don't like it when robert says things
that make me scared
it was like yeah i gave my driver's
license to coinbase
should i be worried now robert comments
and he says i don't understand that's
because they're centralized
yeah yeah and i just like can i assume
that the government knows everything
about me anyways
but probably but the government issued
my would that be like irs tax purposes
yeah i suppose so but i mean
selling my info to the government so i
don't hold my crypto in
uh in a centralized um exchange at all
however i do use the exchange to
transfer funds between
us dollars and bitcoin for example so
you