[Music]
welcome to the coffee break everybody
nice to see you so far i see
peter and marshman and
sasha rickman here i am
how you been good
how's the internet there seems to be
like that little bit of a delay
is there a delay with me a little bit
maybe not okay
let's just all right let's get that
taken care of okay peter
how's everybody doing good
good good good
hey this week i've got uh i've i've
re-uploaded
some of the show because uh i had some
problems with the
recording from the pine book pro so it
was like
2 40 p it was like season one
mm-hmm
sasha tell us about yourself how are
things
oh things are awesome i've i've
just been working away at the house this
is the first day we've been double
digits
so lovely
i hear that other parts of the world
like ontario
are having like a heat wave right now um
yeah but i have my internet hooked up
sasha good to see you nice to see you
your internet is working yeah
that's good and this is like my first
like
trial zoom run beyond like with my
sisters
so oh yeah yeah so you'll let me know if
anything's
weird other than me i'm just generally
weird
join the club
[Laughter]
we're just gonna we're gonna rename this
this broadcast the the weirdo club
how's that yes speaking of weird
i feel like marshman partially
disappeared
he did because well that's what up yep
yeah
he has a background running mystical
that reminds me that background reminds
me of uh
the poltergeist of baldwin ontario
from uh from becca's channel because
that's got the house on the the one side
stars moving in the background very nice
very nice should i should i go back to
the
to the bird background for sasha yes
yes it certainly is entertaining and
it's sure
it doesn't use for a whole half hour
that's my life there's like 10 million
birds in my backyard
one of the trees seems like it's
decorated for christmas with birds
almost all the time they're eating the
pine cones
and they're all so noisy like lovely
noisy they are um
white throated sparrows so they like do
that
starting at like four they sing in morse
code
how cool yeah you may be surprised to
learn
the bird that you see behind bill is in
fact
not real yeah i know
i know it looks so realistic doesn't it
my goodness i i thought for sure
the birds here the birds the seagulls
here are the size of turkeys like
they're
huge and all they do is eat crab all day
long over at the crab plant so they
actually
really
yeah now marshman are you on uh vacation
or
do you have a holiday today too oh
absolutely yes
yep yep it's memorial day today so here
in the states we're on
we've got a holiday so well happy
memorial day well thank you sir
thank you i hope you enjoyed it and i'm
working yeah
yeah you're right you had victoria day
last monday
i want dual citizenship just so i can
take both
right it doesn't work for me i can't
take australian holidays when i'm over
here
so it doesn't work you could you could
you could you could
as well i wouldn't have a very long
employment history if i did that though
do you think
you could just do what i do and pretend
you don't understand time zones and be
like
i'm not late i'm right on time in
australia
oh look at that i had an american
calendar it said it was the stuff
that happened terrible yeah
so hey you know the interesting time
i do there it is it's mounted
it's mounted on my um mounted on my
raspberry pi
we're using using uh they call it post
attack it's
it's a knockoff blue tack and i'm using
it so that
uh there's the there's the back of it
and when i'm ready to program it
i will just connect the wire up and go
i got to that point about midnight last
night and i finally said i'm done i'm
tired i'm gonna
if i keep going with this i'm going to
tear it up and i don't want to tear it
up
so today so listen up kids you've got to
get a strap for that and that's what
you're going to strap to your wrist
right there that just don't get caught
at the border with that
to push the battery out of the way you
know like 90 degrees
so that i can yeah it does look awfully
suspicious with all that um
all that goop around there doesn't it
yeah
[Laughter]
no it doesn't beep it doesn't have a
speaker in it it has the
actuator on it though so okay oh there
you go vibration every second
that's true now the i don't know whether
you've seen this uh robbie
oh you don't have yours yet oh i'm sorry
i oh
oh burn hi soul boo
oh look at that
yeah i was waiting for the meeting to
start and then i um yeah i was
trying to show so uh sasha then the the
meeting idea and i noticed that
it's just oh yeah yeah robbie went and
changed the meeting id
honestly and he also changed the
password yes he did i
i did figure it out this is the you
figured it out
yeah you're here this is you're here
so how do you wire into that you don't
what it is is um okay so
this is the back of the uh of the unit
right
yeah so yeah on this side are the
charging connectors
right and they're also they also have
magnets
and so the whole point is that it'll
drop right into the
charging cradle and then these
connections on the back will
will charge right oh okay this is the
cat this is the camera
oh that not the camera the uh heart
sensor opening
um it's a window and this is the
charging connectors
but i couldn't figure out what this was
and uh what it is it looks like it's a
spring mechanism
it is it's a spring mechanism that that
makes electrical connection with the
circuit board
it is the actual actuator it's the it's
the vibrator
so there's a there's a small weight
you can see it's a silver thing a small
weight right there it just spins that
whenever it wants to um whenever it
wants the thing to vibrate on your rum
on your wrist so yep that's what that's
what that's for
um but in order to program it all i need
is the front face part
which looks really as you noted looks
really suspicious
with wires and all that but it looks a
little a little bulky to have around
your wrist
just a little bit yeah yeah however just
a bit you would
you would stand out yeah i bet
yeah all right look at that time wow
look at that
you're just waiting for someone to say
what time is it
let me tell you not really not really
pull back your suit jacket
i
like a looks like an atx kind of
computer chassis that you've
mounted a whole bunch of high voltage
stuff into that scares the
crap out of me it's only 32 volts
robbie's off dangerous
out so uh um so it's all together now
so uh it looks a bit like bp nine thing
with all the while sticking out of it
at the moment pretty scary in it yeah
it looks like a computer chassis and put
a bunch of components into it
to create his own power supply unit
which is pretty neat so
peter's really uh gifted at that kind of
stuff the circuitry
yeah very cool very cool sasha what's
new like what uh what's going on we
haven't seen you for a while so i feel
like it'd be nice to kind of catch up
while we can
here you know what i'll do is i will um
maybe i'll switch around my camera and i
can like give you a little bit of a walk
through of what
this if i can okay so let's see i'm i'm
really new at this i'm getting really
dizzy wow
okay here we are here we go so have you
ever
um taken carpet adhesive off of uh
floorboard it's horrible very difficult
oh
yeah i've been using that
iron on steam and just steaming
the vegetables out of that
then also i have to remove all of this
wallpaper
some of it's painted um
also it looks like you're getting the
place like you're completely redoing the
place
we are completely redoing the place it's
sad to say
that we are going to get rid of this
mural because there was a bit of smoke
a smoke damage keith painted this
actually keith and dave's
brother tim keith is uh dave's father
for those who don't yes um
this is my bedroom
everything in this house is in disarray
right now so please forgive me
of course this is the guest room for
everybody who's gonna come visit
it's not ready for you though so don't
come yet
uh because of kovid you would not be
allowed in just tell me where the
nearest airport is sasha that's all
that's all i need to know
just a three hour it's a three hour
drive i could use the help actually if
you wanted to show up
yeah it's a three hour drive it's a it's
an hour and a half an hour and a half to
the nearest
walmart oh no see that
powder blue toilet that's a real thing
in life
that's changing it's a big place
this is another house another house
another
another room through this door is
another house
now is it all one is it all one floor
sasha or is there a road so
is there more than one so far there is
more than one floor
i could give you the whole tour i don't
know how much time we have okay
so then here's time that robbie will let
us have okay
stop me if i stop me if i'm getting too
crazy
this is the dining room okay
okay your wi-fi is holding up this is
good yes
this is actually a really good test to
see whether or not it'll hold up through
this is the kitchen you're missing
a kitchen no it looks like a gutted room
to me
that's a huge yes oh is anybody here an
electrician
see this black around the legally what
is this
that's scary that's what that is that's
a scary to me
that's a short circuit you'll need to
replace that you'll need to replace that
insulation and you'll need to
uh have an electrician check the wiring
to make sure it's
outside because and a plumber
also because that's how our sink drains
no that's not common here peter but um
definitely definitely you'll need an
electrician to come here yeah
and check the wiring yeah i think it's
safe
to say with that kind of thing just
don't mess around get somebody in that's
a great license
that knows what they're doing yeah sure
yeah for sure that's what we're doing
okay
it might just be a loose connection
sasha but the fact is if there's if
there's one
in one place then there may be others
they'll switch off
that's what you need to do as well
absolutely so now we are entering into
the abyss
this is this is the attic
these are dave's old childhood toys this
is
dave would die if he knew i was showing
you this that's his potty from when he
was a baby
that's enough a view from the added yeah
that's cool okay and then if i go to the
other side of the attic
obviously there's still like lots of
work that needs to be done up here
this is like a horror movie yeah
when you move really quickly
this is going to be my cat 5
office there's plenty of room out there
is it insulated though i mean what's it
going to be like in the middle of the
summer
that'll be hot it's really stinking hot
right now
i'm not surprised no insulation in the
rafters
no none at all in the winter um
yeah you're gonna have to insulate that
whole area there sasha for that to be
reliable
yeah yes we are we're gonna totally do
up this
section okay now now i know that
i know that you are not as tall as me
but are you standing right now like can
you actually stand in there it looks
like a really really short
in the main in in my office you can't
see my air quotes
but in my office i can stand the rest of
it i have to
i have to um not stand i have to crouch
yeah okay i'm climbing down the crazy
ladder
there's one more spot to show you it
just goes dark for us what
what are you actually calling oh yeah um
i don't know is it one of those is
literally just a dark ladder
is it one of those pull down ladders
that you pull down and fold up or uh or
does it is
no it's it's always there i cleaned the
mouse poo off of it and now it's good
the watch
[Music]
basement it is lovely down here
it's cool and refreshing
and i have a sheer officer did you just
pass a bear
that is my washing machine uh this
should be my office down here
yes you really need to make this part of
your part of this your office it's
far more suitable yeah and yeah and in
really hot days it will be even cooler
it'll be cooler
i have a basement too it's uh it's not
as big as your basement is but um
because it doesn't look like you've got
a garage or anything like that under
there do you
well here's here's the thing
here i walk into what is kind of the
garage
there's it's only a man door so you
can't actually like
drive into it but like it's not a garage
sorry well we're gonna no okay no so
what we're gonna do
is see these weird panels here we're
gonna like
cut that out and then we're gonna put
two doors that
like open out you know what i mean just
make sure that's not a load-bearing wall
you better make sure that's not a
load-bearing wall
[Laughter]
that your house is on
sasha i hope you're gonna be able to
keep your
hold on it's five acres
five acres oh sorry i didn't there we go
we could put we could put an airstrip
right on your property sasha there'd be
room i tell you
there's room we could do that
okay well see there we go i could land
the plane right there next to your house
i'm gonna get back into my face here
hold on there we go there we go
tour is done okay so i'm sort of hiding
out because
um there are feral cats
on in the property on the property and
we're trying to discourage them
but then there are neighbors who are
trying to encourage them
so the neighbors feed the cats in our
back property
and then i go take the food away
[Music]
[Laughter]
they're really hungry on their property
yeah there you go i want the cats to
leave
i want them to want some other property
to go i know what you want but your
neighbors need to put their
your neighbors need to put the food on
their own property not on your property
no but for a very long time there was
nobody here because
keith went to the home um in november
so for a long time there was nobody
stopping them
yeah okay you know really
are you whispering so the neighbors
don't hear you so the castle the catch
remember there's no insulation on those
outside walls bill
hi dara hello
i don't know sasha a well-placed uh
workplace right
hi hi there ella yeah
i was i was all the way across my house
and i went is that sasha
running into the office i guess i have
the speakers up
by the way nice haircut you like that
yes i do i'm impressed a beard trimmer
did it i just
yep yep i've been there done that yep
absolutely
been there done that a friend of mine
and it does the same thing here he used
a trimmer to
shave off the head and then use a
yeah i don't know that i would shave my
hair but i'd certainly cut it short i
have no problem doing that i would
uh give them pointers listen to you guys
talking like you have a choice yeah
jerk
hey buddy hey
[Laughter]
well robbie you have a choice you've got
some fun i mean some hair growing
dude it just grows out like bobo the
clown
that's why you keep it nice and short
huh yeah exactly
yeah sasha knows the first time she saw
me with
with hair she laughed hysterically
that is true it was the funniest
thing i have seen
oh boy well it's great seeing you guys
we're gonna make a coffee break a weekly
thing
i'm going to try it out on mondays at
noon eastern time
so work that into your own your own time
zone
of course um wow see you there actually
just kind of like
dissolved into the background
it worked it worked
oh boy so yeah i'm gonna
try this out on mondays guys um so make
sure you're here if you can be
and those who are watching that wanted
to be a part of it go to our website
category5.tv and just scroll down
and you'll see the coffee break and the
coffee break link will always be there
with the next
date and i also put it on the google
calendar
which you can you can see on our home
page but you can also
subscribe to the ical file by going to
category 5 dot tv slash subscribe
which is going to make sure that you get
a notification beforehand you can set
your notifications
to you know warn you that hey coffee
break is in an hour or something like
that
whenever we schedule it so we'll try the
monday thing for a little while
uh and uh we'll see how that goes uh but
either way uh
we're gonna endeavor to keep this as a
weekly
weekly get together for the community um
is everybody well like i mean the whole
idea behind coffee break was to
bring everybody together and it's been a
trying time for our entire world and
we're kind of all
um i was gonna i was gonna say spaced
out but that has a different
um translation as well yeah we are
totally spaced out but we're
like geographically spaced out and
uh you know i want to know that
everybody's doing well
yeah i'm getting i'm getting a bit crazy
but 300 miles
on saturday so oh yeah yeah the soap is
still going out yeah i'm feeling the
stir craziness too there bp9 to be
honest with you i still go to work every
day
that's why this that keeps me busy keeps
me out of trouble
so it's good to have a project or
something some something to do
um i i love having the show for that
purpose
that's what i do as well yeah
yeah i went for a walk the other day up
to the rectory show
about
yeah i gotta do the same thing i gotta
get out
get out and walk so yeah
yeah i'm trying to get upstream i'm only
at 1300 steps today so i'm not doing
very well
wait i'll tell you what i'm at because
i've been doing work
17 670 steps
it's only 1 30 your time she's got a big
house
she's got a big house that's all i can
say yeah that's what it is it's a big
house
wow it's a huge house that's right you
get up at like oh dark hundred don't you
sasha like
i do i get it i get up at five in the
morning
and actually the sun is already out at
five in the morning here i don't know
what it is about newfoundland but the
days are longer
the um north you go the longer the days
are
it's the same here wait until winter
wintertime
winter time is the other way though the
days are going to be the shortest ever
so you'll get like that was your
daylight
what's crazy too about about the work
hours in newfoundland is that it's
12-hour shifts
it's not eight-hour shifts like ontario
so i'm gonna have to get used to
it yeah because i'm gonna either be
working work
and not only mine as a psw and even
dave's line of work his is 12 hours too
so i'm gonna be working seven in the
morning till seven at night
or seven at night till seven in the
morning oh many days a week though
um i'm on call so i have to be available
seven days a week
um but oh that's to prove myself right
and then i'll and then once i've like
finished the three months and then they
give me a line so then i know
they've met you and they realize how
awesome you are then you're in the clear
yeah yeah absolutely
well they know i'm super eager because
i've already called the support desk to
like see whether or not i could log on
to my
staff stuff just so that i could start
doing my online training sooner than
later
when do you plan to finish they're doing
the the house
you have on the air schedule on how long
you plan to work on the house until it's
more or less done well the plan is to
have it ready for winter by winter um
the correct answer is forever
exactly you're going to be you're going
to be working on that house forever
that's the theme
you know how you said you were working
12 hours a day yeah
add another eight to that i really like
my priority
my priority right now is the kitchen the
bat and the bathroom
obviously yes um and then
and then as soon as that's done um some
sort of source of heat for the winter
because right now
we only have one functioning baseboard
um like baseboard heater so
we'll just remember working on the
bathroom at least you have that body up
in the attic
so you're yeah
just be careful just be careful
that's my studio
take it easy everybody it's great seeing
you i will see you on wednesday for
category 5 technology tv and again
next monday for another community coffee
break see ya
bye bye
sasha good to see you