covering the week's top tech stores
with a slight linux bias well i can't
even get good cell coverage coverage
at my cottage nokia is working with nasa
to bring 4g
to the moon nasa's artemis mission aims
to establish a long-term
human presence on the moon as a stepping
stone toward
mars colonization and to get things
started
nasa is extending 370 million dollars to
14 companies
to provide the technology for the
program
from robotics to power generation and
even cryogenics
but it makes sense that these teams will
need to be able to communicate with the
mother planet
the new network will be designed
specifically for lunar conditions
able to withstand the extreme
temperature shifts and radiation
the tech will also utilize small cell
tech which as the name suggests is
significantly smaller than the tall cell
towers they are used to seeing
here on earth they also use a lot less
power
the plan is for a lunar lander to carry
the 4g communication system to the lunar
surface
in 2022 nokia's bell labs has been
granted 14.1 million dollars
for their part thanks for watching the
category 5
tv newsroom don't forget to like and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
foreign