today we're going to be taking a look at
villagers and how to give them a
profession
if you've been playing minecraft for any
sort of time you're likely to have run
across a village
a village is kind of this generated
area where there's little houses and
hopefully it's not an abandoned village
and there's actually villagers
who have inhabited it are walking around
and you're going hey this is great
there's people here but i don't know
what to do with it so today
we're going to walk you through how to
take those villagers give them a
profession
and turn that around to use it to your
advantage to people start trading for
much needed resources within the game
so we're going to take a look here in my
tutorial world i've created kind of a
setup
with different villagers so that you can
see how to give them a profession and
what they
what they can offer for you so we're
going to switch to first person view
here
and we're going to go inside this little
closed off area now
one of the things when it comes to
villagers that i want to let you know
first is there's three types
of villagers that you need to be aware
of the first one
is a regular villager this guy sitting
in the mine cart
he's got his brown tunic on and
depending on the biome that you're in
within minecraft they'll have a slightly
different look to them
but generally it's all the same and the
basic villager when they're first born
is always going to have that brown tunic
now over to his side you've got this
green tunic villager
he is what's referred to as a nitwit and
the reason they call him a nitwit is
because he's completely
useless within the game he doesn't have
a job he doesn't
uh mine or mine he doesn't uh do
anything with the resources in the
village he just walks around
he also doesn't sleep the same schedule
that the other villagers do
he's completely backwards in that regard
and then the other type of villager
you're gonna run into is this little guy
over here
that's a baby villager so when villagers
create more villagers you're gonna have
baby villagers it takes time for them to
grow
there's nothing you could do with a baby
villager other than wait for it to
become an adult
and then at that point you could look at
giving it a profession so before i show
you
how to give them a profession i want to
let you know the different types of
um materials so to speak that you're
going to need so
you can see them here if you want to
build an armorer you need a blast
furnace
if you want to have a butcher you need a
smoker
if you want to have a cartographer you
need cartography table that makes sense
for a cleric you need a brewing stand
for
farmer it's a composter fisherman is a
barrel
fletcher is a fletching table leather
worker you need a cauldron
now with the leather worker the cauldron
must
have water in it if it's an empty
cauldron like you see here
nothing's going to happen so make sure
that that cauldron has water
for a librarian you need a lectern a
mason
you need a stone cutter for shepard you
need a loom
for the tool smith it's a smithing table
and lastly the weaponsmith
you need a grindstone so now that i've
kind of walked you through the types of
villagers
and the types of tools that you're going
to need in front of them in order to
give them a profession
i'm going to show you in just a moment
when we come back how you actually
give them their profession and start
using it to your advantage so stick
around
[Music]
okay so we're sitting in front of our
villager we want to know how do i take
this
plane clothe villager and turn him into
an armorer
and the way the mechanics work in
minecraft is villagers will walk around
to do the thing but when you
they end up walking in front of
one of these types of
utilities that i've shown you whether it
be the blast furnace the lectern
whatever
if the villager does not already have a
profession assigned to it
and it has not conducted a trade it will
switch its profession in the case of all
these villagers they don't
have a profession they're just a simple
brown coat villager so
in this case i'm going to uh take the
villager and i'm going to move him
towards
the blast furnace now for the purposes
of you being able to see
i'm going to use a fishing rod there we
go so
you can see here that as he moved into
the blast furnace he switched his
uh skin he looks different he's now got
his goggles on
he's got a different type of profession
and so if i now walk up to this armorer
and i right click him i see that i can
now make trades
um you'll see that in this case i can
trade
nine emeralds for iron boots or 14
emeralds for iron chest plate now
if you're seeing here what's changed is
the emeralds used to be four and nine
uh when i was trying to fishing rod that
villager he suddenly got these angry
like smoke steam things above his head
so right now i've heard a villager and
they're actually
charging me higher prices for these
trades because i've hurt him
so we're going to skip away from that
i'm also just going to clear the weather
here
so that you can see a bit better so i'm
going to show you now
a way of moving the villager in so that
i i don't
lose out on some trades so i'm going to
bounce him behind him
and push him forward with the minecart
and you'll see that he's now changed his
skin as well
he had those little green stars around
him and this one has now become
a butcher so i can now trade some raw
chicken for emeralds or some raw
rabbit i'm just going to go down the
line and take all of these
villagers give them a bit of a
profession
[Music]
for the purposes of this demonstration
putting them in mine carts is the only
way to keep them from walking around
and having them stay in front of the
um skill table that they're in front of
now everybody's had their switch so we
now have the weaponsmith in front of the
grindstone
when it comes to villager trading right
here you see weaponsmith
novice right off the hop you're going to
have little trades in this case there's
only two trades you can make
the more you trade with a villager the
more experience
it's going to get and eventually it's
going to level up so if i have
15 coal and i want to trade for an
emerald
it's going to add its experience bar for
every trade that i make
and so for this purpose i'm just going
to switch into creative mode here i'm
going to give myself
a whole bunch of coal
oops and i'm going to try and make a
trade with him
so i'm going to click that oh i need to
give my
myself 15. that wasn't helpful
okay but i'm going to show you that see
how he's holding the emerald
that lets you know that you're holding a
resource
that he would like to do a trade with
and so
as you go down the line they'll be like
oh yes i want to do that this guy
not holding an emerald because he
doesn't want coal same here same here
none of them want coal now with each of
these
you're going to be able to make unique
trades based on what they will offer to
you so i go to cartographer
i can now trade for paper and empty maps
the more that upgrades
you're going to eventually get to the
point where it's a master cartographer
and you'll be able to trade for things
like maps to woodland mansions
and you know ocean monuments that kind
of stuff
so in order to see kind of a villager
trading post in action i'm going to take
you to the minecraft server that we've
created here on category 5.
and we've built this room that's
protected all of the villagers
from outside mobs and stuff like that
but you can see that each of the
crafting tables is in front of them and
all of them have their professions and
some of them have signs in front that
say master
so if i go over here to the lectern and
i take a look at
this villager and i open up for trades i
see that the librarian is now a master
and you can see
all of the different trades that i can
make with him and
some of the discounts i get now the
reason i'm getting these significant
discounts
is over in the corner i've got hero of
the village on right now
and that's because i defeated a raid
last time i logged in but you'll see
i can trade for name tags for clocks for
compass
for glass blocks for lanterns so
different things that you can
can build or craft find whatever in in
the minecraft world but it just saves
you a bit of time
so here's a cartographer and i was
mentioning uh just a few minutes ago
that when they're at a higher level you
can get maps for things like woodland
explorer map
or an ocean explorer map that's going to
take me to an ocean monument
one thing i'd mention to you is we've
shown you the zombie grinder
the zombie experience grinder with that
you're going to get a lot of
rotten flesh and for the cleric you're
going to be able to trade that rotten
flesh
for emeralds so effectively you use
these two to your advantage
and you will have an unlimited supply of
emeralds that you don't have to go
mining for
so that gives you an example of the
benefits of minecraft when you use the
mechanics to your advantage
how you go oh if i do this and then i do
that
i got this so that's really the basics
of how this works
how it comes to giving your villagers
professions so you if you do run across
a village
uh you know take the resources that
you've got build one of those different
crafting tables for what you need
and then have a villager walk up to it
if you want to continue trading with
them on a regular basis
kind of block them in and make a bit of
a like a village or trading post so to
speak
and then you'll be able to make trades
all you want and that's the basics of
villager professions
and how uh you can make them customized
to what you want
[Music]
you