[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
today i'm going to be a little bit
philosophical and the reason being is
that lately
i'm having extensive discussions with
people
trying to argue what is better the
traditional market
gold different coins
and uh yeah it is a discussion that is
never ending it's like you know those
people
that have got an iphone and uh don't
want to admit that there are some
android phones that are better or the
other way around
doesn't matter who you believe in
whether it's android or or
iphone if you're an iphone person you
believe in
an iphone if you're an android person
and you can't i there's no way in the
world
i can convince you of a different
opinion and the same
is with traditional investment
opportunities so there are people of
course and they're absolutely right
they say that you have to go into stocks
or you have to buy property or you have
to diversify
and an end and at the end it really
comes down to you to your preference and
let me give you an example
so andreas antonopoulos came up with the
example of people
flying first class second class and
comparing that to the crypto industry
i think i've got a better one and it's
traveling so i took here
something out of new york google maps
if you if you're in bergen section and
you want to go to a restaurant in the
odeon
then there are multiple ways on how to
get there yeah so you have got
as you can see you can go by car you can
go
with public transport it'll take you 33
minutes but if you're somebody that
doesn't have a car
33 minutes is perfect if you say hey i'm
a health person
then let's walk now we're walking one
hour nine minutes
double is long or moto bike or maybe by
boat
whatever i mean whatever suits you
better whatever you like
that's the preferential way to get from
a to b
and that's the same thing with investing
so if you're a gold park and you believe
in gold
if you are a bitcoin maximalist and you
believe in bitcoin
and that's the only thing that exists
for you perfect i
totally support you so that's one thing
the other thing is just to put some
clarification into okay
i'm interested in cryptocurrencies i
want to invest but how do i do that and
there's a lot of confusion right
yesterday somebody
that you know that we're always saying
here not your coins
um uh not your crypto and
that person was asking me but
i don't want to do anything i mean what
do i want to keep it on an exchange
i want to keep it on robin hood i don't
need to have a wallet
perfect no argument it's just
that that's the preference that you
choose and i've got here i published
that already a while ago
just like like a little recipe on how to
progress with currencies in case you
want to really get your feet wet and so
on
so the phase zero is really when you
absolutely have got no idea you've never
done it before
then use only exchanges like kraken or
coinbase.com
i prefer kraken because they have got a
fantastic support
buy uh transfer the fiat so us dollar
canadian dollar
into that exchange and buy one of these
three top coins xrp
sorry that is uh now a little bit
outdated i would replace this with
cardano
but this is the slide that i used i
think three four months ago so bitcoin
ethereum cardano
those are the ones i would recommend as
a top three coins because they've got
the lowest volatility they're stable
they're in there for the next
at least year bitcoin will be there for
much longer yes i know
and then keep those key cards on the
exchange yeah if you keep them on
kraken.com
no problem uh i doubt that kraken will
be
uh disappearing in the near future
they're a really good company as i said
now that's the real beginner's one yeah
you no problem with that
go and start investing into
cryptocurrencies this is the way to do
that
now phase one is a little bit more
complex so you go
same exchanges but you add also binance
in the u.s binance to
us because they don't binance.com is not
allowing us customers
but they created binance.yes is the
environment so that's
binance and then you take the top 10
clients
and but you need to do some research
first because if you don't do research
and you invest in the coin
that was hyped up like dogecoin i'm sure
you heard of that coin recently
then um yeah you might in be
in for a surprise and then go step by
step i mean start learning what defy is
if you want to get really curious then
learn what yield farming is but i think
these two phases will keep you occupied
and will build a nice portfolio that way
that will keep you hopefully
very healthy in regards to your finances
so um that's it from me today i hope
you like that uh little digression
into philosophy but i think it had to be
said because
uh i had too many discussions in the in
the last future
of people totally confused on what to do
and how to do it and so on so
yeah that's it from me so i wish you a
fantastic week and thank you very much
for watching
bye thank you robert just a reminder
that we're not providing financial
advice
but only sharing what's happening in the
cryptocurrency markets always remember
that the cryptocurrency markets are
ever-changing and always volatile so
only invest
what you can afford to lose
[Music]
you