i'm gonna show you how to turn a zombie
or skeleton spawner
into a zombie and skeleton experience
grinder you're gonna need that
experience do lots of enchantments and
this is a great way to get all the loot
that the zombies are dropping
so stick around i'm going to show you
how
today we're going to teach you how to
make a zombie and skeleton experience
grinder
now if you've been following our series
on minecraft and some of the
other videos that we've shown you you
know how to set up a server
on a raspberry pi you know how to get
started in your minecraft world
and now we're going to show you what to
do if you're in the middle of mining and
you come across
a spawner now specifically this is for
zombies and for skeletons
it will not work for your spiders your
cave spiders all that kind of stuff
a zombie and skeleton grinder is
essentially
a tool for funneling
spawned mobs into a focal point so that
you can easily kill them
and collect the experience and the loot
that drops from them
so we're gonna go and i'm gonna show you
kind of what you need to do to get
started
and what you're gonna end up with as
your final product
as you see behind me this is a spawner
you can see that there's a little tiny
zombie spinning around inside it looks
like a
kind of a jail cage and if you're mining
you're going to come across one
eventually it's in a small room that's
about uh
maybe 10 blocks wide and this will
create
an infinite supply of of mobs that are
going to come at you as soon as you find
it you want to
a kill the mobs that are there but b you
also want to disable
the spawner and you do that by putting
torches on all of the sides and on top
and that's going to disable your spawner
at that point you can start working on
the giant box that's going to go around
it
that's going to funnel everything over
to a system like that
now before you get started you're going
to need to have an infill
infinite water source because you do
need water for this build
and so with that i want to show you how
infinite water works
so we're going to empty this out
and the water disappears if i add a
water bucket to one side
it flows over and you can see how the
water tapers off and you can see that
directional flow
from left to right if i then try and
collect the water in the center
nothing happens if i collect it over
here nothing happens i collect that
block it disappears
so to create an infinite water source
you need to create
three blocks wide of a hole and put
water on
either side and then that center block
fills up
and i can start collecting it and the
two blocks on either side with water
are going to fill that up so you now
have an infinite infinite supply of
water
now to get started with your grinder
you're going to need several things
a sign you're going to need a couple of
those you want to bring at least
four you're going to need your building
blocks for
this monstrosity beside me now most of
that you'll be able to make with
cobblestone because you're going to
collect that as your mining anyway
you're going to need your water bucket
to create your infinite water supply
you'll need a hopper to collect the
drops from the mobs after you kill them
you're going to need some metal or some
slabs so you can use stone slabs
you can use wood slabs whatever you want
as long as it's a half
block height you'll need torches and
you'll need
one block of soul sand you can collect
that from the nether
which is the kind of like the underworld
of minecraft and your scaffolding which
is
dirt that's the simplest it's the
easiest scaffolding to use
now before we go into the zombie grinder
and show you kind of what it looks like
we're going to take a quick break and
then i'm going to give you all the
details you need on how big that space
needs to be
in order for your experience grinder to
work really well
[Music]
so now that you have found your spawner
for a zombie or a skeleton you need to
dig out a
massive room around it
the room that it comes in is only about
10 blocks wide
you need to dig out significantly
further because the mechanics of
minecraft when it comes to these
spawners
is it will spawn that particular mob
within five blocks of either side
up down left right wherever from that
spawner and so you wanna have a room
that goes five blocks wide on either
side
and five blocks above and below
and as you can see in here that's what
this room
fits and i've i've used some marked
blocks here so you can count you've got
one two three
four five blocks above the level that
the spawner is
and one two three four five blocks below
if you do not make this room five blocks
above
blow all around you have the potential
of of
the zombie or the skeleton spawning
outside of that box
and then it's not going to work as well
when you are done making your giant room
like this
and it has to be a square you're going
to need to place water
on the two outside corners
opposite of where you want your mobs to
funnel
so i'm going to put one here and i'm
going to put one
here now as you can see the water
doesn't go
all the way across the floor and so when
the zombies spawn in here the water is
going to push them
but it's only going to push them so far
so we need to make
an adjustment to this room that's going
to allow them to go even further and so
for that i'm going to take you to the
other room that i've made so you can see
everything
in completion
so what i've done is where the water
runs to you can see the edging of it
i've removed one block in so that the
water then flows
over the edge of those blocks and pushes
to the center
and with those two water sources in
either corner
all of the water funnels to this section
right here no matter where
the mobs spawn in the room
once you have done that you need to
clear
all the torches from the room and place
a slab
on top of the spawner the reason why you
want to use a slab
is because the zombies will not spawn on
a half block
they will only spawn on whole blocks and
with that
slot being there no no zombie is going
to spawn on top of it
and then potentially stay there and not
want to fall off because you want them
to
spawn in the water and be funneled to
you now for the purposes
of this tutorial i'm not going to remove
the
torches but i will show you the rest of
the build
and how it works so the water then flows
into this little funnel point
now i've used it out of glass so that
you can see how it works
but you can use stone whatever you want
and when you get inside the tube
there's two signs the reason for those
signs is to stop the water in this
upwards elevator shaft so to speak from
flowing
back into that giant room
so the water will push the zombies into
here and as they pile up in this tube
they'll start pushing one another
into this water elevator now with the
mechanics of minecraft
you have to have soul sand underneath
water
to push them up it creates bubbles
that's going to push the zombies up and
in order to for this to work
you have to have a unique water block
every level of that channel
so there's a water block here a water
block here water block here and here
all the way up to the top and that's why
you want your infinite water source
because if i just put a water block at
the top the water is going to fall
all the way down and then you're not
going to get those bubbles it needs to
be unique bubbles every time
now with the mechanics of zombies they
are 20
health points plus two armor points even
if they don't have armor themselves
so when a zombie or a skeleton falls
they lose half a heart or half a health
point
for every block that they drop so if
they drop two blocks
they lose one heart if they drop four
blocks they lose two hearts
and because they've got 20 hearts and
two health points they can fall a total
of 22 blocks before that
wipes them out obviously we don't want
them to fall to their death we want them
to fall
21 blocks so with this
i'm going to call it water elevator we
need to make sure that we go up
high enough that it's going to push them
to the to the max limit that when they
fall
they're going to be completely reduced
on health but without dying
so we've got one two three four five and
each of these green blocks is five
your upwards elevator needs to be 5 10
15 20 and then 20
21 or 24 blocks
when you get to the top
what you need to do don't want to fall
down the hole there we go i did anyway
is you can see these bubbles that's the
bubbles that comes from the soul sand
and then there's a water source that's
going to
push them over the edge and i leave them
a nice message enjoy
the fall so that when the zombies come
down or the skeletons come down
they're going to be pushed down the tube
and fall onto your hopper and this is
where you want to have your half slabs
leaving just a small gap
where on the other side you can then hit
them at their feet
with just your bare hands and their
experience is going to go to you
the loot is going to fall into the chest
through the hopper and boom you now have
a zombie grinder
so i'm going to play the purpose or the
spot of a zombie in this case
and show you exactly how it works i am
not moving you can see that my hands are
off the keyboard control
it's just the water that's moving me now
i'm turning around
i've hit that point where there is no
water because of these signs so as
other mobs come in it's going to push
you into the elevator
pop me up and then down i go
that's the mechanics of the zombie and
skeleton experience grinder
and now what i want to do is hop into
the game and show you an actual working
copy
that's on the category 5
minecraft test server that we've made
for the show this is an actual
working zombie grinder in uh the world
and as you can see zombies are starting
to get pushed through
the room is actually quite dark
i'm not gonna open it up right now but
you can see through there that it's
quite dark there's no torches
and zombies are starting to spawn and as
this tube fills up
it's going to push the zombies up the
chute that continues up significantly
higher into the rest of the
the mine there and then they're going to
drop down
just over here oh look one's already
dropped um
and as they go up you know you'll see
there's this tube here that'll push them
up and then you're gonna see them drop
down here
and now this zombie that's been captured
in here oh there goes one and here's a
couple that's going to fall
and boom and you can see they kind of go
red when they hit the ground
it's because their health has been taken
away and so now i can just go over here
and a couple of hits and they're dead
and so two hits those zombies go and i'm
getting the experience from it and this
hopper is now collecting all the
resources
and putting them in the chest but in the
case of here we don't have anything in
this chest and that's because we've
actually made
a hopper system with many many chests
so there's the chest that they fall into
the hoppers continue to process
everything down
until you get to that bottom chest and
there's the flesh from the zombies that
i just killed
and that's how you make a zombie or
skeleton experience grinder hopefully
you've enjoyed this tutorial and you'll
be able to use it as you play minecraft
don't forget to like and subscribe lots
of good stuff lots of good content you
don't want to miss any of that
and just a reminder that the tutorial
world that i've got going on
you can download that at the link below
you can play with it yourself
see how it all works and then replicate
that in your own world
and uh stick around because we're gonna
have lots and lots more content coming
up and that's why you want to make sure
that you're watching
what we got going on see ya
[Music]
you