last time we got our colors looking the
way that we want but what you didn't
realize
is that jeff was sitting next to me that
whole time
jeff way to go keep him quiet that's
what i'm here for
setting up an interview shoot or sitting
on a set like we are right now
you might only have one camera let's see
how we can turn
that into several virtual camera shots
with just a few clicks
in davinci resolve in today's demo we're
using a single 4k camera on a tripod
and we're obviously stationary that
keeps things simple in the editing room
later
again comes down to planning our shots
ahead of time
now with only one 4k camera we're gonna
create
three 1080p full hd shots
one will be a wide shot where we're both
on screen
with another on robbie and then one on
me
so let's join future robbie in the
editing room to see how it works
thanks past jeff and welcome present
jeff
so we're always learning here at
category 5 technology tv
and i try to allow what i learned to be
reflected
in this series because this is all about
showing you the tips and tricks that
i use here at category 5 technology tv
and what did we just learn jeff
turn off autofocus turn off your
autofocus
also similarly you should turn off the
auto exposure on your camera
and that's going to avoid the light
changing but the autofocus in particular
you saw how it was phasing in and out of
focus that was the camera's fault
so we're going to learn how to turn this
one camera into these multiple
camera shots that we can do with davinci
resolve
so i'm going to jump right into it jeff
because we've got a lot to cover
and i want to try to be as meticulous
with this as
i can so that you can follow along and
actually kind of understand
what it is that we're doing the first
thing that i need to do though is kind
of go back
to the last video in the series which is
our color correction
i've already done my white balance here
let's jump over i've already
gone to my shot and corrected my white
balance using the doppler and i've added
a little bit of gain
and adjusted the offset so that my
colors are pretty good and everything
looks good
but i do need to now i've pulled back on
the things like the mid
detail i've reset that to default
because there are now two people
that i'm working with and i'm going to
have three camera shots inevitably
so i want to show you how to do that in
a multi-cam scenario it's a little bit
different
also you'll notice that i've removed the
vignette because we don't want a
vignette that's kind of weird when it
punches in on jeff's camera
and there's only half of a vignette
because it was on the wrong shot so
so let's get started with this um so
first thing i want to do
is well you notice that the audio tracks
are connected to
my video and so i'm going to right click
and unlink that so that my video track
is independent that's so that when i
switch cameras on my virtual cameras i'm
not going to have it
going in and out of the audio so um
first thing i want to do is kind of
punch in and set my framing the way that
i want it for
for my wide shot so this is going to be
my bass baseline jeff
just the the shot that we're going to
use when we're both talking basically
right and so i set the frame and then i
just kind of skim forward a little bit
make sure that we don't move
too far out of it and that looks pretty
good to me
the framing looks good so that's really
really simple as far as framing goes
but now we're not going to add a
vignette yet
but we do want to do the facial
retouching that i showed you last time
so i'm going to first create a parallel
node for jeff
and we're going to add facial tracking
for you
once we've got you on there there we go
now let's bring down your mid detail uh
first of all let's zoom in a little bit
so that we can see what we're
what we're actually accomplishing here
ready jeff i am ready here we go
photoshopping you
by just dragging down my mid detail just
want to pull out
any blemishes i should start with me so
that you're not offended
look at you with your perfect complexion
oh i don't know about that but i'll take
it
all right okay so now just frame his
face here
a little bit better yeah the other one
was too wide i'm trying to lose weight
yeah you know now it's okay to go
outside but you don't want to go inside
because
you're going to lose some detail on the
on the edges or have too much detail
where you don't want it
okay so now we're going to do facial
tracking for jeff so what do we want we
want pan
tilt probably not zoom because the
stationary camera is not going to be
going in and out it's it's where it is
rotate is not necessary and definitely
not 3d and let's rewind the track
and start tracking jeff
okay you're done jeff excellent
beautified for the entire video so now
you'll see jeff if i i'm going to zoom
out a little bit
now if i skim see how that thing follows
your face oh yeah
it's actually doing the touch up on your
face there so i want to do the same
thing to me i'm going to rewind to the
very beginning of the video
i'm going to create another parallel
node alt p
and highlight that and add a circle
now you copied from my file
instead of the main file does that
matter what do you mean i copied
well you so you i created a parallel
node so right
but i haven't do we're doing color
correction there's no files involved in
this
no i understand but you did a you
created a parallel file off of mine so
does that mean yours is also going to
have my
no this is parallel so it's it's like
layered effects
ah okay so i'm i'm adding effects to
this shot
and my main shot is this guy up here
okay so everything that i add to it is
being added to that
ah that makes sense yeah so i'm gonna
put
this around my face just like we did
with jeff
let's get in there so you can see how
much of a difference i'm actually making
on my noggin
yeah there it is this is bald and shiny
all right get it around there make sure
we're at the very beginning of the track
i mean you don't have to you can do
reverse tracking as well
but because i've lined it up to the
beginning of the track because see
if if my face moves i would need to
change the positioning
so there it is it's nicely lined up and
we're going to go into tracking
and hit play not the normal play but
this play for tracking
and that's actually tracking me notice
the settings are the same as jeff's
because i haven't changed them
if i zoom out
just continues to track
so all i'm doing here is
basically touching up my face
[Music]
so i haven't yet all i've done is
tracked it with jeff i
i did it on the like in real time um
what i'm going to do now is i'm going to
adjust my mid detail
and see how it's kind of remove the
blemishes from my face without blurring
it without making it look
overly falsified and now that we have
those two
tracking tracks look at how perfect our
complexion looks
we are just a stunning group of people
see that
so there's jeff's there's mine
now we're ready to create our individual
camera shots why did i do that on the
on the wide shot well this way i don't
have to re-track
on each of our individual zoomed in
cameras right
so now i've got this baseline to work
with that i can duplicate
and just change the zoom level for the
camera so i'm going to jump back here
and now i'm going to copy this with ctrl
c
i'm just going to jump over here control
v and then pop it
onto the first additional video track so
now i have
two videos that are identical but see if
i zoom in on this one
i'm going to bring this up to just a
little more than two
let's say 2.3 and bring this over to
jeff
and this is now jeff's camera shot okay
so if i turn off that shot it's going to
be back at our wide shot
see that okay not the greatest shot
there we go let's find one where we're
both smiling
oh i like that it's a good one there we
go
over to jeff wide shot so the wide
shot's great for when we're both talking
and then when jeff is talking and then i
need one for me too so because i want to
keep the same zoom level it's
really really easy just to copy jeff's
track and then paste mine
and on mine i'm just going to simply
move the position
to me i want to get see that thing on
the top right i want to crop that out so
i'm going to kind of position it like
that i can still see the shadow but i'm
not overly concerned
especially because my what is going to
cover that vignette
so there we go all right so now we're
set and ready to do vignettes so
we've got our wide shot we've got our
jeff shot and we've got
our robbie shot so let's start with our
wide shot
i'm going to click here and now i'm
going to add a new serial node
and this is going to add to our
main shot and we're going to create a
vignette so we do that by adding a
circle
and we're going to make that big
basically consider that this is the lens
of your camera
so we want it to be as big as the shot
and then we're going to feather the edge
a little bit with this red one here
just like that now i'm going to
decrease the gain and you'll notice that
it's making the whole
shot really really dark and that i did
on purpose so that i could show you what
it's actually doing because now when i
invert that selection it's just doing
that
on the outside of the circle right see
that so we've got this nice vignette
on the outside so i'm going to do the
same thing on jeff's shot
so let's jump over here and bring up his
color correction notice how it's created
another copy here but it's not got the
vignette
because i'm working on jeff's shot and i
haven't yet added a vignette to jeff's
shot so on jeff's shot we're going to
create a serial node oh
not there we want to highlight that and
put it there
and add a circle and jeff you know what
to do
that's right you go to the edges of the
camera yeah there we go and then you
want to pull your feathering out
just a bit adjust your gain we're going
to invert and
lower the gain see what we're doing
there look at that
beautiful all right now next up is
robbie
as soon as i have enabled that shot now
when i jump over to my color correction
you see that there is a robbie shot
so highlight that alt s for add a serial
node
add my circle make it approximately the
same size i want to hide
that shadow that's on the right hand
side there from the drape system
and add some feather and keep me right
in the center of that
and invert and lower the gain on the
edges
there we go so now we've got these
beautiful vignettes
for all of our shots look at how already
that just looks
so much more professional yes it does
beautiful
okay save your work and now what we want
to do
is create the magic
because now we've got these three shots
and you could go
old school if you want to and start
editing those
all by yourself and cutting out pieces
and
that's extra time oh my goodness no we
want to make this super
brutally easy so what i'm actually going
to do
is i'm just going to right click on my
iso shot so this is the actual camera
file
in my media browser here my media pool
i'm going to right click and go create
new
multi-cam clip using selected clips
and you can name it if you want i'm just
going to hit ok
and now if i right click and open that
in my timeline
oh so notice sorry this one has a little
icon on the bottom left so that is my
multi-cam shot this is the actual
file so the multicam shot i want to
right click on
and open in timeline and it looks like
this so
it's basically reverted the shot to the
original shot which we don't want so
what am i going to do
highlight and delete now back at my
main timeline where i created those
three camera shots i'm going to open
that one
in my timeline and i'm going to cut
those three camera shots
that i created i'm going to go back to
my new multicam shot
open that one in my timeline and paste
it in
there we go so now we have a multicam
um shot that has these three cameras i'm
gonna call mine
robbie so that's robbie
okay when it's on this one is jeff
and this one is wide
okay now i'm going to jump back to my
main timeline
and you'll see that there's no video
because i deleted it i moved it to this
multi-cam shot here
so i'm going to turn off my inspector
change
the view mode to multicam and you'll see
that we've now got two black windows
we've got no video whatsoever but now
i'm going to drag this multicam shot
down
into my timeline now it's all it's
already timed to
my um to my audio
so i don't have to worry about that you
may need to line that up if you've
manipulated that now i need to make sure
that i have just video selected because
i don't want it to do anything with my
audio
just video so that's at the bottom here
and now with
this uh with this multicam shot
highlighted jeff i'm gonna hit play okay
now watch what happens as we're talking
so we're talking talking
talking and all of these shots are
moving you can see the vignette over you
you can see the vignette over me
and now as i'm talking i can actually
click
and it will change the camera shot okay
so if you're okay and down in your
timeline it's doing edit points
i want to show you that in just a moment
so as i'm talking
here we go
now watch here comes jeff right
so i can switch back and forth but then
when we're both talking
i click on the wide shot and it switches
back and as you say jeff
what it's actually done is it placed the
edit point
on my timeline okay so now
if i go back to inspector and just play
my
video this is what it looks like
[Music]
and just fast forward a bit here comes a
switch see that
wow switches are right like that so you
can actually control the camera shot
there's our fuzz
just by clicking on that timeline oh to
the
multi-cam editor here and you can have
as many cameras as you want presumably i
mean i think it supports something like
somewhere around that but so you you can
do it that easily now to take it one
step further jeff
you can use your keyboard what how
wide is one jeff is two
robbie is three so now if i
press play it's going to play just like
it is and notice it's replaying
everything at the top left as well
now i'm gonna push three oh no two
because you're talking so i pushed two
on my keyboard
now i'm pushing three so i'm actually
pushing the keys on my keyboard
okay to switch so i can do it really
really quickly
and i can just sit back and i can be
doing my editing like
this that's amazing now if you mess up
here like you've got all the edit points
right
so oh jeff is talking oh no oh no but
it's still pointed at robbie so
what i can do is i can either rewind
push play and then press 2 to switch to
jeff
or i can go back to my traditional
editing mode which is to say
clip like that and then i can right
click on it
and i can go switch multicam clip to
jeff
oh that's amazing so a couple of
different ways you can correct that
awesome yeah so there you have it folks
multicam editing
with vignetting on each of your virtual
cameras
right in davinci resolve remember
davinci resolve
is available to you free of charge
you don't have to have the studio
version until
you have to have the studio version i
always say like start with the free
version
and do all this stuff until you need
more
that's right and that's when you can
start looking at the commercial version
but there you have it folks
what do you think comment below let us
know what you'd like to see here at
category 5 technology tv how we do
things
we are going to be getting into our
audio end of things over the coming
weeks
so make sure you catch those here in our
series on
how to how we create content for youtube
it's not the defacto this is how you do
it
but i'm going to show you how we do it
and maybe you can glean some ideas and
get some tips that
you may not have thought about and maybe
get some really cool
abilities capabilities that you didn't
have before
so thanks for watching everybody don't
forget to subscribe give us a thumbs up
see ya
[Music]
you