this week the studio comes together just
a little more
as i install ameridroid's easy portal to
get cables from the bridge
to studio e and while we're thinking
about ameridroid we'll give away a 25
gift card to one lucky viewer becca's
got your top news stories
including toshiba exiting the computer
manufacturing business
a possible flaw in the modern debit card
that led to a teenager
being able to spend 20 000 of his mom's
savings and we'll talk about a giant
asteroid that apparently has an
ocean at its core robert koenig is here
to help us
make wise investment decisions in the
cryptocurrency market
this is all coming up so strap in it's
time for the tech
[Music]
our live recordings are trusted only to
solid-state drives by kingston
technology
revive your computer with improved
performance and reliability over
traditional hard drives with kingston
ssds
category 5 tv streams live with
telestream wirecast and nimble streamer
tune in every week on roku cody and
other hls video players for local
showtimes
visit category5.tv ah
welcome back we are back we're back
category 5
technology tv is on the air
i had a bit of downtime did you get any
downtime uh i'm always
on downtime oh okay yeah well hey that
was really really nice thank you to our
community for
continuing to support us through that uh
just a little bit of a break
yeah uh we've been doing this show for
13 years and that's the first time we've
ever
literally taken a break yeah that's true
uh we've had some down time because of
moving or doing but we're working
working working
right yeah power but that's the first
time i've actually just taken some time
with my family
and it's it was just very enjoyable so
thank you very much
speaking of the support of our viewers
the show would not be possible without
your support
and i do want to give a real quick shout
out i've got a big long list here
of some particular viewers who um who i
want to
make mention of so just to say a big
thanks to bp9
scott barkley ron morrissette jerry
kowalski
jonathan garby jens nissen ameridroid
nomen5
bill marshall and nycad now you folks
supported us through the kickstarter
campaign to get us into this space
of course there are a lot more of you as
well who participate
in the show and supporting the show
through our patreon
at patreon.com category5
that's a cool way to support category 5.
that's awesome tv i mean the kickstarter
was to get us safely into this space
get us out of the old studio and into
this one during a pandemic
yeah but the the patronage is what
keeps us going every single month that's
right i can't believe how quickly the
first of the month comes up on us
and you know keeping on top of the bill
is doing well that way
and it's largely thanks to your support
and i appreciate that
very very much uh that makes a world of
difference for us here at category 5 tv
and and we're working on getting some
things done and and part of that
is um is going to be unveiled tonight
with ameridroid's
easy portal a really cool
simple device we've talked about it yeah
and i don't want to get too much into it
right now but we've talked about how
owning a 3d printer may just be a way to
save money by being able to create cool
things that
do a good job yes and easy portal is one
of those products
bo at ameridroid came up with that it's
just so practical
and so just so you know it's basically
an easy conduit through a wall through a
desk through
ceiling tiles whatever you want to go
through and it's completely customizable
but bo has designed it
and made it so that he can 3d print it
at ameridroid so
what we're seeing tonight is 3d printed
yes
yes that's flipping so you can order
those
uh we actually have them through you'll
you'll see the links below but
also just go to ameridroid.com i'll
mention the coupon code in just a couple
of moments
time but what
i love about 3d printing and when bo did
this
created easy portal specifically because
i
said like how am i going to hey bo how
am i going to get through this wall i
got this stupid
abs pipe running all the cables into the
studio
and uh and he came up with this solution
to go through you know
drywall and six inches of air and and it
just made me go
wow bo can like
invent and create and then
3d print to bring his invention to
reality and it's like that's what we
live in that's the world that we live in
as far as how far technology has come
it's mind-bending to me it's true
it's not just ameri droid he's a marine
vent yeah
there you go but it just makes me think
that
3d printing is like hey that's the next
big thing i think it's around to stay i
think it has been for a while
i'm behind it right now it's the thing
but there's been
such a such a slow adoption in the
older community and i'll say the older
community but
like the those of us who you know were
working with computers in the 80s 90s
it's i think maybe that's a
generalization maybe that's
us here in canada maybe it's a little
different down down south but
um i find that we're very slow to adopt
these types of technologies because it
seems like a fly by night it could fail
it could disappear but now i'm seeing
the reality of hey 3d printing you can
do some amazing things
i think also the the big challenge with
3d print printing at the
onset was the cost like if you wanted to
get a
3d printer do you remember when the
toyota 3d was on was on our show
and it was like 2 000 and at the time we
thought that
wow thousand dollars for a consumer 3d
printer
that's fantastic right at the time there
were four thousand dollars yeah
well now you can actually go to our
website category five dot tv click on
shop and you'll see
3d printers there for 250 bucks which is
amazing
what i know well they do a better job
than those two
three thousand dollar units it's true i
love that we can go to our local library
and what we could we could 3d print like
sans pandemic
yeah well yeah exactly yeah we used to
be able to but you could
you could 3d print out the library i'm
like this is how much 3d printing is
has become more readily accessible and
it's like
man now i want to get a 3d printer at
home just to print some cool stuff with
my kids
you have to if you want to do any 3d
printing because all the maker tech
spaces and everything at least here are
closed
yes like we have uh we have um
tech spaces where you can you know you
use well just before the pandemic we
were able to go and
just pay a certain fee for an hour's
like
worth of 3d printing or whatever now you
can't so
but you can get a 3d printer at home
yeah or you just know america
yeah but but this is my point
bo owns 3d printers yes and so when you
say oh i wish i had something to do this
he can go
okay i'll invent it and then i'll print
it and send it to you that's
mind-blowing just totally cool that is
so awesome
and i'm thinking about okay so now we
are in a situation at home
i mean the kids are supposedly maybe
going back to school i don't know if
that's a good idea
but if they do they have to wear masks
it's mandated we have to wear masks
any time we're in in a public space so
even here at the studio
the only reason we're able to take our
masks off right now is because we're
distant from one another and i'm
propelling my moist spittle this
way that's a little nod to our prime
minister
that's right um but um it's like
i'm thinking about having a 3d printer
and being able to create hooks
so that because you've got to wash these
things we i've been buying the uh
like the reusable right so you can wash
it and reuse it
right so you know that's that's pretty
cool but you gotta wash it so then i'm
thinking okay a 3d
printed hook system in the laundry room
that just has a whole bunch of hooks
and like whatever it's just like i could
just do that
easy peasy if i had a 3d printer so i'm
going to work it worth it
got to work toward that yeah i want to
remind you folks
another way you can support us and even
just to know that we're producing videos
is to go onto linuxtechshow.com
click on that subscribe and the bell so
that you receive the notifications
anytime we post new videos
and we are going to be posting tons of
videos and in fact jeff
when we left studio d there were
there was a bank of videos already
pre-produced and ready to go online
right that never went up because because
yeah yeah so those videos are gonna be
going up so it's gonna be really really
weird
um over the next little while you're
gonna start seeing videos coming out
that seem
new that feature jeff and sasha yeah
so sasha and me and jeff standing at
studio d those are coming in the next
coming week so yeah i miss sasha hi
sasha hi sasha
now okay speaking of um youtube
and subscribing how many subscribers are
we at now
oh what were we put me on the spot jeff
i don't know because do you want to
bring up linux techshow.com
well because i know at some point was it
was it the last
was it the last show at some point i do
remember something about you
uh if we hit a certain amount of
subscribers
you were going to i do have to do a
dance yes yeah are bound now
so so we meet we met and exceeded twenty
five thousand
so we did get there yes so i've i've
been working with a uh choreographer i
am very slow going on this because i'm
terrible
i am not a dancer folks so but that's to
come
that's something you have to look
forward to what kind of dancing like she
has salsa or no she's integrated um
she's got
like um a little bit of disco
picking the apples she's got a little
bit of
like head bobbing allah the orville
and the macklin dance moves um
she's got she's got all kinds of crazy
stuff so
uh the matrix where i gotta i have to
fly back like this
and so this is all part this is all like
so i gotta just get the timing right
get the groove right figure out what i'm
gonna do with my feet and my hands
i can't and my face so that's coming in
the future
it is coming in the future yeah you know
what else is coming in the future
that's right jen and i were talking
about this today because someone is his
wife
yeah it's my wife we were talking about
the you know
the the kickstarter that we had to get
into the studio and and how there was
this
big uber unobtainable nobody's ever
gonna do it
[Laughter]
what i thought was a joke oh let's just
throw something crazy on that
to to go through simulated labor and
we still have to schedule that because
somebody was nuts enough
to actually i love nuts people
you know who i'm talking that's right so
we've got to schedule that and
yeah we do like we've gotta get it's
been a weird time and this is the weird
thing it's like okay well when do we do
that i'm not allowed to
physically be any closer than this to
jeff
i know so maybe we'll talk to jen and
see if she can
hook you up and do some of the work for
me the whole point
i'll stand back is 500
500 paintballs yeah they pelted with
sasha was gonna
shoot me so we got to get her back here
exactly but see our borders are closed
at the province level so she can't get
out of her province into our province
because she's had to move out east
too bad there wasn't a way to like
simulate
like uh use a raspberry pi with a 3d
printer i thought about this too
a 3d printer to create a device that
would allow remote shooting
through the app of a paintball gun
so that sasha could do it remotely but
then i thought if ever i created such a
thing
i am opening a pandora's box because i
don't want to be involved
in creating a remote
targeting and shooting system so it's
like there's
uh i don't well just don't put it on
github
it won't be on my thingiverse yeah
that's right oh that'd be
that'd be fun so anyway that's coming
but i was saying to jenna i'm like
when it comes to that we should almost
do like a a a
an extended broadcast and
for the simulated labor just be sitting
here doing the thing and just like
normal contractions you don't know when
they're coming on
oh you won't know and have some
interface where oh that sounds good
where
the oh the where our contributor can
hit the buttons and adjust the levels
crank it up to 11.
yeah and just and how does that sound uh
it'd be neat if we could do that for a
program
so take five years to develop that i can
do
it's not going to take five years four
years
oh man yeah i can already figure out how
to do that yes
all right folks so if you want to help
me turn a tens machine
into an app-driven cloud-based device
and then be involved in controlling said
device
while connected to this guy's gut don't
do it while his wife is standing by
laughing hysterically
the things we do for tech oh yes it's
good
all right well i mentioned the easy
portal from ameridroid
we have that to show you in just a
couple of moments time before we do that
though ameridroid
of course as you know is a company based
out of california we
love them and uh beau and his wife have
been
here rosemary to visit well not here
uh in studio e but um studio d to visit
the show so get onto our website
category5.tv do a quick search for
uh do a search for beau luchnowski
no just just search for ameridroid or
something but yeah um
and and you'll get to see that video and
and it was really really neat to have
them join us but
now we're you know we're finding neat
ways to work together because i i just
love this company and you know we talk
about right now in this time
shop local i'm up here in canada
ameridroid is down in california but it
still feels like i'm supporting local
to shop through ameridroid versus
shopping through say amazon
or some of the bigger companies that
that you can buy things from and even
buying even so much as to say
rather than buying directly from a
vendor like the manufacturer of sbcs
i'm rather i rather buy through
ameridroid so that i'm supporting them
and i'm also in turn supporting the sbc
manufacturer because obviously
ameridroid gets them from them at a
discount as well so
so it's a cool way to to sort of let it
trickle down through a really great
company ameridroid.com
uh and i want to help you to be able to
to shop there
so um back before my vacation time i
mentioned hey we're going to be giving
away
a 25 u.s gift card for ameridroid.com
and jeff
us you 25 us like a billion dollars
canadian a billion dollars
so jeff has come up with a novel way to
figure out
who is going to win because we have not
got everything set up we can't do a
proper draw here
so you've come up with an app yes okay
yeah and so thank you for your ballots
by the way we had some
i printed out some that um you know that
said some really nice things about
ameridroid maybe we can look at those as
well
absolutely and and some of the ideas
that they have but do we just get right
into it so for a 25
gift card for ameridroid yup
okay so i've taken all the ballot
entries i've placed it into the app
and it's like a uh prize wheel yes it's
a it's a prize wheel
and so it is completely randomized i
will flip it right here so you
don't see can't even bring it up on the
screen it's spinning it's spinning
william bauman nice you are the big
winner
what does williams say did i did i print
williams uh you did that's how i got it
oh
fantastic okay let's tell you which one
it is
all right uh william says doesn't tell
us where he's uh viewing from
but says that uh he'd like to put this
gift card toward getting a night vision
for his raspberry pi
oh very cool how cool is that some of
the things that you can do with a
raspberry pi and a camera
are awesome making and ameridroid is a
great company to talk to about those
kinds of things so would that be more so
for like security camera at home kind of
thing you could use it for that
you could use it for uh yeah i mean for
surveillance it's great because it's an
actual you know camera attached to a
single board computer so you can do a
lot more with it
you'll be able to set it up for rtsp be
able to use it
to automatically upload to ftp sites
whatever you want to do
or i like the rtsp uh idea
being able to stream it to like a dvr or
something like that as a
as a network camera much cheaper than
buying like
a full integrated camera kit that's oh
yeah yeah
so thank you everybody for your ballots
um and
uh we really really love reading through
your stories and the things that uh that
you hope to do with
uh with things that you purchase off of
ameridroid of course check out
ameridroid.com
and they have um a plethora of
uh spcs single board computers um so i
get raspberry pi's there i get odroids
and pine 64 devices that you see on the
show
plus i i don't i haven't seen arduino
boards however there are arduino pieces
like
like sensors and things like that and
and that you can add to your raspberry
pi
uh arduino is neat because you can
connect it to the gpio or the
the sensors and things like that and be
able to do some really cool things
we've done a couple of things like the
thermal sensor yeah i could see your
hand
and then i'm thinking we could use that
we could use that to to
check people's temperature by pointing
at their forehead like they're doing
right now right
we use that same device so there's all
kinds of stuff at ameridroid.com plus
easy portal which you're going to learn
all about right after this quick break
stick around
[Music]
remember any time you shop on
ameridroid.com use the coupon code
cat5 tv supporter at checkout no matter
what you're buying
you'll get a buck off your final total
and 10 of the sales profit
will be donated back to category 5 tv to
help us produce videos like these
we moved into our new studio space in
the height of the pandemic
contractors weren't allowed to work at
the time and even hardware stores were
closed
so i couldn't get a conduit installed to
run cables into our studio space
from the production room nor could i
even buy a hacksaw to cut up the single
piece of abs pipe that i had on hand
so i simply made do by drilling a hole
between the two rooms
and i laid the abs into the hole and uh
that was just there to protect the
cables
and it's makeshift and it's messy but it
got us through the past few months but
now i'm ready i want to make find a
basically a solution that is going to be
more permanent and it's going to look
better
so i started looking into ready-made
solutions out there
uh and stuff that i could do myself
without having to hire someone else
with you know all the mad skills to do
contractor work and everything i wanted
to be able to do it
save some money as well so as it turns
out ameridroids
easy portal product is exactly what i
was looking for it's designed
for running cables between rooms you
know for networking or things like that
but ideal for basically any type of
cables if you need to go through walls
or through the floor
uh through a desktop or ceiling tiles
it's really really easy and it's much
more tidy looking and it protects your
cables as they're passing through as
well
easy portal doesn't require any special
tools or skills to install which is
perfect for me
no skills when it comes to carpentry and
things like that but
as long as you've got a hole saw which i
do or some
other kind of tool that will be able to
cut the whole
to the right size for your easy portal
depending on which one you buy
easy portal provides a clean pass
through for your cables and it's
complete with the finished flange which
i'm going to show you
up close and personal here on both sides
of the hole
it's customizable to meet your needs
with port diameters
all the way from itty bitty ones like
this
half inch to two inches
and this guy here is the two inch
model or maybe a little bit bigger than
that uh this one is a custom one that we
had built
um but i have a three inch hole saw
in order to drill uh the hole that i
need for this particular easy portal so
keep in mind of course the diameter
is the inner diameter so when you're
ordering it that's the size of the hole
not the actual size that's going to be
required for the hole through your wall
so just keep that in mind um in addition
to that
the thickness of your wall can be
anywhere from 0.4
inches so very very small
to 16.15 inches so the smaller one is
really ideal
for say something like the ceiling tile
so this is going to be great when we're
doing
lighting if you need to hang a projector
in your projector room or something like
that with a drop ceiling
this will go perfectly on the tile so
you just drill the hole screw it
together and you've got this
nice little pass through for the cables
to go through
and of course you can choose the
diameter if you need something wider for
the hdmi cable or something like that
you can go with something that's going
to be you know smaller this way
but a little bit larger as far as the
whole diameter goes
if you contact ameridroid at the time of
your order you can even custom print
your easy portal
in any of the 13 colors that they have
available so in my case
i actually wanted to have a different
color on each side of the
of the wall with the green being in the
main studio since that matches our logo
color
and white in the production side because
the walls in there are like a light gray
so while there's a modest fee for the
second color
ameridroid was even able to accommodate
that request so it's
very very custom plus as i mentioned
this is an oversized version a little
bit bigger than what's
generically available on their site so i
just requested that we get a
larger conduit for the amount of
hdmi cables and things that i have to
pass through for the studio and they
were more than happy
to oblige me on that so very very cool
easy portal are custom and they are 3d
printed
at ameridroid so i want to be clear
about that
due to the very process of 3d printing
you're going to get some
kind of imperfections visibly
but you can see that that is not
affecting the performance of the
the product at all so that just screws
together
and clamps onto the wall very very
simple but
very very nice so the imperfections are
you know it's not going to affect your
usability whatsoever but if you if
that's a problem for you
just keep in mind these are 3d printed
products so you can see here there is a
little bit of imperfection on the
visible area
it's very very minor and you could
actually just like any 3d printed uh
product you could if you wanted to
use a fine grit wet sandpaper and sand
that down if you wanted to
you could paint them if you wanted to
but again
the imperfections are just because of
the 3d print and i think that is
very very good and in fact this you know
i'm i'm
quite impressed with this it's it's
really really good quality
and exactly what i needed so let's see
how easy it really is
and get the easy portal installed so
that's the hole
in the on the bridge our production room
leading out
into the main studio so um so you can
see all the wires here
going in through the uh the pipe yep
so we'll just pull that through and
no effort whatsoever to do uh to do the
installation you'll see but
uh for me it's just getting all this
stuff out of the way man
i forgot how big and bulky that pipe was
oh jeff all right all right
speaking of big and bulky check out our
old lights that's right now we're all
led so anybody want to buy some
some old lights now here i'm actually
kind of measuring all scientific like
uh the size of the flange to make sure
that the whole
because i did pre-drill a hole for the
pipe so i needed to actually
make this hole a little bit higher which
is a little bit difficult because i
already had a hole there but
i i was able to just kind of quickly
figure out how much room i needed for
the flange
and you can see on the other side and
now there's actually a little bit of a
broken space
on the lower part of the other side of
the wall you'll see that in a moment
here
even better jeff um man it's nice and
flush
yeah so but here on the other side so i
came through from that side so that it
would line up really well
yeah but i think that um previously
there was
some there was another hole there that
wasn't patched properly so that's why it
kind of cracked
at the bottom there right however my i'm
lucky
because the flange is big enough to
cover that so even though
you can see how bad it looks right there
on the other side of the wall
it covers it up yeah the flange is big
enough that it uh that it
really does cover up any of those kind
of like the damage look
see that wow that fits so smoothly it's
perfect
so that looks and i like that it covers
up my
horrible hack job but so super simple so
i'm just
do it by hand and we wondered if it
would spin and i needed someone on the
other side and nope
it worked perfectly incredible so i'm
pushing that through
so much easier now to run cable um
through the wall and it's only going
through that wall i don't have to feed
it through a big long pipe
which was part of the problem i couldn't
i couldn't feed
xlr cables through because there's no
way to push them through a 10 foot pipe
that's right yeah so now i've only got
six inches to go through it's perfect so
so here what i'm doing is i'm i'm
binding the cables together
um using a uh like a uh winding that i
i picked up off amazon um so that
that winding just kind of makes it a lot
nicer it makes it like a snake
and binds all the cables together so
then i can kind of hide them
uh in the easy portal so you don't see
anything other than that snake sticking
out
you don't have this mess of wires like i
did before
which is kind of what we're up against
here at the studio because you have
so many cables going to all the cameras
and everything so
yeah wow that is so slick well done
ameridroid
i like how easy it was jim yeah i guess
oh
smart name easy portal look at that
so there's my so my snake coming out so
there it is on the back of the computer
going through the easy portal
and out to the outside
in the studio that keeps it so
clean so there you have it that's easy
portal
from ameridroid.com don't forget as
you're checking out use our coupon code
cat5 tv supporter
a buck will come off of your final order
but they will in turn know that you saw
this video
and they will throw some money in the
category 5 tv tip jar to help support
what we do here at the show so i
appreciate that very much whether you're
just trying to pass some cables through
your drop ceiling or wall or desk at
home
or whether you're a contractor i mean
these are very practical very easy to
install
and anyone can do it if i can do it and
uh they're
very affordable too so because of
because of the customizability
i think there's just no end to what you
could what you could do with these
so you know in our case here we
installed one between the two studio
spaces for all the hdmi cables
but you can obviously do more these are
going to be used for the lighting
that we're going to be hanging off of
our drop ceiling so we're going to get
to that as well
but you can get them on ameridroid.com
just make sure that you reach out to
them when you place your order to
request your specific colors and things
like that
thanks for watching
[Music]
so
welcome back this is category 5
technology tv and our website
is category5.tv jeff it's great to see
you it's nice to
kind of have everything slowly getting
back to normal and yeah
having you know this is this is how
things are at the moment but
um lots of things are going to be
changing over the next couple of weeks i
don't know
um perhaps you know if you follow us on
if you're a kickstarter supporter or a
patron you you have a bit more
of uh well a lot more of behind the
scenes
knowledge about what's going on um so
in the next couple of days uh so the
contractor is going to be back again
tomorrow
so he's done some work on we're yeah
we're doing some more backdrops we've
got
i've got all kinds of backdrops that are
going up into the system so that we can
pull down different colors and things
like that behind us
we've got some really great stuff that's
happening we're getting the
the the wiring is going to be finished
and right now
the easy portal has made it a lot better
to get the cables from the cameras and
things like that but they're still like
the tv
that we're looking at when we're on the
air and some cables are hanging down
from that and i've got an extension cord
going to a power outlet so
all that's being hidden in the walls and
everything else so there's so much that
has to be done and
i'm so eager for things to get to the
point where
we can have an open house and have
everybody in and and
show you around um and there's already
plans in place that
uh regardless of whether that can happen
in person
uh we are going to be doing a virtual
open house so awesome
so there will be an opportunity to have
a tour de la studio
if regardless of whether you're local or
remote or able to come and visit us or
not
there will be that opportunity so i'm
really looking forward to that yeah
that's exciting
and we'll shoot you with some paintballs
while we're at it
sure so we've got to head over to the
newsroom
here is becca here's what's coming up in
the category 5 dot tv news room
toshiba shuts the lid on laptops after
35 years
the discovery of salt bound to water
molecules on serra's the largest
asteroid in the solar system
suggests that there may be an ocean
lurking beneath the akitore crater
a convincing phishing scam is targeting
targeting
cpanel users with a fake security
advisory
a teenager has spent nearly twenty
thousand dollars in twitch donations
with their mother's debit card and
google is creating a worldwide android
phone-powered earthquake
alert system stick around the full
details and this week's crypto corner
are coming up
this is the category 5 dot tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
it's official japanese giant toshiba has
sold its final stake in the personal
computer maker dynabook
which means the firm no longer has a
connection with making pcs or laptops
sharp bought 80 of toshiba's personal
computing arm in 2018 for 36 million
dollars
27 million pounds and has now bought the
remaining shares
toshiba said in a statement toshiba's
first laptop the t1000
1100 the t1100 launched
in 1985. it weighed four kilograms and
worked with three and a half inch floppy
disks
according to the toshiba science museum
website it was launched only in europe
at first
and had an annual sales target of just
ten 000 units
in the year 2011 toshiba sold more than
17 million pcs
but my how times have changed by 2017
this had fallen to just 1.9 million
in 2016 it had ceased making consumer
laptops for the european market
focusing only on hardware for businesses
recent years have been difficult for the
conglomerate in 2015 the firm
posted a full year loss of 318 million
dollars
that same year its president and vice
president resigned
after an independent panel found the
company had overstated its profits for
the previous
six years last year they wound up their
nuclear business new gen in the uk
after failing to find a buyer for it
consumer demand for laptops has soared
in the last few months because of the
coronavirus pandemic
and global lockdowns but overall the
market for personal computers has been
tough for quite a while
analyst marina kocheva from the firm ccs
insight says only those who have managed
to sustain
scale and price like lenovo or have a
premium
brand like apple have succeeded in the
unforgiving pc market where volumes have
been falling for years
the results of a major exploration
mission showed monday that the dwarf
planet sarah's
long believed to be a barren space rock
is an ocean world with reservoirs of sea
water beneath its surface
maria castine christina de santiff from
the national institute for astrophysics
in italy says of the discovery i'm
extremely excited to find some evidence
of liquid water
together with the fact that this body
has a lot of minerals very interesting
for the formation of life
it's a good combination of chemical
compounds that help in forming
biological molecules
desancti and her colleagues analyzed
high-resolution images in sarah's
of ceres taken by the dawn spacecraft
which orbited the dwarf planet between
and 2018 before it ran out of fuel
in his final phase the spacecraft
orbited just 35 kilometers above the
surface of syrez
focusing on the aquitar crater she
and her team were able to identify salt
by comparing data
including images and spectral analysis
from the dawn spacecraft with equivalent
analysis of chemicals here on earth
earlier observations of bright deposits
on the crater had hinted at the presence
of salty water underneath
but the discovery of hydrated sodium
chloride provides much stronger evidence
of an underground ocean
impact fractures on the surface of the
aquitar crater analyzed in a separate
study
suggests the ocean is some 40 kilometers
below the surface
although the exact size is unknown it's
pretty large says
the snake tea adding that the present
such a large body will certainly have
influenced the geology of sores with
water coming up from below the surface
and bringing minerals with it ralph
jaumann
of the free university of berlin in
germany says
the mineralogy is unique and so far not
observed on
other solar system bodies jawmen says
these findings demonstrate that even
small bodies like sores could have water
in their interior
a clever phishing scam is targeting
cpanel users with a fake security
advisory alerting them
of critical vulnerabilities in their web
hosting management panel
cpanel is administrative software
commonly installed on shared web hosting
services
that allow website owners to easily
administer their site through a
graphical user interface
starting last week cpanel and web host
manager whm
users began reporting a targeted
phishing email campaign
with an email subject of cpanel urgent
update request
that was pretending to be a security
advisory from the company
this fake advisory stated that updates
had been released to fix
security concerns in cpanel and whm
software and recommends all users
install the updates
in addition to a well-worded email with
little or no grammar and spelling issues
the threat actors use language commonly
found in security advisories
the attackers registered the domain
cpanel7831.com
to make the scam appear as a as an
authentic advisory from cpanel
and are using amazon's simple email
service ses to send out the emails
if a recipient of this phishing email
falls for the scam and clicks on the
update your
cpanel and whm installations
they were brought to a website that
prompted a user to log in with their
cpanel credentials
as this is a well done and convincing
scam it would not be surprising if some
users fell for the scam
if you received a similar email recently
and entered your login credentials at
this site
it is strongly suggested that you
immediately log in to your web hosting
provider
and change the password on your account
you should then perform a complete audit
of your site while paying extra
attention to the addition of strange php
files
that can be used as backdoors also be
sure to examine the website's
dot h t access file for changes that
automatically inject malicious code
into every web page or redirect visitors
that's an interesting story because for
a lot of people who don't have a lot of
background knowledge in web development
to be able to go to a
diy web hosting service where you can
build your own website with your own
cpanel
it seems like such an easy thing but
most people wouldn't have that tech
knowledge
to recognize a phishing scam when it
came to the cpanel sure and i mean
some of the stuff that they get access
to if you give them login credentials
can really cause problems
yeah like if they have linux access yeah
but yeah certainly i mean the any like
cheap hosting solution is going to have
some kind of a
portal whether it's cpanel or otherwise
but you think about cpanel and
and as you say a novice user
signing up for the five dollar hosting
account not
really up on the latest security trends
yeah it could be dangerous same thing we
see with wordpress
you get a wordpress site because you
think it's easy to set up and administer
yourself but
you don't realize necessarily i am
generalizing but
maybe you don't realize that that leads
to
major security implications if you are
not
on the up and up it's true super careful
so for somebody who's sitting there
going
uh i do my own website i just happen to
update myself your
cpanel i just gave my login to these
hackers
like what i i know that you know becca
covered in the story you know
checking some certain things but what
are some i think
well she hit on the the first thing i
would do is check for any
recently modified files and on a linux
server it's really easy because you can
do a find
dash m time and and sort by the time
uh that the file was last modified okay
and so
you can see any file that was modified
in the last
10 days and if you don't you know if you
uploaded your site
six months ago you know that hey those
files are suspect so you can just look
at them yeah
yeah because it's not like a virus it's
not like you're running a virus scan
and find the malware no it's like
perfectly legit tools that they're using
to allow them to con
command and control your website yeah or
even going so far
using the wordpress example of creating
users
cpanel same thing maybe they create
users maybe they add
uh an smtp account so they can use your
mail server for
sending spam that's right that's a big
one yeah so if somebody doesn't have the
tech knowledge to go in take a look at
their account
what's another way that they could deal
with that
go through the hosting provider and say
hey can you check my account
jeff if you if you really have that low
of a knowledge when it comes to that
kind of thing
you shouldn't you shouldn't be doing
yourself hosting right
realistically if you're for sure if
you're not familiar with terms like ftps
ftp
and what the difference between those
two things is ssh
ssl smtp pop3 imap
if you don't know what any one of those
terms are
mysql mariadb if you don't know what any
of those words mean
then self-hosting is not for you that's
right
um again i'm b in general
but that's those are red flags for me
and and you don't want to find yourself
in a situation where yes
i'm saving money on hosting but i
part of that is that you are
relinquishing
the desire to pay someone to
maintain that's right and putting that
all on you
so it works great if you're
knowledgeable and you're getting the
five dollar a month hosting account or
whatever
right as an example because you're able
to do that maintenance yourself but this
is where
church websites become illicit websites
yes and other business websites become
defaced
and data theft occurs and
some companies are you know irreparably
uh
have their reputation damaged yes
because of these things
um well and also if you have a website
where you're doing any monetary payments
you know if you're if you're receiving
customer payments like that's even
that's a whole other can of worms you're
getting into there jeff well yeah but
you've got to be careful for that kind
of stuff so
please please please number one change
your password just like becca said
number two start going through the files
on your server to make sure something
hasn't changed
if you haven't logged into your cpanel
for an uh security update
chances are you're probably not hit by
this but if you did
you need to start doing some checking so
good advice good advice
we've got more coming up a teenager has
spent nearly 20
000 in twitch donations
on their mother's debit card and google
is creating a worldwide android phone
powered earthquake alert system
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert is here with the crypto corner so
don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome to the world of cryptos and
welcome to the crypto corner
now it has been an interesting week
hasn't it let's take a look at it
if we look at coin gecko which is my
current favorite
directory then we see that the market
cap has increased since we spoke last
time
to 364 billion with a small decrease at
the moment of 2.7 percent
which is normally nothing unusual there
if we look at the top coins also nothing
unusual here well we've got chain link
with minus 8
but it had an increase of 40 already 40
in the last seven days and as always we
sort by those seven days and then the
picture changes significantly
normally we have got around 15 to 20
coins that achieve more than 15 percent
this time we've got over 50 coins
achieved more than 15
and i guess that one or the other of you
is uh contemplating in investing in
cryptos now
and then i'd like to just uh give you
some recommendations
the first is if somebody recommends
something to you
just be very careful because um
not everybody has got your best interest
uh
in mind and um and you can do the same
research they are doing so let's take a
look at here band protocol that's an
oracle like chain link
if i click on this one here i'm just
showing you how this
this system works then we have got here
the current price uh here is the website
so if you click on this here you it will
be read
you will be redirected to the website
medium.com that's publications
uh etherscan this is an erc20 coin so
based on ethereum
um then you've got the writ reddit
twitter telegram so that's whether you
see
the community talking about this coin
and
if we scroll a little bit further down
then we've got the numbers of this coin
so um in the last 30 days band increased
by 600 percent
um currently we've got a retracement of
uh also i would say this is normal here
and if you're interested
in buying something then there's some
interesting numbers like for example
example
what was the all-time high it was 17
so that's uh uh one day ago
as you can see here one day ago with
chief all-time high here
and the all-time low which was november
25th on
2019 so nine months ago it increased
seven
uh 6 399 from that day
so that's interesting statistics so
probably i would not invest in something
that
just had its all-time high because
i assume that short term there will be
no significant growth in it
if you're interested in any way buying
then you click here on
markets in markets you have got
all those exchanges listed that are
that are trading where you can trade uh
banned so on binance you have got two or
three possibilities one band with usdt
with tether with bitcoin and with the
binance coin
here you see the price so of course
there will be all
more or less the same and then you've
got the debt the debt
means how far can you go before
there is a significant impact on the
price
yeah so if i go for example in to hot
bit no idea what type of
exchange it is and i want to buy four
thousand dollars
then i will get significantly uh higher
price
than those thirteen dollars thirteen
whereby if i've got thousand dollars to
invest in binance with finance
then it will have no effect of this the
price i will get
so this is how you read the my plus two
percent and a minus two percent it's a
it's an interesting number if you want
to invest in coins because some of those
coins
that people are recommending as the next
big thing
i've got absolutely no liquidity and
then it's difficult to buy something and
it's very difficult to sell also
something
yeah and and once you have bought
i my recommendation is always not your
keys not your coins
so um my the recommendation is as always
to put it either on uh on a ledger
which is this here or on a trezor which
is this year
um because that's uh currently the state
of art in regards to
the security of of cryptos
if you're planning to buy one of those
then go only to the original website
um and by there don't buy it on amazon
because you can i heard
sometimes uh some of those uh hardware
wallets have been compromised so always
go to the original it takes you probably
four weeks or three weeks longer to
receive that
device but i think that investment is a
very important and very good investment
otherwise be very careful in where
you're investing
do your research don't trust i mean
listen to what experts have to say
whether they recommend band or
channeling or whatever they recommend
but then do your own research
i showed you how to do that so you go
into every website
and see where you want to put your money
there
and last but not least also be very
careful with exchanges because they're
exchanges that
are dangerous so i mean finance
uh coinbase and so they are here from
the western world you can
more or less trust them although i would
never keep i said never keep any coins
on those exchanges
um but but you never know if you have to
do kyc in other words you have to
give your passport picture or driving
license address telephone number to
these exchanges
you don't know what they're doing with
that like in the case of coinbase
they said that they're going to sell
your data so i don't know if that's in
your interest
anyway that's it from me today so i hope
uh you enjoyed you learned something i
wish you a fantastic week and i
really hope will be uh seeing each other
next week again
thanks bye bye thank you robert and just
a reminder that we're not providing
financial advice but only sharing what's
happening in the
cryptocurrency market always remember
that cryptocurrency markets are
ever changing and always volatile so you
should only spend what you can afford to
lose
i don't like it when robert says things
that make me scared
it's like yeah i gave my driver's
license to coinbase
should i be worried now robert comments
oh i don't know while we're thinking
about that
we're going to throw back to becca in
the newsroom thank you robbie
a teenage twitch viewer sent nineteen
thousand eight hundred and seventy
dollars usd to several streamers
using his mother's debit card over the
course of two weeks
the teen's mother found the charges
toward the card between june 14th to
june 30th
years of savings were taken from her
account over the two-week period
she says these donations went to popular
streamers on the platform
the mother who has decided to remain
anonymous to protect her family
says that nearly all the money she lost
has been credited back to her account
after struggling to contact anyone at
twitch to discuss the issue the woman
successfully received a refund
from the streaming sites paying service
zola
using the company's online chat feature
she got adjusted credits on nearly all
transactions but in exchange was told
the account is permanently blocked to
prevent future unauthorized charges
before contacting sola however she
attempted to communicate with amazon and
even resorted to sending a registered
letter to twitch ceo
emmett shearer when all else failed she
tried contacting her bank
but they could only provide further
assistance if she was willing to press
charges against her son she found out
about sola by discovery by
discovering other parents online who
also had found
success in similar situations although
she was able to receive most of her
money
she said hitting a brick wall with
twitch was the most frustrating thing of
all
the fact that no one would respond and
there was no way to speak with anyone
was horrible she said
that was probably the worst the son is
remorseful according to the mother and
is going to counseling
he's also been limited to one hour of
monitored daily playtime
with a stipulation that he must do
positive activities throughout the day
get exercise and interact with the
family in a positive manner
you know as a father of young kids
are very engrossed
in youtubers and yeah yeah yeah all that
kind of stuff
this story makes me go whoo
am i glad i'm not giving my kids my
debit card
when i first got an amazon fire tv stick
uh i made the mistake of not setting a
pin
oh no and of course you're logged into
your
um your amazon account yeah so
um i was at work and suddenly my phone
started blowing up
i'm like what is going on so finally i
pulled out my phone because i'm getting
all these notifications one after
another after another
and i look at my phone and i'm seeing
amazon charges
one after another after another to the
tune
of 450 dollars now
nothing like 20 000 but this was a case
where my son was playing a video game
yeah
and he determined that if he put zero
zero
zero zero as the pin because that was
the default
yep that he could buy anything in the
game
not realizing not realizing it was
actually my credit card
so did you get it refunded i did amazon
is fantastic that's good for that kind
of thing so they reversed it and and no
problem whatsoever but i can just
i can feel that stress that this woman
must have been going through to realize
twenty thousand dollars gone from my
debit card
and and that makes me think
like is this a failure in our
electronic system right now i mean i
think this about tap
and how three four years ago at the
toronto santa claus parade
somebody had a tap receiver
attached to their phone you know how you
can get these devices and they went
through the parade and they stole
20 at a time just by yes approaching
people's pockets
yes and so walked away with thousands
and thousands of dollars and
i don't even know i never heard if they
ever got caught oh i'm sure they would
have everything's tracing
yeah so it but it just makes me think
about debit cards how they have the visa
logo now yes and so like that has
happened to my wife
um she had a visa debit yeah and
remember when debit was the safeguard
right i remember that
i want to say it was maybe two years ago
yeah um she went to use her debit card
and she couldn't use it
and she was like what's going on oh no
went online and found out that her
account was locked
for suspicious activity so she looked at
it so at least they're doing that
right yeah so she so she looked into it
and over the course of
three days there was hundreds of dollars
in food purchases
from all over california using
uh the visa debit function so somehow
somebody had gotten her
visa debit information yeah and was
making food purchases and so
because it operates just like a visa
exactly yeah and so it was no big deal
to do like 20 bucks to this pizza joint
and 30 bucks to this restaurant and so
whoever was was doing it now thankfully
she got all of her money back it all got
uh you know returned
but i mean in the case of this story so
i mean there's a couple things here one
is
how did the kid get the debit card or
was it just registered to the
justice but second you'd think the bank
accounts
most debits have a daily limit of a
thousand dollars
true and so if he dropped 20 grand over
a two-week period
either she had a higher daily limit or
there was no limit on it
i'm thinking mama has 20 000 in the bank
she probably has a higher limit than i
do well that's probably true
i don't think i've ever had twenty
thousand dollars not all at once maybe
just before my mortgage payment came out
just after that
i put the money in that's right yeah
yeah but
but the other thing is the fact that you
know
there are kids that are out there
they're going i want to donate to my
favorite
person and i mean right my kids are
always talking about their favorite
youtubers and
uh you know our son with his chromebook
like i you know i have an email for him
because he's at the age you can have an
email now
and so i have the you know master login
for his email
and every once in a while i'll just
check up on what he's doing and i'm
finding oh
he's commenting on different youtubers
and i'm going
okay i need to have a conversation with
him about internet awareness and whatnot
and so i'm now very aware of what is
linked up to that account
could he purchase this kind of stuff and
so you have to think very security
conscious as a parent
if you're going to start handing online
accounts to your kids
that's a tough tough situation now my my
producer is is giving us the look that
we
need to move on sorry but i'm a blabber
as a final thought on this particular
story as a content creator
on platforms like youtube uh a twitch
creator
who you know that's that's the biggest
like
fear and burn and even i'll be honest
with you and
some of you may or may not know this but
even having had
such a successful kickstarter campaign
right up until the
moment that the money's in the bank
you're you're on the edge of your seat
as a content creator
thinking what if they back down right
what if
you know i've i've basically budgeted
these funds that have been donated
what if they retroacted that
that would be a real bad situation for
me as a content creator
so to these content creators who
received that twenty thousand dollars
from this child from this teenager
and then had it reversed where did that
leave them like that's such
a hard situation so we need to be there
need to be things put in place to
protect
those content creators the kids the
parents um there need to be
you know i hate to say regulations
that's not what i'm talking about but
but maybe twitch is irresponsible maybe
they're
partly to blame for this maybe there's
something that needs to be said
about that conversation and that's all i
go down i don't know
all i'm doing is just opening that box
and just letting you dive in to comment
below
what are your thoughts we're going to
throw right back to becca google is
creating a worldwide android
phone-powered
earthquake alert system the first part
of that system rolled out tuesday
if you opt in the accelero accelerometer
in your android phone will become one
data point for an algorithm designed to
detect
earthquakes eventually that system will
automatically send warnings to people
who could be impacted
it's a feature made possible through
google's strengths
the staggering numbers of android phones
around the world and clever
clever use of algorithms on big data
as with its collaboration with apple on
exposure tracing and other android
features like car crash detection
and emergency location services it shows
that there are untapped ways that
smartphones could be used for something
important to the community at large
google is rolling out the system in
small stages
first google is partnering with the
united states geogra
geological survey and the california
office of emergency services
to send the agency's earthquake alerts
to android users in that state
those alerts are generated by already
existing shake alert system
which uses data generated by traditional
seismometers
marx delgades principal android software
engineer at google says
it'd be great if they were just
seismometer-based systems everywhere
that could detect earthquakes
that's not really practical and it's
unlikely to have global coverage because
seismometers are extremely expensive
they have to be constantly maintained
you need a lot of them in an area to
really have a good earthquake
early warning system so the second and
third stages of google's plan will be
powered instead
by the android phones the company is
proceeding fairly cautiously though
in the second stage google will show
localized results in google searches
for earthquakes based on the data it's
detecting from android phones
the idea there is that when you feel an
earthquake you'll go to google to see if
that's what you felt or not
an android phone can become a mini
seismometer because it's an excel
an accelerometer that's the thing that
detects
if you've rotated it or not android
system uses the data from that sensor to
see if the phone is shaking
it is only on when an android phone is
plugged in and not in use
to preserve battery life once it has
more confidence in the accuracy of the
system
google will begin actively sending out
earthquake warnings to people who live
in areas where there are not seismometer
based warning systems over the long term
google hopes to create an api based on
its earthquake detection system
it doesn't plan on using the system on
iphones
but if the api comes out then apple
would be free to use it
more interesting though is what other
systems would benefit from an earthquake
detection api
for example somebody could build
something that automatically stops an
elevator at the next floor and opens the
door so that people can get out before
the wave comes
and you can turn off gas valves
automatically you can have something
that stops medical procedures or
open the door to fire stations ahead of
time that's a common problem in
earthquakes where fires are a big deal
and firefighters often just can't get
out
so you can build something that does
that airplanes can stop
landing as they're doing this aboard
their landing trains can be slowed down
there's an entire ecosystem that can be
enabled by using this android-based
detection
and having it publish server-side so
that others can plug into it
google's plan is to minimize false
positives and tune the system right away
and users near earthquake fault zones
will soon see
info in google searches and the
inevitable rollout of local
notifications
it wasn't long ago jeff that simon
weckert berlin based artist
took 99 android smartphones put them in
a red wagon
and walked down the main street that was
completely devoid
of vehicles and yet google's
map service showed that
there were traffic jams everywhere he
went right because there's 99
android phones so you know i hate to put
the thought in people's heads but this
is the thing with
an android-based system such as this
while it sounds amazing well it sounds
like
hey this is a very brilliant idea
how hard is it to take a raspberry pi
zero
and a motor and connect it
to one centralized server
and share the diagrams of that online
and say okay everybody i want you to to
build this take a raspberry pi plug it
into this motor put your phone in this
motor when you go to bed
and because it's internet connected they
can make it
they can set off all the phones
vibrating like this in any area of the
world where they have these devices
it'd be so easy it'd just be it's such
an easy hack so it's like
how can they trust that data well i
think it's
brilliant an accelerometer to detect
earthquake
well and that's the thing like this is
an amazing thing that they're doing
yeah but with amazing ideas also comes
the amazing ability to mess with it
thanks to
human beings yeah i mean not only were
terrible like
what if you have you know if somebody
decides to use it as a
uh a type of social attack so to speak
where there's a group of 15 20 people
they all of the phones
they congregate in a particular area and
they just sit there and start shaking
their phone
and if they also synchronize it with
with
like raspberry pi's through the internet
like you could actually
like pick a spot and make an earthquake
on google maps because
you know it's just so it it'll be
interesting to see if that's
exercising oh really you got steps just
there
nice that's great brilliant just quickly
before becca wraps things up
uh robert k uh robert koenig from the
crypto corner says hey with coinbase
robby you should be okay
they are selling your data to the
government though and it says
i don't understand that because they're
centralized yeah yeah and i just
like can i assume that the government
knows everything about me anyways
but probably but the government issued
my would that be like irs tax purposes
yeah i suppose so but i mean
selling my info to the government so i
don't hold my crypto in
uh in a centralized um exchange at all
however i do use the exchange to
transfer funds between
us dollars and bitcoin for example so
um sad sac 963 makes a really good
comment about the debit card issue and
hack and a child being able to use mom's
credit card
and says what if the or debit card what
if these debit cards had 2fa
wouldn't that be superb so what if there
was 2fa on your debit card that somehow
you you know whether you pull out a
an authenticator token or or the
authenticator app on your phone whatever
it is that you need to
to use to be able to yeah i think that's
very very smart so thanks for submitting
that
becca big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom don't forget to like and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
well it's been great having you here
this week uh that's 660 weeks of
category 5 under our belt
so uh yeah it's been a lot of fun so far
and we've got some exciting
things to come you just check out our
website category5.tv
scroll down on the homepage and you'll
see some of that stuff that's up and
coming
also there is a a coffee break this
sunday at noon so make sure you you join
us for that
again our website category5.tv scroll
down find the coffee break and you'll
get the zoom meeting id
and be able to join us for that
community break
i will uh see you again next week it's
been nice having you here nice having
you here and
thanks for supporting the show everybody
you