covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias google says it
has wiped out its entire carbon
footprint by investing in high quality
carbon offsets
it became carbon neutral in 2007
and says it now has compensated for all
of the carbon it has ever created
chief executive sundar pakai has also
announced
that they intend to run all of their
data centers and offices on carbon free
energy by
twenty thirty they'll do things like
pair wind and solar power sources
together
and increase the use of battery storage
and bakai says they're working on ways
to apply artificial intelligence
to further optimize their electricity
demand and forecasting
while carbon neutrality demands a
certain level of scrutiny
the fact remains it is becoming
fashionable for large companies to work
towards sustainability
reducing their own impact on the
environment
microsoft for example revealed plans to
become carbon negative by 2030 back in
january
and both apple and amazon have plans to
become carbon neutral in the next 10 to
20 years
google's endeavor will also create
around 12 000 jobs
over the next five years
[Music]
you