here's what's coming up in the category
5 tv newsroom
the public beta of spacex starlink
internet service has begun
youtube dl has been hit with a dmca
takedown by the riaa
ubuntu groovy gorilla as raspberry pi as
a first-class citizen
zoom has added end-to-end encryption for
all for free
though there are caveats and will tell
you what they are
and a nasa spacecraft spacecraft
successfully touched down on an
asteroid to collect a sample stick
around the full details and this week's
crypto corner are coming up
this is the category 5.tv newsroom
covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight
linux bias
from the newsroom i'm becca ferguson
the public beta space of spacex starlink
internet service has begun
spacex has begun sending email
invitations to starling's public beta
and will charge beta users 99 per month
plus a one-time fee of 499 dollars for
the user terminal
mounting tripod and router the emails
are being sent to people who previously
registered interest
in the service on the starlink website
spacex is calling it the better than
nothing beta
perhaps partly because the starlink
satellite service will be most useful
to people who can't get cable or fiber
broadband
but the email also says as you can tell
from the title we are trying to
lower your initial expectations
the email reads expect to see data
speeds vary from 50 to
megabits per second and latency from 20
to 40 milliseconds over the next several
months as we enhance the starlink system
there will also be brief periods of no
connectivity at all
as we launch more satellites install
more ground stations and improve our
networking software
data speed latency and uptime will
improve dramatically
for latency we expect to achieve 16 to
19 milliseconds by summer
2021. there is apparently no data cap
a starlink mobile app to help beta users
set up and manage the surface also
just went live on apple's app store and
google play
elon musk recently said that the public
beta will be for the northern u.s
and hopefully southern canada spacex
plans to provide starlink to a school
district in texas in early 2021
but that doesn't mean the public beta is
available to anyone in the south
the wait may not be too long though as
spacex has said it will reach near
global coverage of the populated world
by 2021.
you know that starling story is an
interesting one because for so long
we have been hearing about this project
and hearing about how
it's going to change the face of the
globe with providing internet high-speed
internet to
you know unreachable areas so it's
interesting that
they're offering this beta version to
lower expectations
that's totally contrary to what
companies do they want to
heighten expectations so why would they
take that approach
when quite frankly if you don't have
access to internet
even to hear that you can get you know
50 make download speeds is phenomenal
sure like that that to me is great i
mean
but it's satellite you expect that
there's going to be downtime you expect
that there's going to be
interference from weather so i don't
understand why they
would call this about lowering
expectations like what were people
thinking they were going to well i mean
we know that it's meant to be really
really fast and they're saying
it's not yet there no so let's try it
out but no
it's not yet there yeah so i think you
know they have to set
expectations perhaps to avoid you know
complaints and things like that
but i think about like my you it's
it's hard for us to fathom if we live in
a city that there are places still that
don't have high-speed internet
i i'm literally thinking about my church
yeah
we are yeah you're just on the outskirts
we're less than a kilometer from the
edge of barry
we cannot get anything
internet wise other than sure your basic
dsl
our old studio studio d brutal same deal
my father-in-law is using lte internet
at home because they do not
have high-speed internet where they live
that's what we have at the church
that's unreal 200 bucks a month just to
have basic internet just for basic lte
internet
man so i mean like this star link for
the price it's going to be
could be a great option yes for you for
you then in that
case or for my father-in-law it's a
great option
and it's probably going to be better
than what they currently have so maybe
setting the expectations
low in that you know those of us who
have gig internet
going out and signing up for the new you
know this is the latest and greatest
from spacex right
so it's going to be the best well
they're setting the expectations low
purposefully so that it's the right
market yeah i i guess
if you're in a city where you've got
that high speed but if you have nothing
yes i mean what they're offering for
speeds is phenomenal it is
so i mean i'm i'm excited at first i
wasn't sure how i felt about this
project when i first heard about it
because i'm like oh
he just wants to space debris yeah
but now that i'm starting to see it roll
out
i'm getting excited about but what's
interesting is that it's upper u.s
possibly lower canada for their base
start
why not beta test in like a low cert
like
pick somewhere along the equator of
africa maybe
you know like some remote well it makes
sense though that they would want to
test it in a place where well think of
it this way
if if it went down i have something else
to fall back
on yeah i have the 4g infrastructure to
fall back on if i need it
so maybe that has something to do with
it i mean we're speculating here but
there there are so many thoughts yeah
but hey how
how does something like starlink affect
you is it something that would be better
than what you have or is it
a severe downgrade that's really what it
comes down to but i think in a lot of
cases this is going to bring
high-speed internet to areas that
currently don't have it and not only
that jeff
but we've hit on it in the past when
we've talked about starlink
and that's that in an event of natural
disaster
or infrastructure issues
it's an opportunity to still receive
good solid internet high-speed internet
that is not reliant on things like
towers
yes right now one of the things that
will be interesting is because
i mean this is not new like satellite
internet
is already well good satellite internet
what's new that's
that's the challenge here is uh i mean i
used to
another iteration of my working life i
was a
uh a recognized installer for satellite
internet
um so i have an inner working of or an
inner understanding of how it works and
it was quite
uh cumbersome and unreliable yep i mean
the dish moves just a slight bit from
wind right and you're out
so i'm really interested to see how
starlink's internet works in that regard
and if a little bit of wind
is going to knock it out or if it's a
more stable platform
time will tell maybe the beta test will
show some results so we'll see over the
next couple months
we've got to head back to becca youtube
dl
has been hit with a dmca takedown by the
recording industry association of
america
the ri double a has issued a dmca
takedown on the open source project
youtube dl on their github repository
this is done under the guise of
protecting content creators from having
their ad revenue stolen
youtube dl however is often used by
archivists and users who suffer from a
slow internet connection
in order to allow them to watch the
content there are of course those that
use it to circumvent ads but we can't
pretend ad blockers don't exist
which accomplish the same goal with less
effort so
are ad blockers next on the list here at
category 5 we're content creators
we post our videos on youtube and we
depend on the revenue it generates
but like the electronic frontier
foundation points out
we believe youtube dl is a legitimate
tool with a world of lawful uses
see we know we have viewers who are
watching in areas where internet just
isn't very good
we've heard from troops who watch our
show in their tents while at war
we have fans who live in areas where
high-speed internet just doesn't exist
yet
so we make sure they have access to our
content for free
with the hope that they will support us
through patreon if they're able
we received an email from a viewer this
week asking us how they can watch our
show while circumventing youtube
is it surprising that we the very
content creators who rely on the
revenue youtube provides responded by
providing bittorrent files of all 13
past seasons plus recommended the
download button found on the page of
every episode we publish
on our website as content creators we
understand the need for
revenue it costs a lot of money to do
what we do
but for the riaa to demand youtube dl be
shut down
seems shady the electronic frontier
foundation
fights these types of battles on behalf
of open source projects
you can help protect projects like
youtube dl by donating at
eff.org last week canonical released the
latest intermediate version of ubuntu
20.10
groovy gorilla which for the first time
adds first-class
platform support for the raspberry pi 4.
groovy gorilla itself is a pretty
typical interim release offering an
updated gnome version with lots of bug
fixes
and small feature additions support has
also been added for windows active
directory in the
ubiquiti os installer itself
and while it has been possible for some
time to install ubuntu on raspberry pi
hardware
up until now that has been strictly a
community effort
the pie itself ships with raspberry pi
os at debian based distribution whose
origins began with the pie community
but which has since been officially
adopted and supported by the raspberry
pi foundation itself
while canonical added the pi as a
supported platform in 20.04
earlier this year that support was only
for the ubuntu server distribution
not desktop with 20.10 groovy gorilla
canonical has added full desktop support
for the pi
4. martin wim press canonical's director
of engineering for the ubuntu desktop
says this means the pi is now a
first-class citizen
canonical guarantees the same level of
integration q
a and support from kernel to user space
that it does for a standard pc
the entire ubuntu software repository is
available and supported on the pi
of course that's other than
architecture-specific packages that
start with names like i386
and are therefore not compatible with
the raspberry pi's arm processor
if you'd like to install ubuntu 20.10
desktop on the pi you'll need a four
gigabyte or eight gigabyte raspberry pi
as long as you meet the hardware
requirements the install is a breeze
ubuntu 20.10 desktop is an option in the
standard raspberry pi
imager now the imager itself is
available for linux windows or mac
platforms to get up and running insert a
four gigabyte plus microsd
card open the imager choose ubuntu 20.10
and click
right a few minutes later you'll be able
to boot the official ubuntu 20.10 for
raspberry pi 4.
zoom has added end-to-end encryption for
all
for free though there are caveats and
we'll tell you what they are
and a nasa spacecraft successfully
touched
down on an asteroid to collect a sample
becca has these stories coming up plus
robert is here with the crypto corner
don't go anywhere
[Music]
welcome back to the world of cryptos and
welcome back to the crypto corner
this week i've got some really good news
for you um
if we look at the market by the time i'm
recording this year the price of bitcoin
is at 13
128 which is equivalent to 2.3
increase in the last 24 hours and 14 in
the last seven days
i think that's fantastic news and one
reason why i believe that
is if we compare it to the stock
exchange the u.s stock exchange
or the gold price then there is a
decoupling happening
it is not confirmed yet that will take
some time but at least there is a
decoupling at the moment
this is the charge chart since beginning
of october
and the red line is the red curve
is the u.s stock exchange
the blue is the gold price and so you
see there's a significant gap
especially since yesterday where we had
a huge drop in the stock exchange
in the air stock exchange uh to bitcoin
so i think that's that's great news it's
to be
expected because it's a complete uh
different asset commodity
and so let's see what will happen the
other
good news is paypal
paypal decided to get involved in
cryptocurrencies and so you can buy now
uh some cryptocurrencies on their
platform
and the great news is because they have
got over 340 million
users and you can uh by using paypal pay
for services and goods and you can now
use for example bitcoin to pay for
services and goods
but at least that the offering this year
to this huge community
is i think fantastic news also
one that i have to take with a smile is
our friends from jp morgan
uh one of the largest financial
institutions in the world
and in 2017 jamie dimon their ceo said
that bitcoin is a fraud and will blow up
jose said that he if he finds somebody
in his organization
uh trading uh cryptocurrencies that
person will be fired on the spot
now like in politics things can change
significantly and dramatically and so
this is
uh happened uh this was published uh two
days ago
uh by jp morgan where they're now saying
bitcoin has considerable upside as it's
better competes with gold as an
alternative
currency i find that fantastic news
because the
organization embedded in the old system
like jp morgan suddenly changes their
opinion 180 degrees
is for me extremely bullish not
financial advice
but for me that's a bullish sign so
um yeah one thing i'd like to focus on
is it's a question that a lot of people
are asking
us in regards to private keys and
public keys so i'd like to spend a few
minutes on that subject
and for that i pulled up a website
called ian callman.io because this is
uses um the web the
the content fantastically well and uh
so there's somebody in bitcoin or team
that came up with
this process of how to convert
a private key into a public key and they
expanded that and now a lot of
different cryptocurrencies are using the
same process and that's why it's called
bip 39 or bip 44
because this bitcoin improvement
protocol but other
uh currencies are using that so i just
gen clicked on generated on 24 words
and so out of a repository uh the system
generated 24 words and
that those are the words that you need
to remember when you generate
a wallet for example you create a new
wallet
the wallet will generate those 24 words
and those are the ones that you have to
remember because everything
derives from those 24 words so with
a little bit this little bit technical
here but from those 24 words
we deduct the private key from that
private key we deduct the public key and
that public key and then generates the
address
yeah so and the reason that is done is
that there is no way in the world that
you can get back to the private key
that's why
cryptocurrency is so secure yeah and so
what you do is you take the private key
you hash it that's a special
crypto cryptographic process and with
that you generate the public key
and the public key is hashed twice and
that generates the address
the reason that this is done is that
there might be future some computers
that are able to deduct from the public
key the private key
there don't exist yet but we're thinking
well ahead in the future and that's why
we are using the address as
the key that you send to other people
in case you want to receive some bitcoin
or so
so um this is all the magic behind it
it's based on those 24 words those 24
words generate the private key the
private key generates the public key
and the public key generates the address
and address is what we use
and that set is used in many other
ikea cryptocurrencies they use the same
same process anyway that's it
from me i hope you enjoyed it i hope you
learned something
um thank you very much for watching
please leave a like
it helps us we need to grow and um
yeah come back next week thank you very
much for watching bye
thank you robert just a reminder that
we're not providing financial advice
but only sharing what's happening in the
cryptocurrency markets always remember
that the cryptocurrency markets
are ever changing and always volatile so
only invest what you can afford to lose
now here's becca
thank you robbie zoom has added
end-to-end encryption to his video
conferencing service at no additional
cost for all users
whether they are paying subscribers or
not the feature has been long awaited
given the service's massive adoption as
a result of pandemic lockdowns
something that swung a spotlight on its
patchy security
the company announced on tuesday that
the new feature is available now as a
technical preview for the next 30 days
and is looking for user feedback before
rolling it out on mass
zoom see so jason lee gives kudos to
keybase who joined the company in may to
develop the security feature
taking just six months to do so zoom
says its end-to-end encryption will use
256-bit aes gcm
and a secure key exchange is performed
beforehand to ensure only the
participants on the call can decrypt
each other's part of the conversations
and no eavesdroppers not even zoom
itself can listen in
zoom already encrypted some of its
communications though it wasn't truly
end to end
until now in order to use the end-to-end
encryption an account admin has to
enable the feature
zoom's end-to-end encryption is limited
to 200 participants so for larger
meetings where encryption may not be a
needed feature
such as a public forum or a digital
comic con
it can be disabled to allow more people
to join
other restrictions of the service are a
lack of cloud recording and live
transcription breakout rooms polling and
one-to-one private chats are also
unavailable
when end-to-end encryption are on as are
live emojis
perhaps the biggest caveat of all though
is that each user must have the official
zoom client installed in order to
participate
so browser-based participation will not
be available for encrypted meetings
third-party zoom clients will also not
work when end-to-end encryption is
enabled
the feature is available on new releases
of the zoom software for mac os windows
android linux
and ios after orbiting the near-earth
asteroid bennu for nearly two years
nasa's osiris-rex spacecraft
successfully touched down
and reached out its robotic arm to
collect a sample from the asteroid's
surface
last week the sample will be returned to
earth in 2023
to achieve this historic first for nasa
a van sized spacecraft had to briefly
touch down its arm in a landing site
called nightingale
the site is the width of a few parking
spaces
the arm reached out to collect a sample
which could be between
two ounces and two kilograms then the
spacecraft backed away to safety
we have never done this before we're
actually going to collect a sample
and bring it back down to earth for
further examination by scientists
in order to achieve that objective the
osiris-rex spacecraft has been
navigating around bennu for about the
last two years studying
in great detail and also overcoming a
number of challenges
that bennu has presented we were looking
for locations on venue that were 50
meters in diameter
relatively flat and covered with fine
grained material and by fine-grained
material i mean stuff that's the size of
a dime or smaller
we realized that there were no sites on
bennu that even came close to meeting
this criteria
everywhere we looked was too small and
covered with boulders
so we actually had to fly a number of
additional close passes over the
asteroid
and rethink our entire plan for grabbing
the sample
the tag event is our touch and go event
which is where we'll actually be
retrieving the sample from asteroid
bennu
we start with a series of maneuvers one
of them being the checkpoint burn which
is where we'll actually check our
position velocity in relation
to the sample sites and then the match
point burn about 10 minutes later
we'll zero out our horizontal velocity
relative to the surface
and then about 10 minutes after that we
make contact with the tag sam
fire the gas bottle and then back away
and we hope to get
at least 60 grams of sample and then
we'll be able to store
that and bring it back down to earth
everything went perfectly based on the
data returned by the spacecraft
according to dante loretta
the mission's principal investigator and
a professor at the university of arizona
lunar and planetary laboratory he said
he feels transcendent
and the team is exuberant based on the
current data
loretta said in a statement after over a
decade of planning the team is overjoyed
at the success of today's sampling
attempt
i look forward to analyzing the data and
to determine the mass of sample
collected
we have to verify that we have a proper
sample
first we're going to image the tag sam
head by sticking in front of one of the
cameras then we're going to do a
maneuver called the sample mass
measurement in which we stick out the
arm and we spin the spacecraft
in order for us to decide if we've
collected enough mass to be able to stow
the sample
and return home or if we have to try
again preliminary data show the sampling
head touch bennu's surface for
approximately six seconds
after which the spacecraft performed a
back away burn
thomas zerbuckin associate administrator
for nasa's science mission directorate
said in a statement
a piece of primordial rock that has
witnessed our solar system's entire
history
may now be ready to come home for
generations of scientific discovery
and we can't wait to see what comes next
the mission which stands for origin
spectral interpretation
resource identification security
regolith explorer
launched in september 2016. since
arriving at bennu the spacecraft and its
cameras have been collecting
and sending back data and images to help
the team learn more about the asteroids
composition
and map out the best potential landing
sites to collect samples
the main event of the mission is the
touch and go sample collection event or
tag
that occurred last week the event took
about four and a half hours total to
unfold and the spacecraft executed three
maneuvers to collect the sample from
bennu
which could help scientists understand
not only more about asteroids that could
impact earth
but also about how planets formed and
life began
big thanks to roy w nash and our
community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 dot
tv newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe and
subscribe for all your tech news with a
slight linux bias
and if you appreciate what we do become
a patron at patreon.com
category5 from the category 5 dot tv
newsroom i'm becca ferguson
[Music]
you