here in our studio
i mean we've got to decorate right and
on the bridge i wanted an orville model
and sure enough we got one eagle moss
uh is selling these right now you can go
to cat5 dot tv
slash orville model and that's not an
affiliate link or anything it's just
so that it's really easy for you to get
to the website where they're selling it
there are two different versions of this
there's a 10 point some odd inch
version and then a five point somewhat
inch so basically half size and then the
full size the xl
which is what i'm about to unbox so i
had to
here in canada call up a local
comic book store because they wouldn't
ship it from the website
to us here in canada so i want to tell
you if you're unable to order it direct
give a call to your local comic book
store i call
big b comics here in berry ontario
canada
and they were incredibly helpful they
told me that it would probably ship
around october 31st
and here i am it's september 16th and i
already
have it so it's way ahead of schedule
and i don't know if they did that on
purpose just to impress me but i'm
impressed
and very very happy so just an
encouragement that if you can't get your
hands on one of these and you want to
make sure you give a call to your local
comic book store
because they're able to pull it off of
their order list
again i've got that hot link for you for
eaglemoss at cat5.tv
orville model but let's get in here
first of all the box
says ecv197
orville the uss orville was designed to
explore great distances and map
uncharted
space while the ship is an example of
the superior technology of the year 2418
its ragtag crew are a little less
advanced nice little summary there of
the orville let's get into the box so
this
is a diecast model from eagle moss
the official ships collection with the
orville
here we are okay so it starts out with a
16 page color booklet it's got the
design
specs ship profile right up about the
ship
exploratory class v vessel uss orville
investigates the mysteries of the alpha
quadrant
it's got some great pictures from the
show nicely printed
nice little keepsake there that's a
little bonus
cool
all right so let's get into the box and
see what do we have here
oh before i get right in here remember
back on episode number 628
tom costantino and brooke nazca showed
us a 400
000 dollar model of the oroville ship
there you go oh my goodness so this is
the actual model folks that was
that was used to shoot those 400 000
worth of fun kids
wow well this one is a little bit less
expensive
and will fit on your desk it's only 75
bucks for the xl about 30
for the small one and there we are
wow i am such a geek
i have this shirt i mean come on
and i didn't even have to buy this
special you know
okay so here we've got a base it's just
a black base i have seen some pictures
on twitter
uh with a glass base and i really really
love
that idea but i haven't been able to
find it so i think that that might have
been like a custom base that was
like for maybe for tom or something like
that so that just kind of snaps together
presumably
and into the box
it's cold the metal because it's a die
cast model
the metal is actually you can feel that
it is a metal model
that's cool it's got metal parts now i
can feel these are plastic
i want to call them nacelles we're going
to call them engine loops
the lower two are plastic and the top
one is metal part of the die cast so
this is
uh the cast model here and then the
attachments are
the lower two engine loops
and there you are
ecv197 from cat5
dot tv slash orville model again that's
just to get you there really really
quickly
and there you have it that's going to go
on our bridge as a little ornament
and a little bit of a homage to
tom and brooke and everyone else who put
the show together
and that will represent on our
on our bridge there you have it
beautiful
very nice
you