robbie i got a problem i'm not a
therapist jeff yeah i know but my
problem is
i want to explore some caves in
minecraft yes because 1.17 is out
minecraft 1.16.5 is for babies
but my pinecraft server is not where i
need it to be
also you've used pinecraft to turn your
raspberry pi
4 into a minecraft 1.1 6.5 server
yes i did but okay but i need to go to
1.17 yes and it seems kind of onerous
and we're going to throw a whole bunch
of numbers out there but really
it's super easy so you used minecraft 1
2.6
now we've got minecraft 2.9 and all that
to say
if you want to upgrade stick around
we're going to show you how
to get the latest version of minecraft
server on your pinecraft raspberry pi
this episode is brought to you by
ameridroid.com you need a raspberry pi 4
in order to build your minecraft server
so head on over
to ameridroid.com let's hop right into
it all right i am
ssh into my pinecraft server i'm going
to type
screen dash ls to show me that i indeed
have a screen running called pinecraft
so if i want to see that screen
dash r minecraft and there we go so i'm
gonna stop that server
and it's gone so i'm gonna now i'm
looking in my home folder i see the
pinecraft folder
if you installed this using our previous
video you could just do
git pull now i actually downloaded it
manually and installed it
so mine is not a git repository so what
i'm going to do is i'm going to actually
remove
that first and now i'm going to clone
pinecraft once again so exactly like
uh i was just installing it for the
first time but notice i didn't remove my
minecraft folder
i just removed my pinecraft installer
folder
so keep in mind you absolutely have to
have a
latest and greatest version of your
operating system the distro that's
running on your raspberry pi
if you did this with ubuntu 20.04
well you're going to have to upgrade to
ubuntu 21.
we're only looking at pinecraft
installer you need to head on over to
ubuntu.com get into the forums and learn
how you can use apt to upgrade your
ubuntu to 21.04
or otherwise if you don't mind losing
your work from previous
installations you could just re-download
the
the image file and create a new
pinecraft
server but we want to do this in such a
way that we are upgrading
our minecraft server without losing our
world files
so i've removed pinecraft but i've left
minecraft so that's still there i'm
going to get clone
https colon github.com
cat5 tv slash pinecraft and hit enter
and that's going to get me the latest
and greatest version
of pinecraft now i'm going to type sudo
dot slash install
and you'll see that we are on minecraft
2.9 now i want to
reiterate this as we record this video
we're on pinecraft 2.9
i am by no means telling you go get
minecraft 2.9 so if 3.2 is out
do this with 3.2 because we are
constantly
evolving this installer so that means if
you want the latest and greatest
always just simply go with the latest
and greatest version of minecraft as we
record this
it's 2.9 2.9 of course supports all the
latest features as of the time we record
this so i'm going to hit enter
and hit enter it checks my dependencies
goes through the regular steps i'm going
to speed right through this because
you've already been through it but i'm
going to show you some of the things
that are new
in minecraft installer first of all
you'll notice you no longer have to type
in your linux username it's
automatically detected my username
so i can hit ok what do you want to do
this is a common question
that we get how do i upgrade my
minecraft server well
you simply run pinecraft installer again
and you get this option because it
obviously detects that pinecraft is
already installed
and it asks you do you want to remove
the previous install and
reinstall which would lose all your
world files in progress
or upgrade your software so that's the
one i'm going to choose
because i want to keep my world so what
do we want
fabric paper spigot or vanilla i'm going
to go with paper because
i had previously used paper i could
easily change to fabric and that's okay
but then i might have some compatibility
issues with some of my mods
and i don't want to go through that so
i'm just going to install paper
and i'm going to choose survival because
that's the game mode that i was using
previously and i don't want to change
that
do i accept the eula yes i do
automatically load the server on boot
yes please
now it's going through the regular stuff
it's overclocking my raspberry pi 4 and
it's giving me paper one point what do
you see
1.17 that's what's going to be installed
so hit ok
and it's just warning me that it's going
to overwrite my config.txt so i say
yes robbie while that's installing if
somebody is
new to minecraft and they're going this
is my first time installing i realize
this is an upgrade video
what's the difference between spigot
vanilla paper and fabric oh boy
okay so i've got a link right there and
that link is going to show you a video
that we previously did with 2.6
that explains all of this information it
also shows you how to
connect to the screen session how to set
yourself up as an admin
all of those things remain the same so
just go back and watch that after you're
done seeing this video
or go through that video and come back
here we've covered a lot of stuff about
pinecraft installer
this is a product that we create to make
installing a minecraft server on your
raspberry pi 4
easy breezy there's no easier way that i
know of
and uh so i mean hey go back to previous
videos jeff that's the best way
okay and as quickly as that paper
minecraft server is installed
successfully hit okay
now if i go screen dash ls you'll see
once again
pinecraft is running well i stopped it
so let's see what's going on here
dash r minecraft look at this
it's downloading the vanilla jar it's
patching the vanilla jar
it's actually going through the process
so i can't connect just yet
because my pinecraft installer is just
kind of doing those finishing touches
to get everything up and running let's
let that go i want to remind you to
check the readme
on the github page for pinecraft the
links are in the description below it's
really important because it talks about
things like
your base os we often get the same
questions over and over again like
somebody saying
well i tried to install pinecraft and
it's only giving me 1.16.5
well that would be because the base os
that you're using on your raspberry pi
is not compatible with 1.17 you
absolutely have to follow the steps
to get the right base os similarly we
get questions
like it's only giving me two gigs of ram
but i have eight what's going on
well you again have the wrong base os
maybe you've got a desktop environment
or you're using raspbian or
raspberry pi os and that has a desktop
environment which is not allowed
with a headless server it uses too much
memory and so then you don't have enough
memory for your
minecraft server it's up and running
it's good to go i'm going to
go and hit control a d to
leave the screen session while leaving
my server running and let's fire up my
minecraft
java client and here we are in minecraft
1.17
on the windows client so i'm going to go
into multiplayer and direct
connection i've already entered the
server ip address of my pinecraft server
because i've been playing it previously
when it was 1.16.5
i'm going to join that server and lo and
behold
now ladies and gentlemen we are on
minecraft paper 1.17
on pinecraft this was done completely in
real time
and it was as easy as that you'll notice
i spawned in a village jeff any guesses
why that might be
uh because that's your set spawn point
for the server
it's where i signed off when my server
was 1.16.5
that makes sense and what that means as
we see this
is that my world is still intact
i didn't lose my world but now as i
explore beyond the boundaries that i've
already previously explored
it's going to start doing world gen
using the 1.17
world gen so i'm going to start getting
the new caves and
uh and inevitably other updates
that minecraft adds to that server
so that means that where you've already
explored for instance in a cave
it's not going to update because you've
been there it's already generated
right so keep that in mind you're going
to have to keep exploring
to see the additional stuff but as you
can see the world
as it is as i had already explored it
is still intact so that's all there is
to it i mean pinecraft installer
makes it absolutely simple
to install minecraft server on your
raspberry pi 4 but also
to upgrade it to the latest version as
it's released
so check it out the links are in the
description below
thank you so much for watching and
joining us again this week don't forget
to subscribe give us a thumbs up
and grab yourself a copy of pinecraft
installer it's
absolutely free we'll see you next time
and remember
if you're not having fun you're doing it
wrong see ya bye
[Music]
you