covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias inventor of the
world wide web
tim berners-lee is having another crack
at fixing the internet's biggest
problems
with the launch of a new enterprise
server
the inrupt enterprise solid server is
the first product from a company the
inventor started two years ago
in response to the problem of personal
data online
where tech giants like facebook and
google build vast databases on users
profiles
and sell them to advertisers to make
massive profits
inrupt has worked on a series of new
standards that allow individuals to
store their personal information in pods
whose access they control the
decentralized approach allows for the
free and fast sharing of data
but with control in the hands of its
owners the project is called solid and
after two years of work at mit
the team behind it has released an
enterprise service
the goal being to move the whole idea
from concept to reality
the enterprise server will allow
organizations to build applications
using others data pods
that can do useful things like draw
comparisons across users
or build greater context around user
data while keeping the user in control
of their data for many businesses it
will be a chicken and a conundrum where
it won't be worth investing
in the solid system until there is
sufficient data
and users of the system and users won't
bother providing their data until there
are sufficient companies and
applications
with new regulations like gdpr and
california's privacy law
a system like solid would make it
significantly easier
easier for companies to gather and use
data without having the weight of
administering it at all and being
responsible for constantly updated
permissions
in a blog post monday berners-lee
announced the numbers of big name
partners that will run
pilots including the bbc nat west bank
the national health service
and flanders government the pilots are
small
and the intent is to spark greater
awareness of the technology and grow
adoption big thanks to roy w nash and
our community of viewers for submitting
stories to us this week
thanks for watching the category 5 tv
newsroom
don't forget to like and subscribe for
all your tech news with a slight linux
bias and if you appreciate what we do
become a patron
at patreon.com category5
from the category 5 tv newsroom i'm
becca ferguson
[Music]
[Applause]
you