[Music]
welcome to the world of cryptos
and welcome to the crypto corner of
course um so
how was last week and if we take it our
coin gecko map
as usual then we'll see that
the market cap increased to 392 billion
two percent increase since yesterday um
so quite significant uh changes we're
seeing from week to week
same is here with most of the top
10 or uh all of those cryptocurrencies
bitcoin went up
by three percent ethereum uh almost nine
percent xrp
six percent chain link was on a run
came from nowhere to now be number five
was 27
if we sold by those seven days we found
numer in seven days
went up by 170 percent and waves 116
and on the downside we have got only a
few coins that went
lower than 15 percent nest uh was 26
percent so i'm not really worth
mentioning
now i get a lot of questions from um
from yours
that hey i'm interested in getting into
this year this is looking interesting
i want to participate in that now my
reply is yes
it's a great industry it's an
interesting interesting industry but you
have to be also really careful
on one hand as i mentioned last time
there are not many
real experts that that can talk to you
or can
give you any recommendations doesn't
exist
it's a global thing so what works here
doesn't work
in asia and the other way around and
then things like this can happen so for
example here this is a default token
decentralized finance on a 24-hour chart
it looks good
but if we increase it to 30 days this is
what happens
if you would have invested or you
listened to somebody
that recommended you to buy jams then
you would have lost a lot of money so
yeah please be careful when you do
investing
uh invest in in coins you need to do
your research now i guess i'll next time
i do talk a little bit more on how to do
a very basic research
not complicated much simpler than buying
any stocks or shares in
in a normal traditional market but at
this stage what do i recommend oh
another thing here for example
d5 which is currently the market that is
exploding
and if we look into those top ethereum
defy
applications then we see here synthetic
synthetics
has got only 5 000 users per week yeah
this is sorted by seven days
five thousand uses per seven day in
seven days that's nothing
and that's why these fluctuations are uh
are coming
and things go up and down like like
crazy
but anyway talking about how you can
participate in this year
is uh if you're completely new yeah so
you have never done any cryptos um you
don't know you know where to start
then this is an idea of what people are
doing
not recommending it but this is what
people are doing so
this is for a complete newbie that
doesn't understand much about this here
but wants to participate
so first thing is open an account with
an exchange like kraken.com or
coinbase.com
and why because they're regulated and
they accept fiat
which is important so if you've got some
u.s dollars and you want to spend them
on cryptos
these are the two places i would
recommend they're regulated so they're
serious uh companies from that point of
view
then i would uh only recommend
you going into uh the
top three coins uh so in this case it's
bitcoin ethereum or xrp
um reason being is you've got the
liquidity here
and as you've seen in the last few weeks
they've been pretty stable
uh in in regards to increases so not
much
you will not find this thing that i just
showed you with jam you will not find
that with bitcoin unless something
catastrophically happens
which is very unlikely so those only
invest in those three coins don't fall
for any trap of somebody recommending
you some weird dodgy coin don't do that
and uh and last but not least keep those
coins on an exchange
um don't come up with
uh installing a hardware drive or
software drive a software
wallet just keep them on the exchange
and you'll be good
for the time being now if you start
investing more money
it's a different animal if you stay if
you start understanding
how this whole market works it's a
different thing this is just for the
pure beginner that does not know really
where to start
so i hope that helped and thank you very
much for watching as always
and i'm looking forward to see you next
week next week i'll probably speak
more about how to do some uh
reviews on on coins because i've had a
lot of questions in that regards too
thank you have a great week bye
[Music]
you