what does a geek do
in a pandemic uh they play computer
games yes and buy
geek toys yes lots and lots of geek toys
have you bought any greek toys no no
none i i will say i have looked at many
geek toys but i have restrained myself
what you liar what
what does that say what does what say
bald nerd you literally have a mask
with an led sign board on it yeah sorry
about that
okay i'm gonna just are you loading like
a mustache or something
is it downloading i see 0 7
14 21 28 different numbers
doing lottery picks here we go
category five
[Laughter]
that's what i can do i can do all kinds
of stuff
i can get all like here's a nice
feminine mouth i can download here let's
see
if it there we go download it there
isn't that lovely
little teeth yeah yes
i'll stick with uh there we go
category five that's hilarious yeah so
i'm selling ad space on my face now
[Laughter]
so cat5 dot tv slash mask is where you
can see those
yeah it's just a little bit of fun
that's fun
[Music]
[Applause]
you