covering the week's top tech stories
with a slight linux bias
on thursday another 60 spacex satellites
were launched from the kennedy space
center in florida
to join the rest of the starlink fleet
in just the last month there have been
three successful launches and
deployments
making spacex the largest fleet of
satellites
in the world with more than 700
currently in orbit
spacex founder and ceo elon musk wants
to create a constellation made up of
thousands of starlink satellites that
can offer high-speed internet anywhere
on the planet
in march musk said that at the he said
at the satellite 2020 conference
the world seems to have an insatiable
appetite for bandwidth
we're certainly happy to launch other
satellites
if our appetite for bandwidth was
insatiable
insatiable before a global pandemic
we're even hungrier now
the plan is to ultimately create an
interconnected network of about
12 000 small satellites in low orbit
around
earth using a small dish customers will
be able to connect
and get fast internet speeds with rural
and tough to reach areas being the
primary market
spacex recently said it's building about
120 satellites a month
astronomers are concerned the extra
points of light will make it harder to
observe the night sky
analyst carmi levy says they're trying
to look at things far away in the cosmos
and you have all these pesky little
satellites orbiting in front of them
causing streaks across their imaging
spacex has responded to the concerns by
modifying its satellites to make them
less reflective
the company hopes to use starlink
internet as a way to fund the company's
version of our vision
of going to the moon and to mars spacex
says the service will first be available
in the u.s and parts of canada
public trials are expected to take place
later this year
they said friday that starlink has
already seen extraordinary demand from
potential customers
with nearly 700 000 individuals across
the united states alone
indicating they are interested in the
coming service
[Music]
you